<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>bozulich &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/bozulich/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>Book Review: Get Strong at Tesuji</title>
		<link>/book-review-get-strong-tesuji/</link>
		<comments>/book-review-get-strong-tesuji/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2013 11:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bozulich]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[get strong]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kiseido]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tesuji]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=4014</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Get Strong at Tesuji Description: In the sixth volume of the Get Strong at Go Series, Bozulich has compiled a fantastic set of tesuji problems that focus on developing a player&#8217;s intuition through practicing lots of easier problems. Though there are a few intermediate/hard problems dispersed throughout the book, this is a great book for [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/09/getstrongv6.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-4015" alt="getstrongv6" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/09/getstrongv6.jpg?resize=280%2C400" width="280" height="400" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">Get Strong at Tesuji</h2>
<p><strong>Description:</strong> In the sixth volume of the Get Strong at Go Series, Bozulich has compiled a fantastic set of tesuji problems that focus on developing a player&#8217;s intuition through practicing lots of easier problems. Though there are a few intermediate/hard problems dispersed throughout the book, this is a great book for players of all levels (especially beginnger and intermediate levels).<br />
<span id="more-4014"></span><br />
[expand title=&#8221;Book Details&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
[table]
Title, Get Strong at Tesuji<br />
Series, Get Strong at Go Series<br />
Author, Richard Bozulich<br />
Publisher, <a href="http://www.kiseido.com/">Kiseido</a><br />
Published, &#8220;First Printing September 1996 | Second Printing June 2006&#8243;<br />
Language, English<br />
ISBN, 4-906574-56-4<br />
Length, 184 Pages<br />
Problems, 534 Problems<br />
[/table]
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Table of Content&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Preface</li>
<li>Some Important Terms and Concepts</li>
<li>Tesuji Problems</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Before I Read This Book&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
Besides the common tesuji that everyone learns when they first start out playing (i.e., snapback, crane&#8217;s nest, etc.), I would have to say that I did not feel like I knew that many tesuji. In addition, I always found it very difficult to identify tesuji in the middle of an actual game. So I was hoping that this book would give me a better foothold in identifying tesuji in common shapes and positions that might arise in my games.<br />
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Synopsis&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<strong>What did I enjoy about the book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Problems have a difficulty rating to inform the players how hard the problem is.</li>
<li>The problem set is overall very accommodating to beginner and intermediate players. In fact, a few of the &#8220;advanced&#8221; problems could be even be solved by a high SDK with some ease.</li>
<li>There is a nice repetition of techniques (that are dispersed throughout the book) to allow for excellent reinforcement of the technique.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What did I gain from reading this book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>A greater comfort level with tesuji as a whole.</li>
<li>Increased confidence in my ability to identify tesuji in positions that once were obscure to me.</li>
<li>Renewed faith in my ability to eventually go back and attempt <a title="Book Review: 501 Tesuji Problems" href="//book-review-501-tesuji-problems/">501 Tesuji Problems</a> once again.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What is the format of the book?</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>A set of problems followed by their solutions and explanation. Repeat. Repeat. Repeat.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>What aspects can be improved on?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>No complaints here!</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Is this book easy to read?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Yes. Explanations and solutions are short and clear cut. In addition, the diagrams are not complicated, so the solutions are easy to follow.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Bottom Line</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>Though I was skeptical of the book at first, this book is actually very accessible to beginner and intermediate players (though a bit more towards intermediate players) who want to practice tesuji.</li>
<li>Provides a lot of opportunities for practice and reinforcement of common tesuji techniques.</li>
<li>Continues the quality of content you come to expect from the &#8220;Get Strong at Series&#8221; and is well worth the money.</li>
</ol>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;My Review&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221; expanded=&#8221;true&#8221;]
As some of you are aware, when I tried to work my way through <a title="Book Review: 501 Tesuji Problems" href="//book-review-501-tesuji-problems/">Mastering the Basics: 501 Tesuji Problems</a>, I had an incredibly difficult time getting through it (for whatever reason I stil cannot identify). And since I always thought that the &#8220;Get Strong at Series&#8221; would be considered a more advanced level than the &#8220;Mastering the Basics Series,&#8221; I was a little worried about what I might encounter. Luckily for me though, I did not let my dread delay me any longer and I am so glad that I finally got opened it up!<br />
Get Strong at Tesuji continues the tradition of being a problem book that centers around giving readers numerous opportunities to practice their skills. The problems are not categorized in any particular manner, but a new aspect to the design (that I found very helpful) is the usage of stars in order to designate the problems difficulty. The problems ranged from 1 star (easy) to 4 stars (difficult). The book primarily consists of 1 star and 2 star problems, an occasional 3 star problem, and only a handful of 4 star problems towards the very end. And for those who might be wondering how difficult the 3 star problems are, I am approximately 4 kyu at this time and found them to be manageable. So based on that analysis, it should be pretty clear that the book is actually very accessible to beginner and intermediate players.<br />
Though there is no introductory section on the techniques that are used in the book, something that I want to remind readers out there is that the concept of tesuji is to find a move that works in your favor no matter how your opponent responds. Though some techniques can be neatly categorized and labelled, it would be impossible to collectively explain every technique that might ever arise in your game. So at the end of the day, the best way to build one&#8217;s ability to find and identify tesuji is to be exposed to more ideas and examples that already exist.<br />
Overall, I am very pleased with the quality of content and level of problems that this book provided. Although I wouldn&#8217;t necessarily give this book to someone who is 20 kyu, I would highly recommend this book to any player who has had some basic knowledge to tesuji and is looking for a book on tesuji that will not overwhelm them with overly difficult problems.<br />
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Recommended For&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ol>
<li>Players looking to improve their basic abilities in identifying and using tesuji.</li>
</ol>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Where Can I Buy It?&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>GoGameGuru &#8211; <a title="Get Strong at Tesuji GoGameGuru Purchase Link" href="http://shop.gogameguru.com/get-strong-at-tesuji/?acc=e4da3b7fbbce2345d7772b0674a318d5">$20.99</a> USD (shipping and handling not included)</li>
<li>Kiseido &#8211; <a title="Kiseido Purchase Form" href="http://www.kiseido.com/go_books.htm">$21.00</a> USD (shipping and handling not included)</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Other Books in This Series&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;lastExpandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li><a title="Book Review: Get Strong at the Opening" href="//book-review-get-strong-at-the-opening/">Get Strong at the Opening</a></li>
<li><a title="Book Review: Get Strong at Joseki 1" href="//book-review-get-strong-at-joseki-1/">Get Strong at Joseki 1</a></li>
<li><a title="Book Review: Get Strong at Joseki 2" href="//book-review-get-strong-joseki-2/">Get Strong at Joseki 2</a></li>
<li><a title="Book Review: Get Strong at Joseki 3" href="//book-review-get-strong-joseki-3/">Get Strong at Joseki 3</a></li>
<li>Get Strong at Invading</li>
<li>Get Strong at Tesuji</li>
<li>Get Strong at the Endgame</li>
<li>Get Strong at Life and Death</li>
<li>Get Strong at Handicap Go</li>
<li>Get Strong at Attacking</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
<p style="text-align: center;"><em><strong>Last Updated on September 28th, 2013</strong></em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/book-review-get-strong-tesuji/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">4014</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Book Review: Get Strong at Invading</title>
		<link>/book-review-get-strong-invading/</link>
		<comments>/book-review-get-strong-invading/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2013 13:58:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bozulich]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[get strong]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[invading]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kiseido]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=4011</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Get Strong at Invading Description: In the fifth volume of the Get Strong at Go Series, Bozulich provides a ground-breaking book on a topic that every player in go encounters: invasions. Once the spheres of influences have been established, being able to choose the correct invasions is a key skill to becoming stronger and winning. [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/09/getstrongv5cover.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-4012" alt="getstrongv5cover" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/09/getstrongv5cover.jpg?resize=280%2C400" width="280" height="400" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">Get Strong at Invading</h2>
<p><strong>Description:</strong> In the fifth volume of the Get Strong at Go Series, Bozulich provides a ground-breaking book on a topic that every player in go encounters: invasions. Once the spheres of influences have been established, being able to choose the correct invasions is a key skill to becoming stronger and winning. Through 171 problems, readers will have many opportunities to practice and hone their invasion abilities.<br />
<span id="more-4011"></span><br />
[expand title=&#8221;Book Details&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
[table]
Title, Get Strong at Invading<br />
Series, Get Strong at Go Series<br />
Author, Richard Bozulich<br />
Publisher, <a href="http://www.kiseido.com/">Kiseido</a><br />
Published, &#8220;First Printing May 1995 | Second Printing January 2010&#8243;<br />
Language, English<br />
ISBN, 987-4-906574-55-1<br />
Length, 152 Pages<br />
Problems, 171 Problems<br />
[/table]
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Table of Content&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Preface</li>
<li>Part One &#8211; Invasions on the Side</li>
<li>Part Two &#8211; Invading Corner Enclosures</li>
<li>Part Three &#8211; Invading Large Territories</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Before I Read This Book&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
Since I tend to be more of a &#8220;jump before you look&#8221; type of player, I&#8217;ve played my fair share of invasions without any regards as to whether or not it would be successful or whether it even hits the weak point. So in some regards, I have developed a basic understanding of how to invade based on trial and error. However, there have been numerous times where I wished that my decisions were made with a bit more sound judgment. So when I found out about this book, I couldn&#8217;t get around to ordering it fast enough.<br />
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Synopsis&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<strong>What did I enjoy about the book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Bozulich breaks invasions up into three common categories that players encounter: corner, sides, and frameworks.</li>
<li>There are numerous opportunities to practice identifying a similar type of weakness so that you can reinforce it in your mind.</li>
<li>In addition to identifying weaknesses and common invasion points, there are numerous problems that show the reader how to handle some common responses that their opponent might play.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What did I gain from reading this book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>A greater understanding and ability to identify how stronger players identify places to invade.</li>
<li>A much better grasp of what proper follow up moves are and the reason behind them.</li>
<li>A lot of new ideas regarding how to invade what I once considered &#8220;solid territory.&#8221;</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What is the format of the book?</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>A set of problems followed by their solutions and explanation. Repeat. Repeat. Repeat.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>What aspects can be improved on?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>I&#8217;m not sure of how feasible this really is, but I think it would have been helpful if there was a one-page summary of basic invasion principles that players should keep in mind when invading.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Is this book easy to read?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Yes. Explanations and solutions are very short and clear cut. In addition, the diagrams are not very complicated, so the solutions are typically very easy to follow.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Bottom Line</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>Currently the only book (I&#8217;m aware of) that focuses exclusively on invasions.</li>
<li>Provides a great way for players to get familiar with what are considered good invasion points and how they generally proceed afterwards.</li>
<li>Highly recommended and worth the money for anyone interested in getting stronger at invading.</li>
</ol>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;My Review&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221; expanded=&#8221;true&#8221;]
When I first started playing, I remember how difficult it was for me to choose points of invasion. More often than not, I would stare at my opponent&#8217;s formation and feel so intimidated by it that I would never invade. Luckily for me, this book really helped to open my eyes in regards to where the weaknesses in popular formations are, along with the common follow-up move to make sabaki or life.<br />
The first section on &#8220;Invasions on the Side&#8221; was very informative in helping me recognize what was considered thin and where the weak points were. In addition, there are variation in the problems regarding how the opponent responds and recommended responses along with the rationale for why the result is considered acceptable. Definitely very helpful.<br />
The next section on &#8220;Invading Corner Enclosures&#8221; might be my favorite in this book. The reason for this is that I believe that kyu players often have difficulty identifying where to invade in an opponent&#8217;s corner enclosure. So more often than not, the territory is left untouched and assumed complete. By exposing players to the weaknesses and ways of living in &#8220;completed territory,&#8221; I think this will help a lot of players get stronger since they will feel better equipped to fight back when they are behind in territory.<br />
In the last section on &#8220;Invading Large Territories,&#8221; Bozulich does a great job heping readers identify weak points in very common moyo shapes. Though focused on teaching players common invasion/reduction points, it also serves as a great way to practice analyzing the board as a whole.<br />
My final piece of advice to players thinking about buying this book is this: Being able to choose the right invasion point and being able to make your invasion successful are two VERY DIFFERENT things. Aside from figuring out the proper timing, you must be aware of the fact that successful invasions involve lots of fighting and ability to make living shapes. So while this book will provide you the foundation you need for launching your invasions, just remember that there are multiple aspects to a successful invasion.<br />
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Recommended For&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ol>
<li>Players looking to strengthen their ability to invade their opponent&#8217;s positions.</li>
</ol>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Where Can I Buy It?&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>GoGameGuru &#8211; <a title="Get Strong at Invading GoGameGuru Purchase Link" href="http://shop.gogameguru.com/get-strong-at-invading/?acc=e4da3b7fbbce2345d7772b0674a318d5">$20.99</a> USD (shipping and handling not included)</li>
<li>Kiseido &#8211; <a title="Kiseido Purchase Form" href="http://www.kiseido.com/go_books.htm">$21.00</a> USD (shipping and handling not included)</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Other Books in This Series&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;lastExpandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li><a title="Book Review: Get Strong at the Opening" href="//book-review-get-strong-at-the-opening/">Get Strong at the Opening</a></li>
<li><a title="Book Review: Get Strong at Joseki 1" href="//book-review-get-strong-at-joseki-1/">Get Strong at Joseki 1</a></li>
<li><a title="Book Review: Get Strong at Joseki 2" href="//book-review-get-strong-joseki-2/">Get Strong at Joseki 2</a></li>
<li><a title="Book Review: Get Strong at Joseki 3" href="//book-review-get-strong-joseki-3/">Get Strong at Joseki 3</a></li>
<li>Get Strong at Invading</li>
<li>Get Strong at Tesuji</li>
<li>Get Strong at the Endgame</li>
<li>Get Strong at Life and Death</li>
<li>Get Strong at Handicap Go</li>
<li>Get Strong at Attacking</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
<p style="text-align: center;"><em><strong>Last Updated on September 24th, 2013.</strong></em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/book-review-get-strong-invading/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">4011</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Book Review: Get Strong at Joseki 3</title>
		<link>/book-review-get-strong-joseki-3/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2013 20:25:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bozulich]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[get strong]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[joseki]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kaz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kiseido]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[star point]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=3972</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Get Strong at Joseki 3 Description: In the fourth volume of the Get Strong at Go Series, Bozulich and Kazunari familiarizes the reader with 10 josekis that commonly occur around the star point, how to handle them in regards to their variations, choosing the correct joseki given the whole board, and how to play after [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/09/getstrongv4cover.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3973" alt="getstrongv4cover" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/09/getstrongv4cover.jpg?resize=280%2C400" width="280" height="400" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">Get Strong at Joseki 3</h2>
<p><strong>Description:</strong> In the fourth volume of the Get Strong at Go Series, Bozulich and Kazunari familiarizes the reader with 10 josekis that commonly occur around the star point, how to handle them in regards to their variations, choosing the correct joseki given the whole board, and how to play after the joseki is completed. A great book for players who want a better grasp on joseki as a whole.<br />
<span id="more-3972"></span><br />
[expand title=&#8221;Book Details&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
[table]
Title, Get Strong at Joseki 3 (Vol. 4)<br />
Series, Get Strong at Go Series<br />
Author, Richard Bozulich &amp; Furuyama Kazunari<br />
Publisher, <a href="http://www.kiseido.com/">Kiseido</a><br />
Published, &#8220;First Printing May 1996 | Second Printing August 2008&#8243;<br />
Language, English<br />
ISBN, 987-4-906574-54-4<br />
Length, 208 Pages<br />
Problems, 194 Problems<br />
[/table]
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Table of Content&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Preface</li>
<li>Introduction &#8211; Ten Basic Joseki</li>
<li>Problems Part One &#8211; Joseki Variations (Problems 1-116)</li>
<li>Problems Part Two &#8211; Choosing the Right Joseki (117-140)</li>
<li>Problems Part Three &#8211; How to Play After the Joseki (141-194)</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Before I Read This Book&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
As I mentioned before in the previous two volumes (<a title="Book Review: Get Strong at Joseki 1" href="//book-review-get-strong-at-joseki-1/">GTAJ1</a> &amp; <a title="Book Review: Get Strong at Joseki 2" href="//book-review-get-strong-joseki-2/">GTAJ2</a>), joseki is not a real strength of mine. While I have become aware of some common ones due to experience using them or making mistakes, learning joseki has always been a bit of a challenge for me. With this final volume though, I was really looking forward to seeing star point joseki be featured.<br />
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Synopsis&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<strong>What did I enjoy about the book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>I really liked the fact that Bozulich &amp; Kazunari included joseki that are not commonly found in resources like Josekipedia. An example of this include the high one space double approach.</li>
<li>I enjoy the fact that Bozulich &amp; Kazunari includes some common trick plays and how to handle them.</li>
<li>The problems contain variations on different scenarios that really help acclimate the reader to seeing how just one slight chance in the sequence can completely change the outcome.</li>
<li>There is a whole section devoted to choosing joseki in regards to the entire board.</li>
<li>Proper attention is given to how to play once a joseki is finished.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What did I gain from reading this book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>A realization that there is a lot more to start point joseki than I was aware.</li>
<li>A better understanding of some of the reasons behind why certain joseki are played.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What is the format of the book?</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>Similar to the <a title="Book Review: Get Strong at Joseki 1" href="//book-review-get-strong-at-joseki-1/">GTSAJ1</a> and <a title="Book Review: Get Strong at Joseki 2" href="//book-review-get-strong-joseki-2/">GTSAJ2</a>, there is an introduction section that familiarizes the reader with the featured joseki in the book. Afterwards, the rest are practice problems accompanied by their solutions to help the reader gain a better grasp on the joseki.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>What aspects can be improved on?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>No complaints here!</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Is this book easy to read?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Yes and no. The explanations are short and concise for those who are familiar with much of go strategy and its terminology. For those who might be unfamiliar with things such as a &#8220;severe pincer&#8221; or how moves are &#8220;pressuring another group&#8221; might find it a little hard to comprehend.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Bottom Line</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>Excellent format for players to familiarize themselves with some common star point joseki along with some not so common ones as well.</li>
<li>Gives great practice for trying to see the board as a whole instead of localized sequences.</li>
<li>A fantastic way for players to gain a better handle on using joseki instead of simply memorizing them.</li>
</ol>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;My Review&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221; expanded=&#8221;true&#8221;]
As with the previous volumes, I was very pleased overall with the quality of problems in this book. Bozulich &amp; Kazunari continued to live up to my expectations and did a great job with the star point joseki featured in this book. Just like before though, I found that the first section regarding joseki variations was still quite difficult for me to work through. To be clear though, Bozulich acknowledges that this will be common for many players at first due to unfamiliarity with the material. So it&#8217;s nothing to fret about.<br />
The favorite part of my book is still the section on &#8220;Choosing the Right Joseki and Playing the Right Joseki&#8221; since it is geared toward getting to the reader to take into account the whole board when making their decision. This is a wonderful change of scenery from the narrow perspective that players often practice on (such as focusing on just a corner or two groups for life and death). Definitely the best section of the entire series.<br />
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Recommended For&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ol>
<li>Players looking to study some common (and a couple uncommon) star point joseki and its application to actual board positions.</li>
</ol>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Where Can I Buy It?&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>GoGameGuru &#8211; <a title="Get Strong at Joseki 3 GoGameGuru Purchase Link" href="http://shop.gogameguru.com/get-strong-at-joseki-3/?acc=e4da3b7fbbce2345d7772b0674a318d5">$20.99</a> USD (shipping and handling not included)</li>
<li>Kiseido &#8211; <a title="Kiseido Purchase Form" href="http://www.kiseido.com/go_books.htm">$21.00</a> USD (shipping and handling not included)</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Other Books in This Series&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;lastExpandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li><a title="Book Review: Get Strong at the Opening" href="//book-review-get-strong-at-the-opening/">Get Strong at the Opening</a></li>
<li><a title="Book Review: Get Strong at Joseki 1" href="//book-review-get-strong-at-joseki-1/">Get Strong at Joseki 1</a></li>
<li><a title="Book Review: Get Strong at Joseki 2" href="//book-review-get-strong-joseki-2/">Get Strong at Joseki 2</a></li>
<li>Get Strong at Joseki 3</li>
<li>Get Strong at Invading</li>
<li>Get Strong at Tesuji</li>
<li>Get Strong at the Endgame</li>
<li>Get Strong at Life and Death</li>
<li>Get Strong at Handicap Go</li>
<li>Get Strong at Attacking</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
<p style="text-align: center;"><em><strong>Last Updated on September 14th, 2013.</strong></em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3972</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
