<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>game reviews &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/game-reviews/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>Get Your Game Reviewed Here!</title>
		<link>/get-your-game-reviewed-here/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2013 17:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[game reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[monday go meditation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new announcement]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=2091</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[For those who aren&#8217;t aware, I became a GoTeachingLadder reviewer some time ago; but I have yet to see a request for a review yet. Then, as fate would have it, hilbert90 made a brilliant suggestion for the upcoming Monday Go Meditations series: Why not open the reviews to the readers as well? So, without further [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For those who aren&#8217;t aware, I became a <a title="Website Review: Go Teaching Ladder" href="//website-review-go-teaching-ladder/">GoTeachingLadder</a> reviewer some time ago; but I have yet to see a request for a review yet. Then, as fate would have it, hilbert90 made a brilliant suggestion for the upcoming Monday Go Meditations series: Why not open the reviews to the readers as well?<br />
So, without further ado, I am excited to announce that:</p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">Monday Go Meditations will also feature game reviews for readers!</h2>
<p><strong>Q: What does it cost?</strong><br />
Other than submitting your game record and allowing me to use your game review in a post, it&#8217;s ABSOLUTELY FREE!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!<br />
<strong>Q: Why should I submit my game here instead of GoTeachingLadder?</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>Unless I&#8217;m out of town with no access to any internet, you can expect a turnaround within a week.</li>
<li>When your game review is posted on the blog, you might get some interesting insights from other readers!</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Q: How do I submit my game to you?</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>Use the <a title="Contact" href="//contact/">contact</a> form to submit a SGF file to me.</li>
<li>Save your game on <a title="Eidogo" href="http://www.eidogo.com/">Eidogo</a> and be sure to include the link when you send your email.</li>
</ol>
<p><span id="more-2091"></span><br />
<strong>Q: What can I expect from the game review?</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>An in-depth review that primarily focuses on the game from your perspective.</li>
<li>My thoughts on what I think you&#8217;re trying to do and other ways I might have approached the same situation.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Q: Can I include questions or comments in my game?</strong><br />
Absolutely! In fact, the more you include in your game record, the better tailored the game review will be!<br />
<strong>Q: With Monday Go Meditation being a weekly event, won&#8217;t it take awhile before I see my review?</strong><br />
Excellent point. This is why I will be making sure to send you your review beforehand if the scheduled publish date is more than a week away.<br />
<strong>Q: I&#8217;m not comfortable with people knowing it&#8217;s my game. How do you plan to mitigate that?</strong><br />
<em>Unless you specify otherwise</em>, I will make the following modifications to all games:</p>
<ol>
<li><span style="line-height: 13px;">Both players&#8217; names will be changed to Black and White respectively.</span></li>
<li>Ranks of both players will be kept (if the information is provided) in order to give more perspective on the game.</li>
<li>The date and time of the game will be removed to further anonymize the game.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Q: How will I know when my game is being featured?</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>When you submit your game record, I will send you an email confirming that I received it and an estimated time as to when it will be featured on the blog.</li>
<li>I will send you a confirmation email a week before the game review is posted to inform you of the actual publish date.</li>
<li>A final reminder email will be sent out the day the post is published.</li>
</ol>
<p>If you have any other questions or are having difficulties getting your game to me, just <a title="Contact" href="//contact/">contact</a> me and we&#8217;ll be sure to work it out together! Can&#8217;t wait to see your games!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2091</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Website Review: Go Teaching Ladder</title>
		<link>/website-review-go-teaching-ladder/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2012 17:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Websites]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[free]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[game reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lessons]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[teaching]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=1316</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Rating: 4 /5 Ponnuki Synopsis: A fantastic resource for game reviews when you don&#8217;t have time for real-time reviews. It&#8217;s FREE!!!! The reviews are not instantaneous, but what you&#8217;d expect from a volunteer based service? Detailed Review: GoTeachingLadder is a fantastic resource for players want to have their games reviewed. As it is a completely [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2012/12/goteachingladdermainpage.png"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-1317" title="Go Teaching Ladder Main Page" alt="Go Teaching Ladder Main Page Screenshot" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2012/12/goteachingladdermainpage.png?resize=497%2C364" width="497" height="364" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></h2>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">Rating: 4 /5 Ponnuki</h2>
<h3 style="text-align: left;">Synopsis:</h3>
<ul>
<li>A fantastic resource for game reviews when you don&#8217;t have time for real-time reviews.</li>
<li>It&#8217;s FREE!!!!</li>
<li>The reviews are not instantaneous, but what you&#8217;d expect from a volunteer based service?</li>
</ul>
<h3 style="text-align: left;">Detailed Review:</h3>
<p style="text-align: left;"><a title="Go Teaching Ladder Website" href="http://gtl.xmp.net/">GoTeachingLadder</a> is a fantastic resource for players want to have their games reviewed.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">As it is a completely volunteer based service, one cannot expect the same level of reviews that you might receive from strong players online; but this does not diminish the value of this website.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">The process for submitting a game for review is very simple:</p>
<ol>
<li>Click the link for submitting a game.</li>
<li>Fill out the form.</li>
<li>Verify that the information is correct.</li>
<li>Submit your request.</li>
<li>Enjoy your game review when you receive it!</li>
</ol>
<p>One of the things about GTL that makes it so effective is the fact that they allow you to ask specific questions about your game so that you can be sure those aspects are given the attention you desire. If it weren&#8217;t for this aspect, the value of the reviews would be diminished greatly.<br />
The only downside to this resource is the fact that the wait time can be up to a couple weeks at a time depending on your reviewer. While you should expect nothing less from a volunteer based site, this can diminish the value of the game reviews since you may not quite remember the lessons as vividly as shortly after the game.<br />
For more information and common questions, visit their FAQ page <a title="Go Teaching Ladder FAQ" href="http://gtl.xmp.net/about/faq">here</a>!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1316</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
