<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>focus on profit &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/focus-on-profit/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>Thou Shalt Not Kill&#8230;</title>
		<link>/thou-shalt-not-kill/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2013 22:30:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lessons]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bad habits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[focus on profit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[overly aggressive]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=1686</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Lately, I have noticed that my games have become quite violent. =D And by that, I mean that the theme of my games are: threaten to make a huge moyo, and then kill whatever comes inside of it. While it lets me know that I will win with absolute certainty if I manage to kill [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lately, I have noticed that my games have become quite violent. =D And by that, I mean that the theme of my games are: threaten to make a huge moyo, and then kill whatever comes inside of it.<br />
While it lets me know that I will win with absolute certainty if I manage to kill the group, we all know that this strategy is extremely flawed and is extremely risky. And as if the fact that you will lose most of your games trying to do this wasn&#8217;t bad enough, I just get more discouraged and frustrated as time goes on. So I know that if I continue along this path, I will end up getting fed up and dropping go for no good reason.<br />
So the goal now is to train myself to steer away from that style of play. It&#8217;s not that I will be meek and never fight back, but I will focus on giving my attacks an edge that sends my opponents running while I gain the necessary points to win. For now, I will focus on a profit oriented style instead of the killing style that I am so habituated to. So in terms of the criteria for my games for a while:</p>
<ol>
<li>I will practice attacking while gaining profit.</li>
<li><span style="line-height: 13px">I shall not kill any group unless they are forced into a shape where I am absolutely sure of its demise (e.g., bent in three).</span></li>
</ol>
<p>And to continue a new tradition that frozensoul recommended to me, I will start a repetition exercise of writing any new go lesson I am trying to learn fifty times. By doing so, I&#8217;m hoping that it will sink it better than simply reading once and trying to remember amidst a game.<br />
<figure id="attachment_1687" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/01/lesson3.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1687" alt="&quot;Focus on profit, not killing.&quot;" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/01/lesson3.jpg?resize=300%2C225" width="300" height="225" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">&#8220;Focus on profit, not killing.&#8221;</figcaption></figure>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1686</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
