<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>challenge &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/challenge/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>Taking This Slump Head On</title>
		<link>/taking-slump-head/</link>
		<comments>/taking-slump-head/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2014 16:50:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[challenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[motivation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quote]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[risk]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5492</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The first thing I want to write is that I really appreciate the numerous words of support that have been flooding in. It&#8217;s been great to hear from everyone and to hear everyone&#8217;s perspectives on things. In addition, the feedback has helped reassure me that my return to the more journalistic-type blogging was the correct [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The first thing I want to write is that I really appreciate the numerous words of support that have been flooding in. It&#8217;s been great to hear from everyone and to hear everyone&#8217;s perspectives on things. In addition, the feedback has helped reassure me that my return to the more journalistic-type blogging was the correct choice.<br />
I&#8217;m not feeling much better today. In fact, in a number of ways I&#8217;m feeling worse due to other things happening in life. However, the one thing I wanted to write about were my thoughts on how I&#8217;ve been dealing with this time of turmoil and downfall.<br />
As most of you suggested, taking a break is certainly one of the most viable options out there. However, there are three reasons why I am taking the high road on this one:</p>
<ol>
<li>Yunguseng Dojang is still a going on (weekly) and the matches will not be stopping just because I&#8217;m in a slump.</li>
<li>Most players I know approach this by taking a break, but I haven&#8217;t heard of anyone try to muscle through it instead and be successful.</li>
<li>I feel a strong determination to try and see this through to the end so I can find out whether or not I&#8217;m delusional or not.</li>
</ol>
<p>Of course, I recognize that my method has a risk of extreme/permanent burnout since I&#8217;m already at a low point; but in case you don&#8217;t know this about me, I&#8217;m quite the risk taker when it comes to these kinds of challenges. So I&#8217;m going to take this slump head on, regardless of what obstacles await me.<br />
And paraphrasing from the new wallpaper on my phone:</p>
<blockquote><p>When things get tough, remember you are tougher.</p></blockquote>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/taking-slump-head/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>13</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">5492</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Burnt Out and Quitting Go</title>
		<link>/burnt-out-and-quitting-go/</link>
		<comments>/burnt-out-and-quitting-go/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 18:18:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[april fools]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[challenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[go congress]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[preparation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[time to get serious]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=4859</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[APRIL FOOLS!!!!! xD To be honest, I had no intentions of pranking anyone or anything; but then I started drafting a post for today and then the idea just came to me. So&#8230; *bursts of laughing* you&#8217;ll have to forgive me for trolling you a little bit. (By the way, got to love that GIF. [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_4860" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/justkidding.gif"><img class="size-full wp-image-4860" alt="justkidding" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/justkidding.gif?resize=300%2C237" width="300" height="237" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Credit to <a href="http://giphy.com/gifs/11RUijoqnc1yJW">Giphy</a></figcaption></figure>
<h2 style="text-align: center;"><strong>APRIL FOOLS!!!!! xD</strong></h2>
<p>To be honest, I had no intentions of pranking anyone or anything; but then I started drafting a post for today and then the idea just came to me. So&#8230; *bursts of laughing* you&#8217;ll have to forgive me for trolling you a little bit. (By the way, got to love that GIF. Captures how I&#8217;m feeling perfectly. Cracks me up.)<br />
Anyways&#8230; on a more serious note, today marks the beginning of April and thus a chance to start fresh as the official countdown to <a title="Go Congress Official Site" href="http://www.gocongress.org/">Go Congress</a> begins. Yup&#8230; I&#8217;ve registered. I haven&#8217;t paid yet since I want to make sure that nothing on the schedule alters my plans, but it&#8217;s practically set in stone.<br />
Since this is my first Go Congress, I&#8217;m really hoping to go there with a bang. In order to really reinvigorate my training in preparation for Go Congress, I&#8217;ve started:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Re-watching <a title="Hikaru no Go Wikipedia " href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hikaru_no_Go">Hikaru No Go</a> </strong>&#8211; It&#8217;s always good to start back with one of the most inspiring stories of all go stories.</li>
<li> <strong>Joined <a title="Yunguseng Dojang Official Site" href="http://www.yunguseng.com/">Yunguseng Dojang</a> </strong>&#8211; This is essentially an online insei program (from what I understand). My friend Diego has told me good things about it, so I&#8217;ve decided to give it a shot!</li>
<li><strong>Becoming super-disciplined about my tsumego training</strong> &#8211; In my last few games I&#8217;ve played on KGS, I&#8217;ve been reminded just how important reading is and how it can completely change the tide of the game when you&#8217;re able to read just one step further than your opponent.</li>
<li><strong>Working a lot harder on the blog</strong> &#8211; I know this might seem totally unrelated to my growth. And to some, it&#8217;ll hinder my progress as a player. However, the blog is something that I&#8217;ve come to really enjoy and has helped me be accountable for my own journey as a go player. Definitely do not regret any of the time I&#8217;ve spent on it!</li>
</ol>
<p>With that said, I also wanted to give a quick shoutout to <a title="Maaike's Twitter" href="https://twitter.com/My8ke">Maaike</a> and her <a title="Maaike's April Challenge Post" href="http://thegochallenge.blogspot.com/2014/04/april-challenge.html?utm_source=twitterfeed&amp;utm_medium=twitter">April Challenge</a>! Her April Challenge is to &#8220;get our of your comfort zone.&#8221; So, for this month, <strong>my challenge will be to play a territorial style and avoid a moyo style!</strong> I think that should be a good one right? (If you have a better one for me, please let me know!)<br />
Hope you all are doing well and don&#8217;t get pranked too much today!<br />
<em>PS. I haven&#8217;t forgotten about my Hong Kong posts. They are just taking a lot longer than anticipated.</em><br />
<em>PPS. One last thing, I&#8217;ll be releasing another combo review with frozensoul on the third jubango game next Wednesday (4/9), so be sure to be on a lookout for it!</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/burnt-out-and-quitting-go/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">4859</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
