<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>asr &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/asr/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>A Look Back at February</title>
		<link>/a-look-back-at-february/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2013 22:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[asr]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[february]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[monthly overview]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[study group kyu tournament]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=2125</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[For those who are wondering how my studies of Korean go have gone, while I did not finish all the material that I originally set out to do, I have learned that Korean go is centered on fighting. I know that many people will say that they already knew this, but I will tell you [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For those who are wondering how my studies of Korean go have gone, while I did not finish all the material that I originally set out to do, I have learned that Korean go is centered on fighting. I know that many people will say that they already knew this, but I will tell you that experiencing it firsthand is an entirely separate matter. It wasn&#8217;t until I was being pummeled by 5 dans on Tygem and studying the material they use that I began to really see the impressive feats Korean style go can accomplish. It will definitely become a useful weapon in my arsenal against the calmer players I have seen on KGS.<br />
As March is literally right around the corner, I will have you know that I am now taking a free style approach to my training. If I feel motivated or excited to study something, that is precisely what I will study. I won&#8217;t feel obligated to begrudgingly finish a book because I started it. The only thing I will maintain consistently however, are my life and death problems. That will be the only aspect that will never change.<br />
With my success at rising to the Alpha class in <a href="http://www.advancedstudyroom.com/">ASR</a>, I have also decided that it is time for me to drop the league for now. I will be turning my attention towards playing more ranked games so that I can find out how much I have grown over these last couple of months. In addition, I&#8217;ve decided to join the <a href="http://studygroupkyutournament.webs.com/">Study Group Kyu tournament</a> to see how my skills match up against other SDK&#8217;s. Since I will only be playing each opponent once, it should be less time consuming and may even give me a chance to play more ranked games as well.<br />
Though it seems like just yesterday when I was attending the <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 1" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-1/">NAGC</a>, it has been an exciting month where the experiences and adventures I&#8217;ve had this month will certainly serve as a critical milestone for me. Looking forward to what March will bring!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2125</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Back in Business!</title>
		<link>/back-in-business/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2012 17:30:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kifu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[asr]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[defeat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[even game]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=1137</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;m not sure if anyone else feels this way, but there&#8217;s just something about playing an even game with someone much stronger than you that tends to bring out the best moves in you. And although I did not know this at the time, my game with Tilwen is what I needed to regain my [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;m not sure if anyone else feels this way, but there&#8217;s just something about playing an even game with someone much stronger than you that tends to bring out the best moves in you. And although I did not know this at the time, my game with Tilwen is what I needed to regain my composure and leave behind the reckless go I had been playing.<br />

<div id='glift_display1' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display1","sgf":"http:\/\/bengozen.com\/\/wp-content\/uploads\/2012\/11\/2012.11.26-Im-Back-Baby.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='//wp-content/uploads/2012/11/2012.11.26-Im-Back-Baby.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">[download label=&#8221;Download Kifu&#8221;]//wp-content/uploads/2012/11/2012.11.26-Im-Back-Baby.sgf[/download]
<p style="text-align: left;">After the game was over, Tilwen gave a fantastic review that really opened my eyes regarding vital concepts that I never quite grasped:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><strong>#1. Attack from far away.</strong></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><strong>#2. Contact moves are for defense.</strong></p>
<p>This may be common sense for many of you, but I assure you that the simplicity of the concepts never occurred to me throughout my study of go. Perhaps it was simply the reinforcement I needed after much studying, but his explanations of these concepts really helped to solidify the concepts. For those who still find these concepts difficult to grasp, just read it over a few time for familiarity and I assure you that I will write an article on these to better clarify them for you.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Many thanks again to Tilwen for his help and advice!</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1137</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Return to ASR League</title>
		<link>/return-to-asr-league/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2012 14:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kifu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[asr]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[baduk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[go]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weiqi]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=37</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[For my debut back in the ASR League, I am slightly embarrassed to report that my return to the stage was far less than spectacular. It&#8217;s not so much that I played terribly, it&#8217;s just that I ended up fighting out a ko battle that was very good for my opponent. To illustrate it a [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For my debut back in the ASR League, I am slightly embarrassed to report that my return to the stage was far less than spectacular. It&#8217;s not so much that I played terribly, it&#8217;s just that I ended up fighting out a ko battle that was very good for my opponent.<br />
<span id="more-37"></span><br />

<div id='glift_display2' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display2","sgf":"http:\/\/bengozen.com\/\/wp-content\/uploads\/2012\/08\/2012.08.24-Return-to-ASR-League.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='//wp-content/uploads/2012/08/2012.08.24-Return-to-ASR-League.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
To illustrate it a little more clearly for those who don&#8217;t have time to go through the game, it was a ko battle for my group&#8217;s connectivity while his group was perfectly alive. In the words of Janice Kim, it was a &#8220;picnic ko battle&#8221; for him.<br />
What did I think I was doing? I thought I was threatening to kill the lower right group&#8230;<br />
<strong>Ben&#8217;s Go Fundamental Rule #894 &#8211; Make sure that the group you&#8217;re trying to kill actually can be killed and doesn&#8217;t already have two eyes&#8230;</strong><br />
For higher level players, I know that getting cut off would&#8217;ve been bad news for black either way and this ko battle was probably necessary&#8230; but that wasn&#8217;t what I intended, so it&#8217;s still a red mark in my books.<br />
Did I mention that I seem to be a SDK now?<br />
For shame&#8230; for shame&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">37</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Three Months</title>
		<link>/three-months/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2010 17:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kifu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[asr]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[go]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[progress update]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[slate and shell stones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weiqi]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=49</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Happy 3 months to my Go Quest! Time for the monthly progress update! Major Highlights: KGS &#8211; 12k I joined the ASR League. I&#8217;m officially done with buying Go books for now. I finally broke down and bought a slate and shell set. =D Specifics: Go Ability &#8211; So I&#8217;m still 12k on KGS, but [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Happy 3 months to my Go Quest! Time for the monthly progress update!<br />
<span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>Major Highlights:</strong></span></p>
<ol>
<li>KGS &#8211; 12k</li>
<li>I joined the ASR League.</li>
<li>I&#8217;m officially done with buying Go books for now.</li>
<li>I finally broke down and bought a slate and shell set. =D</li>
</ol>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>Specifics:</strong></span></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><strong>Go Ability</strong> &#8211; So I&#8217;m still 12k on KGS, but I&#8217;m pretty sure that number is now definitely inaccurate. I can&#8217;t really say if I&#8217;ve hit the SDK ability, but I know that the handicaps I&#8217;ve been getting lately aren&#8217;t exactly fair to my opponents. Yesterday I played a 4k with a 6 stones handicap and managed to win by resignation. Below you will find a game against a 6k opponent at 6 stones handicap where I would have won by ~60 some points.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">
<div id='glift_display3' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display3","sgf":"http:\/\/bengozen.com\/\/wp-content\/uploads\/2010\/11\/2010.11.08-Three-Months.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='//wp-content/uploads/2010/11/2010.11.08-Three-Months.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><strong>ASR</strong> <strong>League</strong> &#8211; This is an advanced study group for people serious about getting stronger at go and definitely gives off the whole insei atmosphere. In terms of how I&#8217;m doing, I&#8217;m getting totally demolished and will probably remain in the lowest class for a while. I will post more about this league so other players will get a chance to know more about it.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><strong>Go Library</strong> &#8211; So I&#8217;ve bought a few more books since the last update. I think I&#8217;ll try to simply update the blog to be up to date with my current inventory so people can see what I have and what they might want to see reviewed.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><strong>Slate and Shell Stones Set</strong> &#8211; I know I know&#8230; everyone must be thinking I have lots of money to burn. Not true. I sold off some of my Magic: the Gathering cards and made ~$300. And I wanted that whole classical Go atmosphere which I thought would be achieved with slate and shell stones. Now mind you, they are only jitsuyo grade but there is an argument that they are better since they have more interesting patterns. Anyhow, it was $200 cheaper. That helped a lot too.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>Next Month:</strong></span><br />
So in a broad sense of goals, I&#8217;ll be aiming to be officially SDK in terms of KGS standards. In addition, I&#8217;ll be aiming to create a much more solid content base for the blog. Those two goals combined with staying on top of my grades and the rest of my life should be adequate for growth. Onwards!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">49</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
