<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>The Important Thing to Remember</title>
		<link>/the-important-thing-to-remember/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=6321</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hey everyone. As I&#8217;m sure you&#8217;ve noticed, the weekly posts have not gotten to the point where they are coming out weekly just yet. And to be honest, while I found that initially discouraging, I had to remind myself that the important thing to remember is that go is now a part of my regular [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hey everyone. As I&#8217;m sure you&#8217;ve noticed, the weekly posts have not gotten to the point where they are coming out weekly just yet. And to be honest, while I found that initially discouraging, I had to remind myself that the important thing to remember is that go is now a part of my regular life.</p>
<p>What does this mean exactly?</p>
<ul>
<li>I&#8217;m doing tsumego daily. The amount varies from time to time, but it&#8217;s usually a small batch of ten to twenty-five at a time</li>
<li>Much to the chagrin of my good friend Nate, I&#8217;m playing correspondence games which allows me to going a long time without playing a game.</li>
<li>I walk by my go board that I set up by my desk and occasionally play out a professional game when I need to get out of my head a bit.</li>
</ul>
<p>It&#8217;s not perfect, but it&#8217;s a hell a lot better than before when I would get discouraged from starting the blog up again cause I couldn&#8217;t keep up the pace I used to. After all, as many go players will tell you, this journey is an endless one. So if you remember anything, it&#8217;s that that the name of the game is progress and nothing else.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">6321</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Monday Go Meditation: Game 77</title>
		<link>/monday-go-meditation-game-77/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2018 14:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Commentaries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Monday Go Meditation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blitz go]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kifu]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=6307</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Introduction So what you&#8217;ll probably notice first is that my rank in this game is a lot lower than you might expect. This is because my OGS rank is super outdated as I never played many games and lost a few games due to time around the time I took a break. That said, it [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>Introduction</h2>
<p>So what you&#8217;ll probably notice first is that my rank in this game is a lot lower than you might expect. This is because my OGS rank is super outdated as I never played many games and lost a few games due to time around the time I took a break.</p>
<p><span id="more-6307"></span></p>
<p>That said, it was a blitz game and man I forgot how antsy those made me. I played one previous to this with 10 seconds time and that was one full of mistakes. This one was 30 seconds and also pretty bad, but I thought I would post it nonetheless since there are still things to learn from it. Enjoy!</p>

<div id='glift_display1' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display1","sgf":"http:\/\/bengozen.com\/wp-content\/uploads\/2018\/03\/2018.03.26-MGM-77.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/2018.03.26-MGM-77.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>One Point Lesson</h2>
<p>In blitz go, be prepared to prove you know what you&#8217;re doing because your opponent will test you time and time again&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">6307</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Weekly Go Progress: Week #15</title>
		<link>/weekly-go-progress-week-15/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 22:32:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Progress Reports]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=6305</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Overview I have to say that if you asked me two weeks ago whether or not I&#8217;d be in the midst of getting the go blog back and running, I would have told you that you were crazy because I was in the middle of five other things. Nonetheless, here we are and I&#8217;m very [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>Overview</h2>
<p>I have to say that if you asked me two weeks ago whether or not I&#8217;d be in the midst of getting the go blog back and running, I would have told you that you were crazy because I was in the middle of five other things. Nonetheless, here we are and I&#8217;m very happy to be back in the thick of things.</p>
<p>This week has been focused on simply getting reacquainted with everything again. That means figuring out the apps I&#8217;m using to train, books to read, styles to study, trends I missed, and other things as well. That said, it&#8217;s been wonderful seeing familiar faces in the community again and I can&#8217;t wait to settle into another step towards gaining that next stone.</p>
<h2>Training Regimen</h2>
<ul>
<li>Review a professional game every one to two days</li>
<li>Practice about 20-30 basic / easy go problems every day</li>
<li>Studying with frozensoul</li>
</ul>
<h2>Games</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://online-go.com/user/view/549/BenGoZen">OGS</a> &#8211;  3 ongoing games</li>
</ul>
<h2>Currently Reading</h2>
<ul>
<li>Commented Games by Lee Sedol, Vol. 3 by Lee Sedol 9P and Lee Sena</li>
<li>Positional Judgment by Cho-Chikun 9P</li>
</ul>
<h2>Reflections</h2>
<ol>
<li>With the incredible development in AI, it&#8217;s fascinating to see the entire world of go now being thrown into a new exploration of creativity as things once deemed &#8220;bad moves&#8221; are now being seen in a new light.</li>
</ol>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">6305</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Monday Go Meditation: Game 76</title>
		<link>/monday-go-meditation-game-76/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2018 03:59:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Commentaries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kifu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Monday Go Meditation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iyama-yuta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[park-jeong-hwan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pro game review]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=6296</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Introduction To be honest, I didn&#8217;t expect to release a Monday Go Meditation so quickly; but it seems that the universe had something else in mind. I happened to run across a tweet from @TheGoMovie regarding the Go World Championship final between Park Jeong-Hwan (9p) and Iyama Yuta (9p) that I couldn&#8217;t resist clicking on. [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 style="text-align: center;">Introduction</h2>
<p>To be honest, I didn&#8217;t expect to release a Monday Go Meditation so quickly; but it seems that the universe had something else in mind. I happened to run across a tweet from <a href="https://twitter.com/thegomovie">@TheGoMovie</a> regarding the Go World Championship final between Park Jeong-Hwan (9p) and Iyama Yuta (9p) that I couldn&#8217;t resist clicking on. Next thing I know, I&#8217;m watching the game and deciding I might as well take the opportunity to comment on it as I watched. Enjoy!</p>

<div id='glift_display2' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display2","sgf":"http:\/\/bengozen.com\/wp-content\/uploads\/2018\/03\/2018.03.19-MGM-76.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/2018.03.19-MGM-76.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">One Point Lesson</h2>
<blockquote><p>Treating stones lightly in order to develop whole board strategy is key to getting stronger.</p></blockquote>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">6296</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Return to Tengen</title>
		<link>/return-to-tengen/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 00:30:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=6283</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s been well over fifteen months, but it seems it was time for me to come back from the abyss. And I have to say, it feels good to be back. First Things First I wanted to start by apologizing for leaving the blog in the state that it was before I left. In my [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s been well over fifteen months, but it seems it was time for me to come back from the abyss. And I have to say, it feels good to be back.</p>
<p><span id="more-6283"></span></p>
<h2>First Things First</h2>
<p>I wanted to start by apologizing for leaving the blog in the state that it was before I left. In my previous attempt to leave the WordPress ecosystem, I ended up breaking a lot of old functionality and caused a bit of a mess. I&#8217;m not quite sure how I&#8217;ll be going about fixing it at this time, but know that it&#8217;s a priority of mine to do so in the coming months.</p>
<h2>Why I&#8217;m Back</h2>
<p>To be honest, I&#8217;ve always been keeping an eye on the go world from afar. So it never really left my mind, but part of me always wondered when it would be time to return to the game.</p>
<p>For all those who have read my blog and commented while I was gone, thank you for those little reminders of how much I enjoyed running this blog. Each question and comment certainly helped to slowly pull me back.</p>
<p>That said, I think the straw that broke the camel&#8217;s back was seeing the announcement for <a href="http://www.gocongress.org/">Go Congress</a> 2018. As it just so happens, it&#8217;s happening pretty close to where I live. So I couldn&#8217;t help but look back at my old Go Congress posts and it brought back a wave of nostalgia that made me consider whether I would try to attend it this year.</p>
<p>As you might guess, I&#8217;m most likely going to be attending it this year. Haha.</p>
<h2>Final Thoughts</h2>
<p>My plan for now is to start fixing the infrastructure that made it difficult for me to blog at the time of the redesign. I&#8217;ll try to and post as often as I can, but until the infrastructure is fixed, I know that will serve as a pretty major impediment for me.</p>
<p>Until then, hope everyone has been well and I look forward to talking and playing with you all again! And if you have any pressing features that you think I should fix sooner rather than later, please let me know!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">6283</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Back to My Roots</title>
		<link>/back-to-my-roots/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2016 20:29:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=6286</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[As some of you may have heard, GoGameGuru published a post today that talks about going back to its roots. And while I&#8217;d never compare my work to the accomplishments of David and his team, the post resonated with me. When I first started this blog, I saw it as a way to track my [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As some of you may have heard, <a href="https://gogameguru.com/roots/">GoGameGuru published a post today</a> that talks about going back to its roots. And while I&#8217;d never compare my work to the accomplishments of David and his team, the post resonated with me.</p>
<p><span id="more-6286"></span></p>
<p>When I first started this blog, I saw it as a way to track my progress and as a journal for people to read. Over time, I tested out different ideas: Monday Go Meditation, Thursday Go Tygem, Friday Go Forward, etc. And not to mention, I was in graduate school and had way more free time on my hands than I do now.</p>
<p>There is and always will be a part of me that wishes I could devote all my time and energy to go. Upon reflection, that idealistic desire of being all or nothing has been my problem all along. And this not only applies to go, but other things in my life as well.</p>
<p>If life is the 19&#215;19 board we are all so familiar with, I realized that the boundaries are not static nor permanent. It would be much simpler if things would stay the same, but that&#8217;s not how my life is. As someone who always seeks new experiences, it&#8217;s only natural that my interests are diverse. What was once a corner I thought I had complete control over can become center territory with an exposed side ready to come under attack at any point.</p>
<p>To clarify though, I&#8217;m not saying that my weekly posts will never return; but they&#8217;ll be on hiatus for a while. Or well, at least while I&#8217;m putting back the foundation of this blog together.</p>
<p>So until then, look forward to a return of organic posts that sprout from random thoughts and encounters in go!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">6286</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Monday Go Meditation: Game 72</title>
		<link>/monday-go-meditation-game-72/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2016 01:54:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Kifu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Monday Go Meditation]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://box2018.temp.domains/~bengozen/?p=6017</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[What you have before you is not a game of miraculous play or some game I&#8217;m particularly proud of. Instead, this is evidence of someone who has simply taken the first steps to playing once again. One Point Lesson As far as lessons learned, it is this: No matter how much weaker your opponent might [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>What you have before you is not a game of miraculous play or some game I&#8217;m particularly proud of. Instead, this is evidence of someone who has simply taken the first steps to playing once again.</p>

<div id='glift_display3' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display3","sgf":"http:\/\/box2018.temp.domains\/~bengozen\/wp-content\/uploads\/2018\/03\/2016.03.29-MGM-72.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='http://box2018.temp.domains/~bengozen/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/2016.03.29-MGM-72.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>One Point Lesson</h2>
<p>As far as lessons learned, it is this: No matter how much weaker your opponent might be, there is always an opportunity to learn from each of your moves. Just because you dominated does not mean that your game was perfect and without fault.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">6017</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Off In Development World&#8230;</title>
		<link>/off-in-development-world/</link>
		<comments>/off-in-development-world/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2015 23:07:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5990</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[As some of you are aware, I&#8217;ve gone off the deep end into the software development world. I&#8217;ll be taking a longer sabbatical than anticipated; but you&#8217;ll still be able to catch me for a game of go or discussion on things you can do to progress! So feel free to email me whenever and [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As some of you are aware, I&#8217;ve gone off the deep end into the software development world. I&#8217;ll be taking a longer sabbatical than anticipated; but you&#8217;ll still be able to catch me for a game of go or discussion on things you can do to progress! So feel free to email me whenever and draw me out to a game on KGS whenever, because I could sure use the distraction.<br />
Meanwhile, best of luck to everyone on their games and their progress. I definitely look forward to seeing how much everyone has grown by the time I come back! Ganbatte!<br />
P.S. If you&#8217;d like to keep up with what I&#8217;m up to, I&#8217;ve created a new <a href="http://www.twitter.com/bencodezen">Twitter</a> devoted to my development and UX exploits. Until then everyone!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/off-in-development-world/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">5990</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Encountering My First Chess Advocate</title>
		<link>/encountering-my-first-chess-advocate/</link>
		<comments>/encountering-my-first-chess-advocate/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2015 01:19:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chess vs go]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[enjoyment]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5984</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Today at work I was talking to my co-worker and was scoffed at when he found out I played go. &#8220;Who plays go?!&#8221; he exclaimed. I tried to then jump into a mini-speech on its complexity; but he shut me down pretty quickly by dismissing me and saying that chess was much more complex and [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Today at work I was talking to my co-worker and was scoffed at when he found out I played go.<br />
&#8220;Who plays go?!&#8221; he exclaimed.<br />
I tried to then jump into a mini-speech on its complexity; but he shut me down pretty quickly by dismissing me and saying that chess was much more complex and the only reason why go is as &#8220;mysterious&#8221; as it seems to be is because it essentially hasn&#8217;t had the same exposure here in the Western world. And given enough time, it would be clear that chess was clearly the harder game.<br />
To be honest, I was rather baffled and shocked. I had encountered my fair share of chess vs go arguments, but this was the first time I&#8217;d encountered it in person (and with such vigor as well). Sadly I was too shaken by the encounter to really try and convince him otherwise. (To give some context, he is very intelligent and is extremely knowledgeable about a lot of things. So in other words, I wasn&#8217;t going to win him over with any sort of uplifting speech about go.)<br />
As I sit here thinking about it, I do want to write about my personal take on the chess vs go debate and why I chose go; but that is for another time. For now, what I will say is that I think that trying to argue that one is superior over another is like saying one is better off learning one instrument over another. You can spend all day arguing over minutiae of how one instrument might give better coordination than another; but what really matters at the end of the day is as simple as which one gives you real joy. And if you have that, that is enough to make one thing better for you than another.<br />
Just my two cents.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/encountering-my-first-chess-advocate/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>38</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">5984</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Monday Go Meditation: Game 71</title>
		<link>/monday-go-meditation-game-71/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2015 11:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Commentaries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kifu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[9x9]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[black]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[influence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[resign]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[victory]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5980</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Introduction For this week&#8217;s meditation, we are going to start off nice and easy with a 9&#215;9 game I played on GoQuest a week or so ago. It&#8217;s not too crazy in regards to fighting, but is a great example of how powerful influence can be on such a small board. Hope that you enjoy [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>Introduction</h2>
<p>For this week&#8217;s meditation, we are going to start off nice and easy with a 9&#215;9 game I played on GoQuest a week or so ago. It&#8217;s not too crazy in regards to fighting, but is a great example of how powerful influence can be on such a small board. Hope that you enjoy the game and the commentary!<br />
<span id="more-5980"></span><br />
<iframe id="gokibitz-NkVFPJrM" style="width: 100%; min-height: 500px; display: block; border: 10px solid snow;" src="//gokibitz.com/kifu/NkVFPJrM" width="300" height="150"></iframe><script src="//gokibitz.com/embed/NkVFPJrM"></script></p>
<h2 style="text-align: left;">One Point Lesson</h2>
<p style="text-align: left;">Never hesitate to take influence early on when playing on a small board, it is more powerful than you probably realize.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">5980</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
