<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>origin &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/origin/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>Enter the Eagle</title>
		<link>/enter-the-eagle/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2012 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kifu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Weekly Go Wednesday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[baduk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[go]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kifu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[origin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weiqi]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=30</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Weekly Go Wednesday, Issue #1 Welcome to the start of my Weekly Go Wednesday (WGW) series! This purpose of this series is to add some excitement to the middle of the week, so that before you know it, it&#8217;ll be the weekend again! If you have any requests or would like to be a guest [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 style="text-align: center;"><em>Weekly Go Wednesday, Issue #1</em></h2>
<p style="text-align: left;"><em>Welcome to the start of my Weekly Go Wednesday (WGW) series! This purpose of this series is to add some excitement to the middle of the week, so that before you know it, it&#8217;ll be the weekend again! If you have any requests or would like to be a guest writer on this series, be sure to let me know!</em></p>
<p>Unlike the games I&#8217;ve posted so far, today&#8217;s opponent has a bit of history that deserves to be recorded down for the ages to come. For those who want to check out the game commentary beforehand, go ahead and scroll down to the bottom before settling down with a hot beverage for a tale of a chance encounter that has been a big impact in my life ever since.<br />
<span id="more-30"></span></p>
<h3 style="padding-left: 30px;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>Enter the Eagle</strong></span></h3>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">When I had just begun to become immerse in the world of go, I decided that even though I was stuck in DDK land, I would try and get private lessons. Looking back on it, I shake my head and laugh at myself since I had not even taken the time to properly learn the basics, and there I was trying to get private lessons. Anyhow, during my first lesson, my go teacher happened to mention that one of his students was around the same strength as I. Needless to say, as a new and enthusiastic player, I was thrilled at the idea of being able to play in person with someone around the same strength as me. After all, online go is fun; but it doesn&#8217;t come close to the enjoyment of being able to play on a real board with real stones.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">Unfortunately, that would be my last lesson due to financial constraints; but coincidentally, my go teacher also went to one of the local go clubs to teach/review games. I had not attended club meetings as consistently as I would have liked, but I decided to go on one of his teaching nights. My go teacher had mentioned that the player he had mentioned might be attending that night, but let&#8217;s just say that I was not prepared for what the night would bring.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">With my eagerness to meet this player, I couldn&#8217;t help but nervously scoping out the attendees in an attempt to figure out who it was. I can&#8217;t quite remember who attended that night, but one thing I&#8217;m utterly clear on is that I saw an American guy there with a motorcycle helmet and related gear. I remember looking over at him and thinking, &#8220;Whoa! What is a guy like him doing here?!&#8221; And this wasn&#8217;t in a bad way at all, in fact it was more of a &#8220;What is a cool guy doing here?! And wait a second, he&#8217;s staring at the go board intently?! What&#8217;s going on?!?!?!&#8221; After all, in all my naivety for being new to the go scene, I just had this mental image of all go players being skinny Asian guys who were a bit shy and reserved. In fact, I half expected to meet a little kid that night who would be around my rank and then promptly school me.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">The night went by with everyone huddled around the board as my go teacher went over games and questions. After all was said and done, in the midst of goodbyes with my go teacher, he signaled for the cool motorcycle guy to come on over, and as you might have guessed&#8230; this was the player he told me about. Needless to say, I was flabbergasted&#8230; although I did my best not to show it in my face. Haha.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">Since then, there have been many go games and adventures which would take many more blog posts for me to properly recount. Although I would have to say that one of the major highlights was getting to eat at this incredible ramen place&#8230;. what I would give to have a bowl of that right now&#8230; sigh&#8230;.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">Delicious food aside, he has not only served as a fantastic rival (who has trounced me time and time again); but a valued friend that I look forward to knowing for a long time.</p>
<p>That being said, we began a weekly tradition of playing each other once a week, and this game is the first that I have posted since well&#8230; the other ones were pretty miserable. In fact, I&#8217;ll probably post some of those up in the future when I do a series on lessons that DDK players can learn from.<br />

<div id='glift_display1' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display1","sgf":"http:\/\/bengozen.com\/\/wp-content\/uploads\/2012\/09\/2012.09.26-Enter-the-Eagle.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='//wp-content/uploads/2012/09/2012.09.26-Enter-the-Eagle.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">[download label=&#8221;Download Kifu&#8221;]//wp-content/uploads/2012/09/2012.09.26-Enter-the-Eagle.sgf[/download]
<p>Overall, I felt that this game was a sign of even greater games to come. Even though I lost a major group towards the middle of the game, I feel that it was a sign of growth to know that the game was not yet over. And with the proper fighting spirit, I&#8217;d be able to make it a decently close game. Hopefully, you&#8217;ll feel that I managed to do so as well. Till next week!<br />
&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">30</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Prologue</title>
		<link>/prologue/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2010 03:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bengozen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[origin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prologue]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=145</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[To begin, I think every story deserves an introduction as to how it all began. As a child, I have always been fascinated with the yin-yang symbol and the concepts it embodied. As one may predict, any pattern that even slightly resembled the yin-yang would peak my interest (even the basic color combination of black [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>To begin, I think every story deserves an introduction as to how it all began.<br />
As a child, I have always been fascinated with the yin-yang symbol and the concepts it embodied. As one may predict, any pattern that even slightly resembled the yin-yang would peak my interest (even the basic color combination of black and white). Anyhow, one day (like many others), I came across the widely acclaimed Go manga known as Hikaru no Go.<br />
The funny thing is that the main thing that caught my eye about this series was the fact that the protagonist seemed to have a black and white hair combination (aka yin-yang reminder). Anyone who has watched the actual anime (or looked at the image above) will know that Hikaru (the protagonist) actually has blonde and black hair (and that I&#8217;m an idiot because all manga&#8217;s are drawn in black and white&#8230;.).<br />
Regardless, the manga definitely sparked my interest in Go. Even though my brother (who coincidentally at this time started taking the Go culture class at Chinese School) and I attempted to start learning the game at this time, it wouldn&#8217;t be until after I entered and graduated college to begin taking another look into it.<br />
It wasn&#8217;t until just a month ago when I was watching <span style="text-decoration: underline;">Criminal Minds</span> (Season 1: Episode &#8211; Extreme Aggressor) that I would see the following clip:</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='720' height='405' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/POCtnn4BsC8?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;fs=1&#038;autohide=2&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;wmode=transparent' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;'></iframe>
<p>For those unaware of my background, anything to do with psychology or philosophy will definitely enter the realm of my intellectual interests. After watching this scene, I decided to look back into one of the few games which has held its original nature for all the years it has been in existence. From that point on, my quest begins.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">145</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Introduction</title>
		<link>/introduction/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2010 20:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bengozen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[origin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the beginning]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=146</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Welcome to BenGoZen! As you might&#8217;ve read in the description, this blog is for anyone looking for some personalized Go experience and advice. In case some of you haven&#8217;t had the pleasure of reading ChiyoDad&#8217;s blog, he has about three years of blogging logged in. Even though he has some great information, I thought I&#8217;d [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to BenGoZen! As you might&#8217;ve read in the description, this blog is for anyone looking for some personalized Go experience and advice. In case some of you haven&#8217;t had the pleasure of reading ChiyoDad&#8217;s blog, he has about three years of blogging logged in. Even though he has some great information, I thought I&#8217;d take to a blog with a more personal touch and hopefully more guidance for those who are new to the game or are looking to improve.<br />
So in case you are wondering how the blog got its name, it&#8217;s quite simple.<br />
Ben &#8211; My name<br />
Go &#8211; The name of the game and a pun on the verb as well.<br />
+ Zen &#8211; The calming state I get when playing the game.<br />
&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8211;<br />
= BenGoZen!<br />
In addition, it&#8217;s also three mono-syllabic words strung together with a rhyme which I thought would be catchy. (Hopefully I won&#8217;t be the only one)<br />
As the blog posts fill up, be sure to use the search box if you are searching for something specific. I&#8217;ll keep the titles simple so that you&#8217;ll hopefully find what you&#8217;re looking for without much difficulty. (e.g. If you want book reviews, type &#8220;book reviews&#8221;)<br />
In addition, any links that I post up on the sidebars are sites that I personally have verified and believe to be useful or reliable. This is particularly directed at the &#8220;Places to Buy Go Stuff&#8221; list since I wouldn&#8217;t want you purchasing from anywhere that I had no experience with. Also, the links and blogs will be exclusively English for now since I assume a number of players reading my blog won&#8217;t know Japanese of Chinese. If there is a demand for it, let me know and I&#8217;ll start posting those blogs too.<br />
Sorry for the long introduction, but I hope it gets you a better idea of what BenGoZen is all about and how to best use it for your Go needs.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">146</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
