<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>frustration &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/frustration/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>My First Demotion</title>
		<link>/first-demotion/</link>
		<comments>/first-demotion/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2014 04:22:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[creative]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[doubt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[frustration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inspired]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yunguseng]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5378</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Though there was a small chance that I would be able to stay in League A for Yunguseng Dojang, unfortunately I was unable to rise to the occasion and will receive my first demotion to League B. Before Sabumnim&#8217;s* Review** I always thought that getting demoted would feel similar to seeing my rank drop, but I [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Though there was a small chance that I would be able to stay in League A for <a title="Yunguseng Dojang Official Page" href="http://www.yunguseng.com/">Yunguseng Dojang</a>, unfortunately I was unable to rise to the occasion and will receive my first demotion to League B.<br />
<strong>Before Sabumnim&#8217;s* Review**</strong><br />
I always thought that getting demoted would feel similar to seeing my rank drop, but I have to say that this feels worse. Maybe I&#8217;ll change my mind after the fact, but this feels worse. And if I were to give a reason why, it&#8217;s probably because I spent time and effort over an entire month only to be shown my inadequacy.<br />
I would be lying if I said that I&#8217;m cool with it and feeling whatever about it. A large part of me is frustrated and disappointed with myself.<br />
As I sulk in this aura of frustration and angst, it is causing a lot of doubt to spread. Doubt as to whether or not I actually got any stronger over this last month. Doubt as to whether I have any talent at all since my games were nothing to be proud of (as evident in the past reviews). Doubt as to what the hell I&#8217;ve been doing this entire month since I&#8217;ve been so unstable (especially towards the end of the month).<br />
It&#8217;s stupid and childish to think such thoughts. I know. I guess I&#8217;m just really feeling at a loss for what is going on with me. While part of it might be mental, another part of me feel like there is something wrong with my go. I just feel like I can&#8217;t make sense of what I&#8217;m doing anymore.<br />
<strong>After Sabumim&#8217;s Review</strong><br />
When I started writing this post, my self-pity almost caused me to skip the review since I wasn&#8217;t sure if I could handle hearing that my game was awful or anything that could further my self-doubt. So as I wrote the first section of this post, I thought that I was doomed to feeling awful for the rest of the night. Thankfully though, against my feelings of self-doubt, I decided to go ahead and stay for the review.<br />
To my surprise, I was happy to find out that my game was actually not a bad game at all. In fact, though I have been in a weird funk lately (in regards to the games I&#8217;ve been playing), this final game was probably one of most inspired ones so far. It&#8217;s kind of odd writing that because I ended up losing a rather important match, but I really feel that it was one of my most creative games I&#8217;ve played to date.***<br />
Part of me still carries some of the frustration from earlier, but I&#8217;m in a better place now. Though getting demoted to League B is a bit disappointing, it simply means that I&#8217;ll need to work hard next month to get back to League A. Challenge accepted.<br />
<em>*Note: Sabumnim is the Korean equivalent of sensei when it comes to how to address your teacher. And in case it wasn&#8217;t obvious, sabumnim refers to Inseong.</em><br />
<em>**Part of me debated deleting this section to shelter you from my whining and self-pity, but I felt it would be wrong to try and hide it. As much as it might be pathetic and childish, this is part of my journey to gaining that next stone. The frustration, the self-doubt, and the feeling of wanting to just throw in the towel are all obstacles that I deal with and I don&#8217;t want to sugarcoat it at all. So for that reason, I hope you&#8217;ll understand why I left it in.</em><br />
<em>***I&#8217;m sure many of you will want to see the game, but I promise I&#8217;ll be releasing a full post on my first month in Yunguseng Dojang next week so you can see all of my games along with my thoughts on each of them as well. </em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/first-demotion/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>10</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">5378</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Going On Tilt</title>
		<link>/going-on-tilt/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 13:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Weekly Go Wednesday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bad habits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emotional state]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emotions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[frustration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[on tilt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[poker]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=2203</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Weekly Go Wednesday #20 For those who are not familiar with the realm of poker (or gambling in general), going on tilt refers to a emotionally wild state where a player is prone to make irrational decisions and often ends in their unfortunate demise. To illustrate, imagine that you have a straight flush (5-6-7-8-9), which [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 style="text-align: center;">Weekly Go Wednesday #20</h2>
<figure id="attachment_2223" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/03/wgw19.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-2223" alt="Credit SilverOakCasino" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/03/wgw19.jpg?resize=300%2C225" width="300" height="225" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Credit SilverOakCasino</figcaption></figure>
For those who are not familiar with the realm of poker (or gambling in general), going on tilt refers to a emotionally wild state where a player is prone to make irrational decisions and often ends in their unfortunate demise.<br />
To illustrate, imagine that you have a straight flush (5-6-7-8-9), which happens to be second best hand that a player can have in the game. Mathematically speaking, the odds of your opponents having the royal flush (which is the best hand) is so slim that it&#8217;s practically not worth mentioning. To sweeten the deal, none of your opponents have any idea that you have this amazing hand and you&#8217;ve reeled them in for a ton of money. When time comes to show the cards, you find out that the impossible has happened: one of your opponents has the royal flush and cleans you out.<br />
In a fit of rage and frustration, you go to get more cash and start to play wildly and bet aggressively in an attempt to win back what &#8220;should have&#8221; been yours. Over the next few hours, not only do you fail to win any money back, but now you are in a bit of debt and in the most terrible of moods. That is what going &#8220;on tilt&#8221; is. And it is no different with go.<br />
<span id="more-2203"></span><br />
There are three main scenarios that cause players to go on tilt:</p>
<ol>
<li>Losing a won game.</li>
<li><span style="line-height: 13px;">Losing because of a mistake.</span></li>
<li>Losing because a large group was captured.</li>
</ol>
<p>Each time a player goes on tilt, a general cycle will occur: (1) The player will rush to play another game. (2) In order to &#8220;<a href="http://idioms.thefreedictionary.com/save+face">save face</a>,&#8221; they try to crush their opponent even though it is a completely different opponent than before. (3) They start to go on a losing streak, which only causes them to spiral further downwards. (4) They get fed up with go.<br />
As I said, aside from the fact that go games generally don&#8217;t consist of losing money, it&#8217;s practically one and the same. It&#8217;s a dangerous emotional state that will only do you harm and never any good.<br />
If you&#8217;re still not convinced though, here are three reasons why going on tilt is nothing but bad news:</p>
<ol>
<li><span style="line-height: 13px;"><strong>You will try to kill everything.</strong> For 99% of players out there, there is no greater euphoric feeling than killing off a large group. And since you&#8217;re on tilt and looking to try and make yourself feel better, the allure to kill will just be too strong. Unfortunately, killing things is not as easy as it looks. So instead of feeling better, odds are pretty good that you&#8217;ll end up overextending your attack and resigning when it is your group that dies instead.</span></li>
<li><strong>You start to play by impulse.</strong> No matter how strong your fundamentals are, unless you are a sandbagger, there is no way in hell that your opponent (who is a similar skill level to you) will make the mistakes you will make when playing impulse moves. Your opponent will be reading. You will not. And in case you haven&#8217;t put two and two together, that will spell out disaster for you.</li>
<li><strong>It&#8217;s only going to get worse.</strong> Although there is the rare occasion that you demolish your first opponent and then feel relieved and thus get out of tilt, most of the time you are only going to find yourself spiraling down into the abyss that we all know as a losing streak. And in the worst case scenario, it might get so bad that you just end up quitting go all together.</li>
</ol>
<p>In my journey thus far, these are some of the things I discovered on how to prevent yourself from going on tilt:</p>
<ol>
<li><span style="line-height: 13px;"><strong>Take a break before playing your next game.</strong> Even if it&#8217;s only five minutes, doing something like getting up and washing your face to clear your head will help to calm you down.</span></li>
<li><strong>Do some pushups and shadowbox.</strong> Especially if you&#8217;re feeling very frustrated, some physical activity will help to blow off some steam. Not to mention, exercise is good for you anyways! Although I will note that you should take a couple minutes after to calm down from the adrenaline.</li>
<li><strong>Let go of the emotional attachment to winning and losing.</strong> I know I&#8217;m starting to get in to philosophy territory, but I&#8217;m being perfectly serious. After all, going on tilt is rooted in the egocentric idea of having things go your way. And if you&#8217;re able to achieve this, the benefits you&#8217;ll see in your go and the rest of your life will be astounding.</li>
</ol>
<p>I know that #3 is rather abstract; but don&#8217;t worry, I will write more on this in next week&#8217;s post. So stay tuned. Meanwhile, I pose the following question to you:</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>How do you deal with / prevent going on tilt?</strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2203</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
