<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>Lessons &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/lessons/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>Thou Shalt Not Kill&#8230;</title>
		<link>/thou-shalt-not-kill/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2013 22:30:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lessons]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bad habits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[focus on profit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[overly aggressive]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=1686</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Lately, I have noticed that my games have become quite violent. =D And by that, I mean that the theme of my games are: threaten to make a huge moyo, and then kill whatever comes inside of it. While it lets me know that I will win with absolute certainty if I manage to kill [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lately, I have noticed that my games have become quite violent. =D And by that, I mean that the theme of my games are: threaten to make a huge moyo, and then kill whatever comes inside of it.<br />
While it lets me know that I will win with absolute certainty if I manage to kill the group, we all know that this strategy is extremely flawed and is extremely risky. And as if the fact that you will lose most of your games trying to do this wasn&#8217;t bad enough, I just get more discouraged and frustrated as time goes on. So I know that if I continue along this path, I will end up getting fed up and dropping go for no good reason.<br />
So the goal now is to train myself to steer away from that style of play. It&#8217;s not that I will be meek and never fight back, but I will focus on giving my attacks an edge that sends my opponents running while I gain the necessary points to win. For now, I will focus on a profit oriented style instead of the killing style that I am so habituated to. So in terms of the criteria for my games for a while:</p>
<ol>
<li>I will practice attacking while gaining profit.</li>
<li><span style="line-height: 13px">I shall not kill any group unless they are forced into a shape where I am absolutely sure of its demise (e.g., bent in three).</span></li>
</ol>
<p>And to continue a new tradition that frozensoul recommended to me, I will start a repetition exercise of writing any new go lesson I am trying to learn fifty times. By doing so, I&#8217;m hoping that it will sink it better than simply reading once and trying to remember amidst a game.<br />
<figure id="attachment_1687" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/01/lesson3.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1687" alt="&quot;Focus on profit, not killing.&quot;" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/01/lesson3.jpg?resize=300%2C225" width="300" height="225" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">&#8220;Focus on profit, not killing.&#8221;</figcaption></figure>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1686</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Reckless Go Atonement</title>
		<link>/reckless-go-atonement/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2012 17:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lessons]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[atonement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[redemption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the list]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=1435</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[As promised, here is evidence of my redemption for yesterday&#8217;s atrocious play. Here&#8217;s to hoping that I learned my lesson and never have to do this again. xD]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;">As promised, here is evidence of my redemption for yesterday&#8217;s atrocious play.</p>
<figure id="attachment_1436" style="width: 800px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2012/12/recklessGoPunishment.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1436" alt="recklessGoPunishment" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2012/12/recklessGoPunishment.jpg?resize=720%2C538" width="720" height="538" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">I&#8217;d forgotten how painstaking repetitive hand-writing can be&#8230;</figcaption></figure>
<p style="text-align: center;">Here&#8217;s to hoping that I learned my lesson and never have to do this again. xD</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1435</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Giving Your Opponent a Wedgie</title>
		<link>/giving-your-opponent-a-wedgie/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2012 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lessons]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tactics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Weekly Go Wednesday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[go tactics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wedge]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=17</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Weekly Go Wednesday, Issue #4 Tactic #1: The Wedge Here is a scenario that occurs quite frequently in games. White just played the one point jump. Black to play. Trick question. The answer is to tenuki. Nothing beneficial can come out of playing here locally. Leave the aji for later on when it might be [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 style="text-align: center;"><em>Weekly Go Wednesday, Issue #4</em></h2>
<h3 style="text-align: center;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>Tactic #1: The Wedge</strong></span></h3>
<p style="text-align: center;">Here is a scenario that occurs quite frequently in games.</p>
<p><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2012/10/wedge1.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-243" title="wedge1" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2012/10/wedge1.png?resize=171%2C200" alt="" width="171" height="200" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>White just played the one point jump. Black to play.</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span id="more-17"></span></p>
<p>Trick question. The answer is to tenuki. Nothing beneficial can come out of playing here locally. Leave the aji for later on when it might be useful. (If any stronger players think anything to the contrary, please let me know!)<br />
Up until recently, I was in the camp with the rest of the players who stared at the situation and thought, &#8220;Why don&#8217;t I just wedge in?&#8221; First off, from the reading I&#8217;ve done thus far, the wedge is a tesuji. Secondly, I have read this out thoroughly and I can successfully cut the two groups apart without losing my cutting stone. (See variation below).<br />
<a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2012/10/wedge-variations.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-245" title="wedge variations" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2012/10/wedge-variations.png?resize=400%2C244" alt="" width="400" height="244" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><br />
While you get brownie points for reading out the variations properly and succeeding in your original goal, there is a one earth shattering reason why this misuse of the tactic will consistently cost you game after game:<br />
<strong>Your opponent gets to choose the variation that results from it.</strong><br />
As you are probably well aware, one of the most critical aspects of go is the sente and gote relationship. As a rule of thumb, players ideally want to keep sente for a majority of the game. The reason for this lies in the fact that you are essentially forcing your opponent to go where you would like him/her to. In other words, you become his/her puppet master!<br />
This type of wedge, while seemingly effective in disconnecting your opponent&#8217;s stones, is the equivalent of handing the reigns of the game over to your opponent and say, &#8220;Pick whichever variation you like! I care not whether or not it benefits me, because I am satisfied knowing I was able to disconnect your stones for the time being!&#8221; And so unless your opponent gives no heed to which variation is to his/her benefit, you&#8217;ll often find yourself in a regrettable situation before you know it.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>So&#8230; when does the wedge make sense?</em></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2012/10/wedge2.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-246" title="wedge2" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2012/10/wedge2.png?resize=156%2C200" alt="" width="156" height="200" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></p>
<p>This new scenario is similar to the original diagram, but there are two differences to take note of. First, white is offered a second one point jump for reinforcement. Secondly, and most importantly, black is much stronger this time around. With this crucial difference, the wedge that was once to white&#8217;s benefit is now a strong weapon for black to use.<br />
<a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2012/10/wedge-variations-2.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-247" title="wedge variations 2" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2012/10/wedge-variations-2.png?resize=400%2C263" alt="" width="400" height="263" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><br />
As you can now see, regardless of which variation white chooses, his triangled stones are destined for impending doom.<br />
With the wedge tesuji, the key thing to remember is that your purpose must extend beyond simply cutting off two groups from one another.<br />
After all, which of the following options would you prefer to offer your opponent:</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>&#8220;Please, choose a variation that is best suited for your purposes.&#8221;</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>OR</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>&#8220;Your stones could die this way, or that way. Your choice.&#8221;</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Many thanks to fellow ASR member sita for helping me grasp this concept. </em><br />
<em>All diagrams were generated using CGoban3.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">17</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Small # of Groups = Higher Chance to Win</title>
		<link>/small-of-groups-higher-chance-to-win/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2012 15:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Kifu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lessons]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[baduk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[go]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[small number of groups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weiqib]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=35</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Today&#8217;s game was a reminder of a concept I was told long ago in one of my teaching games: The less groups you have on the board, the more likely it is that you&#8217;re going to win. Sounds simple enough right? And yet at the same time, why is this the case? Let&#8217;s not forget [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Today&#8217;s game was a reminder of a concept I was told long ago in one of my teaching games:</p>
<blockquote><p>The less groups you have on the board, the more likely it is that you&#8217;re going to win.</p></blockquote>
<p>Sounds simple enough right? And yet at the same time, why is this the case?<br />
<span id="more-35"></span><br />
Let&#8217;s not forget an important aspect of Go &#8211; <strong>the players who use their stones the most efficiently are the ones who will most likely surround the most territory</strong>. After all, when you&#8217;re killing two birds with one stone, it becomes just about as close to having two moves as a player will ever get!<br />

<div id='glift_display1' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display1","sgf":"http:\/\/bengozen.com\/\/wp-content\/uploads\/2012\/08\/2012.08.31-Small-Number-of-Groups.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='//wp-content/uploads/2012/08/2012.08.31-Small-Number-of-Groups.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
If we look at the results of my game, you&#8217;ll notice that Black has 5 different groups and White has 4 groups. Yet if you play close enough attention, you&#8217;ll see how much more efficient White&#8217;s stones were at surround territory compared to Black&#8217;s. In fact, a number of Black&#8217;s groups seems like they barely escape death.<br />
In terms of reflecting on my own play, I know that I experimented with a number of different plays that a higher ranked player would have probably punished nice and well. And in a few instances I tenuki&#8217;d when I should have paid more attention to the livelihood of the group. Overall though, I felt rather collected and was happy with each of my moves.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">35</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>My First One Point Lesson</title>
		<link>/my-first-one-point-lesson/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2010 04:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kifu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lessons]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[14k]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[3 step thinking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shidougo]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=65</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[So I played my first teaching game on KGS today. It was a pretty quick game with a 3-dan who UTTERLY demolished me. I couldn&#8217;t help but laugh as I watched my shapes get cut up into tiny little pieces and get swallowed up whole by Leviathan. Don&#8217;t even want to think about what it [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>So I played my first teaching game on KGS today. It was a pretty quick game with a 3-dan who UTTERLY demolished me. I couldn&#8217;t help but laugh as I watched my shapes get cut up into tiny little pieces and get swallowed up whole by Leviathan. Don&#8217;t even want to think about what it would be like to play a pro right now&#8230;. *head explodes*<br />
Anyhow, here is the following onslaught. The 3-dan has an interesting idea called: <strong>One Point Teaching Game</strong>. At first I was like do I pay him a point or something&#8230;. but then it became clear to me at the end. He gives one solid point for the player to work on. BRILLIANT! Considering weak players are being pulled five millions different directions at once (e.g. life and death, tesuji, opening theory, etc.), it&#8217;s nice to have one solid thing to focus on.<br />
So I&#8217;m sure the question then is, what was my one point lesson for today?<br />
<span id="more-65"></span><br />
<strong>Practice 3-Step Thinking for Every Move</strong> &#8211; In other words, think what move you intend to play, how your opponent could respond, and how you&#8217;d respond to your opponent&#8217;s response. This process will give a player a better overview as to the board position and whether it is favorable or not.<br />
He said that a number of SDK don&#8217;t even do this consistently, so it may be difficult for me to incorporate it as second nature. I would like to note that we played a relatively quick game, so most of my moves were instinctual. Nonetheless, I must train myself to do 3-Step Thinking instinctively or else the pursuit to become stronger will be futile. Now grab your bag of popcorn, and enjoy the onslaught.<br />

<div id='glift_display2' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display2","sgf":"http:\/\/bengozen.com\/\/wp-content\/uploads\/2010\/10\/2010.10.17-My-First-One-Point-Lesson.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='//wp-content/uploads/2010/10/2010.10.17-My-First-One-Point-Lesson.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">65</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
