<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>counting &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/counting/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>WGW 29: Why I Never Counted</title>
		<link>/wgw29-never-counted/</link>
		<comments>/wgw29-never-counted/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2013 11:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Weekly Go Wednesday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[board position]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[counting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[estimating]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[evaluation]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=4360</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Weekly Go Wednesday, Issue #29 As I&#8217;ve been working through my own issues or burnout and sense of confusion, I realized that a large cause of it is due to the fact that I have consistently avoided counting and making board position evaluations during my games for the entire time I&#8217;ve been playing. It&#8217;s finally [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 style="text-align: center;">Weekly Go Wednesday, Issue #29</h2>
<p>As I&#8217;ve been working through my own issues or burnout and sense of confusion, I realized that a large cause of it is due to the fact that I have consistently avoided counting and making board position evaluations during my games for the entire time I&#8217;ve been playing. It&#8217;s finally caught up to me, so I thought I would write about this in hopes that it will help you avoid this in the future as well.<br />
Here are my top excuses for why I didn&#8217;t want (or think I needed) to count:<br />
<strong>1. &#8220;I am supposed to find the best move anyways and constantly strive to maximize my return, so counting or estimating territory is not needed if I&#8217;m simply outplaying my opponent.&#8221;</strong><br />
While there may be some merit to this type of thinking, it is flawed as a whole. If you&#8217;re constantly trying to maximize each move without considering how it impacts the board as a whole, how can your move be considered &#8220;maximally efficient&#8221; when it does not work in the whole board context?<br />
<strong>2. &#8220;I don&#8217;t have time to estimate territory. I&#8217;m busy finding the best move.&#8221;</strong><br />
Just like in the first excuse, you can&#8217;t find the best move if you&#8217;re not aware of what it is you need to do to win. In addition, you have to keep in mind that go is more than winning local battles or establishing strong positions in a local context. Go is about how your positions work together <em>as a whole. </em>And whether you like it or not, estimating territory or judging the board position is key to forming the winning strategy.<br />
<strong>3. &#8220;It is better to just find out the score at the end. After all, it&#8217;s more exciting and suspenseful when it&#8217;s a surprise right?</strong><br />
I&#8217;m sure everyone has had that experience of feeling like the game is close when in actuality you have like a 20-30 point lead. It&#8217;s a pretty good feeling right? After all, you actually ended up having a big lead instead of it being a close game! However, I&#8217;m sure there are just as many (if not more) occasions where the complete reverse happens. You thought you were putting up a good fight and it turns out you were losing since move 140. It&#8217;s a complete bummer isn&#8217;t it?<br />
So if what I&#8217;m saying is making any sense at all, and you&#8217;re wondering how you can start incorporating counting into your games, here are a couple of ideas:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Play longer games.</strong> After all, you&#8217;re going to need time to get used to judging the board position at first. It might take some getting used to and may take longer than you might like, but with practice you should get faster over time. And before you know it, it won&#8217;t take much effort or time to figure out what&#8217;s going on on the board.</li>
<li><strong>Practice estimating positions with an experienced counter.</strong> In other words, it&#8217;s not enough to simply estimate positions with a stronger player. After all, my counting skills might be worse than someone who is 8 kyu. So find someone who is strong at counting and get them to help you out. (For those who have no idea where to start, my sensei frozensoul on KGS excels in this area and can be a great help.)</li>
<li><strong>Remember that you&#8217;re &#8220;guesstimating&#8221; and not calculating.</strong> Especially when just starting out, it&#8217;s really important to remember that our ability to count will be off by a decent amount at first. In addition, you don&#8217;t need to be accurate down to the last point. If you can even get a relatively accurate read on who&#8217;s ahead or behind and where the largest areas are coming from, that will be an excellent start. After that, it&#8217;s all about refining your technique till you&#8217;re a counting master. =)</li>
</ul>
<p>If you have any advice or ideas, be sure to leave a comment below. Hope this helps!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/wgw29-never-counted/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">4360</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Book Review: The Endgame</title>
		<link>/book-review-the-endgame/</link>
		<comments>/book-review-the-endgame/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2013 02:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[counting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kiseido]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the endgame]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=3507</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Description: In this installment of the Elementary Go Series, Ogawa and Davies attempts to lay out the basic tactics, strategies, and techniques required to fully master the endgame. While an excellent reference for players with an understanding of endgame, this may prove to be slightly advanced for someone brand new to endgame. [expand title=&#8221;Book Details&#8221; [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/07/egsv7theendgame.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3508" alt="The Endgame Cover" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/07/egsv7theendgame.jpg?resize=276%2C400" width="276" height="400" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><br />
<strong>Description: </strong>In this installment of the Elementary Go Series, Ogawa and Davies attempts to lay out the basic tactics, strategies, and techniques required to fully master the endgame. While an excellent reference for players with an understanding of endgame, this may prove to be slightly advanced for someone brand new to endgame.<br />
<span id="more-3507"></span><br />
[expand title=&#8221;Book Details&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
[table]
Title, The Endgame (Volume 6)<br />
Series, Elementary Go Series<br />
Author, Tomoko Ogawa &amp; James Davies<br />
Publisher, <a href="http://www.kiseido.com/">Kiseido</a><br />
Published, &#8220;September 1976&#8243;<br />
Language, English<br />
ISBN, 978-4-906574-15-5<br />
Length, 214 Pages<br />
[/table]
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Table of Content&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Chapter 1: Introducing the Endgame</li>
<li>Chapter 2: Counting</li>
<li>Chapter 3: Endgame Tesuji</li>
<li>Chapter 4: The Macro-Endgame</li>
<li>Chapter 5: Games</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Synopsis&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221; expanded=&#8221;true&#8221;]
<ol>
<li>A comprehensive book that covers quite a great deal of content regarding the endgame.</li>
<li>Masterfully utilizes multiple choice questions to help train the reader on gaining a better understanding of why one answer is better than another.</li>
<li>It is more advanced than I was anticipating. Not necessarily the most beginner friendly when it comes to endgame.</li>
</ol>
[/expand]
<!--more--><br />
[expand title=&#8221;Before I Read This Book&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<strong>My Abilities</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>I have never formally studied endgame. However, I have some preliminary knowledge of some basic concepts like reverse-sente and doubling the value of a move because it is sente. I also have some exposure to determining value for endgame moves, but I&#8217;m terrible at it.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>My Perspective</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>I was really hoping to clear up any confusion I had about determining the value of endgame moves. In other words, I am hoping that by the end of this book, any failure to play the biggest endgame moves will only be due to laziness and not inability to calculate it.</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;My Review&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221; expanded=&#8221;true&#8221;]
<strong>What did I enjoy about the book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>I really enjoyed the endgame tesuji section. Lots of great explanations along with practice problems.</li>
<li>I was also really surprised by how thorough and useful the macro-endgame chapter was. The use of multiple choice questions was definitely ideal for learning.</li>
<li>They use a sequence of problems with scores for the respective answers to &#8220;grade&#8221; your endgame abilities. I thought this was pretty cool.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What did I gain from reading this book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>A greater appreciation for the importance of endgame.</li>
<li>More perspective on not responding automatically for endgame moves and trying to find sequences that are either sente for myself or at least only give a gote sequence for my opponent.</li>
<li>Improved understanding of whole board decisions when it comes to endgame.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What style of teaching does the book use?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Textbook Approach
<ul>
<li>Explanations can be very dense at times and it uses problems or examples to try and illustrate its message.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Primary Learning Mechanism:
<ul>
<li>Explanations.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Other Learning Mechanisms:
<ul>
<li>Practice problems.</li>
<li>Multiple choice problems.</li>
<li>Examples from professional games.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What aspects can be improved on?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The first chapter is pretty frightening for anyone who is new to endgame and cannot process a million things going on at once.</li>
<li>The material and level of explanation was much more accommodating to players new to endgame as the book progressed, which is contrary to what most people would expect (aka easy to understand into dense material).</li>
<li>The section on teaching how to count could be enhanced to accommodate introduction problems and more opportunity to practice how to count the value of endgame sequences.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Is this book easy to read?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>For the most part, yes. The first chapter was incredibly difficult for me to work through there was a lot of high level discussion that just went over my head. When the book go into the endgame tesujis and multiple choice problems, it became a lot easier to read and understand.</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Recommended For&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Players who have a basic understanding of endgame.</li>
<li>Players looking for an opportunity to test their knowledge of endgame using the graded problems in this book.</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Where Can I Buy It?&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>GoGameGuru &#8211; <a title="Go Game Guru Purchase Link" href="http://shop.gogameguru.com/the-endgame/?acc=e4da3b7fbbce2345d7772b0674a318d5">$17.99</a> USD (shipping &amp; handling not included)</li>
<li>Kiseido &#8211; <a title="Kiseido Purchase Link" href="http://kiseido.com/go_books.htm">$18.00</a> USD (shipping &amp; handling not included)</li>
<li>SmartGo Books &#8211; <a title="SmartGo Book Link" href="http://www.smartgo.com/books.htm">$9.99</a> USD (e-Book for iPad &amp; iPhone Only)</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Other Books in This Series&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;lastExpandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li><a title="Book Review: In the Beginning" href="//book-review-in-the-beginning/">Elementary Go Series, Volume 1 &#8211; In the Beginning</a></li>
<li><a title="Book Review: 38 Basic Joseki" href="//book-review-38-basic-joseki/">Elementary Go Series, Volume 2 &#8211; 38 Basic Joseki</a></li>
<li><a title="Book Review: Tesuji" href="//book-review-tesuji/">Elementary Go Series, Volume 3 &#8211; Tesuji</a></li>
<li><a title="Book Review: Life and Death" href="//book-review-life-and-death/">Elementary Go Series, Volume 4 &#8211; Life and Death</a></li>
<li><a title="Book Review: Attack and Defense" href="//book-review-attack-and-defense/">Elementary Go Series, Volume 5 &#8211; Attack and Defense</a></li>
<li><a title="Book Review: Handicap Go" href="//book-review-handicap-go/">Elementary Go Series, Volume 7 &#8211; Handicap Go</a></li>
</ul>
[/expand]
<p style="text-align: center;"><em><strong>Last Updated on July 22nd, 2013</strong></em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/book-review-the-endgame/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3507</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Book Review: Positional Judgment</title>
		<link>/book-review-positional-judgment/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2013 09:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[counting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[estimating territory]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[evaluating]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[positional judgement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[strategic planning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[whole board thinking]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=2926</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Overall Rating: 9 / 10 Ponnuki Basic Information Title: Positional Judgment: High-Speed Game Analysis Author: Cho Chikun Publisher: Kiseido Publication Date: December 1989 Page Length: 182 pages Synopsis A great book on positional judgment when it comes to whole board thinking. Utilizes multiple choice questions along with example games to help illustrate his points. Requires a basic [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/08/positionaljudgementcover.jpg"><img alt="positionaljudgementcover" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/08/positionaljudgementcover.jpg?resize=300%2C435" width="300" height="435" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></h2>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">Overall Rating: 9 / 10 Ponnuki</h2>
<h3>Basic Information</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Title:</strong> Positional Judgment: High-Speed Game Analysis</li>
<li><strong><strong>Author: </strong></strong>Cho Chikun</li>
<li><strong>Publisher: </strong>Kiseido</li>
<li><strong>Publication Date: </strong>December 1989</li>
<li><strong><strong>Page Length:</strong> </strong>182 pages</li>
</ul>
<h3>Synopsis</h3>
<ul>
<li>A great book on positional judgment when it comes to whole board thinking.</li>
<li>Utilizes multiple choice questions along with example games to help illustrate his points.</li>
<li>Requires a basic level of endgame sequences for the estimations to make sense.</li>
<li>Appropriate for 6 kyu and stronger.</li>
<li>Recommended for serious players.</li>
</ul>
<p><span id="more-2926"></span></p>
<h3>What I Expected</h3>
<ul>
<li><span style="line-height: 13px;">A book that would teach me how to evaluate the board position when the borders are not so clear.</span></li>
<li>Lots of examples that would allow me to practice the concepts introduced in here.</li>
<li>To be able to start applying positional judgment (within a reasonable amount of error) to my own games.</li>
</ul>
<h3>What You Can Expect</h3>
<ul>
<li><span style="line-height: 13px;">A solid explanation on some theory behind estimating territory from three perspectives.</span></li>
<li>Quite a few problems to help test your ability to estimate territory.</li>
<li>A good number of examples that utilize multiple choice questions to test your knowledge and also comes with great explanations.</li>
<li>Two example games from Cho Chikun where he talks about his thought process during two title games.</li>
</ul>
<h3>My Thoughts as a 5 Kyu</h3>
<p>When I first heard of this book, the reviews online were rather mediocre and I was discouraged from purchasing it at the time. However, I am thankful that I finally did because I think that this book is underrated in terms of its ability to shed some light on a topic that I think many kyu players shun away from: accurately analyzing the positions on the board.<br />
Although I found the book to be rather enlightening, I will forewarn potential buyers who are unfamiliar with other basic strategic concepts of the game (e.g., what it means to attack, basic endgame sequences, etc.) will probably find this book rather challenging to grasp. Even though I&#8217;ve begun to apply some of those concepts to my games, I am the first to admit that it will require a lot more practice and probably another few passes before I understand the book entirely.<br />
If I were to critique one thing about the book, it&#8217;s that I would love more practice scenarios where I am forced to evaluate positions and see if my counting is accurate or not. Otherwise though, this book fills a much needed niche when it comes to players wanting to learn more about positional judgment.</p>
<h3>Table of Content</h3>
<ol>
<li>Foreward &#8211; Notes to the Reader</li>
<li>Chapter 1: The Three Main Points of Game Analysis
<ol>
<li>Point 1: First Count the Territory
<ol>
<li>Examples 1 &#8211; 3</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>Point 2: Assess Territory from Thickness
<ol>
<li>Examples 1 &#8211; 4</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>Point 3: Estimate the Territory from a Moyo
<ol>
<li>Examples 1 &#8211; 3</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>Chapter 2: A High-Speed Analysis Test
<ol>
<li>Problems 1 &#8211; 6</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>Chapter 3: A Broad Overview Results From Accurate Analysis
<ol>
<li>Examples 1 &#8211; 10</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>Chapter 4: Large-Scale Analysis Problems: The Type Amateurs Often Get Wrong
<ol>
<li>Problems 1 &#8211; 8</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>Chapter 5: Cho-Style Game Analysis
<ol>
<li>Games 1 &#8211; 2</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ol>
<h3>Recommended Vendors:</h3>
<ol>
<li>Kiseido &#8211; <a href="http://www.kiseido.com/go_books.htm">$18.00</a> (S&amp;H not included)</li>
</ol>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Last updated June 23rd, 2013</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2926</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Estimating Territory</title>
		<link>/estimating-territory/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2013 22:30:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tactics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Weekly Go Wednesday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[counting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[estimating territory]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[estimation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[getting stronger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good habits]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=1586</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Weekly Go Wednesday, Issue #11 Counting (i.e., estimating territory at any point in the game). Although this is a skill that many would say is critical to improving the consistency of your games, this is probably the skill that is most avoided by go players all around. For those who are not aware of the benefits [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 style="text-align: center"><strong><em>Weekly Go Wednesday, Issue #11</em></strong></h2>
<figure id="attachment_1590" style="width: 288px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/01/abacus.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-1590  " alt="Credit to David R. Tribble" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/01/abacus.jpg?resize=288%2C216" width="288" height="216" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Credit to David R. Tribble</figcaption></figure>
Counting (i.e., estimating territory at any point in the game). Although this is a skill that many would say is critical to improving the consistency of your games, this is probably the skill that is most avoided by go players all around. For those who are not aware of the benefits of counting, it boils down to one simple principle: <strong>It provides guidance as to how aggressively/defensively you should be playing</strong>.<br />
<span id="more-1586"></span><br />
For example, if you are ahead by 30 points on the board, the best thing to do is to solidify your positions and reduce the possibility of your opponent successively invading and destroying your territory. Without counting, you might make overplays and take unnecessary risks that could allow your opponent to turn the game around. On the other hand, if you are behind, you better start invading or doing whatever you can to change the flow of the game.<br />
With that benefit, you must be asking yourself, why doesn&#8217;t everyone do it then?</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>It is a time consuming process. </strong>Whether it&#8217;s trying to determine whether you can kill your opponent&#8217;s group, or whether you can win that capturing race, most players (myself included) are so preoccupied with the tactical aspects of go that counting rarely makes the cut when managing our time.</li>
<li><strong>Counting is not as simple as 1 + 1 = 2. </strong>While estimating territory may seem rather easy, it requires a fundamental understanding of where realistic territory exists and what is still undecided. As any player is well aware, the game can be decided by as little as half a point. So overestimation/underestimation can obviously have a huge impact on the result of the game. As a result, the haziness of estimating territory only serves to scare more players away.</li>
<li><strong>The board is constantly changing.</strong> This further discourages players from counting since it&#8217;s difficult to predict where the opponent will go next.</li>
</ol>
<p>Fortunately, all hope is not lost! Although this may seem rather self-explanatory, it is important to remember that the key word to remember when counting is that you are <strong>estimating</strong>. If you can get yourself to within 10 points of the actual score, you are far better off than most amateur players.<br />
In terms of how you can improve your counting abilities, here are some tips to get you started:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Don&#8217;t spend any longer than a minute counting. </strong>If you are spending more time, you are being too exact.</li>
<li><strong>Count in pairs.</strong> This will allow you to count at a much faster pace.</li>
<li><strong>Don&#8217;t count anything that looks questionable.</strong> If it looks like either player can jump in and easily live/escape, throw that territory out the window.</li>
<li><strong>Create a blueprint.</strong> In an ideal world, you would be able to easily remember how much each territory is. For most of us though, we will find ourselves forgetting or confusing how much each section is worth. So to build up to the skill of being able to remember it all, create a quick sketch of the board with your first estimations when you first count, and then modify it accordingly the next time you count.</li>
<li><strong>Compare your estimation with a stronger player&#8217;s estimation.</strong> This can be a huge benefit to helping you understand how to make more accurate decisions regarding how to estimate the score.</li>
</ol>
<p>Like any other skill in life, do not be discouraged if your counting skills are off. The key thing is to keep practicing and making it a habit. Start by counting just once per game, and then increase it to two when you feel comfortable doing so. I assure you that you will definitely get faster over time.<br />
Finally, there is one final matter that must be addressed: estimating score using software. While this is a really convenient tool, it is important to realize that it is far from perfect. I have seen the software mistaken large groups for dead when they are clearly alive. As a result, remember that it is not something you should use as a reference point.<br />
If you have any tips or exercises that helped you improve your counting abilities, please be sure to share it below!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1586</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
