<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>new perspective &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/new-perspective/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>No Turning Back</title>
		<link>/no-turning-back/</link>
		<comments>/no-turning-back/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2013 21:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kyu tunnel vision]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new perspective]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[whole board thinking]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=2791</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In the past, the go board was fragmented in my mind. Depending on the tide of the battle or how certain frameworks were developing, my brain would divide the board into various areas of focus. As a result, I very quickly lost sight of the bigger picture and had a difficult time figuring out what [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In the past, the go board was fragmented in my mind. Depending on the tide of the battle or how certain frameworks were developing, my brain would divide the board into various areas of focus. As a result, I very quickly lost sight of the bigger picture and had a difficult time figuring out what to do next or executing any particular strategy well. In fact, the only time I believe I was able to strategically dominate my opponent is when they jumped head first into a framework I was familiar in utilizing (e.g., the Chinese opening).<br />
To say that I&#8217;ve never experienced the zen of seeing the whole board at once would be untrue, but it wasn&#8217;t until my most recent lesson with frozensoul that I had a shocking awakening that would cause my world to dramatically shift. Games no longer seem like isolated battles that gradually add up to a greater theme. Instead, every move now seems to contribute to the entire picture.<br />
For those who are wondering, this mindset of true &#8220;whole board thinking&#8221; is rather taxing for me. It is far from being instinctively engraved in my brain. I still fall victim to kyu tunnel vision from time to time; but deep down, I can already tell that I have crossed into a new world where there is no turning back.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/no-turning-back/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2791</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A New Perspective on Handicap Go</title>
		<link>/a-new-perspective-on-handicap-go/</link>
		<comments>/a-new-perspective-on-handicap-go/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2013 09:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[excited]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[handicap go]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new perspective]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the possibilities]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=2725</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Over the last couple months, one of the things I&#8217;ve been really wrestling with is my aversion to handicap games: regardless of which side I was on. I can&#8217;t really pinpoint the reason for this fear of playing handicap games, but it was leading me down a path where I was starting to avoid playing handicap games [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Over the last couple months, one of the things I&#8217;ve been really wrestling with is my aversion to handicap games: regardless of which side I was on. I can&#8217;t really pinpoint the reason for this fear of playing handicap games, but it was leading me down a path where I was starting to avoid playing handicap games all together.<br />
There&#8217;s a quote that my brother has on his phone: &#8220;Life begins where your comfort zone ends.&#8221; Although I was not thinking of go when he first showed it to me, it recently dawned upon me that &#8220;getting stronger in go begins where your comfort zone ends.&#8221;<br />
<figure id="attachment_2726" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/05/gru_lightbulb.png"><img class="size-full wp-image-2726" alt="Credit to DespicableMeForum" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/05/gru_lightbulb.png?resize=300%2C169" width="300" height="169" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Credit to <a href="http://www.despicablemeforum.proboards.com/index.cgi?board=movie&amp;action=display&amp;thread=391">DespicableMeForum</a></figcaption></figure>
At that moment, any negative emotions I had about handicap go was instead replaced by excitement for the possibilities that lay beyond the world of handicap go. It&#8217;s not such much that I want to become an expert in handicap go, but there is so much to be learned through playing it that it could mean wonders for my growth. Oh the possibilities&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/a-new-perspective-on-handicap-go/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2725</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
