<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>Advice &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/advice/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>The Importance of Struggling</title>
		<link>/importance-struggling/</link>
		<comments>/importance-struggling/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2014 14:19:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Weekly Go Wednesday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daniel Coyle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[deliberate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[getting stronger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[saxmaam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[struggling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Talent Code]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5370</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Weekly Go Wednesday, Issue #42 For most of the time I studied go, I was always focused on getting the right answer. Perhaps this is a result of being conditioned from school and being obsessed with answering the question correctly, but nonetheless it showed up in my approach to studying go. So more often than [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 style="text-align: center;">Weekly Go Wednesday, Issue #42</h2>
<figure id="attachment_5371" style="width: 420px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/05/wgw42.png"><img class=" wp-image-5371" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/05/wgw42.png?resize=420%2C258" alt="Credit to Business in Canada" width="420" height="258" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Credit to <a href="https://businessincanada.com/2013/08/12/surge-in-proposals-suggests-canadians-are-struggling-to-grapple-with-immense-debt/">Business in Canada</a></figcaption></figure>
For most of the time I studied go, I was always focused on getting the right answer. Perhaps this is a result of being conditioned from school and being obsessed with answering the question correctly, but nonetheless it showed up in my approach to studying go. So more often than not, if I managed to guess what the correct answer was for a particular problem, that would be the end of it and I would move on to the next problem. After all, I got the right answer and that&#8217;s what&#8217;s important isn&#8217;t it?<br />
Of course, the next question is what happened if I got the answer wrong. Well, since I got the answer wrong, the logical choice would be to see what the correct answer is and try to memorize it. In other words, I would focus on understanding why the correct answer was correct and was less concerned with why my answer was wrong. Standard studying mechanism for taking any test in a class right?<br />
Unfortunately, while that sounds okay in theory and may have helped me get through school rather easily, it turns out I have been barking up the wrong tree this entire time.<br />
<span id="more-5370"></span><br />
Recently, fellow go player saxmaam gave her recommendation for <a title="Talent Code Audible Link" href="http://www.audible.com/pd/Science-Technology/The-Talent-Code-Audiobook/B002V8L6MA">The Talent Code</a> by Daniel Coyle, which is themed on the idea of &#8220;unlocking the secret to learning just about any skill.&#8221; I had heard of the book before and been told to read it in the past, but I was too caught up in other things at the time and never got around to it. However, as my approach and perspective on go has been undergoing a lot of transformation recently, so I decided to take it as a sign from the universe that it was time to finally read it.<br />
I haven&#8217;t finished it yet, but I was presented with an idea that inspired the post for today: <strong>one of the key components to learning a skill is making mistakes along the way</strong>. In other words, the essence of getting stronger resides in the struggle it takes to the correct answer and not simply finding the correct answer. And though it seems like such an obvious statement, it is one that I ignored for most of my journey as a go player.<br />
One of the things Coyle talks about is that people who master skills often spend a lot of time focused on what he calls &#8220;deliberate learning.&#8221; In other words, there is a significant conscious effort to constantly critically analyze and patch up weaknesses as the person encounters them. A good analogy for this would be like learning how to play a song on an instrument. Instead of simply trying to play through the whole thing and just barely getting by the tough parts of the song, a person will spend the time to really struggle with that section until they get it right before resuming with the rest of the song.<br />
I grew up playing piano for most of my life and spent many years and hours in the field of music. And when I think back to it, I am rather ashamed of the fact that I was not always the most disciplined when it came to this kind of &#8220;deliberate learning.&#8221; In fact, my thought was always if I could get through most of song without a problem, it would be good enough. After all, who could tell the difference as long as I wasn&#8217;t perfect for the entire song. 80-90% should be good enough right?<br />
When it came to go, the habit of &#8220;winging&#8221; it and getting by with only a general understanding of what was going on became the foundation of how I studied the game. And as a result, the time and energy I spent studying the game was more leisurely and less &#8220;deliberate learning.&#8221;<br />
Upon reflection of my past, I realize now that I was wrong to avoid that stage of struggling during learning. For most of my life, I always felt that if I was struggling, then it was some sign of failure and/or ineptitude. And though you&#8217;ll think I was crazy, I really did think that things coming easy to a person was a sign of talent and the mark of potential success. Perhaps it&#8217;s because I was always surrounded by people more brilliant than I, but those ideas were a part of me for a long time.<br />
I wanted to write this post because I don&#8217;t believe I&#8217;m the only one out there making this mistake. And though I haven&#8217;t figured out the magical equation for how one can ensure they are using &#8220;deliberate learning&#8221; in their study of go (which I will definitely write about when I starting figuring it out), hopefully this post will serve as an inspiration for some of you and a reminder to not get frustrated by those times you struggle with certain ideas and concepts. After all, it is the key to gaining that next stone.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/importance-struggling/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>10</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">5370</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Experience on the Battlefield</title>
		<link>/experience-on-the-battlefield/</link>
		<comments>/experience-on-the-battlefield/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2014 11:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Weekly Go Wednesday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[battlefield]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[experience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[games]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[more]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[playing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[studying too much]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=10</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Weekly Go Wednesday, Issue #41 As many of you are aware, I have been known to prioritize studying and have had no qualms sacrificing playing games in order to do so. My rationale at the time was quite simple: Because I felt like I was always on a time crunch, reading books, studying problems, or [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 style="text-align: center;">Weekly Go Wednesday, Issue #41</h2>
<figure id="attachment_5339" style="width: 494px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2012/10/Keybladesandwarriors.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-5339" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2012/10/Keybladesandwarriors.jpg?resize=494%2C371" alt="Credit to Kingdom Hearts 3 Trailer" width="494" height="371" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Screenshot from <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Q5j8lQ9_9Cc">Kingdom Hearts 2 Secret Ending</a></figcaption></figure>
As many of you are aware, I have been known to prioritize studying and have had no qualms sacrificing playing games in order to do so. My rationale at the time was quite simple: Because I felt like I was always on a time crunch, reading books, studying problems, or even watching videos seemed to be better suited to my lifestyle. 15 minutes here&#8230; 5 minutes there&#8230; That way I could keep &#8220;improving&#8221; without the huge time commitment. Right?<br />
Well, maybe only half right. While I might have picked up a thing or two along the way, my experience at the <a title="1st Washington Open Baduk Championship — Part I" href="//1st-washington-open-baduk-championship-part/">1st Washington Baduk Open Championship</a> was rather traumatic. After getting my butt kicked twice in a row after the first round and deep introspection, I realized I needed to play more. So in light of that realization, I thought it only appropriate to write about the importance of experience on the battlefield.<br />
<span id="more-10"></span><br />
The reason I spent so long focusing on studying instead of playing was for the following reasons:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>&#8220;I will only play long games.&#8221;</strong> &#8211; I forget when I came to this conclusion, but I thought that any game less than 30 minutes main time would be &#8220;too short&#8221; for me. Therefore&#8230;</li>
<li><strong>&#8220;Don&#8217;t have enough time.&#8221;</strong> &#8211; Since 30 min main time games took about 1.5 hours to 2 hours, I felt that I never had that block of time to play.</li>
<li><strong>&#8220;I can study anywhere.&#8221;</strong> &#8211; I&#8217;ve never been a huge fan of playing on my mobile phone, so playing games wasn&#8217;t as convenient as studying books / problems.</li>
</ol>
<p>I mean, sure, I played a few games here and there; but I didn&#8217;t play consistently and definitely did not play as seriously as I might have if I played ranked games. So to no one&#8217;s surprise, my stamina at the tournament was just awful.<br />
After talking with Myung and learning that most Korean players actually play with 10 minute main time, it made me realize that my mandate of only playing &#8220;long games&#8221; was ridiculous and would only stunt my growth. And since I&#8217;ve made the change to play with shorter time settings, it&#8217;s made a huge difference for me.<br />
Whether you like it or not, your skills are only as good as they are on the battlefield. It&#8217;s irrelevant if you can solve dan level problems on your cell phone if you keep making basic mistakes in your actual games.<br />
No amount of book reading or problem solving can replace the invaluable experience of playing actual games, so get out there and play! Brace yourself for the biting wind of intense and competitive play as you charge into the fray to temper your blade. Charge!!!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/experience-on-the-battlefield/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>33</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">10</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>WGW 35: Stop Overthinking</title>
		<link>/wgw-35-stop-overthinking/</link>
		<comments>/wgw-35-stop-overthinking/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2014 01:33:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Weekly Go Wednesday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[overthinking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[too much thinking]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=4839</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Weekly Go Wednesday: Issue #35 Lately I&#8217;ve been piling up topics that I want to write about, but I found myself constantly pushing them off as I wanted to write the perfect article for each and every topic. Similarly, I&#8217;ve also realized that when it comes to playing games, I often find myself sitting there [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 style="text-align: center;">Weekly Go Wednesday: Issue #35</h2>
<p>Lately I&#8217;ve been piling up topics that I want to write about, but I found myself constantly pushing them off as I wanted to write the perfect article for each and every topic. Similarly, I&#8217;ve also realized that when it comes to playing games, I often find myself sitting there thinking about the multiple factors that go into whether or not I&#8217;m &#8220;ready&#8221; to play a game (i.e., how much time do I have, what if my opponent takes forever in byoyomi, what if I have to resign early, what if I&#8217;m not actually ready to play and make silly mistakes, etc. etc. etc.).<br />
Today&#8217;s topic is kind of counter-intuitive since after all, go is a thinking game. However, I think that especially when it comes to amateur players, it&#8217;s actually really important not to overthink things. Because even though we make plenty of stupid moves from the lack of thinking, I think there are a large number of occurrences where players end up making bad moves or not enjoying the game as much as they should due to overthinking.<br />
<span id="more-4839"></span><br />
To some degree, there needs to be a level of acceptance where the dice will fall where they will fall. Once you&#8217;ve reading a fair number of variations, it is useless to sit there and worry that you missed the one variation that would reverse the game in your favor. After all, you&#8217;re on a clock and your growth as a player is measured by the number of games you play and not by the number of perfect moves you make. Or in the instance of my blogging, I could spend hours upon hours trying to write the perfect article; but that would mean I would almost never post and it would take much longer for me to get out the messages I have in my head.<br />
Another instance where overthinking is bad for the go soul is when players play against someone stronger than them. Or well, actually, perceive players to be stronger than them. For example, the mere fact that the number next to a player&#8217;s username is higher is often enough to make players worry about some magic tesuji. As a result, they end up playing inferior moves or &#8220;safe&#8221; moves for fear of &#8220;stronger player-suji.&#8221;<br />
And in my case, I know that I think overthink when it comes to actually playing go. For example, I&#8217;ll login to KGS and look at the Open Games tab. I&#8217;ll gloss over the open games and see if there are any opponents around my level since I don&#8217;t usually enjoy playing handicap games for rank. And then I&#8217;ll consider the time conditions. And once I do that, I click on the challenge and look at my opponent&#8217;s profile to see what kind of player they might be. Are they German? Korean? Russian? Nah I&#8217;m not in a mood to get challenged at every move. Or wait, let&#8217;s see how they played in their past games&#8230; And then usually before I know it, they accept a challenge from another player and I&#8217;m relieved of the burden of playing a game I might lose&#8230;<br />
That was rather lengthy huh? Well that&#8217;s what goes on inside my head and a classic example of me overthinking things. And to be honest, I wouldn&#8217;t be surprised if other people suffered from the same kind of anxiety when it comes to playing games. After all, what if I lose? What if I play poorly and people see? And on and on and on&#8230;.<br />
So hopefully the next time you find yourself overthinking, I hope that you&#8217;ll remember this post and realize that there is only so much you can do before it&#8217;s just not worth worrying about. Think and play to the best of your ability. Don&#8217;t overthink it. In turn, I will stop being so paranoid about each and every game I play. And finally, I will just write more each week instead of trying to craft a perfect post. Off to not overthinking!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/wgw-35-stop-overthinking/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>15</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">4839</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>WGW 26: How to Play as White in Even Games</title>
		<link>/wgw-26-play-white-even-games/</link>
		<comments>/wgw-26-play-white-even-games/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2013 11:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Weekly Go Wednesday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[playing as white]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=4263</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Weekly Go Wednesday, Issue #26 A couple months ago, I had a request put in by fellow go player DecimoKing for an article on my advice on playing as White. This is the first part to a series of posts geared to provide some guidance to players who find themselves feeling burdened when playing White. [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 style="text-align: center;">Weekly Go Wednesday, Issue #26</h2>
<p>A couple months ago, I had a request put in by fellow go player DecimoKing for an article on my advice on playing as White. This is the first part to a series of posts geared to provide some guidance to players who find themselves feeling burdened when playing White. Although this is definitely geared more for beginner/intermediate players, I would appreciate any additional insight from stronger players below to supplement my thoughts here. With that said, let&#8217;s get started with the first scenario as White: even games.<br />
<strong>Concern #1: &#8220;Black is one move ahead! I feel like I&#8217;m behind when I&#8217;m playing White.&#8221;</strong><br />
The first thing to do is to breathe. Inhale. Exhale. Now, what you have to remember is that this is exactly why the komi system was created in the first place. It&#8217;s always very easy to forget that you have komi. In other words, you already start with points when Black starts with none! So if anyone should feel behind, it&#8217;s Black! xD<br />
<strong>Concern #2: &#8220;Black always gets these awesome moyos (i.e., frameworks) that are gigantic and fearsome!&#8221;</strong><br />
What you have to remember here is that you always have a choice of being more aggressive and breaking up Black&#8217;s formation early on in the game.* Will the game get more complicated? Yes. Will it involve a lot more fighting. Absolutely. However, what you have to determine for yourself is which situation do you hate more: a large moyo where you find yourself needing to invade and live or lose, or a game full of fighting that&#8217;s quite complicated.<br />
*The only framework that White can&#8217;t truly stop without ending up in a disadvantageous position is the sanrensei; but if that is what you hate playing against, then the issue is more about learning a counter strategy to sanrensei as opposed to worried about playing White.<br />
In summary, here are a few things to remember when playing White in even games:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Be patient.</strong> Remember that the komi system was designed to compensate for the first move advantage. If you let yourself get caught up in the illusion of being behind, you&#8217;ll find yourself rushing into dangerous situations that will put you at a disadvantage early in the game.</li>
<li><strong>You can always steer the game in a different direction.</strong> If you really hate frameworks like the Chinese Opening and don&#8217;t know any counter strategies to them, go ahead and interrupt the formation before it materializes (aka approach the corner instead of taking a corner for yourself).</li>
<li><strong>Feel honored to play as White.</strong> Don&#8217;t forget that in go, playing as White usually signifies that who is the stronger player. After all, what color do you play if you give your opponent handicap stones? =) So if your intention is to become the strongest player you can possibly be, shouldn&#8217;t White stones become your best friend? xD</li>
</ol>
<p>I hope that this helps and please be sure to leave a comment below if you have any questions or comments!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/wgw-26-play-white-even-games/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">4263</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Stop Being a Worry Wart</title>
		<link>/stop-worry-wart/</link>
		<comments>/stop-worry-wart/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2013 23:52:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[confidence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[courage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[faith in one's strength]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fall and get back up]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[imaginary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[worry]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=4125</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A couple of nights ago, frozensoul mentioned something to me that really struck me. My mind is my greatest opponent. Yup. You read that right. Instead of being trounced by opponents better than me or making dumb mistakes, I often end up out-reading myself. What do I mean by this? I&#8217;m talking about being fearful [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A couple of nights ago, frozensoul mentioned something to me that really struck me.</p>
<blockquote><p>My mind is my greatest opponent.</p></blockquote>
<p>Yup. You read that right. Instead of being trounced by opponents better than me or making dumb mistakes, I often end up out-reading myself.<br />
What do I mean by this? I&#8217;m talking about being fearful of potential aji in X area and adding unnecessary moves &#8220;just in case.&#8221; Now this might sound reasonable, but let&#8217;s think about this one moment. If you are adding a move to an area that doesn&#8217;t require it, are you not essentially passing your turn?<br />
To further illustrate my point, take the following problem:<br />
<figure id="attachment_4139" style="width: 190px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/10/deadgroup.png"><img class=" wp-image-4139 " alt="Black to play." src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/10/deadgroup.png?resize=190%2C189" width="190" height="189" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Black to play.</figcaption></figure>
Is there anyone out there who would suggest that Black capture the White stones &#8220;just to in case?&#8221; Absolutely not. Because any player above 12 kyu would know that it would be completely absurd to do anything but tenuki.<br />
&#8220;But wait Ben! Not all positions are as clear cut as the problem you presented! What happens if you&#8217;re wrong and then you lose because you think you can tenuki when in fact you really can&#8217;t?!&#8221;<br />
Well, to that I have only one question: <strong>Are you trying to get stronger or simply keep winning against opponents of the same strength?</strong><br />
Yes. It would suck if you tenuki when you actually needed a move and then lost a game; but guess what, that is part of growing and learning so that we can get stronger. We make mistakes. We fall. We get back up. We learn. We grow. We get stronger. And the cycle goes on and on&#8230;<br />
So the next time you feel like you&#8217;re in a questionable position, do your best with the reading ability you have and then have faith in your moves. You will make quite a few mistakes along the road, but I assure you that it will be a heck of a lot better than defending against imaginary aji.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/stop-worry-wart/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">4125</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Confidence is Worth Two Stones</title>
		<link>/confidence-worth-two-stones/</link>
		<comments>/confidence-worth-two-stones/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2013 17:59:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[confidence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stop being negative]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zen]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=4059</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Last week, I was playing a game when other players started showing up to watch the game. My opponent then remarked, &#8220;Everyone is here to see me lose.&#8221; And then I promptly replied, &#8220;You&#8217;ve got it wrong. They&#8217;re here to see me lose.&#8221; Though it was said in a joking manner that was also supposed to [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_4111" style="width: 400px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/10/confidence-building.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-4111" alt="Credit to treeofknowledge" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/10/confidence-building.jpg?resize=400%2C300" width="400" height="300" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Credit to <a href="http://www.treeof.com/confidence-building/">treeofknowledge</a></figcaption></figure>
Last week, I was playing a game when other players started showing up to watch the game. My opponent then remarked, &#8220;Everyone is here to see me lose.&#8221; And then I promptly replied, &#8220;You&#8217;ve got it wrong. They&#8217;re here to see me lose.&#8221; Though it was said in a joking manner that was also supposed to be humble, it wasn&#8217;t until after the game that a comment made by a visitng dan player struck me: &#8220;Confidence is worth two stones.&#8221;<br />
It got me thinking about my whole approach to the game, or perhaps life in general. With the way I&#8217;ve been brought up, it&#8217;s expected that one be humble and not be cocky or overconfident. However, I started to wonder whether or not I ended up taking this mentality too far and becoming self-deprecating instead. In other words, even though I would say things like, &#8220;No no, I&#8217;m a weak player&#8221; as a way of being humble; I may have actually been planting seeds of doubt in myself this entire time.<br />
Now to be clear, I&#8217;m not saying that one should prance around saying how they&#8217;ll win every game and rub it in their opponent&#8217;s faces. &#8220;Look at me! I&#8217;m so great!&#8221; I mean sure, sometimes the cockiness works as a placebo effect and some people end up becoming &#8220;stronger,&#8221; but then everyone thinks you&#8217;re an asshole and that is way worse than being a weak player. So instead, I will stop using negative statements and stop worrying about what other people think.<br />
With each stone I play, I will simply aim to play the best go that I can. That is all that matters.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/confidence-worth-two-stones/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">4059</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Finding Time for One Game a Day</title>
		<link>/finding-time-one-game-day/</link>
		<comments>/finding-time-one-game-day/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2013 20:16:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[consistently]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[experience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finding time]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[getting stronger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[one game a day]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[playing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[time]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=3981</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[As many of you are aware, I recently started a discipline of playing at least one game a day. And while I am happy to report that I have been keeping up with it, it occurred to me that there are many people out there who would probably like to attempt something similar; but decide [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/09/findingtime.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-3985" alt="findingtime" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/09/findingtime.jpg?resize=270%2C270" width="270" height="270" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></p>
<p>As many of you are aware, I recently started a discipline of playing at least one game a day. And while I am happy to report that I have been keeping up with it, it occurred to me that there are many people out there who would probably like to attempt something similar; but decide not to due to assuming that it would be too &#8220;time consuming.&#8221; So, I thought that I would go ahead and write about my experience on finding time for one game a day.<br />
<span id="more-3981"></span><br />
When I tried playing blitz (e.g., only 5 periods of 10 second byoyomi) in order to satisfy my &#8220;one game a day,&#8221; I found that the game was more of a blur than an experience and felt like I didn&#8217;t gain anything. After all, blitz games are more about intuition than anything else. On the other hand, when I tried to play a game of typical tournament length (e.g., 30 min main time), I would find my games taking anywhere from an hour to two (which any working person who wants any semblance of a life would agree is death). Therefore, after some experimenting with different time settings, I have found that 10 minutes main time and 3x 30 second byoyomi is about right since it strikes a nice balance between intuition and thinking while not taking too much time out of my day.<br />
Some might quote me on how I once stated that even 20 minute main time games were too short for me; however, the key difference between my analysis then and now is the fact that my focus used to be giving myself the most optimal conditions for winning a game. However, I have come to learn that that approach was too slow. I am fully aware and accept the fact that I will make many mistakes and lose many games as a result of not being able to think every move thoroughly, but the consistent practice and application is something that I am hoping will be beneficial in the long run. After all, the goal with this discipline is not to win; but to gain more experience while not putting a huge strain on your time.<br />
So for those who tend to find themselves studying instead of playing, I ask that you give this habit a shot. Whether it&#8217;s just one game every 3 days or just once a week, go out there, get your feet wet and just play. I don&#8217;t care if it&#8217;s under a secret account that you hide away from the rest of the world, but the important thing is that you do it. That way, when the time comes for you to take the plunge and participate in a tournament, you&#8217;ll feel a lot more comfortable with playing a game and have a much better chance of showing what you&#8217;ve been learning instead of losing because you are rusty from playing.<br />
At the end of the day, no matter how good you are at the various aspects of go (i.e., fuseki, joseki, tesuji, life and death, endgame, etc.), you are only as good as your ability to transition between these skills during a game. The faster you are at moving between them, the better your analysis will be and the stronger you will inevitably be. And no matter what anyone else says, there is nothing that can train this ability better than playing games. So what are you waiting for, get out there and play some go!<br />
<em>For anyone who is wondering where I am playing my daily games, I alternate between KGS and Tygem depending on my mood. Lately, I have been more partial to Tygem since it&#8217;s really easy to find a game and I get to play against players much stronger than me. You are welcome to follow me on my alternate account (that I created awhile ago for the 5 dan Tygem training frozensoul suggested to me): zenblade.  </em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/finding-time-one-game-day/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3981</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nothing But Go</title>
		<link>/nothing-but-go/</link>
		<comments>/nothing-but-go/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2013 21:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[constant pursuit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[discipline]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[focus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[getting stronger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[growth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nothing but go]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=3645</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It occurred to me recently that it seems that all I do is nothing but study, play or write about go. Though I would love that to be the case, I can assure you that it is not the case. I am like any other working soul in society: I have a 9 to 5 [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It occurred to me recently that it seems that all I do is nothing but study, play or write about go. Though I would love that to be the case, I can assure you that it is not the case. I am like any other working soul in society: I have a 9 to 5 job, I live on my own (which means I have to cook, clean, and do all those non-go related chores xD), I have other interests (e.g., web design, coding, tennis, sports, etc.), and I have more familial responsibility than most might care to have. Nonetheless, I have somehow managed to squeeze in go in between all the other things that I care about. Why am I writing about this? Good question.<br />
In most players pursuit to gain another stone, it seems there is an illusion that in order to do so, you must devote all your time and energy the way an insei does. Whether you believe me or not, nothing could be further from the truth.<br />
The reason why I know I can say this with absolute certainty is that most players&#8217; goal is to simply surpass the kyus and successfully live amongst the dan players. In other words, not become a professional. With that in mind, the first step to continuing progress is to realize that progress in go is rarely (if ever) made in leaps and bounds. Similar to building a house, it is important that every level be built with the most solid foundation possible. Otherwise, when the house gets to 4 to 5 stories high, it won&#8217;t take much for the whole thing to come crashing down.<br />
For those who aspire to be professional players, I applaud your tenacity and ambition. In fact, I would have to admit that even I am secretly hoping to rise to the level of a professional. So believe me when I say that the importance of our growth through one solid step at a time is more critical than anyone else. After all, professionals play at a level where the slightest mistake (such as the timing of one forcing move over another) can make the difference between winning and losing.<br />
To those frustrated with their progress, remember that go is a never ending journey where new ideas will constantly be born. The moment we think we know what we&#8217;re doing and have some new &#8220;sure-win&#8221; strategy, someone will come along and blow it away. So just keep at it with an unrelenting discipline to study (even if only for 10 minutes a day) and to focus on playing inspired games where you learn something rather than simply winning. Once you&#8217;ve grasped that, the depth and bottomless pit of wisdom that go has to offer will open its doors to you.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/nothing-but-go/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3645</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Diving into Handicap Games</title>
		<link>/diving-into-handicap-games/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2013 21:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[handicap go]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[playing as black in handicap go]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[playing as white in handicap go]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=2748</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[As I dive further into handicap games, I&#8217;m beginning to gain an appreciation for them. Instead of being something I used to detest and feel powerless to play against, I see each game (regardless of whether I&#8217;m Black or White) as an opportunity to prove that I can elevate my game another notch. When playing [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As I dive further into handicap games, I&#8217;m beginning to gain an appreciation for them. Instead of being something I used to detest and feel powerless to play against, I see each game (regardless of whether I&#8217;m Black or White) as an opportunity to prove that I can elevate my game another notch.<br />
When playing as Black, my goal is to maintain a proactive role while keeping an eye on the connections between my groups while ensuring that my attacks are generating profit at the same time. I do not let overplays scare me into spreading myself out to thin which only serves to White&#8217;s advantage. In addition, I always try to remember that I don&#8217;t need to kill White in order to win. I am already ahead, as long as the territory I gain is more than White is getting, my victory will be assured.<br />
On the opposite end of the spectrum, when I&#8217;m white, my goal is is to aim for any weaknesses in my opponent&#8217;s strategy and position and exploit them while trying to catch up one point at a time. Contrary to my prior approach to playing white in handicap games, the goal is <em><strong>not</strong></em> to make numerous overplays in hopes of the opponents making some tragic mistake.<br />
In addition, one of the hardest things I have found about playing White in handicap games is that the feeling of being behind can become very difficult to handle at certain points in the game. In fact, I feel like for most of the first half of the game, it&#8217;s pretty much an uphill battle the entire time. The crucial point in victory often comes when there are more stones on the board and you can utilize your reading and planning abilities to finally turn the tide.<br />
Anyhow, those are my findings for now. Looking forward to see what else awaits me in the depths of handicap go!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2748</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mental Resilience</title>
		<link>/mental-resilience/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2013 13:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Weekly Go Wednesday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mental resilience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mental strength]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mentality]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=1715</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Weekly Go Wednesday, Issue #23 Imagine a world where boxing was a sport of non-contact sparring. No blood was ever shed. No KO&#8217;s that make you wonder whether or not that person will be okay afterwards. People would crowd around in excitement to watch as two people ran circles around each other shadowboxing the air. [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 style="text-align: center;">Weekly Go Wednesday, Issue #23</h2>
<figure id="attachment_2427" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/04/wgw23.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-2427" alt="Credit to Examiner" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/04/wgw23.jpg?resize=300%2C219" width="300" height="219" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Credit to <a href="http://www.examiner.com/article/boxing-s-future-3d-imax-for-pacquiao-mayweather">Examiner</a></figcaption></figure>
Imagine a world where boxing was a sport of non-contact sparring. No blood was ever shed. No KO&#8217;s that make you wonder whether or not that person will be okay afterwards. People would crowd around in excitement to watch as two people ran circles around each other shadowboxing the air. After all, that&#8217;s why people pay money to watch mixed martial arts (MMA) fights and all right?<br />
Whether you like it or not, one of the reasons that keeps people coming back time and time again to sports like boxing and MMA is that people are putting their skills and pride to the test. With each match, there is an intensity that keeps the audience on their toes when to fighters get into an all out hitting match or whether the underdog will manage to make a miraculous comeback with a perfectly timed uppercut.<br />
If go were simply about surrounding territory with no ability to capture stones, the game would never have gained the popularity it did nor existed for nearly as long. And while you might not get a brain concussion by playing go, the blow of a devastating match can have cause players to even give up the game as a whole. With that said however, there is a critical skill that is essential to every player&#8217;s long term success when it comes to sports and games like boxing and go: mental resilience.<br />
<span id="more-1715"></span><br />
Simply put, mental resilience is a person&#8217;s ability to cope with both positive and negative events in life. It may sound odd to speak of resilience in regards to positive events, but a simple example of this would be winning the lottery. While it is almost universally considered a very fortunate and beneficial event in life, a person&#8217;s inability to handle the aftermath can often bring them down to point lower than before he/she won the lottery.<br />
In go, it is difficult to equate any single game with the equivalent of the lottery (for an amateur player), but simply becoming overconfident due to a winning streak should illustrate the point well enough. With that said however, it should come as no surprise that our focus is on how to toughen your mental resilience so that your losses do not affect you as much as they do now.<br />
One of the major obstacles that many go players face is whether or not to continue forward when faced with a losing streak or traumatizing loss. Like a boxer who has a humiliating defeat when fighting for the a world title, there will always be the pivotal moment of whether the boxer will remain a broken or persevere. And to all go players out there, I am utterly sincere when I say that you must persevere through the difficult times.<br />
In order to help increase your mental resilience, here is some advice:</p>
<ol>
<li><span style="line-height: 13px;"><strong>Create a &#8220;screw-around&#8221; account.</strong> This account is purely for the times where you know that you&#8217;re not quite feeling your normal self at that time. Whether it&#8217;s because you know you might get interrupted, or you have an appointment coming up soon, this account will let you play quick pick-me-up games without the guilt of knowing you caused your rank graph to drop even though you knew you weren&#8217;t in the right mental state to play.</span></li>
<li><strong>Refrain from quick games.</strong> This is particularly for those who don&#8217;t want to create another account. From my experience, quick games for the sake of playing usually lead to feeling in a bad move after a loss due to a regrettable move that you should have easily read out. If you only have 30 minutes for a game before you have to run off somewhere, I&#8217;d be careful.</li>
<li><strong>Play quick games on smaller boards.</strong> For those who know that the itch will be way too strong, just play on a smaller board like 9&#215;9. This will allow you to play to your heart&#8217;s content and will make the defeats have practically zero impact on you.</li>
<li><strong>Each game should be viewed as a punch. A jab. Not a KO.</strong> Although there is an obvious sense of finality to each game, each game should really viewed as a jab in boxing. Sure, you&#8217;re going to completely miss sometimes, but those are necessary in order to refine your punch next time so that you will eventually hit when it actually matters.</li>
<li><strong>Remember: This too shall pass.</strong> Nothing is permanent, and the sooner you understand that will you be able to to bounce back from losses like a little kid on a trampoline.</li>
</ol>
<p>Finally, remember that no matter how good you are at life and death, tesuji, endgame, or any other skill, it is all useless if you do not have the mental resilience to endure the ups and downs of the pursuit of the next stone.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1715</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
