<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>patient &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/patient/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>Book Review: Master Play &#8211; The Style of Lee Changho</title>
		<link>/book-review-master-play-style-lee-changho/</link>
		<comments>/book-review-master-play-style-lee-changho/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2013 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[calm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lee changho]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[patient]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[professional commentary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[style]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=4127</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Master Play: The Style of Lee Changho Description: In the first volume of Yuan Zhou&#8217;s series &#8220;Master Play,&#8221; Zhou provides amateur players with insight into the legendary Lee Changho. Zhou provides two in-depth commentaries on two of Lee Changho&#8217;s games to illustrate Lee Changho&#8217;s brilliance and why his famous &#8220;calm and solid&#8221; style it is so [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/10/Master-Play-Lee-Changho-Cover.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-4129" alt="Master Play Lee Changho Cover" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/10/Master-Play-Lee-Changho-Cover.jpg?resize=288%2C402" width="288" height="402" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">Master Play: The Style of Lee Changho</h2>
<p><strong>Description:</strong> In the first volume of Yuan Zhou&#8217;s series &#8220;Master Play,&#8221; Zhou provides amateur players with insight into the legendary Lee Changho. Zhou provides two in-depth commentaries on two of Lee Changho&#8217;s games to illustrate Lee Changho&#8217;s brilliance and why his famous &#8220;calm and solid&#8221; style it is so effective. Very useful for kyu players who find themselves consistently in violent games.<br />
<span id="more-4127"></span><br />
[expand title=&#8221;Book Details&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
[table]
Title, Master Play: The Style of Lee Changho<br />
Series, Master Play<br />
Author, Yuan Zhou<br />
Publisher, Slate &amp; Shell<br />
Published, &#8220;2007&#8221;<br />
Language, English<br />
ISBN, 1-932001-38-7<br />
Length, 71 Pages<br />
[/table]
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Table of Content&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Lee Changho Wins His First World Title</li>
<li>Lee Changho Wins a Second Fujitsu Cup</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Before I Read This Book&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
When I first started learning about modern day go professionals, it&#8217;s to no one&#8217;s surprise that one of the first names I came upon was Lee Changho. Not only was he extremely famous, but it seemed he was undisputedly #1 at the time (although he might have started dropping ranks by the time I learned about him). So it goes without saying that I was curious what made him so strong, and thus it led me to purchasing this book.<br />
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;My Review&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221; expanded=&#8221;true&#8221;]
Similar to Master Style of Play: Go Seigen, you are initially greeted with a fun little dialogue between Yuan Zhou and two amateur players to give an introduction on Lee Changho and his background. After a couple of pages of this, Zhou then dives right into the game reviews.<br />
One of the things that I enjoyed about the game diagrams in this book is that they are often only a couple moves long. This makes it a lot easier to follow what is going on and allows weaker players to have a chance to understand what is going on. In addition, the variations are kept to a minimum in order to keep a focus on Lee Changho&#8217;s style instead of go theory and technique.<br />
Upon finishing both game commentaries, I am glad that I finally took the time to gain insight into Lee Changho&#8217;s style. It&#8217;s quite simple and straightforward when compared to Go Seigen, but it is one of the more appropriate styles that I feel kyu players should check out first. This is because Lee Changho&#8217;s games convey the prime example of how one does not have to risk battles of epic proportions to win games, which is something I think many kyu players never take the time to learn or realize.<br />
At the end of the day, this is a book that is best suited for those looking to get a glimpse into Lee Changho&#8217;s style and what it means to play calm go. Definitely recommended for kyu players.<br />
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Synopsis&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<strong>What did I enjoy about the book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The introduction on Lee Changho was very entertaining and informative.</li>
<li>The game commentaries focus on Lee Changho&#8217;s brilliance and style instead of go theory and technique.</li>
<li>It is very easy to read and work through.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What did I gain from reading this book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Having my eyes opened to how even the simplest of moves can still determine a decisive victory.</li>
<li>Realized how greedy my style of go is.</li>
<li>Realization of how I need to learn how play more calmly.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What is the format of the book?</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>A biography of Lee Changho that is a few pages long and reads like a story.</li>
<li>Game commentaries that follow the standard structure of diagrams accompanied by their explanations.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>What aspect can be improved on?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>No complaints here!</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Is this book easy to read?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Yes. The book was easy to read and work through.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Bottom Line</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>A fantastic introduction to Lee Changho and his rise to fame.</li>
<li>Contains two memorable games that illustrate the unyielding strength that Lee Changho posseses.</li>
<li>Well worth the price of admission if you are interested in learning about Lee Changho and his style of go.</li>
</ol>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Recommended For&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Players who are interested in learning more about Lee Changho&#8217;s style.</li>
<li>Players who are interested in reading in-depth but understandable commentaries of two of Lee Changho&#8217;s games.</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Where Can I Buy It?&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Slate &amp; Shell &#8211; <a href="http://www.slateandshell.com/SSYZ005.html">$15.50</a> USD (shipping and handling not included)</li>
<li>SmartGo Books &#8211; <a title="SmartGo Books" href="http://www.gobooks.com/books.html">$4.99</a> USD (e-Book)</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Other Books in This Series&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;lastExpandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Master Play: The Style of Lee Changho</li>
<li><a title="Book Review: Master Play — The Style of Go Seigen" href="//book-review-master-play-style-go-seigen/">Master Play: The Style of Go Seigen</a></li>
<li>Master Play: The Style of Takemiya</li>
<li>Master Play: The Fighting Styles of Kato Masao &amp; Seo Bong Soo</li>
<li>Master Play: The Territorial Styles of Kitani Minoru &amp; Cho Chikun</li>
<li>Master Play: the Playing Style of Seven Top Pros</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
<p style="text-align: center;"><em><strong>Last Updated on October 10th, 2013</strong></em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/book-review-master-play-style-lee-changho/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">4127</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
