<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"

	>
<channel>
	<title>Comments on: Monday Go Meditation: Game 56</title>
	<atom:link href="/monday-go-meditation-game-56/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/monday-go-meditation-game-56/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2015 12:34:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
	<item>
		<title>By: Ben</title>
		<link>/monday-go-meditation-game-56/#comment-1988</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ben]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2014 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5232#comment-1988</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Agreed. If they are teaching games, it is a completely different matter. Though you have to understand that sometimes &quot;overplays&quot; are things like intentionally leaving a cut to see if the weaker player has the guts to make it. So keep in mind that &quot;overplays&quot; has a lot of different meanings to it. It&#039;s not always some crazy move that tries to confuse the game. =)]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Agreed. If they are teaching games, it is a completely different matter. Though you have to understand that sometimes &#8220;overplays&#8221; are things like intentionally leaving a cut to see if the weaker player has the guts to make it. So keep in mind that &#8220;overplays&#8221; has a lot of different meanings to it. It&#8217;s not always some crazy move that tries to confuse the game. =)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Ben</title>
		<link>/monday-go-meditation-game-56/#comment-1987</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ben]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2014 03:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5232#comment-1987</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[You are 110% correct. I will be sure to revise the statement in the post.
The reason I wrote it that way at the time is probably due to the specific nature of the lesson I had extrapolated from that game. And perhaps the traumatic nature of doing it against stronger players is what caused me to qualify it that way.
Thanks for your insight and advice! Really appreciate it!]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>You are 110% correct. I will be sure to revise the statement in the post.<br />
The reason I wrote it that way at the time is probably due to the specific nature of the lesson I had extrapolated from that game. And perhaps the traumatic nature of doing it against stronger players is what caused me to qualify it that way.<br />
Thanks for your insight and advice! Really appreciate it!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Ben</title>
		<link>/monday-go-meditation-game-56/#comment-1986</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ben]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2014 03:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5232#comment-1986</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[To be honest, I completely forgot about the -39.5 komi when I was playing. If I had thought about it, I probably would have played a while longer. I guess I was just tired from having such a terrible position on the board. Haha.
Definitely goes to show why positional judgment and counting are so important in this game. Things are not always as obvious as we think they might be...]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>To be honest, I completely forgot about the -39.5 komi when I was playing. If I had thought about it, I probably would have played a while longer. I guess I was just tired from having such a terrible position on the board. Haha.<br />
Definitely goes to show why positional judgment and counting are so important in this game. Things are not always as obvious as we think they might be&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Noam Taich</title>
		<link>/monday-go-meditation-game-56/#comment-1985</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Noam Taich]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 25 May 2014 12:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5232#comment-1985</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Oh it was a -39.5 komi game according to the sgf - if so - in the end position, the game isn&#039;t that far apart to resign yet... Though I admit it is a bit frustrating knowing you have to play a long middlegame/endgame against a much stronger player starting from a bad position...]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Oh it was a -39.5 komi game according to the sgf &#8211; if so &#8211; in the end position, the game isn&#8217;t that far apart to resign yet&#8230; Though I admit it is a bit frustrating knowing you have to play a long middlegame/endgame against a much stronger player starting from a bad position&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Noam Taich</title>
		<link>/monday-go-meditation-game-56/#comment-1984</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Noam Taich]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 25 May 2014 12:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5232#comment-1984</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[You say - &quot;When playing against a player significantly stronger than you, creating multiple weak groups is about the worst thing you could possibly do.&quot;
Allow me to suggest that you remove the qualification in that sentence - that should help in any game, regardless of opponent - that is - remove the first half of the sentence -
&quot;creating multiple weak groups is about the worst thing you could possibly do&quot;.
Whether the opponent is stronger or weaker is irrelevant.
To play better, that&#039;s one of the most important things to work on. Playing multiple weak groups even against a weaker player, just means that if you lose because of it, you have only yourself to blame, but if you win, it might be worse, as you may be getting yourself used to playing in a bad way, which would prevent you from playing well in the long run, and therefore hinder your improvement.
If you follow Battousai&#039;s lectures on KGS (dwyrin on youtube. He has a huge amount of his Go related lectures there, highly recommended) - I like his way of putting it -
&quot;Being a dan player is mostly a matter of being able to count to 2...&quot;.
Over time, I got to realize that this minimalistic view is closer to the truth than most people realize.
The important thing is - If you have, or am forced to make 2 or more weak groups, either the opponent has the same number of problems (at least), or you&#039;re in bad shape :)
Good thing to play according to against equally skilled opponents as well :)]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>You say &#8211; &#8220;When playing against a player significantly stronger than you, creating multiple weak groups is about the worst thing you could possibly do.&#8221;<br />
Allow me to suggest that you remove the qualification in that sentence &#8211; that should help in any game, regardless of opponent &#8211; that is &#8211; remove the first half of the sentence &#8211;<br />
&#8220;creating multiple weak groups is about the worst thing you could possibly do&#8221;.<br />
Whether the opponent is stronger or weaker is irrelevant.<br />
To play better, that&#8217;s one of the most important things to work on. Playing multiple weak groups even against a weaker player, just means that if you lose because of it, you have only yourself to blame, but if you win, it might be worse, as you may be getting yourself used to playing in a bad way, which would prevent you from playing well in the long run, and therefore hinder your improvement.<br />
If you follow Battousai&#8217;s lectures on KGS (dwyrin on youtube. He has a huge amount of his Go related lectures there, highly recommended) &#8211; I like his way of putting it &#8211;<br />
&#8220;Being a dan player is mostly a matter of being able to count to 2&#8230;&#8221;.<br />
Over time, I got to realize that this minimalistic view is closer to the truth than most people realize.<br />
The important thing is &#8211; If you have, or am forced to make 2 or more weak groups, either the opponent has the same number of problems (at least), or you&#8217;re in bad shape 🙂<br />
Good thing to play according to against equally skilled opponents as well 🙂</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: RisingStar</title>
		<link>/monday-go-meditation-game-56/#comment-1983</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[RisingStar]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2014 12:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5232#comment-1983</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I agree.
Guess I should remember never to play handicap games with you, Ben XD]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I agree.<br />
Guess I should remember never to play handicap games with you, Ben XD</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: RisingStar</title>
		<link>/monday-go-meditation-game-56/#comment-1982</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[RisingStar]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2014 12:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5232#comment-1982</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Good point. However, I think that if it is a teaching game or some other kind of non-competitive game in which White is trying to help Black, then White should avoid overplays. I have played too many handicap &quot;teaching&quot; games in which whites objective ended up being to make overplays in attempts to confuse me. Those games never ended well XD]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Good point. However, I think that if it is a teaching game or some other kind of non-competitive game in which White is trying to help Black, then White should avoid overplays. I have played too many handicap &#8220;teaching&#8221; games in which whites objective ended up being to make overplays in attempts to confuse me. Those games never ended well XD</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Ben</title>
		<link>/monday-go-meditation-game-56/#comment-1981</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ben]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2014 10:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5232#comment-1981</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Fascinating observation! I&#039;ve never quite thought of it that way. Perhaps I&#039;ve been too entrenched in kyu level handicap games. Haha. Thanks for pointing this out!]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Fascinating observation! I&#8217;ve never quite thought of it that way. Perhaps I&#8217;ve been too entrenched in kyu level handicap games. Haha. Thanks for pointing this out!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Moboy78</title>
		<link>/monday-go-meditation-game-56/#comment-1980</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Moboy78]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2014 02:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5232#comment-1980</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I think overplays appear not because the handicaps are incorrect, but because white isn&#039;t strong enough to only play moves that aren&#039;t overplays.  I&#039;m not say that white isn&#039;t necessarily capable of that, but what I&#039;ve found is that unless kyu players are playing people substantially weaker than they are, then they&#039;ll play overplays to make up the difference because they aren&#039;t strong enough to fully take advantage of their opponent&#039;s mistakes.  Mid to high dan level players that I&#039;ve seen play handicap against weaker players usually make up their point deficit in the endgame or in fighting, where their weaker opponents would naturally make mistakes without white having to make an overplay.  Though, I could be completely wrong about all this since it&#039;s just my opinion =)]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I think overplays appear not because the handicaps are incorrect, but because white isn&#8217;t strong enough to only play moves that aren&#8217;t overplays.  I&#8217;m not say that white isn&#8217;t necessarily capable of that, but what I&#8217;ve found is that unless kyu players are playing people substantially weaker than they are, then they&#8217;ll play overplays to make up the difference because they aren&#8217;t strong enough to fully take advantage of their opponent&#8217;s mistakes.  Mid to high dan level players that I&#8217;ve seen play handicap against weaker players usually make up their point deficit in the endgame or in fighting, where their weaker opponents would naturally make mistakes without white having to make an overplay.  Though, I could be completely wrong about all this since it&#8217;s just my opinion =)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Ben</title>
		<link>/monday-go-meditation-game-56/#comment-1979</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ben]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2014 01:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5232#comment-1979</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[But if White doesn&#039;t expect Black to make a mistake and simply plays calmly, how does White ever make up the handicap difference?
If you think about it, the reason for the handicap stones is because Black is more likely to make mistakes in the game that White can take full advantage of. So the handicap stones are to help him out.
Don&#039;t forget, if Black could punish the overplays, then he wouldn&#039;t need the handicap stones and White would get destroyed. But if you look at any handicap game that White wins, Black almost always makes an error of some sort that allows White to reverse the game. Otherwise White would never win.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>But if White doesn&#8217;t expect Black to make a mistake and simply plays calmly, how does White ever make up the handicap difference?<br />
If you think about it, the reason for the handicap stones is because Black is more likely to make mistakes in the game that White can take full advantage of. So the handicap stones are to help him out.<br />
Don&#8217;t forget, if Black could punish the overplays, then he wouldn&#8217;t need the handicap stones and White would get destroyed. But if you look at any handicap game that White wins, Black almost always makes an error of some sort that allows White to reverse the game. Otherwise White would never win.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
</channel>
</rss>
