<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>fall 2010 &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/fall-2010/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>First Tournament!</title>
		<link>/first-tournament/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Oct 2010 14:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fall 2010]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tournament]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[umbc go tournament]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=58</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[So the UMBC Go Tournament was the first tournament I helped to run and play in. What a fortunate occasion! Anyhow, it was a bit of craziness trying to transport everything. I need to figure out a better system for the future (although thank goodness I had portable carts, an empty box, and an empty [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>So the UMBC Go Tournament was the first tournament I helped to run and play in. What a fortunate occasion! Anyhow, it was a bit of craziness trying to transport everything. I need to figure out a better system for the future (although thank goodness I had portable carts, an empty box, and an empty luggage).<br />
<strong>Tournament Summary</strong>: We had about 20 people show up. It was apparently not a huge showing but I think it was pretty good for a tournament that was planned and announced within a month. We&#8217;ll aim for better next time.<br />
<strong>Results</strong>: Justin Teng and Jason Long took 1st place in their respective divisions. How did I do? 0-3. (There was an odd number of players in Round 2 so I dropped out for that round).<br />
<strong>Overview</strong>: The first two games I lost were against SDKs. I took no handicap against the first match which proved to be disadvantageous but I don&#8217;t think I played poorly. In the other SDK game I actually played quite well but my opponent managed to bring a large group back to life. In the final loss against a DDK, there was a lot of fighting but I spread myself out too thin.<br />
<strong>Meta-Analysis</strong>: I&#8217;m happy with my results. I played interesting games where I wasn&#8217;t afraid to jump into questionable territory for fear of not gaining a win. I fought well and believe that my issue is the inability to maintain well balanced play throughout the entire game. That&#8217;s okay with me, because that means there is very obvious and definite growth in the horizon.<br />
<strong>Take-Away Lesson</strong>: What does it mean to lose? What does it mean to win? There&#8217;s a scene in Hikaru no Go where Akira&#8217;s dad (who was considered the best player in that day in age) loss a game against Ogata. And instead of focusing on the fact that he lost, the audience focused on the fact that his game of Go had taken a new life and was evolving in new and exciting ways. That&#8217;s the way one should view the results. It&#8217;s always nice to have a solid win, but growing and learning from your game is the only we can progress not only on the board, but in life as well.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">58</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
