<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>turn based go &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/turn-based-go/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>Up and Roaring on DGS</title>
		<link>/up-and-roaring-on-dgs/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2013 13:07:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dgs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dragon go server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[turn based go]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=2250</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Thanks to Paul, it seems that I may never ever be in a playing slump ever again. Haha. I am now officially active on Dragon Go Server (DGS)! The first time I tried playing on DGS, I never turned on the notifications feature and thus could not quite grasp the beauty of turn based go. [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Thanks to Paul, it seems that I may never ever be in a playing slump ever again. Haha. I am now officially active on <a href="http://www.dragongoserver.net/">Dragon Go Server</a> (DGS)!<br />
The first time I tried playing on DGS, I never turned on the notifications feature and thus could not quite grasp the beauty of turn based go. Now that the feature has been turned on though, I find it pretty exciting when I get an email telling me it&#8217;s my turn to play.<br />
For those who find that they are a bit short on time and can&#8217;t block out a couple hours for a good game of go, I completely agree with Paul in that this is a fantastic way to fill the void of not being able to play. In fact, I think there may be some validity in Paul&#8217;s sentiment of turn based go helping him to improve faster since &#8220;a subconcious piece of my mind [is] dwelling on board positions&#8221; as he goes about his day. As someone who is starting to play turn based go, I certainly hope he&#8217;s right!<br />
Especially for those of you who are busy with school and can never find time to play a game with me, I definitely think DGS is the way to go. And to sweeten the deal, there is even a free Android (search for <strong>anDGS</strong>)/iPhone app (search for <strong>Dragon Go Client</strong>) so you can play on the go! My username is bengozen on there as well, so add me and send me an invite for a game! Looking forward to seeing you across the board!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2250</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
