<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>no rushed games &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/no-rushed-games/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>A Playing Slump</title>
		<link>/a-playing-slump/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2013 03:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[no rushed games]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[no time]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[playing slump]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=2215</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It seems I&#8217;ve hit a bit of a playing slump recently. Every time I&#8217;m asked to play a game, I find myself turning down most games (except in rare cases where frozen or a friend asks for a game). It&#8217;s not so much that I don&#8217;t like playing anymore, but each time I want to [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It seems I&#8217;ve hit a bit of a playing slump recently. Every time I&#8217;m asked to play a game, I find myself turning down most games (except in rare cases where frozen or a friend asks for a game).<br />
It&#8217;s not so much that I don&#8217;t like playing anymore, but each time I want to start a game, I have this nagging feeling that something else needs to be done or start feeling worried that I&#8217;ll be interrupted. After all, a full game of go for me can easily take anywhere from 1.5 to 2 hours without skipping a beat. And frankly, life has not been too lenient in terms of giving me 2 hour blocks of time to play a game of go. As a result, I&#8217;ve been rather hesitant lately to play any ranked/tournament games for fear of needing to leave, resign, or rush the game.<br />
For those who have been following, that is a recipe for disaster for my go. Odds are very good that I will end up regretting the game I played. So to avoid me possibly going on tilt or becoming frustrated, I&#8217;ve been doing a bit of reading, studying, watching, and reviewing other people&#8217;s games in order to get my go fix. Although I know it isn&#8217;t quite the same as playing the game, my little workaround will have to suffice until life eases up a bit.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2215</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
