<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>fighting &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/fighting/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>Book Review &#8211; Fighting Fundamentals</title>
		<link>/book-review-fighting-fundamentals/</link>
		<comments>/book-review-fighting-fundamentals/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2014 14:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fighting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fundamental]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jasiek]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[textbook]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=4665</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Fighting Fundamentals Description: When it comes to fighting, many players are often confused with the principles behind fighting. In this book, Jasiek tries to answer all the essential questions about fighting. This book covers a wide array of material that is more suited for the very studious players. [expand title=&#8221;Book Details&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;] [table] Title, Fighting [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/02/Fighting_Fundamentals_Cover.png"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-4676" alt="Fighting_Fundamentals_Cover" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/02/Fighting_Fundamentals_Cover.png?resize=284%2C402" width="284" height="402" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">Fighting Fundamentals</h2>
<p><strong>Description:</strong> When it comes to fighting, many players are often confused with the principles behind fighting. In this book, Jasiek tries to answer all the essential questions about fighting. This book covers a wide array of material that is more suited for the very studious players.<br />
<span id="more-4665"></span><br />
[expand title=&#8221;Book Details&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
[table]
Title, Fighting Fundamentals<br />
Author, Robert Jasiek<br />
Publisher, Robert Jasiek<br />
Published, &#8220;May 27th, 2013&#8243;<br />
Language, English<br />
Length, 256 Pages<br />
[/table]
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Table of Content&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Chapter 1 &#8211; Introduction</li>
<li>Chapter 2 &#8211; Basics
<ul>
<li>The Most Basic Terms and Ideas</li>
<li>Important and Valuable</li>
<li>Life and Death</li>
<li>Stability</li>
<li>Thickness and Influence</li>
<li>Aji</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Chapter 3 &#8211; Types of Fights
<ul>
<li>Problems</li>
<li>Mutual Settling Fight</li>
<li>Reduction</li>
<li>Mutual Reduction Fight</li>
<li>Invasion</li>
<li>Attack on One Group</li>
<li>Splitting Attack</li>
<li>Multiple Groups Fight</li>
<li>Mutual Running Fight</li>
<li>Cutting Fight</li>
<li>Leaning Attack</li>
<li>Exchange</li>
<li>Capturing Race</li>
<li>Complex Fight</li>
<li>Answers</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Chapter 4 &#8211; Primary Aims
<ul>
<li>Problems</li>
<li>Defended Life</li>
<li>Capture versus Sacrifice and Exchange</li>
<li>Threatened versus Prevented Capture of a Group</li>
<li>Threatened versus Prevented Capture of Part of a Group</li>
<li>Threatened versus Defended Stability</li>
<li>Offering a Strategic Choice</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Chapter 5 &#8211; Secondary Aims
<ul>
<li>Territory
<ul>
<li>Making Territory</li>
<li>Shifting the Territory Balance</li>
<li>Strengthening One&#8217;s Own Territory</li>
<li>Preventing Opposing Territory</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Influence
<ul>
<li>Making Influence</li>
<li>Strengthening One&#8217;s Own Influence</li>
<li>Preventing or Restricting Opposing Influence</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Aji
<ul>
<li>Exploiting Aji</li>
<li>Creating Aji</li>
<li>Eliminating Aji</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Playing Elsewhere</li>
<li>Answer</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Chapter 6 &#8211; Fighting Techniques and Moves
<ul>
<li>Problems</li>
<li>Reading</li>
<li>interruption</li>
<li>Attacking Life
<ul>
<li>Capturing</li>
<li>Cut</li>
<li>Blocking Directions</li>
<li>Attacking Eyespace</li>
<li>Maintaining Connection and Life</li>
<li>Flexibility</li>
<li>Severity</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Defending Life
<ul>
<li>Simplicity</li>
<li>Maintaining Connection</li>
<li>Connection to Another Group</li>
<li>Improving Eyespace</li>
<li>Running</li>
<li>Capturing</li>
<li>Options</li>
<li>Contact Plays</li>
<li>Flexibility</li>
<li>Efficiency</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Forcing
<ul>
<li>The Attacker&#8217;s Forcing</li>
<li>The Defender&#8217;s Forcing</li>
<li>Combining Attack and Defense</li>
<li>Resistance</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Timing</li>
<li>Sacrifice</li>
<li>Answers</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Chapter 7 &#8211; Strategy
<ul>
<li>Problems</li>
<li>About What and Where to Fight</li>
<li>General Fighting Strategy</li>
<li>Reduction and Invasion</li>
<li>Answers</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Chapter 8 &#8211; Index</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;My Review&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221; expanded=&#8221;true&#8221;]
Like many other players, when I first saw the title of this book, I wanted to get my hands on it as soon as I possibly could. However, while the idea of having all of the &#8220;fighting fundamentals&#8221; covered in a single book sounds enticing and attractive, there is way more than meets the eye.<br />
In order to understand my review on the book and how it relates to you, it is critical to first emphasize the following: fighting is a complicated topic. And when I say complicated, I mean it is probably by far the most complex and intricate of all the topics in go. Other things in go like joseki and fuseki can be explained rather simply with relative ease. Fighting, however, is a far more difficult animal to tackle. As a result, the thing I want you to realize from the get go is that fighting in go does not fit into easy principles like &#8220;approach from the wider side&#8221; the way you want it to.<br />
Secondly, I want to clearly state that my learning style is perhaps different than the average go player. If I were to use the analogy of a bird learning how to fly, I would have to say that there are a number of people out there who would learn flying methodically. In other words, they might learn to flap their wings first, and then maybe learn about air currents and how they impact flight patterns, etc. However, I am more of the jump out of the nest and learn to fly on the way down kind of person. I prefer experience and practical application over deep theories that require significant time of study.<br />
With that said, Jasiek has done a great job in producing the first English go book to really try and approach this monstrosity of a topic. As you can see from the table of contents, there are so many different aspects of fighting that Jasiek covers. And to be honest, I wouldn&#8217;t be surprised if there were a lot more that could be written on. However, as far as my personal experience goes, I have to say that working through the book felt a lot like the time I took organic chemistry in college.<br />
What do I mean by that? Well, at the very fundamental level, I accepted and understood the basic logic behind what was being taught. There were rules and general principles that applied to why things worked the way they did. Before I knew it though, I was drowning in a sea of different theories, terms and intricacies that overwhelmed my brain and it didn&#8217;t take long before I started losing interest. &#8220;If you attack here, you must keep in mind of X; but also realize that Y might impact Z in a way that implicates the life of X and Y.&#8221; *dizzy*<br />
The thing to realize is this: fighting is complicated. And while Jasiek has done a great job trying to organize it into different sections and try to break everything down into principles, it doesn&#8217;t change the fact that fighting is a multi-faceted skill that will not improve simply because you read a book. There are so many aspects that go into it: your reading ability, your positional judgment ability, your life and death, etc. So unless those are up to par, fighting will still seem like a chaotic whirlwind that you won&#8217;t be able to make much sense of.<br />
At the end of the day, while I personally had a difficult time absorbing the material in the book, this book is truly a milestone for Western go literature in its effort to pioneer a way for us to learn about fighting. And to be honest, I think that I might just be a weird outlier who doesn&#8217;t have the diligence or tenacity to absorb the material. So if even a small part of you believes that you have the personality and learning style suited to benefiting from this book, then I would disregard my experience of the book and recommend you get it whenever possible.<br />
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Synopsis&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<strong>What did I enjoy about the book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>There are lots of examples throughout the book.</li>
<li>Utilizes typographic elements like bullet points and bold to emphasize its points.</li>
<li>A very thorough breakdown of topics that fit together well logistically.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What did I gain from reading this book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Realization that I am a far cry from being able to truly grasp and apply the material in the book.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What is the format of the book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Textbook. Concepts are introduced and are accompanied by numerous examples along with a few practice problems at the end of each section as well.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What aspects can be improved on?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>I am only commenting on this from a weak amateur perspective, but the information was very difficult to process as a whole for myself. And to be fair, I recognize that this book is an important step to creating a more &#8220;user-friendly&#8221; version of teaching fighting principles, but overall I had a harder time working through and learning with this book due to my learning style.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Is this book easy to read?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>There is so much information in this book that it is not easy to gloss through at all. It definitely reads more like an academic textbook that requires slow and deliberate reading. Almost as if you were taking a course and you were trying to memorize all the different theories and how they fit together.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Bottom Line</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>A great first milestone for Western literature on the topic of fighting.</li>
<li>Suited for players who are very studious and enjoy learning through an intricate textbook.</li>
<li>Not recommended for players looking to get a light overview of fighting.</li>
</ol>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Recommended For&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Players interested in a methodical and textbook approach to the study of fighting.</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Where Can I Buy It?&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221; expanded=&#8221;true&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Robert Jasiek (Printed) &#8211; <a href="http://home.snafu.de/jasiek/PositionalJudgement.html">EUR 26.50 (shipping and handling not included)</a></li>
<li>Robert Jasiek (e-Book) &#8211; <a href="http://home.snafu.de/jasiek/PositionalJudgement.html">EUR 13.25</a></li>
</ul>
[/expand]
<p style="text-align: center;"><em><strong>Last Updated on February 20th, 2014</strong></em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/book-review-fighting-fundamentals/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>10</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">4665</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Book Review: The Fighting Styles of Kato Masao and Seo Bong Soo</title>
		<link>/book-review-fighting-styles-kato-masao-seo-bong-soo/</link>
		<comments>/book-review-fighting-styles-kato-masao-seo-bong-soo/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2013 13:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[attacking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[defense]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fighting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fighting style]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kato masao]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[killer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[korean]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[seo bong soo]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=4301</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Master Play: The Fighting Styles of Kato Masao &#38; Seo Bong Soo Description: In this X volume of the Master Play series, Yuan Zhou does a magnificent job taking amateur players through what is actually considered &#8220;fighting style&#8221; in the professional world of go. Due to the chaotic nature that go can take in crazy [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/11/MasterPlay-fighting.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-4302" alt="MasterPlay fighting" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/11/MasterPlay-fighting.jpg?resize=288%2C419" width="288" height="419" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">Master Play: The Fighting Styles of Kato Masao &amp; Seo Bong Soo</h2>
<p><strong>Description:</strong> In this X volume of the Master Play series, Yuan Zhou does a magnificent job taking amateur players through what is actually considered &#8220;fighting style&#8221; in the professional world of go. Due to the chaotic nature that go can take in crazy cross-cuts and blown out battles, it is no surprise that many kyu players might consider themselves &#8220;fighters,&#8221; but once you read this book, it might open to your eyes as to what fighting really means.<br />
<span id="more-4301"></span><br />
[expand title=&#8221;Book Details&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
[table]
Title, The Fighting Styles of Kato Masao &amp; Seo Bong Soo<br />
Series, Master Play Series<br />
Author, Yuan Zhou<br />
Publisher, Slate &amp; Shell<br />
Published, &#8220;2009&#8221;<br />
Language, English<br />
ISBN, 1-932001-45-X<br />
Length, 484 (iPhone) Pages (Smartbook Version)<br />
[/table]
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Table of Content&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Introduction</li>
<li>A Brief Biography of Kato Masao</li>
<li>Kato&#8217;s Big Breakthrough</li>
<li>Kato at Full Strength</li>
<li>A Brief Biography of Seo Bong Soo</li>
<li>Seo Becomes a World Champion</li>
<li>Seo Stops Another Top Japanese Pro</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Before I Read This Book&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
Like many kyu players out there, I always considered myself to have a &#8220;fighting style.&#8221; After all, my games consisted primarily of big battles and trying to kill things. If that&#8217;s not fighting, what is right? Well I wanted to find out for myself whether I could see my go in famous professional players actually known for their fighting. So as I&#8217;m in a bit of a haze in my journey at the moment, it wasn&#8217;t long before I found myself purchasing this book to try and shed some light on my own style.<br />
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;My Review&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221; expanded=&#8221;true&#8221;]
Similar to the previous volumes I read (Master Play: The Style of Lee Changho and The Style of Go Seigen), Yuan Zhou began each section with a brief introduction to the player&#8217;s background. Being as I am still quite unfamiliar with the professional go scene, it was very entertaining while very informative. Without the introductions, I imagine that the game review would not have been nearly as enjoyable.<br />
In this volume, Zhou reviews two monumental games from each players&#8217; career. With each one, the diagrams are usually quite short and the accompanying explanations really helped me to follow the games without much issue. It definitely feels like the explanations were written with kyu amateur players in mind.<br />
It was just utterly astounding seeing how these infamous &#8220;fighters&#8221; actually played.<br />
Yet again, Yuan Zhou does not fail to amaze me with how he is able to explain what is going on in the board.<br />
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Synopsis&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<strong>What did I enjoy about the book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Focused on a topic of great interest to me: fighting.</li>
<li>Did a great job showing what &#8220;fighting&#8221; looks like at the professional level.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What did I gain from reading this book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Realization that &#8220;fighting style&#8221; is actually different from what I thought.</li>
<li>Better understanding of what fighting is.</li>
<li>Greater appreciation for Kato Masao and Seo Bong Soo.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What is the format of the book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Standard game review structure: Game Sequence &#8211;&gt; Explanation &#8211;&gt; Variations &#8211;&gt; Explanations &#8211;&gt; Repeat.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What aspect(s) can be improved on?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>No complaints here.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Is this book easy to read?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Yes. The diagrams are short and the accompanying explanations are easy to understand.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Bottom Line</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>Games and explanations are not overbearing and relatively easy to follow.</li>
<li>Really helped to start shedding light on what &#8220;fighting style&#8221; really is.</li>
<li>Highly recommended for anyone interested in seeing professional level &#8220;fighting style.&#8221;</li>
</ol>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Recommended For&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Kyu players interested in seeing great examples for actual &#8220;fighting style.&#8221;</li>
<li>Players who are fans of either Kato Masao and Seo Bong Soo and would love to learn more about them.</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Where Can I Buy It?&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Slate &amp; Shell &#8211; <a title="Slate and Shell Book" href="http://www.slateandshell.com/SSYZ008.html">$17.50</a> USD</li>
<li>SmartGo Books &#8211; <a title="SmartGo Books" href="http://gobooks.com/books.html">$6.99</a> USD (e-Book)</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Other Books in This Series&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;lastExpandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li><a title="Book Review: Master Play — The Style of Lee Changho" href="//book-review-master-play-style-lee-changho/">Master Play: The Style of Lee Changho</a></li>
<li><a title="Book Review: Master Play — The Style of Go Seigen" href="//book-review-master-play-style-go-seigen/">Master Play: The Style of Go Seigen</a></li>
<li>Master Play: The Style of Takemiya</li>
<li>Master Play: The Fighting Styles of Kato Masao &amp; Seo Bong Soo</li>
<li>Master Play: The Territorial Styles of Kitani Minoru &amp; Cho Chikun</li>
<li>Master Play: the Playing Style of Seven Top Pros</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
<p style="text-align: center;"><em><strong>Last Updated on November 16th, 2013.</strong></em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/book-review-fighting-styles-kato-masao-seo-bong-soo/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">4301</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Book Review: Fight Like a Pro &#8211; The Secrets of Kiai</title>
		<link>/book-review-fight-like-a-pro-the-secrets-of-kiai/</link>
		<comments>/book-review-fight-like-a-pro-the-secrets-of-kiai/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2013 09:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fighting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[innovative]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kiai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[resistance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spirit]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=3586</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Fight Like a Pro &#8211; The Secrets of Kiai Description: In the final installment of the Mastering the Basics Series, Zeijst and Bozulich bring the first significant effort to trying to put the concept of kiai on paper. In this book, you will find 16 fighting games by some of the world&#8217;s strongest players from [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/07/mtbsv8cover.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3587" alt="Mastering the Basics 8 Cover" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/07/mtbsv8cover.jpg?resize=300%2C444" width="300" height="444" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">Fight Like a Pro &#8211; The Secrets of Kiai</h2>
<p><strong>Description:</strong> In the final installment of the Mastering the Basics Series, Zeijst and Bozulich bring the first significant effort to trying to put the concept of kiai on paper. In this book, you will find 16 fighting games by some of the world&#8217;s strongest players from Korean, China, and Japan along with problems to give the reader practice at trying to figure out the &#8220;kiai move.&#8221; This book can be seen a culmination of everything that the reader has been learning throughout the series and will be a classic in go literature.<br />
<span id="more-3586"></span><br />
[expand title=&#8221;Book Details&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
[table]
Title, Fight Like a Pro &#8211; The Secrets of Kiai (Volume 8)<br />
Series, Mastering the Basics Series<br />
Author, Rob van Zeijst &amp; Richard Bozulich<br />
Publisher, <a href="http://www.kiseido.com/">Kiseido</a><br />
Published, &#8220;December 2012&#8243;<br />
Language, English<br />
ISBN, 978-4-906574-78-0<br />
Length, 282 Pages<br />
[/table]
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Table of Content&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ol>
<li>What is kiai?</li>
<li>Kiai and komi</li>
<li>Fear and kiai</li>
<li>Psychological warfare</li>
<li>Players featured in these games</li>
<li>Tournaments in which the games were played</li>
<li>Game One: Wang Yuhui vs. Kim Seong-ryong</li>
<li>Game Two: Yuki Satoshi vs. Takao Shinji</li>
<li>Game Three: Kobayashi Satoru vs. O Meien</li>
<li>Game Four: Yuki Satoshi vs. Hane Naoki</li>
<li>Game Five: Li He vs. Fan Yunruo</li>
<li>Game Six: Takao Shiji vs. Cho U</li>
<li>Game Seven: Iyama Yuta vs. Yoda Norimoto</li>
<li>Game Eight: Chang Hao vs. Yi Se-tol</li>
<li>Game Nine: Gu Li vs. Weon Seong-chin</li>
<li>Game Ten: Gu Li vs. Weon Seong-chin</li>
<li>Game Eleven: Pak Cheong-sang vs. Hane Naoki</li>
<li>Game Twelve: Gu Li vs. Chang Hao</li>
<li>Game Thirteen: Liu Xing vs. Chang Hao</li>
<li>Game Fourteen: Yi Ch&#8217;ang-ho vs. Qiu Jun</li>
<li>Game Fifteen: Pak Yeong-hun vs. Kong Jie</li>
<li>Game Sixteen: O Meien vs. Miyazawa Goro</li>
<li>Mastering the Basics</li>
</ol>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Before I Read This Book&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<strong>My Abilities</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Of the various styles that exists in go, I&#8217;m pretty sure most people would agree that mine leans towards fighting. However, my attacks and fighting abilities are still rather wild, ineffective and often misdirected.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>My Perspective</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>As my style naturally leans towards fighting, I was sold the moment I saw &#8220;fight like a pro.&#8221; Based on the trends of the series, I was hoping to see the principles behind fighting and then a bunch of practice problems to hone my fighting skills.</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Synopsis&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<strong>What did I enjoy about the book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>There are problems that allows players to guess what the kiai move was.</li>
<li>There is a short section at the beginning explaining some of the philosophy and background behind what kiai really is.</li>
<li>Whenever an idea like &#8220;Black cutting there would be disastrous, so he avoided it,&#8221; you can be sure that there will be a diagram to illustrate and prove it to the reader.</li>
<li>I really enjoyed getting to see analysis on professional games by some of the most well known players (i.e., Gu Li, Lee Changho, Lee Sedol, etc.) in today&#8217;s go scene.</li>
<li>They had a blitz game!!! It was epic!!!</li>
<li>Though difficult to understand at times, Zeijst and Bozulich do an incredible job breaking down professional games to an understandable level.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What did I gain from reading this book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>A better understanding of what kiai is and how to use kiai in my own games.</li>
<li>Realization that kiai is not equivalent to starting random fights, trying desperately to kill something, or starting a fight that endangers the life of one of your groups. Instead, they are very calculated moves that are meant to open up opportunities to make a comeback or disrupt the opponent&#8217;s plans.</li>
<li>Insight into what goes into a professional&#8217;s decision and what I can do myself to try and apply it to my own games.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What is the format of this book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>After a short introduction on what kiai is and its significance in go, the book is universally structured as a game review. Each chapter will start with what colors each respective player had (for the featured game) followed by how much komi was played, the amount of time each player had, and where and when it was played. Then, as one might expect with any game review, there are the accompanying diagrams of the actual kifu (broken out in chunks at a time) along with variations along the way. The one refreshing aspect that gives the reader a break from simply reading are the questions that Zeijst and Bozulich pose along the way (e.g., &#8220;Where do you think Black played in response to 34?&#8221;).</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What aspect can be improved on?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>This is extremely nit-picky, but what would have made each game kifu complete is if the ruleset that was used in each game was included. Again, super super minor; but something that would have been nice to have.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Is this book easy to read?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>For the most part, the book is very easy to follow and understand. The diagrams are never too long. In addition, Zeijst and Bozulich take each game at a pretty steady pace so that weaker players like myself have an opportunity to think through certain important moves instead of just rushing through the kifu. A word of caution though, the explanations can be a little advanced at times; but this is also what is part of its charm since I can look forward to learning more when I read it again in the future.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Bottom Line</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>A very comprehensive application of all the fundamentals you learn from the rest of the series along with other books as well.</li>
<li>Contains a great collection of games from current professionals (e.g., Gu Li, Lee Sedol, etc.), which is always a treat!</li>
<li>The focus of the book is more on kiai and not fighting techniques.</li>
<li>A pioneer in go literature on the topic of kiai that amateur players will definitely come to appreciate in the years to come.</li>
</ol>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;My Review&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221; expanded=&#8221;true&#8221;]
One of the things I really enjoyed about this book is the fact though the explanations can be difficult to comprehend at times, the diagrams are usually only a few moves long and really allows the reader to take the game in bite sizes.<br />
In addition, I really like how Zeijst and Bozulich takes great care in ensuring that their statements are backed up by a variations. An example of this would be like, &#8220;The commonsense move of Black A would be disastrous.&#8221; Once they make a statement like this, there is almost always a diagram to show why. Whether you can fully grasp it is a whole different matter, but the proof is there.<br />
Finally, though there were a number of times where I felt lost and unable to quite comprehend the severity of what was going on, I definitely felt something awaken inside of me after playing through all the kifus in this book. And even though I didn&#8217;t end up learning &#8220;fighting principles,&#8221; the lesson and multiple demonstrations of true kiai through the games of many strong professionals I have come to respect has truly been an eye opening experience.<br />
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Recommended For&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Players who have a thorough understanding of the fundamentals introduced in the previous Mastering the Basics series.</li>
<li>Players who enjoy reviewing professional games and having the games broken down to them while learning about kiai.</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Where Can I Buy It?&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Kiseido &#8211; <a title="Kiseido Purchase Link" href="http://kiseido.com/go_books.htm">$25.00</a> USD (shipping and handling not included)</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Other Books in This Series&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;lastExpandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li><a title="Book Review: 501 Opening Problems" href="//book-review-501-opening-problems/">Mastering the Basics, Volume 1 &#8211; 501 Opening Problems</a></li>
<li><a title="Book Review: 1001 Life and Death Problems" href="//book-review-1001-life-and-death-problems/">Mastering the Basics, Volume 2 &#8211; 1001 Life and Death Problems</a></li>
<li><a title="Book Review: Making Good†Shape" href="//book-review-making-good-shape/">Mastering the Basics, Volume 3 &#8211; Making Good Shape</a></li>
<li><a title="Book Review: 501 Tesuji Problems" href="//book-review-501-tesuji-problems/">Mastering the Basics, Volume 4 &#8211; 501 Tesuji Problems</a></li>
<li><a title="Book Review: The Basics of Go Strategy" href="//book-review-the-basics-of-go-strategy/">Mastering the Basics, Volume 5 &#8211; The Basics of Go Strategy</a></li>
<li><a title="Book Review: All About†Ko" href="//book-review-all-about-ko/">Mastering the Basics, Volume 6 &#8211; All About Ko</a></li>
<li><a title="Book Review: Attacking and Defending Moyos" href="//book-review-attacking-and-defending-moyos/">Mastering the Basics, Volume 7 &#8211; Attacking and Defending Moyos</a></li>
<li>Mastering the Basics, Volume 8 &#8211; Fight Like a Pro &#8211; The Secrets of Kiai</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
<p style="text-align: center;"><em><strong>Last Updated on September 4th, 2013</strong></em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/book-review-fight-like-a-pro-the-secrets-of-kiai/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3586</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Book Review: The ABC&#039;s of Attack and Defense</title>
		<link>/book-review-abcs-attack-defense/</link>
		<comments>/book-review-abcs-attack-defense/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2013 12:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[attack and defense]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fighting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[redmond]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=3868</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The ABC&#8217;s of Attack and Defense Description: In this book, Redmond takes a different approach to teach attack and defense through handicap positions. And though the title of the book seems rather docile and cuddly, I can say for certain that this book is more advanced than the title suggests. There is quite a bit [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/08/abcattackanddefensecover.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3869" alt="The ABC's of Attack and Defense Cover" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/08/abcattackanddefensecover.jpg?resize=191%2C298" width="191" height="298" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">The ABC&#8217;s of Attack and Defense</h2>
<p><strong>Description:</strong> In this book, Redmond takes a different approach to teach attack and defense through handicap positions. And though the title of the book seems rather docile and cuddly, I can say for certain that this book is more advanced than the title suggests. There is quite a bit the book has to offer, but it is not for the faint of heart and is not a book I would recommend as your first exposure to attack and defense.<br />
<span id="more-3868"></span><br />
[expand title=&#8221;Book Details&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
[table]
Title, The ABC&#8217;s of Attack and Defense<br />
Author, Michael Redmond (9P)<br />
Publisher, Slate and Shell<br />
Published, &#8220;Second Printing 2005&#8243;<br />
Language, English<br />
ISBN, 1-932001-00-X<br />
Length, 218 Pages<br />
[/table]
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Table of Content&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Glossary of Japanese Go Terms</li>
<li>Introduction</li>
<li>Chapter 1: To start an attack, first separate
<ul>
<li>How to think about attacking &#8211; 1</li>
<li>How to think about attacking &#8211; 2</li>
<li>Fighting in the Center</li>
<li>Sealing the opponent in</li>
<li>Avoid being sealed in</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Chapter 2: Handling the double approach
<ul>
<li>Handling the double approach</li>
<li>First poke your head out</li>
<li>Sealing in and taking the initiative</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Chapter 3: Using pincers to fight
<ul>
<li>An enterprising pincer</li>
<li>Aiming for the weak points</li>
<li>Speed is important</li>
<li>Looking at the whole board</li>
<li>The power of the cap</li>
<li>First, seal in</li>
<li>Seal in, then build a moyo &#8211; 1</li>
<li>Seal in, then build a moyo &#8211; 2</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Chatper 4: Miai and exchanges
<ul>
<li>The correct direction to block</li>
<li>Learning approach moves</li>
<li>Playing against a 3-4 point play</li>
<li>Let your opponent surround territory</li>
<li>Cutting and being cut</li>
<li>Finding miai</li>
<li>Responding to 4-5 and 3-5 point plays: It&#8217;s easy!</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Before I Read This Book&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<strong>My Abilities</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>I have some basic knowledge of techniques involved with attacking and defense, but am still rather poor at applying it in my own games.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>My Perspective</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>With a title like &#8220;The ABC&#8217;s of Attack and Defense,&#8221; I was really hoping for a very simplistic breakdown of attacking and defense.</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Synopsis&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<strong>What did I enjoy about the book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Though the book is about attack and defense, I appreciate how Redmond utilizes handicap positions (which most players are familiar with) to help illustrate his basic ideas.</li>
<li>His approach to attack and defense is probably the simplest one I&#8217;ve encountered thus far in terms of presentation. Being able to properly implement it is a completely separate idea though.</li>
<li>Redmond&#8217;s explanations in his examples are quite extensive and detailed.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What did I gain from reading this book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>A new approach to attack and defense.</li>
<li>A better understanding of how attacking and defense works in handicap games (as Black).</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What is the format of the book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The writing style of the book is similar to a lecture and primarily uses examples and diagrams as the teaching mechanism. Though there are some simplistic explanations here and there, the explanations can quickly become very complex and bewilder the unsuspecting reader. In other words, you can expect your standard explanations accompanied with diagrams for this book. One of the things I do appreciate about the format of the book however, is that there are occasional one liners that are italicized to catch your attention in case your eyes start to gloss over.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What aspect(s) can be improved on?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Though I am sure that this book has a lot of wisdom that players can benefit from, I would have to say that this book is still very advanced and lacks the foundation necessary for weaker players (like myself) to be able to truly grasp Redmond&#8217;s messages. One way to improve this might be practice problems.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Is this book easy to read?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The book started off easy to follow and read, but as I progressed further into the book I became more confused and found it harder to follow what Redmond was trying to say. Now granted, I am a weak player and I&#8217;m sure someone stronger would disagree with me; but as a 4 kyu, I would have to say that this book was not the easiest to read.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Bottom Line</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>Offers a new perspective on how to approach attack and defense.</li>
<li>Contains information that players new to attack and defense can appreciate, but also contains more advanced discussions regarding example scenarios that advanced players would appreciate.</li>
<li>Worth purchasing as a collector&#8217;s item or for seriously hardcore players, but I would steer clear if you are just looking to learn about attack and defense.</li>
</ol>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;My Review&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221; expanded=&#8221;true&#8221;]
Redmond&#8217;s writing style makes feel like I am having a high level conversation with a professional go player. In the midst of his explanations, you&#8217;ll find little humorous statements like, &#8220;if you have to huddle up in a corner while being sealed in, bad things happen.&#8221; With that said however, I definitely need to emphasize the fact that this book is NOT for the light-hearted. In other words, while there are golden nuggets of simple wisdom that can easily be followed by most players, the explanation very quickly dive into numerous variations that are complicated and hard to follow for amateurs.<br />
Overall though, I believe that Redmond&#8217;s book does offer a new perspective and approach on how to handle attack and defense. Though not necessary &#8220;new&#8221; material to those very strong in attack and defense, Redmond does a great job giving players, who are weak at attack and defense, simple advice that they can try to follow. Unfortunately, this advice is really just condensed down to a few pages, whereas the rest of the book can be confusing for weaker players and thus the message can be lost otherwise. So although I would love to recommend this book whole heartedly, it&#8217;s rather bitter-sweet for me at the moment. I&#8217;ll be sure to let you know if my opinion changes.<br />
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Recommended For&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Players familiar with attack and defense and are looking for another perspective.</li>
<li>Players who are 8 kyu and stronger who want to strengthen their understanding of attack and defense.</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Where Can I Buy It?&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;lastExpandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>It currently seems to be out of print. =( Let me know if it ever comes back on the presses though!</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
<p style="text-align: center;"><em><strong>Last Updated on August 31st, 2013</strong></em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/book-review-abcs-attack-defense/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>9</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3868</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Book Review: Attack and Defense</title>
		<link>/book-review-attack-and-defense/</link>
		<comments>/book-review-attack-and-defense/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2013 02:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[attack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[defense]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fighting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kiseido]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[offense]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=3104</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Description: Ishida and Davies lay down some basic principles, ideas, and tactics for attack and defense. There are a lot of examples from professional play, along with opportunities for you to practice what you learn. [expand title=&#8221;Book Details&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;] [table] Title, Attack and Defense (Volume 5) Series, Elementary Go Series Authors, Akira Ishida and James [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/06/egsattackanddefensecover.jpg"><img class="aligncenter" alt="egsattackanddefensecover" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/06/egsattackanddefensecover.jpg?resize=300%2C432" width="300" height="432" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><br />
<strong>Description: </strong>Ishida and Davies lay down some basic principles, ideas, and tactics for attack and defense. There are a lot of examples from professional play, along with opportunities for you to practice what you learn.<br />
<span id="more-3104"></span><br />
[expand title=&#8221;Book Details&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
[table]
Title, Attack and Defense (Volume 5)<br />
Series, Elementary Go Series<br />
Authors, Akira Ishida and James Davies<br />
Publisher, Kiseido<br />
Published, 1st Edition December 1973 | 8th Edition November 2009<br />
Language, English<br />
ISBN, 978-4-906574-14-8<br />
Length, 254 Pages<br />
[/table]
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Table of Content&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Chapter One &#8211; Territory and Power</li>
<li>Chapter Two &#8211; Attacking Strategy</li>
<li>Chapter Three &#8211; Attacking Moves</li>
<li>Chapter Four &#8211; Defense</li>
<li>Chapter Five &#8211; Forcing Moves</li>
<li>Chapter Six &#8211; Inducing Moves</li>
<li>Chapter Seven &#8211; Reducing and Invading Large Frameworks</li>
<li>Chapter Eight &#8211; Invasions into Three-Space Extensions</li>
<li>Chapter Nine &#8211; Ko Fights</li>
<li>Chapter Ten &#8211; Problems</li>
<li>Guide to Further Study</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Synopsis&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221; expanded=&#8221;true&#8221;]
<ol>
<li>A fantastic introductory book on attack and defense.</li>
<li>In addition to providing great exposure to attack and defense, it goes into tactics and examples that provide really thorough material for the reader.</li>
<li>Contains 20 formal problems at the end that do a great job testing the basic concepts of attack and defense that the reader just finished reading.</li>
</ol>
[/expand]
<!--more--><br />
[expand title=&#8221;Before I Read This Book&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<strong>My Abilities</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>My style of play is a fighting style. The problem that often occurs is that I often find myself overextended or playing moves that seem like they are &#8220;attacking&#8221; but put no pressure on the opponent.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>My Perspective</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>I was really hoping to get a better understanding of attack and defense so that I could really sharpen my blade and increase the potency of my attacks. In addition, I was hoping to get a better understanding of how to defend properly since I hardly hesitate to invade.</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;My Review&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221; expanded=&#8221;true&#8221;]
<strong>What did I enjoy about the book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>There is an anecdote about a player who felt that &#8220;territory meant nothing unless it contained a dead group&#8221; that was incredibly eye-opening and changed the way I saw attacking groups.</li>
<li>Does a great job explaining topics (that previously seemed hard to grasp) such as power, forcing moves, inducing moves, etc.</li>
<li>The problems at the end of the book were a great way for me to see if I understood what I had been learning.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What did I gain from reading this book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>A much better understanding of attacking, defense, and the importance and role that power plays in a game.</li>
<li>An improvement in my ability to attack groups properly.</li>
<li>A better understanding of how to find multi-purpose moves that serve both attack and defense purposes.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What style of teaching does the book use?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Lecture Approach
<ul>
<li>The writing is far more substantial in this book than what readers might have become accustomed to in Tesuji and Life and Death.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Primary Learning Mechanism:
<ul>
<li>Explanations with diagrams</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Other Learning Mechanisms:
<ul>
<li>Practice problems</li>
<li>Examples from actual games</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What aspect(s) can be improved on?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>In all honesty, I have a hard time finding anything to criticize about this book; but if I had to request one thing, it would have to be more problems at the end of the book to continue reinforcing what I learned.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Is this book easy to read?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Yes. The writing style in this book makes you feel as if you are having a conversation with Davies and Ishida, which ultimately makes for an enjoyable read.</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Recommended For&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Players looking for a reference on numerous shapes that are frequently encountered in games.</li>
<li>Players who have read other life and death books and are looking to expand their knowledge and test their skills.</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Where Can I Buy It?&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>GoGameGuru &#8211; <a title="Go Game Guru Purchase Link" href="http://shop.gogameguru.com/attack-and-defense/?acc=e4da3b7fbbce2345d7772b0674a318d5">$17.99</a> USD (shipping &amp; handling not included)</li>
<li>Kiseido &#8211; <a title="Kiseido Purchase Link" href="http://kiseido.com/go_books.htm">$18.00</a> USD (shipping &amp; handling not included)</li>
<li>SmartGo Books &#8211; <a title="SmartGo Book Link" href="http://www.smartgo.com/books.htm">$9.99</a> USD (e-Book for iPad &amp; iPhone Only)</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Other Books in This Series&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;lastExpandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li><a title="Book Review: In the Beginning" href="//book-review-in-the-beginning/">Elementary Go Series, Volume 1 &#8211; In the Beginning</a></li>
<li><a title="Book Review: 38 Basic Joseki" href="//book-review-38-basic-joseki/">Elementary Go Series, Volume 2 &#8211; 38 Basic Joseki</a></li>
<li><a title="Book Review: Tesuji" href="//book-review-tesuji/">Elementary Go Series, Volume 3 &#8211; Tesuji</a></li>
<li><a title="Book Review: Life and Death" href="//book-review-life-and-death/">Elementary Go Series, Volume 4 &#8211; Life and Death</a></li>
<li><a title="Book Review: The Endgame" href="//book-review-the-endgame/">Elementary Go Series, Volume 6 &#8211; The Endgame</a></li>
<li><a title="Book Review: Handicap Go" href="//book-review-handicap-go/">Elementary Go Series, Volume 7 &#8211; Handicap Go</a></li>
</ul>
[/expand]
<p style="text-align: center;"><em><strong>Last Updated on July 12th, 2013</strong></em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/book-review-attack-and-defense/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3104</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Officially on Tygem</title>
		<link>/officially-on-tygem/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 14:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kifu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fighting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tygem]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[white]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=1570</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Happy 2013!!!! For my first post of 2013, I&#8217;m happy to inform you all that I will now be on Tygem as well as KGS! My username is still bengozen, so be sure to request a game if you ever see me on! (If you&#8217;re wondering what my thoughts are on the server, be on [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 style="text-align: center;">Happy 2013!!!!</h2>
<p>For my first post of 2013, I&#8217;m happy to inform you all that I will now be on Tygem as well as KGS! My username is still bengozen, so be sure to request a game if you ever see me on! (If you&#8217;re wondering what my thoughts are on the server, be on the lookout for the review in the near future!)<br />
When I asked frozensoul what his thoughts were about me getting on Tygem, he told me that I should set my rank at 18k and then fight my way up. I really liked the idea, except I realized that I had already registered my account as 8-9k (a few months ago) and it seems I cannot change it anymore. So even though I am missing out on the DDK fighting, it&#8217;ll still be nice to see if I can climb up to my KGS rank this way.<br />
Thus far, the opponents I have played on have a completely different style from what I&#8217;m used to on KGS. Lots and lots of fighting&#8230;.<br />
Case and point: see my first game record for 2013 below!<br />

<div id='glift_display1' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display1","sgf":"http:\/\/bengozen.com\/\/wp-content\/uploads\/2012\/12\/2013.01.01-Starting-with-a-Bang.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='//wp-content/uploads/2012/12/2013.01.01-Starting-with-a-Bang.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">[download label=&#8221;Download Kifu&#8221;]//wp-content/uploads/2012/12/2013.01.01-Starting-with-a-Bang.sgf[/download]
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1570</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
