<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>online go school &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/online-go-school/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>Kaz&#039;s Go School is Finally Here!</title>
		<link>/kazs-go-school-finally/</link>
		<comments>/kazs-go-school-finally/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2014 16:33:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[getting stronger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kaz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lessons]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online go school]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=4513</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Kaz&#8217;s Online Go School is finally here! For those who don&#8217;t know about Kaz, I discovered him from his site (http://www.kazsensei.com)/ a couple of years ago and have been waiting for his website to become fully live and functional. The website is a bit hard to navigate, but after going through it, I thought that [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kaz&#8217;s Online Go School is finally here! For those who don&#8217;t know about Kaz, I discovered him from his site (<a href="http://www.kazsensei.com/">http://www.kazsensei.com/</a>) a couple of years ago and have been waiting for his website to become fully live and functional. The website is a bit hard to navigate, but after going through it, I thought that it would be great if I ever got a chance to learn from him. So after waiting for a couple of years, I am psyched to tell you that the opportunity is finally here!<br />
So for those curious about this online go school, let me start with this: <strong>The first session of Kaz&#8217;s Online Go School is 8 classes for only $6 USD.</strong> Now that I have your attention, here&#8217;s my elevator pitch for the school.</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>His teaching style emphasizes teaching amateur players who are adults which is quite unique!</strong> In fact, he states in his ad that the range of players he normally teaches is 30 to 70+ years old and talks about how teaching children is very different from teaching adults! So in other words, it sounds like he has a lot of experience working with amateur players (which is precisely what many of us need).</li>
<li><strong>Kaz will generate a text for student&#8217;s to study after each lesson.</strong> It&#8217;s great to get online reviews and such, but I think it&#8217;s great that Kaz will also be generating offline content for students to study as well in order to reinforce the concepts learned from the last lesson.</li>
<li><strong>You get 8 two-hour group lessons with Kaz for only $6 USD.</strong> This is such an incredible value and such a great deal if anyone has done even the slightest bit of research on the other online schools available. For those who haven&#8217;t, one of the most popular online go schools charges about $135 a month. So yeah. &#8216;Nuff said.</li>
</ol>
<p>Bottom line: I think any player who has even been remotely interested in participating in an online go school needs to do this. There is just no reason for why you shouldn&#8217;t give this a shot for $6 USD. It&#8217;s seriously an incredible deal.<a href="//wp-content/uploads/2014/01/Kaz-Go-Problem-Set.zip"><br />
</a><br />
For more details on his school, you can find it here <a href="//wp-content/uploads/2014/01/Kaz’s-Online-Go-School.pdf">Kaz’s Online Go School (PDF)</a>. I took the liberty of taking his email and updating some of the language and structure in order to make it easier to find the information you need. And for those interested in the free problems set that he attached to his email, you can download it [download label=&#8221;here&#8221;]//wp-content/uploads/2014/01/Kaz-Go-Problem-Set.zip[/download].<br />
And just in case it isn&#8217;t clear, I have already paid my $6 and will definitely be participating in this. Let me know if you guys have any other questions and I&#8217;ll do my best to answer them. Hope to see you in class!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/kazs-go-school-finally/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">4513</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
