<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>basics &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/basics/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>No More Cutting Corners</title>
		<link>/cutting-corners/</link>
		<comments>/cutting-corners/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2014 00:43:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[basics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dojang]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[level up]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[no cutting corners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[studying]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yunguseng]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5283</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Up till now, my go studies have been pretty sporadic. I may have read my fair share of books and watched my fair share of videos, but I would have to say that I really never spent the time and energy really absorbing them. Sure, I was exposed to lots of new concepts and ideas; [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Up till now, my go studies have been pretty sporadic. I may have read my fair share of books and watched my fair share of videos, but I would have to say that I really never spent the time and energy really absorbing them. Sure, I was exposed to lots of new concepts and ideas; but implementing them in my games was a whole different animal.<br />
After reading a <a title="What Was Nonsense Becomes Possible - Noseki" href="http://noseki.com/2014/05/08/what-was-nonsense-becomes-possible/">post</a> from fellow go blogger Noseki, I was inspired to take a new approach with my go studies by fully immersing myself in it. For example, in my game for <a title="Yunguseng Dojang" href="http://www.yunguseng.com/">Yunguseng Dojang</a>, I replayed every move on the real board and really took my time to absorb each and every move (which is the reason I ended up losing on time since I completely did not pay attention to my computer which was telling me I was running out of time).<br />
In addition, I&#8217;ve also revamped my primary study materials for books. I&#8217;m going back to the Level Up Series (starting with <a title="Book Review: Level Up Review 1" href="//book-review-level-up-review-1/">Level Up! Review 1</a> since I don&#8217;t have time to start all the way back at <a title="Book Review: Level Up 1" href="//book-review-level-up-1/">Level Up 1</a>) and working my way through it with extreme thoroughness. In other words, no solution whatsoever. I will work through every problem and solve it with absolute certainty before moving on.<br />
If I have any hope of becoming any stronger, I think that it&#8217;s finally time that I stopped cutting corners. The time for me to be knocking at the door of the dans is fast approaching, and I have no intention of letting myself be caught unawares when that time comes.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/cutting-corners/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">5283</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>WGW 34: The Value of Repetition</title>
		<link>/wgw-34-value-repetition/</link>
		<comments>/wgw-34-value-repetition/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2014 11:15:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Weekly Go Wednesday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[again]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[basics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fundamentals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[repeat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[repetition]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=4792</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Weekly Go Wednesday: Issue #34 As most of you know, I own a majority of the English go literature that exists out in the market. And in conjunction with that notion, I&#8217;ve also reviewed quite a few books as I&#8217;ve progressed throughout my journey. What some of you may not realize however, is that one [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 style="text-align: center;">Weekly Go Wednesday: Issue #34</h2>
<p>As most of you know, I own a majority of the English go literature that exists out in the market. And in conjunction with that notion, I&#8217;ve also reviewed quite a few books as I&#8217;ve progressed throughout my journey. What some of you may not realize however, is that one of the downsides to me trying to review books in quick succession means that I am unable to spend a lot of time absorbing the material. As a result, my growth as a player is not necessarily correlated with the number of books I&#8217;ve read.<br />
Lately I&#8217;ve been really starting to see the detrimental effect of my poor reading abilities. I have found myself in numerous positions where I may have made strategically sound decisions and had aims that should have worked in actuality, but due to my weak reading skills I was unable to follow through or execute my plan properly. So after numerous frustrating games and irritation with my own growth, I&#8217;ve decided to take a step back in my studies.<br />
<span id="more-4792"></span><br />
Instead of moving onto new books that I&#8217;ve yet to read or try to solve problems much higher than my reading ability, I am going back to ground zero. In other words, I&#8217;m going back to the basics of basics. For example, I have decided to start the Level Up series over again and start at <a title="Book Review: Level Up 1" href="//book-review-level-up-1/">Level Up 1</a>. And in the case of the go problems I&#8217;m solving, I&#8217;m spending my time cycling through the same 600 problems (not all at once though) over and over again.<br />
Now you might wonder, where is the value in that?<br />
Well the thing about a game as complex as go is that there are often so many variables going on at any point in the game. Are you checking the life and death of a group? Perhaps you are estimating the board territory to see what to do next. Or what about those two groups over there, is there a way to cut them off? Can you ignore your opponent&#8217;s threat?<br />
The fact is that the more efficient you are at making decisions about things associated with reading, the more time you will have to spend on things like your strategy and which direction of play is better. And as most of you probably know from your own research, the kinds of problems that amateur players constantly mess up in games are actually quite simple ones.<br />
In order to speed up your reading ability, I believe that the key is honing in on your instinctual abilities. For example, if I were to give most of you a position where your opponent had a bent in three shape, you probably wouldn&#8217;t have to spend any time trying to read it out. BAM. Right on the vital point. Dead. No questions about it. Imagine the kinds of things you could do if you could do that with more shapes and positions?<br />
So by going back to the basics and the &#8220;easy stuff,&#8221; I intend on improving my own instinctual reading abilities. As Kageyama emphasized again and again in his book, <a title="Book Review: Lessons in the Fundamentals of Go" href="//book-review-lessons-in-the-fundamentals-of-go/">Lessons in the Fundamentals of Go</a>, many amateur players blow off the fundamentals and then wind up wondering why they can&#8217;t get any stronger.<br />
Don&#8217;t make that same mistake. <strong>Do not underestimate the power of repetition and its abilities to improve your basics.</strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/wgw-34-value-repetition/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>9</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">4792</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Book Review: Lessons in the Fundamentals of Go</title>
		<link>/book-review-lessons-in-the-fundamentals-of-go/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2013 14:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[basics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fundamentals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[getting stronger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kageyama]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lessons]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shape]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tesuji]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=1393</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Overall Rating: 5 / 5 Ponnuki Basic Information Title: Lessons in the Fundamentals of Go Author: Toshiro Kageyama 7-dan Translator: James Davies Publisher: Kiseido Publication Date: May 1978 Page Length: 272 pages Synopsis A hybrid of theoretical/conceptual explanations along with problems to illustrate the ideas. While may seem advance, Kageyama&#8217;s personality really shines through and makes [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/03/lessonsinthefundamentalsofgocover.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2181" alt="lessonsinthefundamentalsofgocover" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/03/lessonsinthefundamentalsofgocover.jpg?resize=248%2C400" width="248" height="400" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></h2>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">Overall Rating: 5 / 5 Ponnuki</h2>
<h3>Basic Information</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Title:</strong> Lessons in the Fundamentals of Go</li>
<li><strong>Author: </strong>Toshiro Kageyama 7-dan</li>
<li><strong>Translator:</strong> James Davies</li>
<li><strong>Publisher: </strong>Kiseido</li>
<li><strong>Publication Date: </strong>May 1978</li>
<li><strong>Page Length:</strong> 272 pages</li>
</ul>
<h3>Synopsis</h3>
<ul>
<li>A hybrid of theoretical/conceptual explanations along with problems to illustrate the ideas.</li>
<li>While may seem advance, Kageyama&#8217;s personality really shines through and makes this such an interesting read (regardless of your level).</li>
<li>Appropriate for 20 kyu and stronger.</li>
<li>Recommended for all types of players.</li>
</ul>
<p><span id="more-1393"></span></p>
<h3>Detailed Review</h3>
<h4>Readability &#8211; 10 / 10</h4>
<p>When it comes to readability, I&#8217;m not sure there&#8217;s a single go book out there that can outclass Kageyama&#8217;s ability to show his humorous and delightful personality through his writing. There is almost never a dull moment in this book. Often times, he will seem to be going off on a tangent (like baseball), but he will always find a way to bring it back full circle to emphasize one of his points. His pragmatic and straight forward advice is something that every go player can make use of, regardless of how strong you desire to be. In fact, even if we set aside the actual treasure trove of go advice that is in this book, I would argue that the entertainment value of his writing makes the book worth every penny.</p>
<h4>Content Quality &#8211; 10 / 10</h4>
<p>Although this is not your classic tsumego book, it does have a similar style to the <a href="http://senseis.xmp.net/?ElementaryGoSeries">Elementary Go Series</a> where there are a few problems at the end of most chapters. In addition, I will be the first to admit that some of these problems are rather difficult and can be discouraging if you are under the impression you need to be able to solve them the first time you see them. In fact, the value of this book lies in its ability to expose you to so many different concepts and ideas. Considering the size of the book and the how short each of the chapters are, the amount of content he covers is nothing short of incredible.</p>
<h4>Final Thoughts</h4>
<p>Although this is my third time reading the book, and it still has not lost a bit of its charm. I continue to learn something new every time I read it, and never fail to crack a smile when Kageyama goes on one of his rants about how amateur players always try to find shortcuts to reading ladders. Nonetheless, this is truly a classic that I believe will never be outdated. So do yourself a favor, and if you are going to only have a small collection of go books, this is definitely one you will want to have.</p>
<h4>Table of Contents</h4>
<ol>
<li>Chapter 1: Ladders and Nets</li>
<li>Chapter 2: Cutting and Connecting</li>
<li>Chapter 3: The Stones Go Walking</li>
<li>Chapter 4: The Struggle to Get Ahead</li>
<li>Chapter 5: Territory and Spheres of Influence</li>
<li>Interlude: Lecturing on NHK-TV</li>
<li>Chapter 6: Life and Death</li>
<li>Chapter 7: How to Study Joseki</li>
<li>Chapter 8: Good Shape and Bad</li>
<li>Chapter 9: Proper and Improper Moves</li>
<li>Chapter 10: Tesuji: The Snap-Back; Shortage of Liberties; The Spiral Latter; The Placement; The Attachment; Under the Stones</li>
<li>Chapter 11: Endgame Pointers</li>
<li>Appendix: Game Commentary: Beating the Meijin</li>
</ol>
<h4>Recommended Vendors:</h4>
<ol>
<li>Amazon &#8211; <a title="Amazon Purchase Link" href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/4906574289/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=4906574289&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=be09a-20">$18.00</a> (S&amp;H not included)</li>
<li>GoGameGuru- <a title="GoGameGuru Purchase Link" href="http://shop.gogameguru.com/lessons-in-the-fundamentals-of-go/?acc=e4da3b7fbbce2345d7772b0674a318d5">$17.99</a> (S&amp;H not included)</li>
<li>Kiseido &#8211; <a title="Kiseido Order Form" href="http://www.kiseido.com/go_books.htm">$18.00</a> (S&amp;H not included)</li>
</ol>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Last updated March 8th, 2013 &#8211; 6 kyu</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1393</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Look Both Ways Before You Play</title>
		<link>/look-both-directions-before-you-play/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2013 14:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Weekly Go Wednesday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[basics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[common mistake]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[look both ways]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=1822</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Weekly Go Wednesday, Issue #16 As every player progresses, one of the skills that clearly shows signs of improvement is the ability to read ahead. Whether it is only one or twenty moves more, this gives a player a significant advantage if he/she is able to read further than his/her opponent. However, one of the [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 style="text-align: center;"><em>Weekly Go Wednesday, Issue #16</em></h2>
<figure id="attachment_1832" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/02/wgw16.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1832" alt="Crossing by Matt Eaton" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/02/wgw16.jpg?resize=300%2C202" width="300" height="202" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Crossing by Matt Eaton</figcaption></figure>
As every player progresses, one of the skills that clearly shows signs of improvement is the ability to read ahead. Whether it is only one or twenty moves more, this gives a player a significant advantage if he/she is able to read further than his/her opponent. However, one of the things I&#8217;ve noticed in my own progress is that the attempt to read out longer sequences can sometimes causes you to forget a the most important purpose of reading: <strong>analyzing multiple variations</strong>.<br />
During the opening of a game I played recently, I chose a rather complicated joseki that was dependent on having the ladder in my favor. After much thought and reading, I confidently concluded that the ladder worked in my favor. As my opponent played out the joseki, I delightfully plodded along as I thought that my opponent had not read thoroughly enough and that I would soon greatly profit from his mistake. When the time came to play out the ladder, I watched in horror as my opponent chose the opposite direction&#8230; which conveniently worked in his favor.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>*faceplant*</em></p>
<p>Whether you like it or not, being able to read 100 moves in a sequence is only good if you can do it for multiple variations quickly. We are all aware of that time is almost always a factor so we must be careful of how we manage our time. As a result, here are some tips for how you can increase the effectiveness of your reading abilities:<br />
<span id="more-1822"></span></p>
<ol>
<li><span style="line-height: 13px;"><strong>Read out fewer moves for more variations</strong>. In other words, if you can read out 10 moves easily for one sequence, read out 5 moves for different sequences to have a better understanding of what potential dangers might arise.</span></li>
<li><strong>At the bare minimum, read out the two most obvious directions. </strong>If you find that reading out multiple sequences is rather cumbersome, you can at least read out the two most obvious sequences that can arise. Two easy examples would be when you want to atari a stone or when a ladder is coming into play.</li>
</ol>
<p>If you make sure to do the two things above, you will be sure to reduce the frequency of self-induced mistakes that you end up paying for later on. After all, it is much better to have your opponent surprise you with a new tesuji or move than to cause your own impending doom.<br />
So remember, just like your parents used to tell you before crossing the street:</p>
<blockquote><p>Look both ways before playing your next move.</p></blockquote>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1822</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
