<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>yunguseng &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/yunguseng/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>Trying to Put the Pieces Back Together</title>
		<link>/trying-put-pieces-back-together/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2014 15:55:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kifu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dojang]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[journey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[one step at a time]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[progress]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yunguseng]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5545</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I played the second round of my Yunguseng match tonight. To be honest, it was a game of mixed feelings. Though I hate to admit it, I&#8217;m not quite out of my slump yet. I could definitely feel it as I started getting antsy when the game began. I started being negative and worried that [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I played the second round of my Yunguseng match tonight. To be honest, it was a game of mixed feelings. Though I hate to admit it, I&#8217;m not quite out of my slump yet. I could definitely feel it as I started getting antsy when the game began. I started being negative and worried that I would lose again. Yet on the other hand, there were moments where I managed to give my game some life as I surged forth with a desire to attack and try to harass my opponent&#8217;s group with as much vigor as I could muster up.<br />

<div id='glift_display1' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display1","sgf":"http:\/\/bengozen.com\/\/wp-content\/uploads\/2014\/07\/YSD-S9-Round12.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='//wp-content/uploads/2014/07/YSD-S9-Round12.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">[download label=&#8221;Download Kifu&#8221;]//wp-content/uploads/2014/07/YSD-S9-Round12.sgf[/download]
<p>It was a bit weird being in this bi-polar/gray area of feeling like my go was rather aimless, having it spring back to life, making bad moves where I was completely off with my reading, and then having lively energy again. Then again I guess this is all part of trying to put the pieces together again. They don&#8217;t quite fit together at the moment, but I&#8217;m optimistic that they will become whole once again.<br />
And though I would normally be concerned with how fast it would take or when it would happen, I’ve realized that doing so will not do me any good. I’ll just keep working on my weaknesses and play to the best of my ability. Everything will fall into place in due time.<br />
PS. There won&#8217;t be any detailed commentary for this game, but I just wanted to mention that there are quite a number of mistakes and overplays in this game. So in case anyone wants to point out things like my lower left corner was supposed to die and so forth, no worries, got it all in the review.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">5545</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>My Experience with YSD &#8211; S9 &#8211; Part 1</title>
		<link>/experience-ysd-s9-part-1/</link>
		<comments>/experience-ysd-s9-part-1/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2014 11:15:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kifu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Websites]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[anatoly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brian]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[commentary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dojang]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kifu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[league]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oren]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sauk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[season 9]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yunguseng]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5395</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Part I &#8211; Part II &#8211; Part III Overview Prelude: Out of respect to Sabum-nim (i.e., In-seong), the lessons learned are kept to a minimum since it is paid content and I do not want to infringe on that in any way, shape, or form. The game reviews also only contain highlights of concise highlights instead of my normal detailed [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>Part I</strong> &#8211; <a title="My Experience with YSD — S9 — Part 2" href="//experience-ysd-s9-part-2/">Part II</a> &#8211; Part III</p>
<h2>Overview</h2>
<p><em>Prelude: Out of respect to Sabum-nim (i.e., In-seong), the lessons learned are kept to a minimum since it is paid content and I do not want to infringe on that in any way, shape, or form. The game reviews also only contain highlights of concise highlights instead of my normal detailed reviews since I would inadvertently write about what Sabum-nim taught in the review (which would essentially replicate his lecture). </em><br />
As a new member to the <a title="Yunguseng Dojang Official Site" href="http://www.yunguseng.com/">Yunguseng Dojang</a> (YSD) during Season 9 of 2014, I was assigned to League A as my starting league (this is the highest league possible in the American division). I wasn&#8217;t sure what I was to expect, but I was excited at the prospect at being part of a formal training program.<br />
<span id="more-5395"></span></p>
<h2>Lectures &amp; Homework</h2>
<p>For this month, the three lecture topics were:</p>
<ol>
<li><a href="http://ayd.yunguseng.com/videos/index.php?id=1138">Knight move across attachment / Break the dog&#8217;s face / Indirect defense</a></li>
<li><a title="1-3-5 Opening Link" href="http://ayd.yunguseng.com/videos/index.php?id=1156">1-3-5 opening</a></li>
<li><a title="All About 3-3 Invasion Link" href="http://ayd.yunguseng.com/videos/index.php?id=1174">All about 3-3 invasion</a></li>
</ol>
<p>Overall, I felt that Sabum-nim was very good at selecting topics that were relevant to his students. After watching his student&#8217;s play their games, he would often notice trends that were occurring and would then select lecture topics to address them.<br />
In addition, the lectures were much more valuable if you could attend them in person because he made them interactive. There were usually numerous examples to show what he was trying to illustrate and to give the students a chance to show whether or not they understood what was being taught.<br />
Unfortunately, I was didn&#8217;t end up participating in the second aspect of lectures which were the homework (which consists of taking what you learned in the lecture and applying it to your own games). I&#8217;m sure I could come up with some bogus excuse for why I couldn&#8217;t do it, but it was my own fault and I plan to do every homework next month.<br />
Finally, another thing cool thing that Sabum-nim does is a lecture series that highlights the most important points from the games played that week (from both Europe and America division). It&#8217;s a cool series that has a lot of concise highlights and cool techniques that came up in actual games.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: left;">My Games</h2>
<h3 style="text-align: center;">Round 1</h3>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>Preliminary Thoughts</strong> &#8211; As this was the first game I would play in YSD, I felt a lot of pressure to try and play the best go I possibly could. To top it off, my opponent was known as one of the strongest players in the league, so I was more anxious than I would&#8217;ve liked. And so one of the things I did was to play out the game on a real board simultaneously. By doing so, I was hoping it would calm me down.</p>

<div id='glift_display2' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display2","sgf":"http:\/\/bengozen.com\/\/wp-content\/uploads\/2014\/06\/YSD-S9-Round1.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='//wp-content/uploads/2014/06/YSD-S9-Round1.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">[download label=&#8221;Download Kifu&#8221;]//wp-content/uploads/2014/06/YSD-S9-Round1.sgf[/download]
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>After the Game</strong> &#8211; Playing the game out on a real board ended up helping me calm down, but it also led to me being more adventurous/experimental and to also lose on time. When the pop-up flashed, &#8220;bengozen loses on time,&#8221; I sat there flustered as I tried to collect myself in thinking that at least I played a good game.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>After the Review</strong> &#8211; Turns out I was wrong on all counts. Not only was I not complimented on my play, but I was shown how badly I should have lost. I made numerous mistakes and deserved to lose (even regardless of time). Sigh. Definitely did not make the good impression I wanted to make on Sabum-nim.</p>
<h3 style="text-align: center;">Round 2</h3>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>Preliminary Thoughts</strong> &#8211; Since my last game was so disastrous, I was eager to yet again prove myself. Similar to the first match however, my opponent was considered one of the strongest players in the league as well, so there was a bit of pressure to try and do well against the veteran.</p>

<div id='glift_display3' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display3","sgf":"http:\/\/bengozen.com\/\/wp-content\/uploads\/2014\/06\/YSD-S9-Round2.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='//wp-content/uploads/2014/06/YSD-S9-Round2.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">[download label=&#8221;Download Kifu&#8221;]//wp-content/uploads/2014/06/YSD-S9-Round2.sgf[/download]
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>After the Game</strong> &#8211; Though I lost my Round 1 game in part due to experimenting, I still ended up doing it again this round. And just like before, I lost again. I was really starting to doubt my abilities as a player and whether I even belonged in League A.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>After the Review</strong> &#8211; Similar to the Round 1, I didn&#8217;t play particularly well this game either. The only reprieve that I got was that the game resulted in a fun reading problem on the bottom that Sabum-nim liked. Otherwise than that though, I was still feeling pretty crappy about my performance so far.</p>
<h3 style="text-align: center;">Round 3</h3>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>Preliminary Thoughts</strong> &#8211; Seeing as how I had lost my last two games, I had much lower expectations of myself this time around. I really had no idea if I was going to win. If anything, I was simply hoping I wouldn&#8217;t play another game that would add another mark of disappointment to Sabum-nim&#8217;s impression of me.</p>

<div id='glift_display4' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display4","sgf":"http:\/\/bengozen.com\/\/wp-content\/uploads\/2014\/06\/YSD-S9-Round3.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='//wp-content/uploads/2014/06/YSD-S9-Round3.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">[download label=&#8221;Download Kifu&#8221;]//wp-content/uploads/2014/06/YSD-S9-Round3.sgf[/download]
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>After the Game</strong> &#8211; The game was still a rather weird one for me. Still a lot more experimenting than I necessarily would have wanted, but it seemed I was not destined to play games that were in my comfort range. Luckily for me though, I was able to secure an advantage early on that allowed me to win the game.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>After the Review</strong> &#8211; Though this was my first win for YSD, the review still felt a bit mediocre for me overall. What I remember feeling like is that I was really only able to win because of my opponent&#8217;s overplay early on. Otherwise however, it wasn&#8217;t a particularly good game for me either.</p>
<h3 style="text-align: center;">Round 4</h3>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>Preliminary Thoughts</strong> &#8211; I was unable to make the original time scheduled for Round 4, but I was lucky that my opponent could reschedule to the prior Sunday. Unfortunately, unlike my previous games, I was unable to play in a focused state of mind because I was at a local Starbucks and had a lot of other work needed to be done. So I was unable to give this game my all like I normally would.</p>

<div id='glift_display5' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display5","sgf":"http:\/\/bengozen.com\/\/wp-content\/uploads\/2014\/06\/YSD-S9-Round4.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='//wp-content/uploads/2014/06/YSD-S9-Round4.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">[download label=&#8221;Download Kifu&#8221;]//wp-content/uploads/2014/06/YSD-S9-Round4.sgf[/download]
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>After the Game</strong> &#8211; After my opponent resigned, I breathed a sigh of relief; but I was not terribly proud of the game that I had just played. After looking back over it, it was a haphazard game that I was lucky to win only because my opponent made a mistake and I got away with a few overplays that allowed me to reverse the game in my favor. So even though I won, it felt more like I had loss since my play was rather disappointing.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>After the Review</strong> &#8211; Continuing the trend of being a disappointment, Sabum-nim was quick to show how I was able to get away with numerous overplays in order to win the game. &#8220;This wasn&#8217;t supposed to work. And then that wasn&#8217;t supposed to work.&#8221; Although this time around, I knew that my play was rather abysmal since I was unable to give it my all at the time; so I was accepting of his criticism.</p>
<h3 style="text-align: center;">Round 5</h3>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>Preliminary Thoughts</strong> &#8211; With my record at 2-2, my ability to stay in League A rested on this final match. And so the pressure was particularly high for this game since I was unsure if I would be able to pull it off and the idea of being demoted terrified me. On top of all of that, it was against a friend who I&#8217;ve gotten to know quite well over the last few weeks, so it was a mixed bag of emotions as we dove into the epic clash that would determine my fate.</p>

<div id='glift_display6' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display6","sgf":"http:\/\/bengozen.com\/\/wp-content\/uploads\/2014\/06\/YSD-S9-Round5.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='//wp-content/uploads/2014/06/YSD-S9-Round5.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">[download label=&#8221;Download Kifu&#8221;]//wp-content/uploads/2014/06/YSD-S9-Round5.sgf[/download]
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>After the Game</strong> &#8211; After clicking the resign button, I knew my fate was sealed. I was rather downtrodden, but there was a part of me that actually felt really good about the game. Unlike the other games, though I was <a title="My First Demotion" href="//first-demotion/">wrestling with disappointment of demotion at the time</a>, I actually felt like this game was something I could actually be proud of.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>After the Review </strong>&#8211; Finally, after four weeks of being a disappointment, I felt like I was finally able to play a game that Sabum-nim actually approved of. Of course as expected, I made a number of mistakes, but it felt like maybe I had finally played a game worthy of Sabum-nim&#8217;s time and energy. And on top of that, I felt start to awaken inside of me as a result of that game; but more on that later.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: left;">Final Thoughts</h2>
<p style="text-align: left;">When I first learned about how YSD worked, I have to admit that I thought 5 games a month would be a piece of cake. In reality, it is actually more difficult than it sounds since the games often take more than 90 minutes to complete and are scheduled. And well, you all know how life likes to get in the way of things. Nonetheless, I was really grateful that the program spurred us on to play more since that was one of my weaker areas at the time.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">As I look back at my thoughts after the reviews, I just wanted to clarify that Sabum-nim is really not an overly harsh or mean teacher. He simply tells it as it is without sugar-coating things since his goal is to teach you where your mistakes are and not to coddle you. In addition, it&#8217;s important to keep in mind that a major component to how I felt after each review derives from the fact that I am extremely self-critical of myself. So what else could you expect from someone rubbing salt into their own wounds? Haha.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">And though I was more disappointed and frustrated about being demoted to League B than I probably should have been, my exposure to League A was a great experience to show the gaps in my skills as a go player. I don&#8217;t know what is in store for me in League B, but I look forward to the challenge of climbing back up to League A. Until next month!</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>Part I</strong> &#8211; <a title="My Experience with YSD — S9 — Part 2" href="//experience-ysd-s9-part-2/">Part II</a> &#8211; Part III</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/experience-ysd-s9-part-1/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>17</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">5395</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>My First Demotion</title>
		<link>/first-demotion/</link>
		<comments>/first-demotion/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2014 04:22:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[creative]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[doubt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[frustration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inspired]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yunguseng]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5378</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Though there was a small chance that I would be able to stay in League A for Yunguseng Dojang, unfortunately I was unable to rise to the occasion and will receive my first demotion to League B. Before Sabumnim&#8217;s* Review** I always thought that getting demoted would feel similar to seeing my rank drop, but I [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Though there was a small chance that I would be able to stay in League A for <a title="Yunguseng Dojang Official Page" href="http://www.yunguseng.com/">Yunguseng Dojang</a>, unfortunately I was unable to rise to the occasion and will receive my first demotion to League B.<br />
<strong>Before Sabumnim&#8217;s* Review**</strong><br />
I always thought that getting demoted would feel similar to seeing my rank drop, but I have to say that this feels worse. Maybe I&#8217;ll change my mind after the fact, but this feels worse. And if I were to give a reason why, it&#8217;s probably because I spent time and effort over an entire month only to be shown my inadequacy.<br />
I would be lying if I said that I&#8217;m cool with it and feeling whatever about it. A large part of me is frustrated and disappointed with myself.<br />
As I sulk in this aura of frustration and angst, it is causing a lot of doubt to spread. Doubt as to whether or not I actually got any stronger over this last month. Doubt as to whether I have any talent at all since my games were nothing to be proud of (as evident in the past reviews). Doubt as to what the hell I&#8217;ve been doing this entire month since I&#8217;ve been so unstable (especially towards the end of the month).<br />
It&#8217;s stupid and childish to think such thoughts. I know. I guess I&#8217;m just really feeling at a loss for what is going on with me. While part of it might be mental, another part of me feel like there is something wrong with my go. I just feel like I can&#8217;t make sense of what I&#8217;m doing anymore.<br />
<strong>After Sabumim&#8217;s Review</strong><br />
When I started writing this post, my self-pity almost caused me to skip the review since I wasn&#8217;t sure if I could handle hearing that my game was awful or anything that could further my self-doubt. So as I wrote the first section of this post, I thought that I was doomed to feeling awful for the rest of the night. Thankfully though, against my feelings of self-doubt, I decided to go ahead and stay for the review.<br />
To my surprise, I was happy to find out that my game was actually not a bad game at all. In fact, though I have been in a weird funk lately (in regards to the games I&#8217;ve been playing), this final game was probably one of most inspired ones so far. It&#8217;s kind of odd writing that because I ended up losing a rather important match, but I really feel that it was one of my most creative games I&#8217;ve played to date.***<br />
Part of me still carries some of the frustration from earlier, but I&#8217;m in a better place now. Though getting demoted to League B is a bit disappointing, it simply means that I&#8217;ll need to work hard next month to get back to League A. Challenge accepted.<br />
<em>*Note: Sabumnim is the Korean equivalent of sensei when it comes to how to address your teacher. And in case it wasn&#8217;t obvious, sabumnim refers to Inseong.</em><br />
<em>**Part of me debated deleting this section to shelter you from my whining and self-pity, but I felt it would be wrong to try and hide it. As much as it might be pathetic and childish, this is part of my journey to gaining that next stone. The frustration, the self-doubt, and the feeling of wanting to just throw in the towel are all obstacles that I deal with and I don&#8217;t want to sugarcoat it at all. So for that reason, I hope you&#8217;ll understand why I left it in.</em><br />
<em>***I&#8217;m sure many of you will want to see the game, but I promise I&#8217;ll be releasing a full post on my first month in Yunguseng Dojang next week so you can see all of my games along with my thoughts on each of them as well. </em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/first-demotion/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>10</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">5378</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Friday Go Forward: Week 62</title>
		<link>/friday-go-forward-week-62/</link>
		<comments>/friday-go-forward-week-62/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2014 11:15:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Progress Reports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dojang]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[experimenting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[level up]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[losing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[territorial style]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yunguseng]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5250</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Overview This week has been a continuation of trying to get used to the new training regimen that I started last week. Believe it or not, I have been rather successful at playing more instead of solely focusing on studying. So in that regard, things are a success. On the other hand, I lost again [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 style="text-align: left;">Overview</h2>
<p>This week has been a continuation of trying to get used to the new training regimen that I started last week. Believe it or not, I have been rather successful at playing more instead of solely focusing on studying. So in that regard, things are a success.<br />
On the other hand, I lost again in my match this week for <a title="Yunguseng Dojang Official Website" href="http://www.yunguseng.com/">Yunguseng Dojang</a>. After some thought and introspection, I have come to the conclusion that my go has become very impatient lately. I try to complicate the game with every move while also experimenting with a territorial style that just ends up not working out for me. Sigh.<br />
Ah well. It has been fun experimenting with the territorial style. And who knows? Maybe this little detour of mine will help to patch up some of my weaknesses from my normal style. Guess we&#8217;ll have to see!</p>
<h2>Training Regimen</h2>
<ul>
<li>Spend about 50% of your time playing games.</li>
<li>Spend 10 minutes/day perusing a new book of go.</li>
<li>Spend 20 minutes/day diligently working on the Level Up series.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Games</h2>
<ul>
<li><a title="TygemGo Official Site" href="http://www.tygemgo.com/">Tygem</a> &#8211; 6 games</li>
<li><a title="IGS PandaNet Official Site" href="http://www.pandanet-igs.com/">IGS</a> &#8211; 2 games</li>
<li><a title="KGS Website" href="http://www.gokgs.com/">KGS</a> &#8211;  3 games</li>
<li><a title="Dragon Go Server - BenGoZen's Profile" href="http://www.dragongoserver.net/userinfo.php?uid=60385">DGS</a> &#8211; 5 ongoing games</li>
<li><a title="Online Go Server - BenGoZen's Profile" href="http://online-go.com/user/view/549/BenGoZen">OGS</a> &#8211; 3 ongoing games</li>
</ul>
<h2>Books</h2>
<ul>
<li><a title="Book Review: Level Up Review 1" href="//book-review-level-up-review-1/">Level Up Review 1</a></li>
<li><a title="Book Review: Level Up Review 2" href="//book-review-level-up-review-2/">Level Up Review 2</a></li>
<li>The Theory and Practice of Semeai</li>
</ul>
<h2>Lessons Learned</h2>
<ul>
<li>Patience is an important value when playing go.</li>
<li>When you have an overwhelming advantage, (1) don&#8217;t become overconfident and (2) don&#8217;t give your opponent a chance to turn it around.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/friday-go-forward-week-62/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">5250</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Another Notch of Defeat</title>
		<link>/another-notch-defeat/</link>
		<comments>/another-notch-defeat/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2014 15:50:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crummy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dojang]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yunguseng]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5309</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I just finished my second round of Yunguseng Dojang. As the title of the post states explicitly, it was another sound defeat to be added to my battle staff of go. On one hand, I want to make myself feel better by telling myself that I played well. On the other hand though, I also was [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I just finished my second round of Yunguseng Dojang. As the title of the post states explicitly, it was another sound defeat to be added to my battle staff of go.<br />
On one hand, I want to make myself feel better by telling myself that I played well. On the other hand though, I also was playing completely out of my style this game as well.<br />
I don&#8217;t know why it is, but lately I&#8217;ve been trying really hard to use the territorial style as White. And then on top of that, I&#8217;ve been hell bent on making the game as complicated as possible from the start. So that ends up putting me in experimental territory that I&#8217;m completely unfamiliar with.<br />
Do I wish I would have managed to win my second round? Yeah. Feeling a bit crummy at the moment. Hopefully the review will shed some light on my mistakes. Ah well. Off to bed I go.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/another-notch-defeat/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">5309</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>No More Cutting Corners</title>
		<link>/cutting-corners/</link>
		<comments>/cutting-corners/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2014 00:43:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[basics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dojang]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[level up]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[no cutting corners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[studying]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yunguseng]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5283</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Up till now, my go studies have been pretty sporadic. I may have read my fair share of books and watched my fair share of videos, but I would have to say that I really never spent the time and energy really absorbing them. Sure, I was exposed to lots of new concepts and ideas; [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Up till now, my go studies have been pretty sporadic. I may have read my fair share of books and watched my fair share of videos, but I would have to say that I really never spent the time and energy really absorbing them. Sure, I was exposed to lots of new concepts and ideas; but implementing them in my games was a whole different animal.<br />
After reading a <a title="What Was Nonsense Becomes Possible - Noseki" href="http://noseki.com/2014/05/08/what-was-nonsense-becomes-possible/">post</a> from fellow go blogger Noseki, I was inspired to take a new approach with my go studies by fully immersing myself in it. For example, in my game for <a title="Yunguseng Dojang" href="http://www.yunguseng.com/">Yunguseng Dojang</a>, I replayed every move on the real board and really took my time to absorb each and every move (which is the reason I ended up losing on time since I completely did not pay attention to my computer which was telling me I was running out of time).<br />
In addition, I&#8217;ve also revamped my primary study materials for books. I&#8217;m going back to the Level Up Series (starting with <a title="Book Review: Level Up Review 1" href="//book-review-level-up-review-1/">Level Up! Review 1</a> since I don&#8217;t have time to start all the way back at <a title="Book Review: Level Up 1" href="//book-review-level-up-1/">Level Up 1</a>) and working my way through it with extreme thoroughness. In other words, no solution whatsoever. I will work through every problem and solve it with absolute certainty before moving on.<br />
If I have any hope of becoming any stronger, I think that it&#8217;s finally time that I stopped cutting corners. The time for me to be knocking at the door of the dans is fast approaching, and I have no intention of letting myself be caught unawares when that time comes.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/cutting-corners/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">5283</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Friday Go Forward: Week 61</title>
		<link>/friday-go-forward-week-61/</link>
		<comments>/friday-go-forward-week-61/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2014 11:15:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Progress Reports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dojang]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[myung]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[playing more]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yunguseng]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5202</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Overview This week has been focused on one thing: playing more games. As you&#8217;ll notice in my games section, I played a whopping 18 live games this week! And though I have been on an epic losing streak (with an occasional win to here and there), I can definitely feel the inexperience of being on the [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 style="text-align: left;">Overview</h2>
<p>This week has been focused on one thing: <strong>playing more games</strong>. As you&#8217;ll notice in my games section, I played a whopping 18 live games this week! And though I have been on an epic losing streak (with an occasional win to here and there), I can definitely feel the inexperience of being on the battlefield affect my play. Hopefully in time I will be losing due to actual mistakes instead of just playing moves on the board &#8220;just because.&#8221;<br />
Another milestone for this week is the official start of the <a title="Yunguseng Dojang Official Site" href="http://www.yunguseng.com/">Yunguseng Dojang</a>! The first official lecture was on Monday (May 5th) and it was on local techniques. Though I had heard of the techniques before (i.e., across attachment, break the dog&#8217;s face, and indirect defense), it was really great to have Inseong break down the different techniques while also showing where they appear within real games.<br />
I also played my first round as well last night. I ended up losing by time (because I was playing the game on a real board and lost track of time), but I felt that it was a game I wasn&#8217;t ashamed of. I tried a number of new things and tried to avoid any egregious errors. Of course, in the review, I got torn apart so it didn&#8217;t feel so great; but I think those are the kinds of lessons that tend to burn in your memory. Ah well. Next game I&#8217;ll do better!</p>
<h2>Training Regimen</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Spend about 50% of your time playing games</strong> &#8211; Though I haven&#8217;t measured this out with accuracy, I am simply trying to make sure that I play as much as I can. Believe it or not, I&#8217;ve started playing 10 minute games in order to ease up time pressure on myself. I used to hate this time setting, but I&#8217;m starting to gain a new appreciation for it. More on this when I&#8217;ve solidified my position on it.</li>
<li><strong>Spend 10 minutes/day perusing a new book of go</strong> &#8211; I happen to have a lot of books that I own but haven&#8217;t read, so I created this new task in order to allow me to actually go through all the books that I own. I know it&#8217;s not quite the same as studying, but it&#8217;s fun for me and plus it&#8217;ll allow me to put more book reviews up in the future.</li>
<li><strong>Spend 20 minutes/day focusing on one topic of go</strong> &#8211; I&#8217;ve noticed that my attention span for a particular subject is super volatile these days. One day I&#8217;m interested in positional judgment, and the next day I&#8217;m curious about joseki. So instead of binding myself down to the same book (which gets boring for me), I devised this task in order to allow for topic changes while still giving myself adequate time to really study and absorb one topic per day. Lectures also can be used in place of books as well.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Games*</h2>
<ul>
<li><a title="KGS Website" href="http://www.gokgs.com/">KGS</a> &#8211;  6 games</li>
<li><a title="TygemGo Official Site" href="http://www.tygemgo.com/">Tygem</a> &#8211; 20+ games</li>
<li><a title="GoPanda IGS Official Site" href="http://pandanet-igs.com/communities/gopanda">IGS</a> &#8211; 5+ game</li>
<li><a title="Dragon Go Server - BenGoZen's Profile" href="http://www.dragongoserver.net/userinfo.php?uid=60385">DGS</a> &#8211; 5 ongoing games</li>
<li><a title="Online Go Server - BenGoZen's Profile" href="http://online-go.com/user/view/549/BenGoZen">OGS</a> &#8211;  3 ongoing games</li>
</ul>
<p><em>*I&#8217;m probably going to need a new structure for doing this. I&#8217;m starting to play a lot more now and it&#8217;s getting hard to track the exact number of games I&#8217;ve been playing. Do you think it&#8217;s useful that I keep specific metrics? Or is there something better I can do. Any suggestions would be greatly appreciated!</em></p>
<h2>Books</h2>
<ul>
<li>Dictionary of Basic Joseki, Volume 1</li>
<li>The Theory and Practice of Tsumego</li>
<li>Positional Judgment</li>
</ul>
<h2>Videos</h2>
<ul>
<li><a title="Yunguseng Dojang Lectures" href="http://ayd.yunguseng.com/lectures.html">YSD</a> &#8211; AYD S9 1st lecture Knight move across attachment / Break the dog&#8217;s face / Indirect defense</li>
<li><a title="Yunguseng Dojang Lectures" href="http://ayd.yunguseng.com/lectures.html">YSD</a> &#8211; Season 1 Fri 1st July 20:00 Opening Theory, ABC Examples (In Progress)</li>
<li><a title="Yunguseng Dojang Lectures" href="http://ayd.yunguseng.com/lectures.html">YSD</a> &#8211; Season 6 1st lecture Theme lecture &#8216;1-2-3 reading&#8217; (In Progress)</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/friday-go-forward-week-61/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">5202</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Friday Go Forward: Week 57</title>
		<link>/friday-go-forward-week-57/</link>
		<comments>/friday-go-forward-week-57/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2014 11:15:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Progress Reports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dojang]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jubango]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[korean insei]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yunguseng]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=4882</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Overview Man. I really fell off the wagon this week in terms of my training regimen. I was super disciplined about my reading training a couple of weeks ago, but I really got bum rushed with other priorities in life and just couldn&#8217;t do the regimen properly. The only thing that is redeeming about this [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>Overview</h2>
<p>Man. I really fell off the wagon this week in terms of my training regimen. I was super disciplined about my reading training a couple of weeks ago, but I really got bum rushed with other priorities in life and just couldn&#8217;t do the regimen properly. The only thing that is redeeming about this week is that I was able to practice problems here and there, but just not in one session the way I might have preferred.<br />
In addition, the silver lining of it all is that I&#8217;ve been much more involved with my game reviews and trying to really improve upon them. In case you missed it, this week there were two game reviews that were released (<a title="Monday Go Meditation: Game 50" href="//monday-go-meditation-game-50/">MGM 50</a> and <a title="WGW 36: Gu Li vs Lee Sedol — Jubango Game 3 Amateur Review" href="//wgw-36-gu-li-vs-lee-sedol-jubango-game-3-amateur-review/">Jubango Game 3</a>). And oy vey did they take a long time to do! Regardless, I would like to think that it will be valuable to my own growth and journey.<br />
Finally, I&#8217;ve started digging into the lectures on <a title="Yunguseng Dojang Official Site" href="http://www.yunguseng.com/">Yunguseng Dojang</a> and really have loved what I have been able to watch so far. I can only imagine what it will be like when I&#8217;m actually participating in the reviews and having my own games reviewed. So excited for the season to start!</p>
<h2>Training Regimen</h2>
<ul>
<li><b>Currently on pause at the moment. Will hopefully have an update next week.</b></li>
</ul>
<h2>Games</h2>
<ul>
<li><a title="KGS Website" href="http://www.gokgs.com/">KGS</a> &#8211;  5 games</li>
<li><a title="PandaNet IGS Official Website" href="http://pandanet-igs.com/">IGS</a> &#8211; 4 games</li>
<li><a title="Dragon Go Server - BenGoZen's Profile" href="http://www.dragongoserver.net/userinfo.php?uid=60385">DGS</a> &#8211; 5 ongoing games</li>
<li><a title="Online Go Server - BenGoZen's Profile" href="http://online-go.com/user/view/549/BenGoZen">OGS</a> &#8211;  3 ongoing games</li>
</ul>
<h2>Books</h2>
<ul>
<li>N/A</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/friday-go-forward-week-57/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">4882</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Friday Go Forward: Week 56</title>
		<link>/friday-go-forward-week-56/</link>
		<comments>/friday-go-forward-week-56/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2014 11:15:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Progress Reports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[congress]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dojang]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[go]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[insei]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[korean]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[school]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yunguseng]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=4845</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Friday Go Forward: Week 56 Overview This week marked the start of April and thus the official countdown to US Go Congress! In addition, I am uber psyched to announce that I officially joined the Yunguseng Dojang and will definitely be part of Season 9 2014! Even though it hasn&#8217;t started yet, since it&#8217;s a [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 style="text-align: center;">Friday Go Forward: Week 56</h2>
<h2>Overview</h2>
<p>This week marked the start of April and thus the official countdown to <a title="US Go Congress Official Site" href="http://www.gocongress.org/">US Go Congress</a>! In addition, I am uber psyched to announce that I officially joined the <a title="Yunguseng Dojang Official Site" href="http://www.yunguseng.com/">Yunguseng Dojang</a> and will definitely be part of Season 9 2014! Even though it hasn&#8217;t started yet, since it&#8217;s a break month, I was able to get started on checking out some of the recorded material in there. And while I would love to rant on and on about it right now, I will keep it short and just say that there is a lot of great stuff waiting for me to discover.<br />
I think I have come up with a new training regimen for my training my tsumego and reading, but I haven&#8217;t finalized it yet so I&#8217;ll wait till next week to update the section with what I&#8217;m doing. And in terms of playing go, it has been a bit quieter this week, but I&#8217;m definitely hoping to get online and play a game soon! Hope you all are doing well and I&#8217;ll see you next week!</p>
<h2>Training Regimen</h2>
<ul>
<li><b>Reading Ability &#8211; </b>Work on the tasks below until whichever comes first.*
<ul>
<li>Work on go problems for 30 minutes.</li>
<li>Work on 300 go problems.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p>*<em>This is a way to split the difference between task based versus time based training. If you work faster than normal, and can get through 300 (or whichever number you decide on) problems. Kudos to you. But in the event you&#8217;re having trouble and need more time to work on the problems, just keep at it until 30 minutes is up (or whatever time you think it best for you).</em></p>
<h2>Games</h2>
<ul>
<li><a title="KGS Website" href="http://www.gokgs.com/">KGS</a> &#8211;  2 games</li>
<li><a title="Dragon Go Server - BenGoZen's Profile" href="http://www.dragongoserver.net/userinfo.php?uid=60385">DGS</a> &#8211; 5 ongoing games</li>
<li><a title="Online Go Server - BenGoZen's Profile" href="http://online-go.com/user/view/549/BenGoZen">OGS</a> &#8211;  4 ongoing games</li>
</ul>
<h2>Books</h2>
<ul>
<li>Worked on <em>Life and Death Problems 1 &#8211; Basics</em> by Robert Jasiek.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/friday-go-forward-week-56/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">4845</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
