<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>global thinking &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/global-thinking/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>Book Review: The Direction of Play</title>
		<link>/book-review-the-direction-of-play/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2013 09:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[direction of play]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fuseki]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[global thinking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[opening]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[strategy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[whole board strategy]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=2924</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[[expand title=&#8221;Book Details&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;] [table] Title, The Direction of Play Author, Takeo Kajiwara Translators, John Fairbairn and The Ishi Press Staff Publisher, Kiseido Published, &#8220;1st Edition &#8211; March 1979&#8243; Language, English ISBN, 978-4-896574-26-2 Length, 250 Pages [/table] [/expand] [expand title=&#8221;Table of Content&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;] Introduction Chapter 1: The Direction of Play in the Opening: The Corner Stones Chapter 2: The Early [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/07/directionofplaycover.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3058" alt="directionofplaycover" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/07/directionofplaycover.jpg?resize=251%2C400" width="251" height="400" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><br />
[expand title=&#8221;Book Details&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
[table]
Title, The Direction of Play<br />
Author, Takeo Kajiwara<br />
Translators, John Fairbairn and The Ishi Press Staff<br />
Publisher, <a title="Kiseido Home Page" href="http://www.kiseido.com/">Kiseido</a><br />
Published, &#8220;1st Edition &#8211; March 1979&#8243;<br />
Language, English<br />
ISBN, 978-4-896574-26-2<br />
Length, 250 Pages<br />
[/table]
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Table of Content&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Introduction</li>
<li>Chapter 1: The Direction of Play in the Opening: The Corner Stones</li>
<li>Chapter 2: The Early Stages Are Decisive</li>
<li>Chapter 3: Move Two Lost This Game</li>
<li>Chapter 4: The Professional Approach</li>
<li>Chapter 5: The Direction of Play and Joseki</li>
<li>Chapter 6: Once Upon a Game</li>
<li>Chapter 7: Test Yourself</li>
<li>Chapter 8: The Direction of Play for Fighting</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Synopsis&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221; expanded=&#8221;true&#8221;]
<ol>
<li>An excellent, although a bit advanced, book on direction of play.</li>
<li>Fills a much needed gap in understanding the opening and fuseki as a whole.</li>
<li>Requires a basic understanding of whole board thinking to really appreciate and understand the explanations.</li>
</ol>
[/expand]
<span id="more-2924"></span><br />
[expand title=&#8221;Before I Read This Book&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<strong>My Abilities</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>I had little to no understanding of direction of play. I had heard the term used a lot in my reviews, but my understanding of it was practically nonexistent and any proper application of direction of play was usually just due to sheer luck. Although in my defense, I did have a moderate understanding of whole board thinking which would provide a good stepping stone to understanding this book.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>My Perspective</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Since I was going pretty much blind into the subject, I was really hoping to gain a good grasp on direction of play and be able to apply it when I was finished with the book.</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;My Review&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221; expanded=&#8221;true&#8221;]
<strong>What did I enjoy about the book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Direction of play is broken down into very simple components that make it easier for the reader to follow.</li>
<li>Kajiwara&#8217;s writing style makes for an entertaining read and helps make the lesson more memorable.</li>
<li>Although it is rather advanced and kind of went over my head, the book even goes into an explanation on how direction of play impacts fighting in a game.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What did I gain from reading this book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>A much better understanding of direction of play.</li>
<li>Though far from perfect, my ability to apply direction of play in my games has greatly improved.</li>
<li>A much greater appreciation for how important the opening and fuseki is in a game.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What style of teaching does the book use?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Lecture Approach
<ul>
<li>While there are numerous diagrams to try and illustrate the Kajiwara&#8217;s point, the gold mine of information in this book lies in his explanations and opinions about direction of play.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Primary Learning Mechanism:
<ul>
<li>Explanations with diagrams.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Other Learning Mechanisms:
<ul>
<li>Examples from actual games</li>
<li>Practice problems</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What aspect(s) can be improved on?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>While I loved the explanations and accompanying diagrams, it would have been great to have more practice problems.</li>
<li>Introductory problems that utilize the multiple choice format would also be nice for people new to direction of play.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Is this book easy to read?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Yes. Although not as entertaining as Kageyama&#8217;s writing style, Kajiwara&#8217;s writing style was still fun to read and really helped to make me feel comfortable with a topic that was once completely foreign to me.</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Recommended For&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Players looking to learn more about direction of play, even if only to simply be exposed to its concepts.</li>
<li>A basic understanding of the opening and whole board thinking is recommended to really appreciate the book as a whole, but this should not be a deterrent since this is a book that players will read multiple times in their journey as a go player.</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Where Can I Buy It?&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;lastExpandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>GoGameGuru &#8211; <a title="Go Game Guru Purchase Link" href="http://shop.gogameguru.com/the-direction-of-play/?acc=e4da3b7fbbce2345d7772b0674a318d5">$17.99</a> (shipping &amp; handling not included)</li>
<li>Kiseido &#8211; <a href="http://www.kiseido.com/go_books.htm">$18.00</a> (shipping &amp; handling not included)</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
<p style="text-align: center;"><em><strong>Last Updated on July 7th, 2013</strong></em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2924</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ranked Games and My Slow Brain</title>
		<link>/ranked-games-and-my-slow-brain/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 03:52:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fear of losing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fuseki]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[global thinking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[opening]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ranked games]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=2279</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Lately I&#8217;ve noticed that I seem to have trouble finding time to play ranked games. On the other hand, whenever a friend asks to play a game, I always manage to scrounge up the necessary time to play. After some thought, I believe it is for any of the following reasons: With ranked games, I [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lately I&#8217;ve noticed that I seem to have trouble finding time to play ranked games. On the other hand, whenever a friend asks to play a game, I always manage to scrounge up the necessary time to play. After some thought, I believe it is for any of the following reasons:</p>
<ol>
<li><span style="line-height: 13px;">With ranked games, I have this subconscious fear of not playing my best and losing. </span></li>
<li>When playing against friends, the burden of playing to win is lifted from my shoulders. As a result, even though the games take just as long as a ranked game normally would (or even longer), I&#8217;m at ease playing them because I don&#8217;t have a problem resigning the game if anything were to come up.</li>
<li>Continuing with that idea, I think part of me is fearful that I will be unable to complete a ranked game in its entirety. In my defense though, I have lost a game on time before because I was interrupted and needed to take care of some things. So the idea of losing a ranked game because of anything other than skill makes me shudder.</li>
</ol>
<p>Also, I&#8217;m at this weird point in my growth where my abilities are directly proportional with how much time I spend thinking about a move. Although this may sound common sense to many, I have heard that there are a number of players who can think all day long but will still come up with the same types of moves regardless. An obvious example of this would be joseki. Some players play joseki faithfully by the book because it says that the result is even. For me, it seems that the longer I spend thinking about a move, the more likely it is a better move than what I thought of previously.<br />
Recently, I have found myself spending more and more time in the opening trying to figure out how certain moves or potential responses will affect the game as a whole. As a result, I am finding myself in byoyomi even as early as the middle game sometimes. Since it&#8217;s such a new way of thinking for me, it is a very laborious and intensive process that takes a while for my brain to trudge through. Can&#8217;t wait till it becomes more innate and engrained into my go&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2279</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
