<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>james &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/james/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>North American Go Convention &#8211; Day 4</title>
		<link>/north-american-go-convention-day-4/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2013 22:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kifu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[9p]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[james]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[myung wan kim]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nagc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[north american go convention]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartgo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tournament]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=1932</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Introduction &#8212; Day 1 &#8212; Day 2 &#8212; Day 3 &#8212; Day 4 &#8212; Day 5 &#8212; Conclusion For Day 4, I had the honor of having my mom come and join me for the day! She just learned the rules recently and I was excited when she told me that she wanted to come to [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><a title="North American Go Convention!!!" href="//north-american-go-convention/">Introduction</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 1" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-1/">Day 1</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 2" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-2/">Day 2</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 3" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-3/">Day 3</a> &#8212; <strong>Day 4</strong> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 5" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-5/">Day 5</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Conclusion" href="//north-american-go-convention-conclusion/">Conclusion</a></p>
<p><em>For Day 4, I had the honor of having my mom come and join me for the day! She just learned the rules recently and I was excited when she told me that she wanted to come to an all day go convention!! Woot!!</em><br />
When we arrived at the convention, I was pleasantly surprised to see a lot of people at the registration room. As we settled down, I heard an announcement that everyone needed to check in if they wanted to compete. At the time, I was rather split as to what to do. On one hand, I wasn&#8217;t sure what the schedule for the professional events (i.e. lectures, simul games, reviews) was. In addition, I wasn&#8217;t sure I was okay with the idea of my mom sitting around for hours on end watching me play games when she was still so new to the game.<br />
Once registration was finished, I thought it would be a good idea to show my mom what competitive go looks like. Upon our arrival upstairs, we found them posting up the pairings for the first round. For some reason, I had a feeling that I might have been included even though I did not check in. Sure enough, I found my name after a quick glance at the list.<br />
<span id="more-1932"></span><br />
Shortly afterwards, I noticed that they posted up the schedule for the day and saw that the professional events had been scheduled at the end of Round 1 and 3. To clarify though, I do not mean that the events were scheduled after the rounds were over. In fact, they were scheduled at the tail end of the round time which meant that if I wanted to attend a pro event, I would face one of two situations: (1) I play in every round, but I&#8217;m forced to rush and hope that the game ends before the event. (2) I play every round, but end up resigning most of my games since I like to take my time with each move anyways.<br />
As I stood there trying to figure out what to do, my opponent found me. After panicking for a moment, I quickly found the tournament director and tried to tell him that I was not going to be playing (at least in the first round). Coincidentally, a fellow go player who was around our level had shown up late and so I tried to get the director to make a swap since it would keep the pairings equal. There was a bit of resistance at first, and it took quite a bit of back and forth before  they resolved the situation amongst themselves.<br />
In my defense though, I never checked in as they told us to do in order to be paired, so why would should I expect to be included? Not to mention, I was not in the mood to showing my mom a rushed game where I don&#8217;t play my best. And if that weren&#8217;t enough, I would probably end up resigning all my games since the pro events were during the rounds. So why make the day extra stressful and draining? No thank you.<br />
While we waited for the simul game with Myung to start, my mom and I had the pleasure of chatting with a local player (by the name of Mr. Choi) who was a director of some sort at a local Korean Baduk club. We found out that he was a 7 dan amateur who had won numerous competition in the United States before and enjoyed teaching go. In fact, we seemed to get along so well that he even started a teaching game with me. Haha.<br />
We only got a few moves into the game before it was time to start the simul game though. And before I knew it, I was sitting once again before Myung as I placed 9 stones on the board. With a renewed spirit from my defeat on <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 3" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-3/">Day 3</a>, it was time to try again! Ikuzo!<br />

<div id='glift_display1' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display1","sgf":"http:\/\/bengozen.com\/\/wp-content\/uploads\/2013\/02\/2013.02.20-NAGC-Day-4.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='//wp-content/uploads/2013/02/2013.02.20-NAGC-Day-4.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">[download label=&#8221;Download Kifu&#8221;]//wp-content/uploads/2013/02/2013.02.20-NAGC-Day-4.sgf[/download]
<p>Once the game was over, Mr. Choi, Myung, my mom and I went out to grab lunch at <a href="http://www.yelp.com/biz/el-pollo-rico-arlington">El Pollo Ricco</a> and had a delicious lunch!<br />
<figure id="attachment_1973" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/02/elpolloricco.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1973" alt="elpolloricco" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/02/elpolloricco.jpg?resize=300%2C225" width="300" height="225" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Credit to Yelp (Andrew C.)</figcaption></figure>
<p style="text-align: left;">Afterwards, we drove Myung back to the hotel so he could rest for the afternoon. Since we were going to pick him up later on and there were no pro events for the rest of the afternoon, my mom and I just went to a nearby mall to hangout. While it was a detour from the &#8220;all-day go convention,&#8221; we had some great conversation and the thought that I could be at the go convention instead never crossed my mind.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Later on that day, after picking Myung and James up, I found myself sitting in my first professional lecture. Myung was giving a lecture on the final game between Lee sedol and Gu Li in the recent Samsung Cup. Even though we were only able to really spend time on the opening (and a little bit of endgame), it was a really interesting review that definitely opened my eyes to some new ideas. I&#8217;ll be sure to write more about them when I&#8217;ve managed to digest them and can write them in a comprehensible fashion. One thing I can say for sure though, is that my appreciation for pro lectures has definitely grown since then!</p>
<p>With the day coming to an end, I thought that it would be a good idea to take Myung and James out to a local Vietnamese restaurant that we love called <a href="http://www.yelp.com/biz/viet-royale-falls-church">Viet Royale</a> (FYI. The Yelp reviews do not do the restaurant justice. I don&#8217;t think people know what to order. =D). I wish I had taken pictures of all the food we ordered, but it is suffice to say that it was full of delicious food and great conversation.<br />
<figure id="attachment_1975" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/02/pho.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1975" alt="Credit to Yelp (Ruth C.)" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/02/pho.jpg?resize=300%2C225" width="300" height="225" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Credit to Yelp (Ruth C.)</figcaption></figure>
All in all, it was a fantastic day full of great company and great memories. Here&#8217;s to hoping that Day 5 will live up to even 50% of it!</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a title="North American Go Convention!!!" href="//north-american-go-convention/">Introduction</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 1" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-1/">Day 1</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 2" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-2/">Day 2</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 3" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-3/">Day 3</a> &#8212; <strong>Day 4</strong> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 5" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-5/">Day 5</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Conclusion" href="//north-american-go-convention-conclusion/">Conclusion</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1932</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>North American Go Convention &#8211; Day 3</title>
		<link>/north-american-go-convention-day-3/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2013 17:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kifu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[9p]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[james]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[myung wan kim]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nagc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[north american go convention]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[simul game]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tournament]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=1929</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Introduction &#8212; Day 1 &#8212; Day 2 &#8212; Day 3 &#8212; Day 4 &#8212; Day 5 &#8212; Conclusion Shortly before leaving the convention on Day 2, I had mentioned to Myung and James that if they were free and didn&#8217;t have plans, I would be happy to take them out to dinner since they didn&#8217;t [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><a title="North American Go Convention!!!" href="//north-american-go-convention/">Introduction</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 1" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-1/">Day 1</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 2" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-2/">Day 2</a> &#8212; <strong>Day 3</strong> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 4" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-4/">Day 4</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 5" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-5/">Day 5</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Conclusion" href="//north-american-go-convention-conclusion/">Conclusion</a></p>
<p>Shortly before leaving the convention on <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 2" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-2/">Day 2</a>, I had mentioned to Myung and James that if they were free and didn&#8217;t have plans, I would be happy to take them out to dinner since they didn&#8217;t know the area very well. They told me that they would let me know how their schedule was the next day, so you can imagine how excited I was when I received a phone call letting me know that they would like to get dinner with me! Since they were in the Annandale area, I suggested that we meet at the Bonchon to get dinner.<br />
As per usual, the traffic to Virginia was not cooperating with me as I attempted to make my way to them. When I finally reached my destination, I arrived to find Myung and James outside with a local Korean go player. I was a bit bewildered at first as to why they were outside, but then I realized that the Bonchon was closed!!! Bleh. Definitely not what I anticipated. So we adapted and headed off to the Fairfax location.<br />
<figure id="attachment_1947" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/02/bonchonwings.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1947" alt="Credit to HauteLiving.com" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/02/bonchonwings.jpg?resize=300%2C224" width="300" height="224" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Credit to HauteLiving.com</figcaption></figure>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>If you&#8217;ve never had it before, it&#8217;s just heavenly&#8230;. Just thinking about it is making me hungry&#8230;.</em></p>
<p>Before I knew it, we were munching and chatting the night away. Time passed us by rather quickly because before we knew it it was 7:00pm and we needed to rush back to the convention. Fortunately we weren&#8217;t too far away, but I did feel bad that I didn&#8217;t do a better job keeping track of the time. Since we were running a behind though, we went ahead and dropped Myung off before heading off to do a coffee run.<br />
Once we got back and arrived at the building, we ran into a local go player who had stopped by for the convention but was leaving since there were only dans upstairs. When James hit the button to go to the 9th floor and nothing happened, you can imagine my face as I could only laugh as I realized that we would have to take the stairs once again. On the upside, having James helped to make the climb pass by much quicker.<br />
<span id="more-1929"></span><br />
When we finally arrived on the 9th floor, I was relieved to see familiar faces and the tournament room in clear sight. As we made our way into the tournament room, I saw that Myung was already in the middle of two simul games. At first I wasn&#8217;t sure if we would be too late to join, but before I knew it James took a seat and setup his handicap stones. I quickly followed suit and before I knew it, I was playing my third official professional simul game (the second one with Joanne Missingham doesn&#8217;t count since it never finished and was played in a more blitz manner than anything else). Below is the game record from that night:<br />

<div id='glift_display2' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display2","sgf":"http:\/\/bengozen.com\/\/wp-content\/uploads\/2013\/02\/2013.02.19-NAGC-Day-3.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='//wp-content/uploads/2013/02/2013.02.19-NAGC-Day-3.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">[download label=&#8221;Download Kifu&#8221;]//wp-content/uploads/2013/02/2013.02.19-NAGC-Day-3.sgf[/download]
<p>After I resigned, I spent a good 10 minutes going over the game and looking at Myung&#8217;s responses. I could only marvel in their simplicity as I tried to make my way through the game I had just played. I didn&#8217;t get too far because James and I decided to play a game together while Myung was focusing on his simul games. James is around 2 kyu, so I think the game took him by surprise when he learned my fighting abilities were not quite the same as a typical meek 6 kyu. I don&#8217;t have the game record for that night, but it was a fun game that was full of experiment and new ideas. =) Once all was said and done though, it seemed that Myung and James&#8217; ride still had things he needed to do, so I was more than happy to give them a ride back to their hotel.<br />
Once I dropped them off, I realized that I probably needed to get gas before heading home. I was a bit frustrated with past me for procrastinating this task because finding a gas station at 11:30pm is not very easy to do. My GPS was great at finding nearby gas stations, only they were all closed. (&gt;.&lt;) So after driving around for 15 minutes and burning more gas, I decided that it would be better to take my chances of getting home than getting stranded in the middle of Virginia. Fortunately for me, I ran into an open gas station before getting on a highway. So glad to know that I would not end the night stranded on the highway. Whew.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a title="North American Go Convention!!!" href="//north-american-go-convention/">Introduction</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 1" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-1/">Day 1</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 2" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-2/">Day 2</a> &#8212; <strong>Day 3</strong> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 4" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-4/">Day 4</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 5" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-5/">Day 5</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Conclusion" href="//north-american-go-convention-conclusion/">Conclusion</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1929</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
