<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>9 dans &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/9-dans/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>New Go Server &#8211; Go9Dan!!!</title>
		<link>/new-go-server-go9dan/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2012 13:03:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[9 dans]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[go9dan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lee sedol]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new go server]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=1359</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[After Kaya.gs came out with their go server, I would have never suspected that I would be sitting here telling you about a brand new go server; but reality always has a way of surprising you and I am thrilled to tell you about a brand new go server!!! Go9Dan will be approaching the server [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After <a title="Kaya Go Server" href="http://www.kaya.gs/">Kaya.gs</a> came out with their go server, I would have never suspected that I would be sitting here telling you about a brand new go server; but reality always has a way of surprising you and I am thrilled to tell you about a brand new go server!!!</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.go9dan.com/"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1360" alt="Go9Dan" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2012/12/go9dan-logo.png?resize=178%2C66" width="178" height="66" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><a title="Go9Dan Go Server" href="http://www.go9dan.com/">Go9Dan</a> will be approaching the server in a brand new way by adding the element of currency to the game. This means that players will now have the ability to put more than just their rank at stake when they play. There are multiple kinds of currency, but in general, they will allow players to bet on games, observe professional games, teaching games (which I believe are from professionals&#8230; but don&#8217;t quote me on this), buy instructional videos and books, and so on. For more information on the currency, click <a title="Go9Dan Currency Info Page" href="http://go9dan.com/Home/Getstarted#currencies">here</a>. And for the record, while I don&#8217;t agree with all the aspects that they plan to utilize the currency for, I do think it will bring a new aspect to online play that will motivate more people to play.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">If that wasn&#8217;t enough to get you interested in checking <a title="Go9Dan Go Server" href="http://www.go9dan.com/">Go9Dan</a> out, would it be of any interest to you if I told you that 9 dan professionals will be on this server?!?!?! 9 dans like Lee Sedol?!?!?!!? *<em>runs around like a little kid</em>*</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Here are some of the fantastic benefits that you can get by signing up before February 8th, 2013:</p>
<ol>
<li>3 months of Lite Membership</li>
<li>500 Gold</li>
<li>1,000,000 MPoints</li>
<li>Entered into a raffle for a chance to play a game against <a title="Lee Sedol Sensei's Library Page" href="http://senseis.xmp.net/?LeeSedol"><strong>Lee Sedol</strong></a>!!!!!!!</li>
<li>Having the possibility of being one of three players to win a free teaching game with <a title="Lee Sedol Sensei's Library Page" href="http://senseis.xmp.net/?LeeSedol"><strong>Lee Sedol</strong></a>!!!!!!!!</li>
</ol>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">AHHHHHH!!!!!!!!!!!!</h2>
<p style="text-align: left;">Now for those who have now explored the sight and are coming back to tell me, &#8220;Whoa. Ben. You forgot to mention that this will be a server with a monthly subscription.&#8221; False. I intentionally left it off until this point because people need to see the value of the go server first. Now that you&#8217;ve seen the potential value of this server, I want to emphasize to you that <strong>signing up now is a win-win situation</strong>. No money commitment, and the potential benefits are ENORMOUS!!!! And like with any service or product, a 3 month trial to see if you think its worth the money is about as good as it is going to get.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">So don&#8217;t delay! Go sign up now and be sure to put down bengozen as your referral! See you guys there!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1359</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
