<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>frustrated &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/frustrated/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>Stumbling Through the Dark</title>
		<link>/stumbling-dark/</link>
		<comments>/stumbling-dark/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2014 03:24:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kifu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[1k opponent]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[2 stone handicap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[black]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[frustrated]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[w+resign]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5484</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Today I added another notch to my losses. It was a 2 stone handicap game against a 1k and I completely goofed at the end. No reason I shouldn&#8217;t have won, but I just couldn&#8217;t see it through. [download label=&#8221;Download Kifu&#8221;]//wp-content/uploads/2014/06/2014.06.25-Stumbling-Through-the-Dark.sgf[/download] And the funny thing is that this trend seems to be consistent with other things [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Today I added another notch to my losses. It was a 2 stone handicap game against a 1k and I completely goofed at the end. No reason I shouldn&#8217;t have won, but I just couldn&#8217;t see it through.<br />

<div id='glift_display1' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display1","sgf":"http:\/\/bengozen.com\/\/wp-content\/uploads\/2014\/06\/2014.06.25-Stumbling-Through-the-Dark.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='//wp-content/uploads/2014/06/2014.06.25-Stumbling-Through-the-Dark.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">[download label=&#8221;Download Kifu&#8221;]//wp-content/uploads/2014/06/2014.06.25-Stumbling-Through-the-Dark.sgf[/download]
<p>And the funny thing is that this trend seems to be consistent with other things I tried to switch my attention to momentarily (like League of Legends). Part of me wonders whether I&#8217;ve acquired some sort of &#8220;losing&#8221; mindset; but on second though, it&#8217;s rather unlikely since I know that starting off any game being like &#8220;I&#8217;m going to lose anyways&#8221; is a recipe for disaster.<br />
As this is the first day in my quest to return back to my origins, I shouldn&#8217;t be surprised that things are not much different than yesterday. There&#8217;s a big mix of frustration, loss, and clarity all at the time. And to be honest, it feels as if stumbling through the dark blindly reaching for anything I can hold on to to feel like I&#8217;m making progress. I have no idea if it&#8217;s going to get me where I want to go, but it certainly seems to beat standing still.<br />
On the bright side, I&#8217;m glad I&#8217;m not gambling any time soon.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/stumbling-dark/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>16</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">5484</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Frustrating Evening</title>
		<link>/a-frustrating-evening/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2010 03:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[daily overview]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[frustrated]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[growth]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=87</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It seems I can&#8217;t seem to get my wrapped up properly in a game tonight. Every time I try to play online, it has been a miserable game each and every time. I always start out playing solid, and then always seem to mess up later on. On the upside, playing with Todd and Keith [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div style="clear: both; text-align: center;"></div>
<p><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2010/10/stress-relief-kit.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-826" title="Stress Relief Kit" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2010/10/stress-relief-kit.png?resize=264%2C320" alt="" width="264" height="320" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><br />
It seems I can&#8217;t seem to get my wrapped up properly in a game tonight. Every time I try to play online, it has been a miserable game each and every time. I always start out playing solid, and then always seem to mess up later on.<br />
On the upside, playing with Todd and Keith today was insightful and I learned a lot. It&#8217;s still frustrating how little I feel that I&#8217;ve grown in the (almost) two months time frame. I clearly haven&#8217;t been studying as much as I should have been lately. I should probably modify my regimen for improving my abilities.<br />
Five more days until the second month is up&#8230;. sigh&#8230;.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">87</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Chaotic Fusion</title>
		<link>/chaotic-fusion/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2010 14:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[compartmentalization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[frustrated]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[no growth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[whole board thinking]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=108</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s funny sometimes, how everyone thinks that they can compartmentalize portions of their lives: work, school, family, relationship, friends, and hobbies. We reserve parts of ourselves to deal with the independent portions, yet we all have moments where one compartment overflows to another. This brings to question how realistic compartmentalizing everything is. The problems, the [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s funny sometimes, how everyone thinks that they can compartmentalize portions of their lives: work, school, family, relationship, friends, and hobbies. We reserve parts of ourselves to deal with the independent portions, yet we all have moments where one compartment overflows to another. This brings to question how realistic compartmentalizing everything is.<br />
The problems, the stress, and the conflicts we run into end up being nothing more than local battles. Fights destined to take place at the corner or sides of the board due to simple stone interactions. The commentaries that would come from each move exists in our world as well, &#8220;You did this wrong. How stupid could you be? Didn&#8217;t we discuss why you shouldn&#8217;t do this already? What were you thinking?&#8221;<br />
Eventually we all hit this point I&#8217;m feeling right now, where attempts at fusing everything into one solid mindset comes to a halt. Nothing looks clear, and you&#8217;ve lost sight of everything. I&#8217;m frustrated with the progress of things and can&#8217;t shake the irritation I have. It&#8217;s at this point that I think it&#8217;s time to take a sabbatical and get away from it all. I don&#8217;t mean to run away or go on vacation, but to simply take a step back from it all. Although many of us have our various aspects of our lives, the one thing for certain is that we cannot ignore our own personal goals. There&#8217;s a time limit for each and every one of us, and it would be disappointing for us not to give our lives the meaning we desire it to.<br />
I played a game of Go this morning. It was supposedly against an 18 kyu (there was a question mark), but I just couldn&#8217;t hold it together and resigned in the end. Everything seems to be clashing, and it&#8217;s probably time for me to take a step back from it all for now. After all, trying to compartmentalize our lives is anything but futile. Like the Go board, every play affects the whole board.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">108</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
