<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>dalan &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/dalan/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>Go Congress 2014 &#8211; Day 4</title>
		<link>/go-congress-2014-day-4/</link>
		<comments>/go-congress-2014-day-4/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2014 12:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dalan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[evan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[go congress]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[haengma]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mark]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[michael]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[myung]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nathan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[satoru]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[variant]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5710</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Prelude &#8211; I &#8211; II &#8211; III &#8211; IV &#8211; V &#8211; VI &#8211; VII &#8211; Conclusion Today was the official rest day for Congress. In other words, this meant that there would be no tournament matches so that people could go and explore New York if they wanted. As you might suspect though, there was a group of people who were [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><a title="Go Congress 2014 — Prelude" href="//go-congress-2014-prelude/">Prelude</a> &#8211; <a title="Go Congress 2014 — Day 1" href="//go-congress-2014-day-1/">I</a> &#8211; <a title="Go Congress 2014 — Day 2" href="//go-congress-2014-day-2/">II</a> &#8211; <a title="Go Congress 2014 — Day 3" href="//go-congress-2014-day-3/">III</a> &#8211; <strong>IV</strong> &#8211; <a title="Go Congress 2014 — Day 5" href="//go-congress-2014-day-5/">V</a> &#8211; <a title="Go Congress 2014 — Day 6" href="//go-congress-2014-day-6/">VI</a> &#8211; <a title="Go Congress 2014 — Day 7" href="//go-congress-2014-day-7/">VII </a>&#8211; <a title="Go Congress 2014 — Conclusion" href="//go-congress-2014-conclusion/">Conclusion</a></p>
<p>Today was the official rest day for Congress. In other words, this meant that there would be no tournament matches so that people could go and explore New York if they wanted. As you might suspect though, there was a group of people who were here for go and just that alone. So in honor of these dedicated players, they had a “Die Hard Tournament” for these players.<br />
When I arrived at Hotel Pennsylvania, I found Nate and the gang hanging out.<br />
<a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/09/2014GC-D04-01.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5716" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/09/2014GC-D04-01.jpg?resize=720%2C540" alt="2014GC-D04-01" width="720" height="540" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><br />
<span id="more-5710"></span><br />
They seemed to have various plans for the day, so my brother and I decided to head out to try this soup dumpling place that he had been telling me about. Just as we were waiting for the metro to come however, I got a call from Myung inviting us for lunch. Doesn’t take a genius to guess what we did right? We hightailed it right out of the metro and went to meet up with Myung.<br />
When we arrived in Koreatown, we found Myung, Evan Cho (who was a strong amateur dan player that I had heard Myung talk about numerous times), and Mark Lee (who was another strong amateur from Korea). Both Evan and Mark were participating in the Master’s Tournament for Congress (which was reserved essentially for 5d and higher). So we talked a little about that and proceeded with the normal introductions and conversation.<br />
The food at the restaurant was traditional and authentic Korean food. And by that I mean we didn’t just eat Korean BBQ, but actual dishes that Korean people would normally eat at home or at a typical sit down restaurant. Apparently beef is pretty expensive in Korea. So while some of us would like to dream that every restaurant in Korea is just Korean BBQ, that is not the case. Haha.<br />
After finishing a delicious lunch, my brother and I planned go with Myung, Evan, and Mark one of the popular museums in New York (I can’t remember which); but after some time projections, we realized that we wouldn’t have time to go to the museum and also get my brother back in time to Penn Station. So we parted ways with them and headed off to let my brother get his things together.<br />
When the time came for him to leave, I have to admit I was a little sad to see my brother go. It might be some older brother instinct, but I had a great time hanging with him in NY and felt a little anxious watching him board the train on his own. I know I know… the guy is in his early 20’s, but I don’t think I’ll ever stop looking out for him. Haha.<br />
To get my mind off whether or not he’d be okay taking the train back on his own, I went back to Hotel Pennsylvania to see what everyone was up to. As I walked into the lobby, a little serendipity to have been in play because I ran into Michael as he was heading out. For those who don’t know, he was only able to stay for half the Congress, so I was really happy to be able to catch him before he left.<br />
<a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/09/2014GC-D04-02.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5717" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/09/2014GC-D04-02.jpg?resize=600%2C800" alt="2014GC-D04-02" width="600" height="800" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><br />
When I got to the top floor, I remember that I couldn’t really find anyone. It seemed everyone had headed off to do their own thing, so I sat down with my laptop and started working on some things. Sometime later, fellow UMBC alumni Nathan Epstein (henceforth referred to as Nathan and is not to be confused with Nate Eagle) came over to chat.<br />
In the midst of talking about the tournament and my withdrawal from the tournament, he pulled out this dice that he had gotten from one of the teaching seminars.<br />
<figure id="attachment_5719" style="width: 600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/09/2014GC-D04-04.jpg"><img class="wp-image-5719 size-full" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/09/2014GC-D04-04.jpg?resize=600%2C800" alt="asdf" width="600" height="800" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">(Current side) One-space jump, (Bottom side) Large knight move, (Other sides) Small knight move, Diagonal, Two-space jump, Large diagonal move (i.e., elephant jump)</figcaption></figure>
Apparently this was a teaching apparatus for helping teach players about haengma (i.e., stone movement) and shape. So when he asked me if I wanted to try playing a game, I couldn’t refuse! For those who are wondering how this variant of go works, the rules are pretty simple:</p>
<ol>
<li>Start with a cross-fuseki formation with stones on the star points for both players.</li>
<li>Black goes first.</li>
<li>Player rolls the die.</li>
<li>Based on the haengma that shows up, you can use any stone of the board to move according to that haengma.</li>
<li>After player makes his move, the other player takes his turn.</li>
</ol>
<p>Though it took a little getting used to, I actually really enjoyed playing it and hope to play it again. And if anyone knows anyone selling those die, please be sure to let me know!<br />
After that fun game, I headed out for the remainder of the day since my girlfriend was arriving in town. And with that, the first half of Go Congress had come and gone. Tomorrow, the start of the second half of Go Congress!</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a title="Go Congress 2014 — Prelude" href="//go-congress-2014-prelude/">Prelude</a> &#8211; <a title="Go Congress 2014 — Day 1" href="//go-congress-2014-day-1/">I</a> &#8211; <a title="Go Congress 2014 — Day 2" href="//go-congress-2014-day-2/">II</a> &#8211; <a title="Go Congress 2014 — Day 3" href="//go-congress-2014-day-3/">III</a> &#8211; <strong>IV</strong> &#8211; <a title="Go Congress 2014 — Day 5" href="//go-congress-2014-day-5/">V</a> &#8211; <a title="Go Congress 2014 — Day 6" href="//go-congress-2014-day-6/">VI</a> &#8211; <a title="Go Congress 2014 — Day 7" href="//go-congress-2014-day-7/">VII </a>&#8211; <a title="Go Congress 2014 — Conclusion" href="//go-congress-2014-conclusion/">Conclusion</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/go-congress-2014-day-4/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>14</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">5710</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Go Congress 2014 &#8211; Day 3</title>
		<link>/go-congress-2014-day-3/</link>
		<comments>/go-congress-2014-day-3/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2014 11:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kifu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dalan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[deguchi mariko]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ding bo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[go congress]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jungsang]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[michael]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[myung]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pro simul]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[satoru]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zhang hong yu]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5682</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Prelude &#8211; I &#8211; II &#8211; III &#8211; IV &#8211; V &#8211; VI &#8211; VII &#8211; Conclusion When I woke up, I sat in silence for a while as I thought about what I was going to do. Although some would simply shrug off the forfeit and continue playing in the tournament, I couldn’t stand the idea of continuing in the tournament. [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><a title="Go Congress 2014 — Prelude" href="//go-congress-2014-prelude/">Prelude</a> &#8211; <a title="Go Congress 2014 — Day 1" href="//go-congress-2014-day-1/">I</a> &#8211; <a title="Go Congress 2014 — Day 2" href="//go-congress-2014-day-2/">II</a> &#8211; <strong>III</strong> &#8211; <a title="Go Congress 2014 — Day 4" href="//go-congress-2014-day-4/">IV</a> &#8211; <a title="Go Congress 2014 — Day 5" href="//go-congress-2014-day-5/">V</a> &#8211; <a title="Go Congress 2014 — Day 6" href="//go-congress-2014-day-6/">VI</a> &#8211; <a title="Go Congress 2014 — Day 7" href="//go-congress-2014-day-7/">VII </a>&#8211; <a title="Go Congress 2014 — Conclusion" href="//go-congress-2014-conclusion/">Conclusion</a></p>
<p>When I woke up, I sat in silence for a while as I thought about what I was going to do. Although some would simply shrug off the forfeit and continue playing in the tournament, I couldn’t stand the idea of continuing in the tournament. And with my brother in town and my girlfriend coming up to visit the second half of the trip, my mind was made up.<br />
When I arrived at Hotel Pennsylvania, I went and officially withdrew myself from the tournament. I know that this decision might not sit well with some of you, but it was really the best decision for me as a whole. While it would have been great to have played in the tournament, withdrawing from the tournament freed up my schedule to spend time with my brother (and girlfriend eventually) while also allowing me the freedom to do whatever I wanted (i.e., spending time with professionals).<br />
Anyhow, I then entered the tournament room to see if anyone was up and around. As I walked around, I found Diego and Gurujeet in the middle of an intense game.<br />
<a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/09/2014GC-D03-01.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5689" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/09/2014GC-D03-01.jpg?resize=720%2C540" alt="2014GC-D03-01" width="720" height="540" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><br />
I vaguely remember catching Nate and Michael before the round started and wishing them the best of luck. And before I left, I went ahead and signed up for three simuls that day. After all, I could play in tournaments anytime I wanted back at home, it’s the professionals that made Congress as epic as it is.<br />
<span id="more-5682"></span><br />
After going to breakfast, I came back to play my first simul against Zhang Yu Hong, 5p.<br />
<a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/09/2014GC-D03-04.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5690" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/09/2014GC-D03-04.jpg?resize=600%2C800" alt="2014GC-D03-04" width="600" height="800" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><br />
The game record is as follows:<br />

<div id='glift_display1' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display1","sgf":"http:\/\/bengozen.com\/\/wp-content\/uploads\/2014\/09\/2014.08.12-US-Go-Congress-Yuhong-Zhao-5p.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='//wp-content/uploads/2014/09/2014.08.12-US-Go-Congress-Yuhong-Zhao-5p.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">[download label=&#8221;Download Kifu&#8221;]//wp-content/uploads/2014/09/2014.08.12-US-Go-Congress-Yuhong-Zhao-5p.sgf[/download]
<p>Shortly after finishing my simul, I got a call from Myung 9p asking me if I was free to help take pictures for him and Dahye 4p while they were teaching a class. Since the next simul was not for a while and I had finished my game early, I rushed off to help them take pictures.<br />
<a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/09/2014GC-D03-10.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5691" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/09/2014GC-D03-10.jpg?resize=720%2C480" alt="2014GC-D03-10" width="720" height="480" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><br />
Once the class was done, I headed up to the top floor (where the main convention was held). When I arrived, I ran into Michael who informed me that the store was now open. Words cannot describe how excited I was to go check the store out. After all, one of the major aspects of a convention is the store where you can spend your money on souvenirs and such!<br />
<figure id="attachment_5692" style="width: 800px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/09/2014GC-D03-28.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-5692" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/09/2014GC-D03-28.jpg?resize=720%2C540" alt="You can see Michael in this shot!" width="720" height="540" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">You can see Michael in this shot!</figcaption></figure>
It was like being a kid in the candy store. I seriously couldn’t believe my eyes as tables full of books were stretched across the room. There wasn’t as much go equipment as I would have liked to seen, but it was a respectable collection nonetheless. And on that note, they were selling autographed fans from professionals as well! Though memory isn’t serving me well at the moment, Michael purchased one of these fans. I can’t remember which professional it was, but I’m pretty sure he’ll be commenting below on which one he got whenever he sees this.* Nonetheless, it was great to see so much go merchandise in one place.<br />
<em>*Update: Michael got a Sakata Eio fan. Many thanks to Satoru for the reminder! I should&#8217;ve remembered! Haha.</em><br />
Once we were done browsing the shop, I can&#8217;t remember if this is precisely when it happened, but Michael and I finished our game from yesterday. The following is the game record:<br />

<div id='glift_display2' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display2","sgf":"http:\/\/bengozen.com\/\/wp-content\/uploads\/2014\/09\/2014.08.12-US-Go-Congress-Michael.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='//wp-content/uploads/2014/09/2014.08.12-US-Go-Congress-Michael.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">[download label=&#8221;Download Kifu&#8221;]//wp-content/uploads/2014/09/2014.08.12-US-Go-Congress-Michael.sgf[/download]
<p>After the game, I was scheduled for another simul and parted ways with Michael. I was slotted to play against another Chinese professional, Ding Bo, 5p. The following is the game record:<br />

<div id='glift_display3' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display3","sgf":"http:\/\/bengozen.com\/\/wp-content\/uploads\/2014\/09\/2014.08.12-US-Go-Congress-Bo-Ding-5p.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='//wp-content/uploads/2014/09/2014.08.12-US-Go-Congress-Bo-Ding-5p.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">[download label=&#8221;Download Kifu&#8221;]//wp-content/uploads/2014/09/2014.08.12-US-Go-Congress-Bo-Ding-5p.sgf[/download]
<p>After the simul, I can’t really remember what I did; but I imagine it consisted of exploring New York city with my brother and trying more food. Towards the evening though, I came back to Hotel Pennsylvania to play my third and final simul of the day. Nate, Michael and Dalan were scheduled to play against one of the new Japanese professional, Francis Meyers, 1p. You can see them here in action!<br />
<a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/09/2014GC-D03-29.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5693" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/09/2014GC-D03-29.jpg?resize=720%2C540" alt="2014GC-D03-29" width="720" height="540" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><br />
<a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/09/2014GC-D03-36.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5700" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/09/2014GC-D03-36.jpg?resize=720%2C540" alt="2014GC-D03-36" width="720" height="540" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><br />
I had signed up to play against a Japanese professional as well, Deguchi Mariko, 1p. Satoru was on the waiting list, but fortunately the people who signed up didn’t show up and he was allowed to play.<br />
<a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/09/2014GC-D03-40.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5702" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/09/2014GC-D03-40.jpg?resize=720%2C540" alt="2014GC-D03-40" width="720" height="540" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><br />
The following is the game record:<br />

<div id='glift_display4' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display4","sgf":"http:\/\/bengozen.com\/\/wp-content\/uploads\/2014\/09\/2014.08.12-US-Go-Congress-Mariko-Deguchi-1p.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='//wp-content/uploads/2014/09/2014.08.12-US-Go-Congress-Mariko-Deguchi-1p.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">[download label=&#8221;Download Kifu&#8221;]//wp-content/uploads/2014/09/2014.08.12-US-Go-Congress-Mariko-Deguchi-1p.sgf[/download]
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/09/2014GC-D03-41.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5703" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/09/2014GC-D03-41.jpg?resize=720%2C540" alt="2014GC-D03-41" width="720" height="540" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></p>
<p>After the game, I ran into Myung who asked me if I was up for getting food. Like he needed to ask. Haha. Jungsang hadn’t even yet however, so we waited for him to finish him simul game before heading out.<br />
<figure id="attachment_5701" style="width: 800px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/09/2014GC-D03-38.jpg"><img class="wp-image-5701 size-full" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/09/2014GC-D03-38.jpg?resize=720%2C540" alt="2014GC-D03-38" width="720" height="540" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">That guy stared at the board for so long trying to find a way to win&#8230; Let it go man.</figcaption></figure>
To keep a long story short, Jungsang’s simul game was an informal one he agreed to that took FOREVER. Seriously, the guy was playing to win and taking forever to make his moves. And when it comes to go etiquette, that’s extremely rude when you consider the fact that it is an informal game that also is a simul.<br />
While we waited, I went around and took pictures of the crazy go event that was going on on the other side of the room. Here you’ll see pictures of go in all shapes and sizes:<br />
<a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/09/2014GC-D03-30.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5694" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/09/2014GC-D03-30.jpg?resize=720%2C540" alt="2014GC-D03-30" width="720" height="540" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><br />
<a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/09/2014GC-D03-31.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5695" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/09/2014GC-D03-31.jpg?resize=720%2C540" alt="2014GC-D03-31" width="720" height="540" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><br />
&nbsp;<br />
<a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/09/2014GC-D03-32.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5696" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/09/2014GC-D03-32.jpg?resize=720%2C540" alt="2014GC-D03-32" width="720" height="540" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><br />
<a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/09/2014GC-D03-33.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5697" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/09/2014GC-D03-33.jpg?resize=720%2C540" alt="2014GC-D03-33" width="720" height="540" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><br />
<a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/09/2014GC-D03-34.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5698" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/09/2014GC-D03-34.jpg?resize=600%2C800" alt="2014GC-D03-34" width="600" height="800" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><br />
<a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/09/2014GC-D03-35.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5699" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/09/2014GC-D03-35.jpg?resize=720%2C540" alt="2014GC-D03-35" width="720" height="540" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><br />
After what seemed like forever, Myung, Jungsang and I were finally off to grab Shake Shack again. Haha. Except this time, we didn’t have the luxury of eating in since it was so crowded. So we brought the food back to Hotel Pennsylvania and holed up in one of the lecture rooms on the 6th floor.<br />
As we were sitting there and eating our delicious burgers, we talked about numerous things. Of course, as usual though, there were times where Jungsang wanted to say something more complicated and switched to Korean. And as I sat there listening to Myung and Jungsang talk, I came to a conclusion: I need to learn Korean. There’s just no getting around it. Haha. After all, with how invested I am in the go world and my increasing exposure to Korean professionals, it just didn’t make sense not to learn it.<br />
Anyhow, before long it was time for everyone to head off to bed and get some rest. And as I prepared to go to sleep, I couldn’t help but feel even more assured in my decision to withdraw from the tournament. After all, if I had participated in the tournament, I probably would have been too tired to play in all those simul games. And if I left early to find food, I wouldn’t have gotten a chance to hangout with Myung and Jungsang! No matter though, I had experienced the day fully and nodded off to sleep with no regrets.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a title="Go Congress 2014 — Prelude" href="//go-congress-2014-prelude/">Prelude</a> &#8211; <a title="Go Congress 2014 — Day 1" href="//go-congress-2014-day-1/">I</a> &#8211; <a title="Go Congress 2014 — Day 2" href="//go-congress-2014-day-2/">II</a> &#8211; <strong>III</strong> &#8211; <a title="Go Congress 2014 — Day 4" href="//go-congress-2014-day-4/">IV</a> &#8211; <a title="Go Congress 2014 — Day 5" href="//go-congress-2014-day-5/">V</a> &#8211; <a title="Go Congress 2014 — Day 6" href="//go-congress-2014-day-6/">VI</a> &#8211; <a title="Go Congress 2014 — Day 7" href="//go-congress-2014-day-7/">VII </a>&#8211; <a title="Go Congress 2014 — Conclusion" href="//go-congress-2014-conclusion/">Conclusion</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/go-congress-2014-day-3/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">5682</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
