<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>strategy &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/strategy/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>Taking a Second Look at the Blog</title>
		<link>/taking-second-look-blog/</link>
		<comments>/taking-second-look-blog/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2014 21:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[content]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[revising]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[strategy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[update]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5462</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Lately I&#8217;ve been reconsidering what direction the blog has been heading in. Although it&#8217;s been great starting a new series and having content flow consistently, lately the blog has felt more like a newspaper or e-magazine of sorts instead of a personal journal. For example, the game reviews that are being published are now usually like [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lately I&#8217;ve been reconsidering what direction the blog has been heading in. Although it&#8217;s been great starting a new series and having content flow consistently, lately the blog has felt more like a newspaper or e-magazine of sorts instead of a personal journal. For example, the game reviews that are being published are now usually like a month behind where I am now, which can be confusing for you as a reader and also throws my blog into a weird clashing timeline.<br />
As a result, I&#8217;ve been thinking a lot about what I can do to fix that, and I&#8217;ve come up with the following items in order to better optimize my time and produce content that better fits my vision for the blog:<br />
Starting next week&#8230;</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Thursday Go Tygem will now be discontinued</strong> in order to pave way for #2 and #3.</li>
<li><strong>Monday Go Meditation is going to undergo a reboot</strong> with an updated format that takes some elements of Thursday Go Tygem and should improve the overall quality and value of the weekly column. In addition, I will be clearing out the queue in Monday Go Meditation in order to make way for current games and realign the blog with the games I&#8217;m currently playing as opposed to games I played weeks or even months ago.</li>
<li><strong>There will be a new post every weekday (i.e. Mon-Fri)</strong>. This might seem extreme and be a point of concern for some, but I&#8217;ve reached a new level of comfort with my blogging that should make this very viable. I&#8217;m hoping that this should help the blog start to return to its origins of being a chronicle of my journey (in real-time).</li>
</ol>
<p>In addition, you&#8217;ll start noticing little changes around the blog like new tagging or categories appear as I restructure the content in order to make it more user friendly, but those shouldn&#8217;t impact your reading experience on the blog much.<br />
Starting in July&#8230;</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>I&#8217;m going to update the format and change the schedule of Friday Go Forward </strong>&#8211; Although some don&#8217;t realize it, Friday Go Forward currently captures my progress from the last Friday afternoon/evening to the next Thursday evening since it gets published every Friday morning. In order to better capture my weekly progress, I will be changing it to Saturday so it fully captures that week. In addition, everyone&#8217;s feedback  was really helpful on figuring out next steps, so be on the lookout in the future for an improved format!</li>
</ol>
<p>Whew. Been meaning to unload that from my brain for some time. I&#8217;m hoping that you&#8217;ll like these new changes; but as always, please be sure to leave feedback in case I&#8217;m missing something or you see something I can do to improve what you&#8217;re seeing here on the blog. See you around!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/taking-second-look-blog/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">5462</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Book Review: Otake&#039;s Secret of Strategy</title>
		<link>/book-review-otakes-secret-strategy/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2013 17:02:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hideo otake]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hinoki press]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[otake 9p]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[strategy]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=4250</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Otake&#8217;s Secrets of Strategy Description: In the third volume of The Heart of Go Series, Hideo Otake 9P illustrates 10 fundamental strategic principles. Afterwards, there is a set of problems to apply what you learned. This is the followed up by a set of amateur game reviews and professional game reviews. [expand title=&#8221;Book Details&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;] [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/10/heartofgov3cover.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-4251" alt="heartofgov3cover" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/10/heartofgov3cover.jpg?resize=251%2C400" width="251" height="400" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">Otake&#8217;s Secrets of Strategy</h2>
<p><strong>Description:</strong> In the third volume of The Heart of Go Series, Hideo Otake 9P illustrates 10 fundamental strategic principles. Afterwards, there is a set of problems to apply what you learned. This is the followed up by a set of amateur game reviews and professional game reviews.<br />
<span id="more-4250"></span><br />
[expand title=&#8221;Book Details&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
[table]
Title, Otake&#8217;s Secrets of Strategy<br />
Series, Heart of Go Discovery Series<br />
Author, Hideo Otake 9P<br />
Translators, Robert J. Terry<br />
Publisher, Hinoki Press<br />
Published, &#8220;December 2007&#8243;<br />
Language, English<br />
ISBN, 978-0-9788874-4-5<br />
Length, 254 Pages<br />
[/table]
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Table of Content&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Forward</li>
<li>Ten Conditions of Go Knowledge
<ul>
<li>Otake Strategy #1 &#8211; The Attacking Force Must Be Properly Deployed</li>
<li>Otake Strategy #2 &#8211; Avoid Engaging Strong Enemy Forces in Battle</li>
<li>Otake Strategy #3 &#8211; Understanding the Opponent and Oneself, If a Fight Occurs, There is No Contest</li>
<li>Otake Strategy #4 &#8211; Attack at the Place Where It is Easiest to Attack</li>
<li>Otake Strategy #5 &#8211; Fighting Does Not Arise for Fixed Shape</li>
<li>Otake Strategy #6 &#8211; Controlling the High Ground is Fundamental to Victory</li>
<li>Otake Strategy #7 &#8211; When Attacking, Think About How to Withdraw</li>
<li>Otake Strategy #8 &#8211; While Keeping the Left in Check, Move on the Right</li>
<li>Otake Strategy #9 &#8211; Make Use of Every Resource Available</li>
<li>Otake Strategy #10 &#8211; Creative Application of Principles is Important</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Chapter 1 &#8211; Practical Application of Strategy: Problem Collection
<ul>
<li>33 Model Positions</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Chapter 2 &#8211; Amateur Game Guidance
<ul>
<li>Game 1 &#8211; A Game of Huge Reversal (5D vs. 5D)</li>
<li>Game 2 &#8211; A Game with a Clash of strength (5D vs. 5D)</li>
<li>Game 3 &#8211; A Professional Teaching Game (Professional vs. 4D)</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Chapter 3 &#8211; Appreciating Famous Professional Games
<ul>
<li>Game 1 &#8211; The Start of the Otake-Rin Rivalry (Otake Hideo vs. Rin Kaiho)</li>
<li>Game 2 &#8211; A Masterpiece of Positional Judgment (Otake Hideo vs. Kobayashi Koichi)</li>
<li>Game 3 &#8211; A Masterpiece of Sacrifice and Attacking (Honinbo Dosaku vs. Yasui Chitetsu)</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Before I Read This Book&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
After reading the first two volumes of this series, I have to say that I was feeling pretty apprehensive about this next one. The only glimmer of hope I saw was that Otake Hideo 9P would be discussing amateur games. I did not have very high hopes though. After all, a professionals secrets of strategy is something I thought would definitely go way over my head.<br />
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;My Review&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221; expanded=&#8221;true&#8221;]
When I opened up to the first section, &#8220;Ten Conditions of Go Knowledge&#8221; (aka Ten Strategies for Go), I was incredibly relieved to actually see summarized concepts of what Otake 9P considered to be ten strategies that players should keep in mind. The explanations were a little complicated, but I felt hope as I was able to maneuver my way through them and not be completely lost since it was also relatively brief as well. This section was definitely a bit advanced, but I see no reason why a SDK (i.e., single digit kyu) would not be able to understand it with some effort.<br />
Upon opening the first chapter, &#8220;Practical Applications of Strategy: Problem Collection,&#8221; I was afraid that I would find myself in the same boat as the last volume. To my greatest relief however, not only would I find this section to be one of my favorites; but I could actually understand what Otake 9P was trying to illusrate a good number of times and actually got the correct answers a handful of times! Woot! What a relief after being dragged through the mud in the last volume.<br />
In the second chapter, &#8220;Amateur Game Guidance,&#8221; I couldn&#8217;t help but be thrilled at the fact that we would be going over amateur games. Now granted, the players tended to be in the high dan rankings, but the fact that they were amateurs seemed to put my mind more at ease. The figures and explanations are moderately advanced, but I see no reason why any mid to high single digit kyu player wouldn&#8217;t be able to follow with relative ease. In fact, I believe low single digit kyus might also be able to follow with some effort.<br />
In the final chapter, &#8220;Appreciating Famous Professional Games,&#8221; Otake 9P continues the general review style you become accustomed to in the second chapter; but I have to say that the explanations seemed to be a bit more advanced. To be clear though, I wasn&#8217;t completely lost by any stretch of the means. It&#8217;s just that it required more effort than I would have liked. =)<br />
Overall, I am glad that I did not give up on this series and really appreciate what Otake 9P did with this book. However, I would stress the fact that I still consider this book to be in the intermediate to advanced category. It&#8217;s recommended if you&#8217;re intending on intensely studying the game as if it were a course in school; but otherwise, it&#8217;s not what I would consider light study material for the casual player.<br />
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Synopsis&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<strong>What did I enjoy about the book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>A lot easier to comprehend compared to the Volume 2.</li>
<li>Has problems that are not overly advanced and are quite helpful.</li>
<li>Seems like it was actually written for kyu players to actually understand.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What did I gain from reading this book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>A better sense of some of Otake 9P&#8217;s strategic principles.</li>
<li>Greater appreciation for being able to keep whole board perspective.</li>
<li>Increased confidence in that my abilities are improving.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What is the format of the book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The problems are presented and are then followed by the solution and variations with accompanying explanations. Unlike Volume 2, the correct solution was very easy to identify which made for a much more pleasant experience.</li>
<li>The game commentaries are structured like most normal books: diagrams accompanied by their explanations.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What aspects can be improved on?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Honestly, for what the book was intended to do, nothing really comes to mind.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Is this book easy to read?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Mostly. There are a number of occasions where the phrasing or choice of words seems rather odd and can throw off the reader, but overall the translation is comprehensible (though it definitely does not read as easily as say Kageyama&#8217;s books).</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Bottom Line</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>An enjoyable read for those looking to learn about some strategic principles in go.</li>
<li>Contains a nice set of problems that kyu players (around mid SDK) can solve).</li>
<li>Decently heavy and dense study material that is not suited for casual players just looking for a light read.</li>
</ol>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Recommended For&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Recommended for mid to high single digit kyus and stronger players looking for an intermediate-advanced book on strategic concepts.</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Where Can I Buy It?&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>GoGameGuru &#8211; <a href="http://shop.gogameguru.com/otakes-secrets-of-strategy/?acc=e4da3b7fbbce2345d7772b0674a318d5">$22.99</a> (shipping and handling not included)</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Other Books in This Series&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;lastExpandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li><a title="Book Review: Perceiving the Direction of Play" href="//book-review-perceiving-direction-play/">Heart of Go Series &#8211; Volume 1: Perceiving the Direction of Play</a></li>
<li><a title="Book Review: Scent of Victory" href="//book-review-scent-victory/">Heart of Go Series &#8211; Volume 2: Catching Scent of Victory</a></li>
<li>Heart of Go Series &#8211; Volume 3: Otake&#8217;s Secrets of Strategy</li>
<li>Heart of Go Series &#8211; Volume 4: Changing One&#8217;s Conceptions: Awaji&#8217;s Aphorisms</li>
<li>Heart of Go Series &#8211; Volume 5: The Way of Creating a Thick and Strong Game</li>
<li>Heart of Go Series &#8211; Volume 6: Zone Press Park</li>
<li>Heart of Go Series &#8211; Volume 7: Breakthrough Attacking Power Yamashita Style</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
<p style="text-align: center;"><em><strong>Last Updated on November 2nd, 2013.</strong></em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">4250</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Book Review: Whole Board Thinking in Joseki, Vol 1</title>
		<link>/book-review-whole-board-thinking-in-joseki-vol-1/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2013 09:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[application]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[joseki]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[multiple choice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[problems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[strategy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[whole board thinking]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=3109</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Description: In the first volume of Whole Board Thinking in Joseki series, Yilun Yang uses an innovative approach to teaching how one can apply global strategy to help make the right choice in local situations for the 3-4, low kakari. [expand title=&#8221;Book Details&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;] [table] Title, &#8220;Whole Board Thinking in Joseki, Volume One: 3-4 Point, [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/06/wholeboardjosekiv1cover.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3111" alt="wholeboardjosekiv1cover" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/06/wholeboardjosekiv1cover.jpg?resize=287%2C229" width="287" height="229" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><br />
<strong>Description: </strong>In the first volume of Whole Board Thinking in Joseki series, Yilun Yang uses an innovative approach to teaching how one can apply global strategy to help make the right choice in local situations for the 3-4, low kakari.<br />
<span id="more-3109"></span><br />
[expand title=&#8221;Book Details&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
[table]
Title, &#8220;Whole Board Thinking in Joseki, Volume One: 3-4 Point, Low Kakari&#8221;<br />
Authors, Yi-Lun Yang with Phil Straus<br />
Publisher, Fourth Line Press<br />
Published, 1996<br />
Language, English<br />
ISBN, 0-9653546-0-1<br />
Length, 197 Pages<br />
Problems, 112 Problems<br />
[/table]
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Table of Content&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ol>
<li>Preface</li>
<li>One-Space Low Pincer</li>
<li>Two-Space Low Pincer</li>
<li>Three-Space Low Pincer</li>
<li>One-Space High Pincer</li>
<li>Two-Space High Pincer</li>
<li>Three-Space High Pincer</li>
<li>Glossary of Terms</li>
<li>About the Authors</li>
</ol>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Synopsis&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221; expanded=&#8221;true&#8221;]
<ol>
<li>Though it may seem like a book about joseki, I feel it&#8217;s more of a book about understanding whole board thinking.</li>
<li>Offers a great opportunity to practice whole board thinking while getting a better understanding of why one move is better or worse in different positions.</li>
<li>Very easy to read and work through.</li>
</ol>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Before I Read This Book&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<strong>My Abilities</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Although I&#8217;ve had some exposure to joseki, I have avoided studying them like the plague. I really, really don&#8217;t like studying joseki.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>My Perspective</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Though I was skeptical of the book due to seeing the work joseki, I had heard a lot of good things about this book. In addition, since I was interested in trying to learn more about whole board thinking, I thought this book might be interesting to check out.</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;My Review&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221; expanded=&#8221;true&#8221;]
<strong>What did I enjoy about the book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The problems use a multiple choice format to help players like me who don&#8217;t know any joseki.</li>
<li>There are clear and easy to understand explanations for every answer choice that allows the reader to compare and contrast why the correct answer is better than the others.</li>
<li>The problems and solution diagrams are put on completely different pages to prevent the player from accidentally seeing the solution.</li>
<li>The layout of the book was very easy to read. Each section is clearly defined and the book is not cluttered at all.</li>
<li>Though the book seems to be centered on joseki, this seems more like a book on whole board thinking than anything else.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What did I gain from reading this book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Improved understanding of how certain moves work with the board as a whole.</li>
<li>Reduction in kyu tunnel vision since I have more practice considering the whole board position.</li>
<li>Slightly better understanding of joseki patterns for the 3-4 point, low kakari.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What style of teaching does the book use?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Off the Cliff Style
<ul>
<li>There is no gradual progression into the material.</li>
<li>You learn through trial and error as you progress through the book.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Primary Learning Mechanism:
<ul>
<li>Multiple choice practice problems.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Other Learning Mechanisms:
<ul>
<li>Clear and concise explanations with an accompanying diagram to illustrate his point.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What aspect can be improved on?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>I wish there were more problems! =D But in all seriousness, this book is amazing as it stands. Top notch!</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Is this book easy to read?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Absolutely. The explanations are no longer than a paragraph long and are very clear and concise.</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;In Comparison to Similar Books&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
[expandsub1 title=&#8221;38 Basic Joseki&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;cBookTitle&#8221;]
<a title="Book Review: 38 Basic Joseki" href="//book-review-38-basic-joseki/">38 Basic Joseki</a>, like most joseki books, actually focuses on teaching the reader about the various sequences from joseki. There is some mention of how they affect the board as a whole, but there is a lack of illustration as to how it is truly impacted. Whole Board Thinking in Joseki, on the other hand, does a perfect job filling this gap.<br />
[/expandsub1]
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Recommended For&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Players looking to practice their whole board thinking.</li>
<li>Players looking to understand why some moves are better or worse than others when in certain board positions.</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Where Can I Buy It?&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Slate and Shell &#8211; <a title="Slate and Shell Purchase Link" href="http://www.slateandshell.com/SSYY002.html">$26.00</a> USD (shipping and handling not included)</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Other Books in This Series&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;lastExpandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Whole Board Thinking in Joseki &#8211; Volume Two</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
<p style="text-align: center;"><em><strong>Last Updated on July 20th, 2013</strong></em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3109</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Book Review: The Direction of Play</title>
		<link>/book-review-the-direction-of-play/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2013 09:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[direction of play]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fuseki]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[global thinking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[opening]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[strategy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[whole board strategy]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=2924</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[[expand title=&#8221;Book Details&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;] [table] Title, The Direction of Play Author, Takeo Kajiwara Translators, John Fairbairn and The Ishi Press Staff Publisher, Kiseido Published, &#8220;1st Edition &#8211; March 1979&#8243; Language, English ISBN, 978-4-896574-26-2 Length, 250 Pages [/table] [/expand] [expand title=&#8221;Table of Content&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;] Introduction Chapter 1: The Direction of Play in the Opening: The Corner Stones Chapter 2: The Early [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/07/directionofplaycover.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3058" alt="directionofplaycover" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/07/directionofplaycover.jpg?resize=251%2C400" width="251" height="400" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><br />
[expand title=&#8221;Book Details&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
[table]
Title, The Direction of Play<br />
Author, Takeo Kajiwara<br />
Translators, John Fairbairn and The Ishi Press Staff<br />
Publisher, <a title="Kiseido Home Page" href="http://www.kiseido.com/">Kiseido</a><br />
Published, &#8220;1st Edition &#8211; March 1979&#8243;<br />
Language, English<br />
ISBN, 978-4-896574-26-2<br />
Length, 250 Pages<br />
[/table]
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Table of Content&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Introduction</li>
<li>Chapter 1: The Direction of Play in the Opening: The Corner Stones</li>
<li>Chapter 2: The Early Stages Are Decisive</li>
<li>Chapter 3: Move Two Lost This Game</li>
<li>Chapter 4: The Professional Approach</li>
<li>Chapter 5: The Direction of Play and Joseki</li>
<li>Chapter 6: Once Upon a Game</li>
<li>Chapter 7: Test Yourself</li>
<li>Chapter 8: The Direction of Play for Fighting</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Synopsis&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221; expanded=&#8221;true&#8221;]
<ol>
<li>An excellent, although a bit advanced, book on direction of play.</li>
<li>Fills a much needed gap in understanding the opening and fuseki as a whole.</li>
<li>Requires a basic understanding of whole board thinking to really appreciate and understand the explanations.</li>
</ol>
[/expand]
<span id="more-2924"></span><br />
[expand title=&#8221;Before I Read This Book&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<strong>My Abilities</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>I had little to no understanding of direction of play. I had heard the term used a lot in my reviews, but my understanding of it was practically nonexistent and any proper application of direction of play was usually just due to sheer luck. Although in my defense, I did have a moderate understanding of whole board thinking which would provide a good stepping stone to understanding this book.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>My Perspective</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Since I was going pretty much blind into the subject, I was really hoping to gain a good grasp on direction of play and be able to apply it when I was finished with the book.</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;My Review&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221; expanded=&#8221;true&#8221;]
<strong>What did I enjoy about the book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Direction of play is broken down into very simple components that make it easier for the reader to follow.</li>
<li>Kajiwara&#8217;s writing style makes for an entertaining read and helps make the lesson more memorable.</li>
<li>Although it is rather advanced and kind of went over my head, the book even goes into an explanation on how direction of play impacts fighting in a game.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What did I gain from reading this book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>A much better understanding of direction of play.</li>
<li>Though far from perfect, my ability to apply direction of play in my games has greatly improved.</li>
<li>A much greater appreciation for how important the opening and fuseki is in a game.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What style of teaching does the book use?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Lecture Approach
<ul>
<li>While there are numerous diagrams to try and illustrate the Kajiwara&#8217;s point, the gold mine of information in this book lies in his explanations and opinions about direction of play.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Primary Learning Mechanism:
<ul>
<li>Explanations with diagrams.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Other Learning Mechanisms:
<ul>
<li>Examples from actual games</li>
<li>Practice problems</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What aspect(s) can be improved on?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>While I loved the explanations and accompanying diagrams, it would have been great to have more practice problems.</li>
<li>Introductory problems that utilize the multiple choice format would also be nice for people new to direction of play.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Is this book easy to read?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Yes. Although not as entertaining as Kageyama&#8217;s writing style, Kajiwara&#8217;s writing style was still fun to read and really helped to make me feel comfortable with a topic that was once completely foreign to me.</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Recommended For&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Players looking to learn more about direction of play, even if only to simply be exposed to its concepts.</li>
<li>A basic understanding of the opening and whole board thinking is recommended to really appreciate the book as a whole, but this should not be a deterrent since this is a book that players will read multiple times in their journey as a go player.</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Where Can I Buy It?&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;lastExpandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>GoGameGuru &#8211; <a title="Go Game Guru Purchase Link" href="http://shop.gogameguru.com/the-direction-of-play/?acc=e4da3b7fbbce2345d7772b0674a318d5">$17.99</a> (shipping &amp; handling not included)</li>
<li>Kiseido &#8211; <a href="http://www.kiseido.com/go_books.htm">$18.00</a> (shipping &amp; handling not included)</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
<p style="text-align: center;"><em><strong>Last Updated on July 7th, 2013</strong></em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2924</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Book Review: The Nihon Ki-in Handbook of Proverbs</title>
		<link>/book-review-the-nihon-ki-in-handbook-of-proverbs/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2012 17:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[5 ponnuki revew]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fighting strategy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[proverbs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shape theory]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[strategy]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Overall Rating: 5 / 5 Ponnuki Basic Information Title: The Nihon Ki-in Handbook of Proverbs (Volume One) Author: Translated and Edited by Max Golem Publication Date: March 19, 1999 Page Length: 163 pages Synopsis This is a fantastic book for players who want to be exposed to lots of different concepts without being inundated with [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-703" title="Nihon Ki-in Handbook of Proverbs" alt="" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2012/01/proverbs.jpg?resize=245%2C380" width="245" height="380" data-recalc-dims="1" /></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">Overall Rating: 5 / 5 Ponnuki</h2>
<h3><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Basic Information</span></h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Title:</strong> <span style="text-decoration: underline;">The Nihon Ki-in Handbook of Proverbs (Volume One)</span></li>
<li><strong>Author:</strong> Translated and Edited by Max Golem</li>
<li><strong>Publication Date:</strong> March 19, 1999</li>
<li><strong>Page Length:</strong> 163 pages</li>
</ul>
<h3 style="text-align: left;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Synopsis</span></h3>
<ul>
<li style="text-align: left;">This is a fantastic book for players who want to be exposed to lots of different concepts without being inundated with dense diagrams and explanations.</li>
<li style="text-align: left;">The book covers a very broad range of material that makes it a valuable purchase for those who have a difficult time with some of the other more dense material.</li>
<li style="text-align: left;">Appropriate for 20 kyu and stronger.</li>
<li style="text-align: left;">Recommended for all players.</li>
</ul>
<div style="text-align: left;"><span id="more-1854"></span></div>
<h3 style="text-align: left;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Detailed Review</span></h3>
<h4 style="text-align: left;">Readability &#8211; 9 / 10</h4>
<p>The <span style="text-decoration: underline;">Nihon Ki-in Handbook of Proverbs</span> reads just like a book on fables. All of the proverb explanations (including diagrams) only ranges from half a page to two at most. The message is generally delivered in a very concise manner, which prevents it from being onerous to newer players.<br />
One of the frustrating aspects about some other go books is the fact that the explanations can be extremely long and dense. This makes it difficult on two different levels. First, newer players get incredibly bored (and even discouraged) since the information goes way over their heads. Secondly, players who only have a chance to occasionally read find themselves stopping at odd places within an explanation of a concept. And by the time they return to reading again, they may have forgotten what was mentioned in the first half of the explanation.<br />
As a result, it is perfect for any player who wants to do some light reading since they will easily finish a concept in its entirety in a single session.</p>
<h4 style="text-align: left;">Content Quality &#8211; 9 / 10</h4>
<p>As you can expect from a book of proverbs, <span style="text-decoration: underline;">The Nihon Ki-in Handbook of Proverbs</span> focuses on a broader overview of multiple topics. Its delivery of quality information in a concise and easy to read format is why it gets such a top rating. In addition, the fact that it covers the topic of fighting is fantastic since very few of the mainstream books spend any time of that area. If I had to gripe about a an aspect of content however, it would be that I would liked to see more material on endgame. Otherwise, the concepts and ideas provided are very valuable and will serve as a great foundation for players who will go off to read more in depth books.</p>
<h4>Conclusion</h4>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">The Nihon Ki-in Handbook of Proverbs</span> continues to remain a classic amongst the go literature out there due to its availability and timeless advice. In addition, its ability to be light reading is a rare characteristic for many go books that I&#8217;ve encountered and is something I greatly appreciate. Any person even remotely interested in studying the game will definitely find this book to be a treasure trove of information.</p>
<h3 style="text-align: left;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Table of Contents</span></h3>
<ol>
<li>Basic Moves and Concepts</li>
<li>Good Shape and Bad</li>
<li>Playing Ko</li>
<li>The Opening</li>
<li>Joseki</li>
<li>Territorial Frameworks</li>
<li>Life and Death</li>
<li>Running, Connecting, and Capturing</li>
<li>Clever Moves, Forcing Moves, and Sacrifices</li>
<li>A Guide to Fighting</li>
<li>A Potpurri of Proverbs</li>
</ol>
<h3 style="text-align: left;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Recommended Vendor</span></h3>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">&#8211; Yutopian  for <a title="Yutopian Purchase Link for Proverbs" href="https://www.yutopian.com/yutop/cat?product=PAY23&amp;category=PAY">$17.00</a> (S&amp;H included)</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Last updated December 6th, 2012 &#8211; 6 kyu</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1854</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Book Review: Opening Theory Made Easy</title>
		<link>/book-review-opening-theory-made-easy/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2010 13:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good shape]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[opening theory]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[strategy]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=81</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Overall Rating: 5 / 5 Ponnuki Basic Information Title: Opening Theory Made Easy Author: Hitake Odeo, 9 dan Publication Date: October 1992 Page Length: 170 pages Synopsis The best introductory book to opening theory. Concise, easy to read, and easy to carry. Appropriate for 15 kyu and stronger. Recommended for any player with an interest [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2010/10/opening-theory-made-easy-cover.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-1495" alt="opening-theory-made-easy-cover" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2010/10/opening-theory-made-easy-cover.jpg?resize=206%2C288" width="206" height="288" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">Overall Rating: 5 / 5 Ponnuki</h2>
<h3><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Basic Information</span></h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Title: </strong>Opening Theory Made Easy</li>
<li><strong>Author: </strong>Hitake Odeo, 9 dan</li>
<li><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 1992</li>
<li><strong>Page Length: </strong>170 pages</li>
</ul>
<h3 style="text-align: left;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Synopsis</span></h3>
<ul>
<li style="text-align: left;">The best introductory book to opening theory.</li>
<li style="text-align: left;">Concise, easy to read, and easy to carry.</li>
<li style="text-align: left;">Appropriate for 15 kyu and stronger.</li>
<li style="text-align: left;">Recommended for any player with an interest in understanding the opening.</li>
</ul>
<div style="text-align: left;"><span id="more-81"></span></div>
<h3 style="text-align: left;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Detailed Review</span></h3>
<h4 style="text-align: left;">Readability &#8211; 9 / 10</h4>
<p>There are twenty chapters in this book, hence the twenty principles. Hideo does a fantastic job of reviewing basic principles of opening theory while keeping his responses short and concise. This makes it extremely easy to gain lots of exposure to various important concepts so that you can try implementing it in your games instead of being caught up in dense theory that will take ages before you see it appear in your game.</p>
<h4 style="text-align: left;">Content Quality &#8211; 9 / 10</h4>
<p style="text-align: left;">This is a book that delivers on exactly what the title says. Opening theory made easy. As if that wasn&#8217;t enough to get you excited, they have twenty one-line principles to simplify it even further. Every concept is explained within 5-10 pages including diagrams! This might seem short to some, but the key is gaining a solid grasp of the principles so that they appear in your play. The details regarding opening theory will be dealt with when you get to it.</p>
<h4 style="text-align: left;">Conclusion</h4>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Opening Theory Made Easy</span> is what <span style="text-decoration: underline;">In the Beginning</span> should have been. When a new player buys a book that says &#8220;in the beginning&#8221; and is the first volume in an &#8220;elementary&#8221; go series, you&#8217;d think that it would be simple to follow. For those who haven&#8217;t invested in this series, steer clear for now. If you&#8217;ve already purchased it, don&#8217;t worry about it. That book will be a nice book to study after you understand this one.<br />
This will definitely be a classic that I will re-read over and over again. Bravo Otake Hideo. This one will definitely go in the hall of fame in my library of Go books.<br />
In summary though, if you are even remotely interested in the opening theory of the game, this is THE book to buy. It&#8217;s portability and ease of reading will have you blowing through it in no time and learning a lot of crucial principles that will be critical to your growth in the game. Don&#8217;t delay! Buy it now!!!</p>
<h3 style="text-align: left;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Table of Contents</span></h3>
<ol>
<li>Chapter One &#8211; Fuseki Fundamentals
<ol>
<li>Corner enclosures aim at side extensions</li>
<li>Be flexible in deploying from the star-point</li>
<li>Find the right pincer</li>
<li>Have a counterplan to deal with invasions</li>
<li>The 5-4 stone aims at outside influence</li>
<li>The 4th line is the line of development, the 3rd line is the line of completion</li>
<li>Build box-like moyos</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>Chapter Two &#8211; Good Shape
<ol>
<li>Family feuds waste resources</li>
<li>Don&#8217;t permit a hane at the head of your stones</li>
<li>You can never catch up if you push from behind</li>
<li>The empty triangle is bad shape</li>
<li>The ponnuki is worth 30 points</li>
<li>Don&#8217;t atari automatically | Beginners Play Atari</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>Chapter Three &#8211; Strategy
<ol>
<li>Attack the opponent by stealing his base</li>
<li>Don&#8217;t attach against weak stones</li>
<li>Try to kill two birds with one stone</li>
<li>Use thickness to attack</li>
<li>Keep away from solid positions</li>
<li>Reduce a large moyo lightly</li>
<li>Don&#8217;t cling to stones that have served their purpose</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ol>
<h3 style="text-align: left;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Recommended Vendors</span></h3>
<ol>
<li>GoGameGuru &#8211; <a title="GoGameGuru Purchase Link for Opening Theory Made Easy" href="http://shop.gogameguru.com/opening-theory-made-easy/?acc=e4da3b7fbbce2345d7772b0674a318d5">$17.99</a> (S&amp;H not included)</li>
<li>Kiseido &#8211; <a title="Kiseido Purchase Link" href="http://www.kiseido.com/go_books.htm">$18.00</a> (S&amp;H not included)</li>
</ol>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>Last updated October 6th, 2010 &#8211; 15 kyu</em></strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">81</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
