<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>smartgo &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/smartgo/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>Pro Event at the Japanese Embassy</title>
		<link>/pro-event-at-the-japanese-embassy/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2013 21:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kifu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[4p]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[japanese]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[narumi osawa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[professional]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rengo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartgo]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=2299</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[On April 2nd, 2013, I had the honor of being able to attend a professional go event that featured Narumi Osawa (4p) and was hosted by the Japanese Embassy in Washington D.C. It was a free event that consisted of a short talk designed for beginners, a simultaneous game against Narumi, and a lecture/review on [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/04/japanembassy.jpg"><img alt="japanembassy" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/04/japanembassy.jpg?resize=300%2C225" width="300" height="225" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></p>
<p>On April 2nd, 2013, I had the honor of being able to attend a professional go event that featured Narumi Osawa (4p) and was hosted by the Japanese Embassy in Washington D.C. It was a free event that consisted of a short talk designed for beginners, a simultaneous game against Narumi, and a lecture/review on one of the games.<br />
<span id="more-2299"></span><br />
For those who don&#8217;t know Narumi, here is a short biography on her.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/04/narumi-osawa.jpg"><img alt="narumi osawa" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/04/narumi-osawa.jpg?resize=208%2C303" width="208" height="303" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></p>
<ul>
<li>Born in Saitama Prefecture, Japan on May 22nd, 1976.</li>
<li>Became professional 1-dan in 1998, promoted to 2-dan in 1999, 3-dan in 2003, and 4-dan in 2009.</li>
<li>Won the Women’s Kakusei Title（女流鶴聖戦） in 1999 and 2003, and the Women’s JAL Title（JAL女流早碁戦）in 2005.</li>
<li>Participated in the 16th Asian Tournament as a member of the Japanese National Team.</li>
</ul>
<p>Being as the event was in D.C. on a weekday night, I made sure to pad extra time for any possible metro delays or my own inability to find the place. Luckily I did, because even though I arrived about half an hour early, it took me walking into two different buildings before I finally found the Japanese Embassy.<br />
In all honesty, I was a little skeptical as to how many people would be able to attend since it was in D.C. and on a Tuesday. For those who don&#8217;t live in the area, traffic can be crazy when trying to get into the city during rush hour; but I was pleasantly surprised to see that a lot of people showed up! On top of that, there were actually a number of beginners who came as well! It was certainly very uplifting to see so many people attend.<br />
<figure style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/04/japanembassy5.jpg"><img alt="japanembassy5" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/04/japanembassy5.jpg?resize=300%2C225" width="300" height="225" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">As you can see, the place is filled with people!</figcaption></figure>
When the time came to meet Narumi, I was a little more nervous than usual because I knew that she didn&#8217;t speak very much English. Fortunately, there was a translator that helped to facilitate some basic conversation between her and I regarding how strong I was. One of the interesting questions I got from her was what we considered beginners to be in terms of rank. I responded that we considered beginners to be anywhere from 30-20k. As she nodded to acknowledge my statement, I couldn&#8217;t help but be reminded of how most players in Asia probably only recognize dan as an actual rank. Haha.<br />
When it came time for the event to start, we were still short on boards and missing the demonstration board. Narumi was quick on her feet however, and she suggested that the beginners form two teams and she would comment on the game as they played. After a little bit of shuffling around, two teams of five were formed and play began. Here are some photographs from the beginner event:<br />
<figure style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/04/japanembassy2.jpg"><img alt="japanembassy2" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/04/japanembassy2.jpg?resize=300%2C400" width="300" height="400" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">The two kids here are choosing for color.<br />Side Note: It was exciting when we found out that the boy is an elementary student who aspires to be a professional player!</figcaption></figure>
<figure style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/04/japanembassy3.jpg"><img alt="japanembassy3" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/04/japanembassy3.jpg?resize=300%2C225" width="300" height="225" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Each player was permitted 3 moves before letting the next player rotate in.</figcaption></figure>
<figure style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/04/japanembassy4.jpg"><img alt="japanembassy4" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/04/japanembassy4.jpg?resize=300%2C225" width="300" height="225" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Narumi Osawa (4p) explaining a concept to the audience.</figcaption></figure>
<p style="text-align: left;">Afterwards, in order to try and accommodate the number of players, Narumi thought it would be best to have people play rengo (e.g, pair go) against her. So without hesitation, I asked my friend Gurujeet to join me in the battle to try and survive against a professional. As neither Gurujeet nor I have played much pair go, it was approached with fun and adventure as we played a game that was not necessarily our best, but certainly yielded a rather interesting game. =)</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Due to time constraints and the need to move on to the next part of the event, we were unable to finish the game in its entirety. (Although in all honesty, both Gurujeet and I were already preparing to say &#8220;I resign&#8221; in Japanese anyways. xD) To my surprise however, Narumi wanted me show our game on the demonstration board for her commentary. Needless to say, I was happy to do so (and silently thanking SmartGo again for always being there in my time of need for a solid kifu app).</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">When I got up on the stage, it felt a little surreal to think that I was the person helping the professional put stones on the demonstration board. I mean, I&#8217;ve seen it on videos a ton of times, but to actually be the one doing it! So cool! And to top it all off, it was my game as well!</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">As I stood up there listening to Narumi explain various aspects of our game in Japanese, for the first time ever, I felt go transcend the language barrier. I know that sounds really odd, but even though I have practically no knowledge of Japanese, I felt as if I could understand the core concept of each of her messages as she spoke and moved stones around. Call me crazy, but it was an incredible experience.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">The following is the game record from that night with any commentary from Narumi clearly marked.</p>

<div id='glift_display1' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display1","sgf":"http:\/\/bengozen.com\/\/wp-content\/uploads\/2013\/04\/2013.04.04-Pro-Event-at-the-Japanese-Embassy.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='//wp-content/uploads/2013/04/2013.04.04-Pro-Event-at-the-Japanese-Embassy.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">[download label=&#8221;Download Kifu&#8221;]//wp-content/uploads/2013/04/2013.04.04-Pro-Event-at-the-Japanese-Embassy.sgf[/download]
<p style="text-align: left;">Well, with that night, I have played a go pro from each of the major countries: Korea, China, Japan, and Taiwan! Woot! Now onwards to grow my collection of pro games!</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2299</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>North American Go Convention &#8211; Day 4</title>
		<link>/north-american-go-convention-day-4/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2013 22:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kifu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[9p]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[james]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[myung wan kim]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nagc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[north american go convention]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartgo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tournament]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=1932</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Introduction &#8212; Day 1 &#8212; Day 2 &#8212; Day 3 &#8212; Day 4 &#8212; Day 5 &#8212; Conclusion For Day 4, I had the honor of having my mom come and join me for the day! She just learned the rules recently and I was excited when she told me that she wanted to come to [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><a title="North American Go Convention!!!" href="//north-american-go-convention/">Introduction</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 1" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-1/">Day 1</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 2" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-2/">Day 2</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 3" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-3/">Day 3</a> &#8212; <strong>Day 4</strong> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 5" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-5/">Day 5</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Conclusion" href="//north-american-go-convention-conclusion/">Conclusion</a></p>
<p><em>For Day 4, I had the honor of having my mom come and join me for the day! She just learned the rules recently and I was excited when she told me that she wanted to come to an all day go convention!! Woot!!</em><br />
When we arrived at the convention, I was pleasantly surprised to see a lot of people at the registration room. As we settled down, I heard an announcement that everyone needed to check in if they wanted to compete. At the time, I was rather split as to what to do. On one hand, I wasn&#8217;t sure what the schedule for the professional events (i.e. lectures, simul games, reviews) was. In addition, I wasn&#8217;t sure I was okay with the idea of my mom sitting around for hours on end watching me play games when she was still so new to the game.<br />
Once registration was finished, I thought it would be a good idea to show my mom what competitive go looks like. Upon our arrival upstairs, we found them posting up the pairings for the first round. For some reason, I had a feeling that I might have been included even though I did not check in. Sure enough, I found my name after a quick glance at the list.<br />
<span id="more-1932"></span><br />
Shortly afterwards, I noticed that they posted up the schedule for the day and saw that the professional events had been scheduled at the end of Round 1 and 3. To clarify though, I do not mean that the events were scheduled after the rounds were over. In fact, they were scheduled at the tail end of the round time which meant that if I wanted to attend a pro event, I would face one of two situations: (1) I play in every round, but I&#8217;m forced to rush and hope that the game ends before the event. (2) I play every round, but end up resigning most of my games since I like to take my time with each move anyways.<br />
As I stood there trying to figure out what to do, my opponent found me. After panicking for a moment, I quickly found the tournament director and tried to tell him that I was not going to be playing (at least in the first round). Coincidentally, a fellow go player who was around our level had shown up late and so I tried to get the director to make a swap since it would keep the pairings equal. There was a bit of resistance at first, and it took quite a bit of back and forth before  they resolved the situation amongst themselves.<br />
In my defense though, I never checked in as they told us to do in order to be paired, so why would should I expect to be included? Not to mention, I was not in the mood to showing my mom a rushed game where I don&#8217;t play my best. And if that weren&#8217;t enough, I would probably end up resigning all my games since the pro events were during the rounds. So why make the day extra stressful and draining? No thank you.<br />
While we waited for the simul game with Myung to start, my mom and I had the pleasure of chatting with a local player (by the name of Mr. Choi) who was a director of some sort at a local Korean Baduk club. We found out that he was a 7 dan amateur who had won numerous competition in the United States before and enjoyed teaching go. In fact, we seemed to get along so well that he even started a teaching game with me. Haha.<br />
We only got a few moves into the game before it was time to start the simul game though. And before I knew it, I was sitting once again before Myung as I placed 9 stones on the board. With a renewed spirit from my defeat on <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 3" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-3/">Day 3</a>, it was time to try again! Ikuzo!<br />

<div id='glift_display2' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display2","sgf":"http:\/\/bengozen.com\/\/wp-content\/uploads\/2013\/02\/2013.02.20-NAGC-Day-4.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='//wp-content/uploads/2013/02/2013.02.20-NAGC-Day-4.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">[download label=&#8221;Download Kifu&#8221;]//wp-content/uploads/2013/02/2013.02.20-NAGC-Day-4.sgf[/download]
<p>Once the game was over, Mr. Choi, Myung, my mom and I went out to grab lunch at <a href="http://www.yelp.com/biz/el-pollo-rico-arlington">El Pollo Ricco</a> and had a delicious lunch!<br />
<figure id="attachment_1973" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/02/elpolloricco.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1973" alt="elpolloricco" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/02/elpolloricco.jpg?resize=300%2C225" width="300" height="225" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Credit to Yelp (Andrew C.)</figcaption></figure>
<p style="text-align: left;">Afterwards, we drove Myung back to the hotel so he could rest for the afternoon. Since we were going to pick him up later on and there were no pro events for the rest of the afternoon, my mom and I just went to a nearby mall to hangout. While it was a detour from the &#8220;all-day go convention,&#8221; we had some great conversation and the thought that I could be at the go convention instead never crossed my mind.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Later on that day, after picking Myung and James up, I found myself sitting in my first professional lecture. Myung was giving a lecture on the final game between Lee sedol and Gu Li in the recent Samsung Cup. Even though we were only able to really spend time on the opening (and a little bit of endgame), it was a really interesting review that definitely opened my eyes to some new ideas. I&#8217;ll be sure to write more about them when I&#8217;ve managed to digest them and can write them in a comprehensible fashion. One thing I can say for sure though, is that my appreciation for pro lectures has definitely grown since then!</p>
<p>With the day coming to an end, I thought that it would be a good idea to take Myung and James out to a local Vietnamese restaurant that we love called <a href="http://www.yelp.com/biz/viet-royale-falls-church">Viet Royale</a> (FYI. The Yelp reviews do not do the restaurant justice. I don&#8217;t think people know what to order. =D). I wish I had taken pictures of all the food we ordered, but it is suffice to say that it was full of delicious food and great conversation.<br />
<figure id="attachment_1975" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/02/pho.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1975" alt="Credit to Yelp (Ruth C.)" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/02/pho.jpg?resize=300%2C225" width="300" height="225" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Credit to Yelp (Ruth C.)</figcaption></figure>
All in all, it was a fantastic day full of great company and great memories. Here&#8217;s to hoping that Day 5 will live up to even 50% of it!</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a title="North American Go Convention!!!" href="//north-american-go-convention/">Introduction</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 1" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-1/">Day 1</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 2" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-2/">Day 2</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 3" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-3/">Day 3</a> &#8212; <strong>Day 4</strong> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 5" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-5/">Day 5</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Conclusion" href="//north-american-go-convention-conclusion/">Conclusion</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1932</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>North American Go Convention &#8211; Day 2</title>
		<link>/north-american-go-convention-day-2/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2013 22:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kifu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[6p]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[9p]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[joanne missingham]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[myung wan kim]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nagc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[professional review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartgo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tournament]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=1915</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Introduction &#8212; Day 1 &#8212; Day 2 &#8212; Day 3 &#8212; Day 4 &#8212; Day 5 &#8212; Conclusion Although the weather was much nicer this time around, it seems the fates were conspiring against me as I spent a good twenty minutes stuck in traffic due to an accident. Fortunately for me, I had left early [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><a title="North American Go Convention!!!" href="//north-american-go-convention/">Introduction</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 1" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-1/">Day 1</a> &#8212; <strong>Day 2</strong> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 3" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-3/">Day 3</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 4" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-4/">Day 4</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 5" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-5/">Day 5</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Conclusion" href="//north-american-go-convention-conclusion/">Conclusion</a></p>
<p>Although the weather was much nicer this time around, it seems the fates were conspiring against me as I spent a good twenty minutes stuck in traffic due to an accident. Fortunately for me, I had left early enough that the delay was not going to make me incredibly late. On top of that, based on my experience yesterday, I didn&#8217;t have good reason to believe that arriving late would cause me to miss anything nor should I have worried that a huge crowd of people would suddenly appear on a Thursday night. Nonetheless, I still couldn&#8217;t help but feel anxious that I would arrive to find that the teaching/simultaneous games had started or were full.<br />
By the time I parked my car, it was about 3 minutes prior to 7pm. I rushed into the building fully expecting to grab the first elevator and make it there just on time. Lo and behold, what do I see when I walk in the lobby? The elevators are being maintained. In case you&#8217;re not getting the full effect of what I felt, remember that the convention is on the 9th floor. (-.-)<br />
Next thing I know, I&#8217;m bolting up 9 flights (although more like 18 since they were two flights per level) of stairs in a rush to get there on time. And when I finally make it up to the 9th floor, I am crestfallen as I look around and fail to see anyone around. The room that was setup for go lecture was full of employees holding a meeting, and the room where the we played our simul game yesterday was completely covered up.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">&#8220;CRAP. Did I miss the memo about it getting cancelled or the address moving?!?!?!&#8221;</p>
<p><span id="more-1915"></span><br />
Panic mode started to set in as I thought back to the fact I just rushed up all those stairs and might actually be in the wrong place. Gah!!! After a couple of calls in hopes of getting in contact with someone (which were all failures), I stood around a bit helpless and frustrated as I thought I had missed something. Fortunately, I did not leave in a big rush because I see someone who looks like they are associated with the convention walking around and he lets me in (the doors to the office are locked from the elevator lobby).<br />
When I&#8217;m outside the go room, I find out that Joanne Missingham is being interviewed (by a group that I cannot remember right now). I breathed the biggest sigh of relief as I realized that I had not missed anything and that nothing was cancelled. Since it didn&#8217;t seem like anyone was there yet, I sat outside in the hall listening to music and practicing some easy tsumego problems. After 20 minutes or so, I notice that some of the staff are looking for an overflow room in case a lot of people show up. They never come back to the interview area, so I figure that they must have found it.<br />
I walk around and end up finding everyone sitting in the waiting area enjoying iced tea. I hesitated for a moment before joining them, but realized that it was probably in my best interest to wait with them since they will be the first to find out if anything is starting. To my great surprise, the next thing I know I am being introduced to Myung Wan Kim (9P) and his friend James.<br />
<figure id="attachment_1922" style="width: 241px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/02/MyungwanKim.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1922" alt="Myung Wan Kim (9P)" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/02/MyungwanKim.jpg?resize=241%2C300" width="241" height="300" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Myung Wan Kim (9P)</figcaption></figure>
After the basic introductions and finding out I was 6 kyu, Myung asked me if I had a game for him to review. I was a bit taken aback at first since I did not expect such an incredible opportunity, but told him I did and started getting my iPad out. In the middle of getting my iPad however, the conversation somehow turned into wondering if we could play on my iPad. And without missing a beat I responded, &#8220;Of course!&#8221; (Thank you SmartGo Kifu!!!!!) Myung then suggested that I play with James and then he would review the game afterwards. Words cannot describe how excited I was to hear him suggest that.<br />
We were about 11 moves in when we were interrupted and asked if we would be willing to play with Joanne. The interviewers wanted to get some footage of Joanne playing amateurs. Play with Joanne? Possibly be part of some interview footage? Yes please!<br />
In a whirlwind change of events, I suddenly find myself in front of Joanne once again. Earlier in the day, I thought that I might ask if it would be okay to play an even game with her since I wanted to see how she would play under non-handicap circumstances. With the video recording and all though, I thought it best just to play at 4 stones again. Below is a partial record of the game since I thought the game was more for show than for a serious game, so this was the best I could do with the recreation in the midst of all the craziness.<br />

<div id='glift_display3' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display3","sgf":"http:\/\/bengozen.com\/\/wp-content\/uploads\/2013\/02\/2013.02.15-NAGC-Day-2.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='//wp-content/uploads/2013/02/2013.02.15-NAGC-Day-2.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">[download label=&#8221;Download Kifu&#8221;]//wp-content/uploads/2013/02/2013.02.15-NAGC-Day-2.sgf[/download]
<p>We got a little further than my record, but the game was ended prematurely in order to allow the interviewers to get other footage.<br />
As everyone took a break and went off to get a drink and such, I stood around wondering what would happen next. After all, it seemed that Joanne was rather busy with the interview and was clearly in high demand. A tournament was out of the question since I was one of two local players who came. So, what would happen the rest of the night?<br />
Before I could think too much about it though, Myung and James walked over to where I was standing and Myung asked if I would like to review the game I mentioned earlier. Um&#8230; YES!!!! (And I should mention that being able to tether my iPad to my phone so I could download SGF files from the KGS Archives was a 1000% win!)<br />
For my first professionally reviewed game, the best way I can summarize it is to say that I was absolutely blown away. Myung&#8217;s review and insight into various aspects of the game were so eye opening and revealing. I wish there was a way for me to capture everything onto an SGF, but so much of what I was told involved conceptual gaps that I still haven&#8217;t quite come to terms with. When I do though, I promise that I will make it my first priority to write an article on it.<br />
As someone who has had his games reviewed a number of times, I had forgotten what it was like to have a game reviewed in person. It&#8217;s really a completely different atmosphere. Although much of the credit is due to Myung&#8217;s ability to teach and illustrate his points clearly, I do think that reviews flow much better in person. Not only can Myung use my facial expressions to determine whether or not I&#8217;m understanding something, a real board makes it very easy to switch out positions and show why one is better than another. Maybe it&#8217;s just me or the fact that Myung was reviewing my game, but the game review just felt extremely effective.<br />
Although the night was rather uneventful in the sense that I was the only person there, the time that I got to spend talking and learning with Myung and James was invaluable and has already made the convention incredibly worthwhile. Definitely looking forward to tonight!</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a title="North American Go Convention!!!" href="//north-american-go-convention/">Introduction</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 1" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-1/">Day 1</a> &#8212; <strong>Day 2</strong> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 3" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-3/">Day 3</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 4" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-4/">Day 4</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 5" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-5/">Day 5</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Conclusion" href="//north-american-go-convention-conclusion/">Conclusion</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1915</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
