<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"

	>
<channel>
	<title>Comments on: Monday Go Meditation: Game 51</title>
	<atom:link href="/monday-go-meditation-game-51/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/monday-go-meditation-game-51/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2015 12:34:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
	<item>
		<title>By: Nate Eagle</title>
		<link>/monday-go-meditation-game-51/#comment-1802</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nate Eagle]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2014 14:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=4884#comment-1802</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Thanks for the response and for the review - it&#039;s fun to get so much reflection on our game. And congratulations on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.usgo.org/news/2014/04/kyu-review-of-lee-gu-jubango-game-3-posted/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;the shout-out from the E-Journal&lt;/a&gt;!]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Thanks for the response and for the review &#8211; it&#8217;s fun to get so much reflection on our game. And congratulations on <a href="http://www.usgo.org/news/2014/04/kyu-review-of-lee-gu-jubango-game-3-posted/" rel="nofollow">the shout-out from the E-Journal</a>!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Ben</title>
		<link>/monday-go-meditation-game-51/#comment-1801</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ben]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2014 14:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=4884#comment-1801</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[First, before I start on my journey to respond to your comment, I want to thank you for such a thorough and informative response. With that said, let me get started:
Move 4 - I&#039;m glad to have you clear that up. I think at the time, I was thinking that you had had one too many traumatic experiences with my getting a huge moyo that you preferred to just stop it from the get go. But I think your point about White being confident with interrupting Black&#039;s flow of play is completely valid and great. Something I&#039;ll have to keep in mind for myself!
Move 95 - Wow. I didn&#039;t even consider that I could connect with the counter atari, but often verification I could have. Haha. How silly of me! Thanks for pointing that out!
Move 138 - Yeah that move was rather frustrating for me at the time. Seeing my shapes get exploited so easily after getting 3 extra moves than you in that area felt like an attack on my pride. Haha. But lately I&#039;ve been thinking about things like that, and it was foolish for me to feel so frustrated. Haha.
Though it seems like such an obvious thing, I have to say that until your statement, I didn&#039;t realize how important emotional states play into the decision in making a move. When I&#039;ve been reviewing the games lately, I&#039;ve gotten into this habit of just making objective observations most of the time, but I think it&#039;s time I start incorporating my emotions in each move to really give more context to everything. Thanks for that suggestion!
Thanks again for the great feedback and for the game as well! I certainly look forward to our next one and hope that I will be able to play with fewer mistakes as well, win or lose.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>First, before I start on my journey to respond to your comment, I want to thank you for such a thorough and informative response. With that said, let me get started:<br />
Move 4 &#8211; I&#8217;m glad to have you clear that up. I think at the time, I was thinking that you had had one too many traumatic experiences with my getting a huge moyo that you preferred to just stop it from the get go. But I think your point about White being confident with interrupting Black&#8217;s flow of play is completely valid and great. Something I&#8217;ll have to keep in mind for myself!<br />
Move 95 &#8211; Wow. I didn&#8217;t even consider that I could connect with the counter atari, but often verification I could have. Haha. How silly of me! Thanks for pointing that out!<br />
Move 138 &#8211; Yeah that move was rather frustrating for me at the time. Seeing my shapes get exploited so easily after getting 3 extra moves than you in that area felt like an attack on my pride. Haha. But lately I&#8217;ve been thinking about things like that, and it was foolish for me to feel so frustrated. Haha.<br />
Though it seems like such an obvious thing, I have to say that until your statement, I didn&#8217;t realize how important emotional states play into the decision in making a move. When I&#8217;ve been reviewing the games lately, I&#8217;ve gotten into this habit of just making objective observations most of the time, but I think it&#8217;s time I start incorporating my emotions in each move to really give more context to everything. Thanks for that suggestion!<br />
Thanks again for the great feedback and for the game as well! I certainly look forward to our next one and hope that I will be able to play with fewer mistakes as well, win or lose.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Nate Eagle</title>
		<link>/monday-go-meditation-game-51/#comment-1800</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nate Eagle]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2014 13:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=4884#comment-1800</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I went over this game in my most recent lesson with Shifu (http://zhouyuan.com)./ I keep meaning to put as much of his commentary as I can remember in a game record, but then I do something else instead.
Move 4. &quot;I guess Nate must dislike having to deal with that fuseki as White, so he immediately approached here.&quot; It&#039;s not just a dislike of the fuseki, it&#039;s a preference for complicating the game early and pushing both white and black into unfamiliar ground. Part of black&#039;s advantage in going first is the chance to guide the game: I like disrupting that. It also is a way to assert your confidence as white, something that I find valuable. Recently I&#039;ve been approaching with move 4 as white against everything but nirensei. Your move five in response is a strong one.
My invasion at move 30 was too deep, and it was unnecessary. It&#039;s an unwelcome resurgence of jealous play. The only reason I thought it was viable was because that is the vital point against a shimari, with miai of attachments on either side, but you had too much support on the outside. Once I died, black was unquestionably in a winning position, but Shifu did allow, &quot;The one good thing you could say about it is that white died inside black&#039;s framework - it&#039;s territory black should have ultimately gotten anyway.&quot; I was so frustrated at dying that early and that foolishly that I determined immediately to force as many important kos as I could. (Something I&#039;m not used to doing.)
The three ko threats at the bottom, starting with move 85, were absolutely the biggest mistakes for black. I had nothing left to lose - I didn&#039;t spend a second thinking about whether to respond. In those situations, you have to use local ko threats, which you had available.
Move 95 was a mistake, I think - you could have just played at N17 to connect. It&#039;s not easy to find a way for white to live underneath black&#039;s then-connected shape, either.
Move 114 was a huge mistake for me. Black should win the capturing race, at that point. I needed to descend to H19 to remove an invisible liberty on the side. Also, good job for spotting in the review that you could have won the capturing race if you ignored the throw-in.
Move 138 is the move I&#039;m proudest of - instead of just running, it finds the one vulnerable spot in black&#039;s position to fight back. We both made a bunch of mistakes after that, but we both found good moves, too. At move 166, I should have threatened first at O9, then connected at O11.
Anyway - the best Shifu would say for me is that it was good to see the ways I made chances, as it&#039;s an essential part of getting stronger. As we get stronger, our opponents won&#039;t offer us so many easy chances to come from behind, and we have to learn to hunt for them. I think it&#039;s helpful the way you show the way emotion influences our moves in your review - that&#039;s a huge part of go, and it&#039;s something I struggle with a lot.
Thanks for the review and thanks for the game! I hope in our next game I can play with fewer mistakes, whether I win or not.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I went over this game in my most recent lesson with Shifu (<a href="http://zhouyuan.com/" rel="nofollow">http://zhouyuan.com/</a>). I keep meaning to put as much of his commentary as I can remember in a game record, but then I do something else instead.<br />
Move 4. &#8220;I guess Nate must dislike having to deal with that fuseki as White, so he immediately approached here.&#8221; It&#8217;s not just a dislike of the fuseki, it&#8217;s a preference for complicating the game early and pushing both white and black into unfamiliar ground. Part of black&#8217;s advantage in going first is the chance to guide the game: I like disrupting that. It also is a way to assert your confidence as white, something that I find valuable. Recently I&#8217;ve been approaching with move 4 as white against everything but nirensei. Your move five in response is a strong one.<br />
My invasion at move 30 was too deep, and it was unnecessary. It&#8217;s an unwelcome resurgence of jealous play. The only reason I thought it was viable was because that is the vital point against a shimari, with miai of attachments on either side, but you had too much support on the outside. Once I died, black was unquestionably in a winning position, but Shifu did allow, &#8220;The one good thing you could say about it is that white died inside black&#8217;s framework &#8211; it&#8217;s territory black should have ultimately gotten anyway.&#8221; I was so frustrated at dying that early and that foolishly that I determined immediately to force as many important kos as I could. (Something I&#8217;m not used to doing.)<br />
The three ko threats at the bottom, starting with move 85, were absolutely the biggest mistakes for black. I had nothing left to lose &#8211; I didn&#8217;t spend a second thinking about whether to respond. In those situations, you have to use local ko threats, which you had available.<br />
Move 95 was a mistake, I think &#8211; you could have just played at N17 to connect. It&#8217;s not easy to find a way for white to live underneath black&#8217;s then-connected shape, either.<br />
Move 114 was a huge mistake for me. Black should win the capturing race, at that point. I needed to descend to H19 to remove an invisible liberty on the side. Also, good job for spotting in the review that you could have won the capturing race if you ignored the throw-in.<br />
Move 138 is the move I&#8217;m proudest of &#8211; instead of just running, it finds the one vulnerable spot in black&#8217;s position to fight back. We both made a bunch of mistakes after that, but we both found good moves, too. At move 166, I should have threatened first at O9, then connected at O11.<br />
Anyway &#8211; the best Shifu would say for me is that it was good to see the ways I made chances, as it&#8217;s an essential part of getting stronger. As we get stronger, our opponents won&#8217;t offer us so many easy chances to come from behind, and we have to learn to hunt for them. I think it&#8217;s helpful the way you show the way emotion influences our moves in your review &#8211; that&#8217;s a huge part of go, and it&#8217;s something I struggle with a lot.<br />
Thanks for the review and thanks for the game! I hope in our next game I can play with fewer mistakes, whether I win or not.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
</channel>
</rss>
