<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>sword &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/sword/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>Shattered Blade</title>
		<link>/shattered-blade/</link>
		<comments>/shattered-blade/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2013 21:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blade]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[broken]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reforge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[starting over]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sword]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weak attacks]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=3740</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Over the weekend, I have been giving a lot of thought to some insight that I received recently from my friend moboy78.  I am paraphrasing a bit, but the bottom line message I remember was: Your attacks are just awful. How do you expect to win any games with those sorry excuses you call attacks? [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/08/narsil_shards.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3741" alt="narsil_shards" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/08/narsil_shards.jpg?resize=349%2C190" width="349" height="190" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a>Over the weekend, I have been giving a lot of thought to some insight that I received recently from my friend moboy78.  I am paraphrasing a bit, but the bottom line message I remember was:</p>
<blockquote><p>Your attacks are just awful. How do you expect to win any games with those sorry excuses you call attacks?</p></blockquote>
<p>I must admit that since I always thought I was more of a fighter and power type of player, this was a bit of a shock to me. After all, up until this point, I always thought that I simply had misguided attacks that were strong while lacking in precise and accurate movements. In reality though, I may have been entirely delusional.<br />
While there have been times where I have scared my opponents into running for their lives, I actually realized that these &#8220;successful attacks&#8221; were more like &#8220;paranoid delusional chasing.&#8221; In other words, I used to think that I was brandishing a magnificent blade as I chased down my opponents. As I look down at my blade now, I realized that it was shattered long ago and all that&#8217;s left is the hilt. In the few times I successfully struck down my opponents, I guess I was just lucky that my opponents were paranoid and thought my blade was longer and more dangerous than it actually was.<br />
But no longer do I wish to win by brandishing an imaginary blade against a paranoid opponent. I want my attacks to come forth with unspeakable fury and to be able to slice my opponent in two if they are not careful. With that said, it is high time I return to the forge to rebuild my sword. Let&#8217;s the forging process begin!<br />
**Edit: In case it wasn&#8217;t clear, I&#8217;m not mad or upset in any way at moboy78. What he told me was a valued wake up call that I know I will look back and always be thankful to him for. =D</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/shattered-blade/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3740</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
