<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>kageyama &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/kageyama/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>Returning to the Fundamentals</title>
		<link>/returning-fundamentals/</link>
		<comments>/returning-fundamentals/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2014 11:15:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Weekly Go Wednesday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[building blocks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[directionless]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fundamentals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kageyama]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lessons in the fundamentals of go]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5442</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Weekly Go Wednesday, Issue #44 Up until a month or so ago, my go had become quite rigid. In fact, it could be compared to an ice sculpture where the curves and angles have all been predefined. And though it is admirable in one aspect, it also represents a sense of rigidity and does not [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 style="text-align: center;">Weekly Go Wednesday, Issue #44</h2>
<figure id="attachment_5444" style="width: 488px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/06/wgw44.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-5444" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/06/wgw44.jpg?resize=488%2C299" alt="Credit to TheChangeBlog" width="488" height="299" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Credit to <a title="Source for featured image" href="http://www.thechangeblog.com/success-in-life/">TheChangeBlog</a></figcaption></figure>
Up until a month or so ago, my go had become quite rigid. In fact, it could be compared to an ice sculpture where the curves and angles have all been predefined. And though it is admirable in one aspect, it also represents a sense of rigidity and does not have much room for growth. And since my goal was to build something way better, it was only natural that it was time to set it on fire and let it melt away. And now that I am left with this pool of water, while the prospect of building a grand ice sculpture sounds great, it&#8217;s been rather difficult figuring out where to begin.<br />
For those who don&#8217;t use <a title="BenGoZen's Twitter" href="http://www.twitter.com/bengozen">Twitter</a>, I recently tweeted about picking up <a title="Book Review: Lessons in the Fundamentals of Go" href="//book-review-lessons-in-the-fundamentals-of-go/"><em>Lessons in the Fundamentals of Go</em></a> by Kageyama 7P again. You might wonder why I&#8217;m doing this. After all, I&#8217;ve read this book at least four or five times at this point. However, I&#8217;ve noticed that my progress in go has reached a vulnerable stage. It&#8217;s not stagnant, yet it is not necessarily progressing either in the traditional sense of climbing ranks. Instead of complaining and being frustrated however, I&#8217;ve decided that this is as good a time as any to return to the fundamentals.<br />
<span id="more-5442"></span><br />
I am currently at a place where my go feels directionless, so I have been trying to establish some new foundations through standard training exercises: life and death problems, studying the <a title="Book Review: Jump Level Up 1" href="//book-review-jump-level-1/">Jump Level Up</a> series, replaying Go Seigen&#8217;s games, and playing games as well. While all those activities will surely benefit me somehow in the future, my go felt as shapeless as ever. And since I don&#8217;t have a true teacher and mentor (in terms of taking private lessons), I was rather lost in terms of what to do next.<br />
As I was perusing my bookshelf and picking up book after book (i.e., The Basics of Go Strategy, Positional Judgment, etc.), the bright yellow binding caught my eye and I breathed a sigh of relief as it hit me. <strong>Just go back to the fundamentals.</strong><br />
It&#8217;s true that having a teacher would make my life a lot easier. After all, he/she would know me so well that devising a customized training program would be a piece of cake. However, for the numerous players out there who either haven&#8217;t found a teacher or it is too expensive, I wrote this post to remind you that there is still hope out there for people like us.<br />
While gaining a stone becomes harder as you climb the ladder, remember that it only becomes truly difficult as you climb into the higher ranks of dan. Until then, remember that a lot of our weaknesses can be found in our lack of the fundamentals. And if there is anyone who can give you a swift kick in the butt to remind you of that, it is Kageyama.<br />
So if you&#8217;re serious about getting stronger at go, make sure you have a copy of <em><a title="Book Review: Lessons in the Fundamentals of Go" href="//book-review-lessons-in-the-fundamentals-of-go/">Lessons in the Fundamentals of Go</a> </em>in your collection of go books. It will be your beacon of light as you try and make your way into the dan levels and above.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/returning-fundamentals/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>17</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">5442</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Book Review: Kage&#039;s Secret Chronicles of Handicap Go</title>
		<link>/book-review-kages-secret-chronicles-of-handicap-go/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2013 21:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[handicap go]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kageyama]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=2784</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Overall Rating: 8 / 10 Ponnuki Basic Information Title: Kage&#8217;s Secret Chronicles of Handicap Go Author: Toshiro Kageyama, 6-dan (translated by James Davies) Publisher: The Ishi Press, Inc. Publication Date: October 1975 Page Length: 204 pages Synopsis An entertaining book from Kageyama that illustrates handicap go concepts through a conversational style of writing. Does not explain handicap go from [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/05/kschgcover.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-2785" alt="kschgcover" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/05/kschgcover.jpg?resize=210%2C337" width="210" height="337" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></h2>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">Overall Rating: 8 / 10 Ponnuki</h2>
<h3>Basic Information</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Title:</strong> Kage&#8217;s Secret Chronicles of Handicap Go</li>
<li><strong>Author: </strong>Toshiro Kageyama, 6-dan (translated by James Davies)</li>
<li><strong>Publisher: </strong>The Ishi Press, Inc.</li>
<li><strong>Publication Date: </strong>October 1975</li>
<li><strong>Page Length:</strong> 204 pages</li>
</ul>
<h3>Synopsis</h3>
<ul>
<li>An entertaining book from Kageyama that illustrates handicap go concepts through a conversational style of writing.</li>
<li>Does not explain handicap go from a traditional textbook like style.</li>
<li>Appropriate for 5 kyu and stronger.</li>
<li>Recommended for serious players who already have a foundation on handicap go.</li>
</ul>
<p><span id="more-2784"></span></p>
<h3>What I Expected</h3>
<ul>
<li><span style="line-height: 13px;">A format similar to <a title="Book Review: Lessons in the Fundamentals of Go" href="//book-review-lessons-in-the-fundamentals-of-go/">Lessons in the Fundamentals of Go</a> except for handicap go.</span></li>
<li>To gain a better understanding of how handicap go should be played from both White and Black&#8217;s perspective.</li>
<li>A thorough explanation of different concepts in handicap go.</li>
</ul>
<h3>What You Can Expect</h3>
<ul>
<li>The format of the book consists more of Kageyama&#8217;s conversations during handicap games and some of his thoughts on the position at hand.</li>
<li>Tidbits of wisdom and advice are hidden among the conversation, but it is not as apparent as one would see from a textbook style book.</li>
<li>Multiple choice questions about where the reader thinks the player in question should play next along with explanations as to why each answer is wrong or right.</li>
</ul>
<h3>My Thoughts as a 5 Kyu</h3>
<p>Although this book was not quite what I expected, this book has two shining qualities:</p>
<ol>
<li><span style="line-height: 13px;">Kageyama&#8217;s entertaining writing and thoughts.</span></li>
<li>The multiple choice questions embedded throughout the games.</li>
</ol>
<p>To no one&#8217;s surprise, Kageyama&#8217;s writing continues to entertain and provide a very easy read for just about anyone who understands go terminology. The only unfortunate aspect is that the book is not structured in a topic format similar to <a title="Book Review: Lessons in the Fundamentals of Go" href="//book-review-lessons-in-the-fundamentals-of-go/">Lessons in the Fundamentals of Go</a>. If it was, this book would probably be another the holy grail of handicap go information.<br />
For the multiple choice questions, even though some might view the questions as a sort of tsumego, the questions felt a lot more like a teacher asking the student where he/she would play and then explaining why each option is better or worse than the others. And to be honest, now that I&#8217;ve been exposed to this style of question, I wish that other tsumego books would follow a similar format since it makes each learning point much more organic and easier to understand.<br />
Finally, since this book is rather difficult to find, I would advise that you not spend a lot of money trying to obtain it unless you are a collector of some sorts. It&#8217;s a great book to have in your collection, but the content is not so earth shattering that you absolutely need to have this book in order to further your understanding of handicap go.<br />
<em>Note: As some of you might have noticed, the appropriate rank is higher than normal. The reason for this is because the conversation writing style yields a rather high level and abstract discussion of the game that most beginner players would probably find bewildering. And since the last thing I want is for you to spend your limited time on something you&#8217;ll find difficult to understand, I chose to recommend it at a higher rank then normal.</em></p>
<h3>Table of Content</h3>
<ol>
<li>Introduction</li>
<li>Five-Stone Game
<ol>
<li>Game 1 &#8211; Koichi Yokoyhama, 5-dan (White) v. Toshiro Kageyama, 6-dan (Black)</li>
<li>Game 2 &#8211; Koichi Yokoyhama, 5-dan (White) v. Toshiro Kageyama, 6-dan (Black)</li>
<li>Game 3 &#8211; Koichi Yokoyhama, 5-dan (White) v. Kenji Nakano, 3-dan (amateur) (Black)</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>Four-Stone Games
<ol>
<li>Game 1 &#8211; Toshiro Kageyama, 6-dan (White) v. Koichi Yokohama, 5-dan (Black)</li>
<li>Common Sense Classroom</li>
<li>Game 2 &#8211; Toshiro Kageyama, 6-dan (White) v. Koichi Yokohama, 5-dan (Black)</li>
<li>Game 3 &#8211; Koichi Yokoyhama, 5-dan (White) v. Yoshio Suzuki, 4-dan (amateur) (Black)</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>Three-Stone Games
<ol>
<li>Game 1 &#8211; Toshiro Kageyama, 6-dan (White) v. Koichi Yokohama, 5-dan (Black)</li>
<li>Game 2 &#8211; Koichi Yokoyhama, 5-dan (White) v. Bin Suzuki, 5-dan (amateur) (Black)</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>Two-Stone Game
<ol>
<li>Game 1 &#8211; Koichi Yokoyhama, 5-dan (White) v. Toshiro Kageyama, 6-dan (Black)</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ol>
<h3>Recommended Vendors:</h3>
<ol>
<li>Out of Print</li>
</ol>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Last updated June 5th, 2013</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2784</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Book Review: Lessons in the Fundamentals of Go</title>
		<link>/book-review-lessons-in-the-fundamentals-of-go/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2013 14:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[basics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fundamentals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[getting stronger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kageyama]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lessons]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shape]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tesuji]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=1393</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Overall Rating: 5 / 5 Ponnuki Basic Information Title: Lessons in the Fundamentals of Go Author: Toshiro Kageyama 7-dan Translator: James Davies Publisher: Kiseido Publication Date: May 1978 Page Length: 272 pages Synopsis A hybrid of theoretical/conceptual explanations along with problems to illustrate the ideas. While may seem advance, Kageyama&#8217;s personality really shines through and makes [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/03/lessonsinthefundamentalsofgocover.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2181" alt="lessonsinthefundamentalsofgocover" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/03/lessonsinthefundamentalsofgocover.jpg?resize=248%2C400" width="248" height="400" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></h2>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">Overall Rating: 5 / 5 Ponnuki</h2>
<h3>Basic Information</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Title:</strong> Lessons in the Fundamentals of Go</li>
<li><strong>Author: </strong>Toshiro Kageyama 7-dan</li>
<li><strong>Translator:</strong> James Davies</li>
<li><strong>Publisher: </strong>Kiseido</li>
<li><strong>Publication Date: </strong>May 1978</li>
<li><strong>Page Length:</strong> 272 pages</li>
</ul>
<h3>Synopsis</h3>
<ul>
<li>A hybrid of theoretical/conceptual explanations along with problems to illustrate the ideas.</li>
<li>While may seem advance, Kageyama&#8217;s personality really shines through and makes this such an interesting read (regardless of your level).</li>
<li>Appropriate for 20 kyu and stronger.</li>
<li>Recommended for all types of players.</li>
</ul>
<p><span id="more-1393"></span></p>
<h3>Detailed Review</h3>
<h4>Readability &#8211; 10 / 10</h4>
<p>When it comes to readability, I&#8217;m not sure there&#8217;s a single go book out there that can outclass Kageyama&#8217;s ability to show his humorous and delightful personality through his writing. There is almost never a dull moment in this book. Often times, he will seem to be going off on a tangent (like baseball), but he will always find a way to bring it back full circle to emphasize one of his points. His pragmatic and straight forward advice is something that every go player can make use of, regardless of how strong you desire to be. In fact, even if we set aside the actual treasure trove of go advice that is in this book, I would argue that the entertainment value of his writing makes the book worth every penny.</p>
<h4>Content Quality &#8211; 10 / 10</h4>
<p>Although this is not your classic tsumego book, it does have a similar style to the <a href="http://senseis.xmp.net/?ElementaryGoSeries">Elementary Go Series</a> where there are a few problems at the end of most chapters. In addition, I will be the first to admit that some of these problems are rather difficult and can be discouraging if you are under the impression you need to be able to solve them the first time you see them. In fact, the value of this book lies in its ability to expose you to so many different concepts and ideas. Considering the size of the book and the how short each of the chapters are, the amount of content he covers is nothing short of incredible.</p>
<h4>Final Thoughts</h4>
<p>Although this is my third time reading the book, and it still has not lost a bit of its charm. I continue to learn something new every time I read it, and never fail to crack a smile when Kageyama goes on one of his rants about how amateur players always try to find shortcuts to reading ladders. Nonetheless, this is truly a classic that I believe will never be outdated. So do yourself a favor, and if you are going to only have a small collection of go books, this is definitely one you will want to have.</p>
<h4>Table of Contents</h4>
<ol>
<li>Chapter 1: Ladders and Nets</li>
<li>Chapter 2: Cutting and Connecting</li>
<li>Chapter 3: The Stones Go Walking</li>
<li>Chapter 4: The Struggle to Get Ahead</li>
<li>Chapter 5: Territory and Spheres of Influence</li>
<li>Interlude: Lecturing on NHK-TV</li>
<li>Chapter 6: Life and Death</li>
<li>Chapter 7: How to Study Joseki</li>
<li>Chapter 8: Good Shape and Bad</li>
<li>Chapter 9: Proper and Improper Moves</li>
<li>Chapter 10: Tesuji: The Snap-Back; Shortage of Liberties; The Spiral Latter; The Placement; The Attachment; Under the Stones</li>
<li>Chapter 11: Endgame Pointers</li>
<li>Appendix: Game Commentary: Beating the Meijin</li>
</ol>
<h4>Recommended Vendors:</h4>
<ol>
<li>Amazon &#8211; <a title="Amazon Purchase Link" href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/4906574289/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=4906574289&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=be09a-20">$18.00</a> (S&amp;H not included)</li>
<li>GoGameGuru- <a title="GoGameGuru Purchase Link" href="http://shop.gogameguru.com/lessons-in-the-fundamentals-of-go/?acc=e4da3b7fbbce2345d7772b0674a318d5">$17.99</a> (S&amp;H not included)</li>
<li>Kiseido &#8211; <a title="Kiseido Order Form" href="http://www.kiseido.com/go_books.htm">$18.00</a> (S&amp;H not included)</li>
</ol>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Last updated March 8th, 2013 &#8211; 6 kyu</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1393</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
