<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>ranked games &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/ranked-games/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>Ranked Games and My Slow Brain</title>
		<link>/ranked-games-and-my-slow-brain/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 03:52:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fear of losing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fuseki]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[global thinking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[opening]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ranked games]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=2279</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Lately I&#8217;ve noticed that I seem to have trouble finding time to play ranked games. On the other hand, whenever a friend asks to play a game, I always manage to scrounge up the necessary time to play. After some thought, I believe it is for any of the following reasons: With ranked games, I [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lately I&#8217;ve noticed that I seem to have trouble finding time to play ranked games. On the other hand, whenever a friend asks to play a game, I always manage to scrounge up the necessary time to play. After some thought, I believe it is for any of the following reasons:</p>
<ol>
<li><span style="line-height: 13px;">With ranked games, I have this subconscious fear of not playing my best and losing. </span></li>
<li>When playing against friends, the burden of playing to win is lifted from my shoulders. As a result, even though the games take just as long as a ranked game normally would (or even longer), I&#8217;m at ease playing them because I don&#8217;t have a problem resigning the game if anything were to come up.</li>
<li>Continuing with that idea, I think part of me is fearful that I will be unable to complete a ranked game in its entirety. In my defense though, I have lost a game on time before because I was interrupted and needed to take care of some things. So the idea of losing a ranked game because of anything other than skill makes me shudder.</li>
</ol>
<p>Also, I&#8217;m at this weird point in my growth where my abilities are directly proportional with how much time I spend thinking about a move. Although this may sound common sense to many, I have heard that there are a number of players who can think all day long but will still come up with the same types of moves regardless. An obvious example of this would be joseki. Some players play joseki faithfully by the book because it says that the result is even. For me, it seems that the longer I spend thinking about a move, the more likely it is a better move than what I thought of previously.<br />
Recently, I have found myself spending more and more time in the opening trying to figure out how certain moves or potential responses will affect the game as a whole. As a result, I am finding myself in byoyomi even as early as the middle game sometimes. Since it&#8217;s such a new way of thinking for me, it is a very laborious and intensive process that takes a while for my brain to trudge through. Can&#8217;t wait till it becomes more innate and engrained into my go&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2279</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Not a Sandbagger</title>
		<link>/not-a-sandbagger/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2013 05:30:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[defeat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[my ego]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ranked games]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tilt]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=1637</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Originally, as you all well know, I had intended on just continuing abstaining from ranked games, but it seems that the time has come for me to return to ranked games. What spurred this sudden change of ideas? Well, I was talking to Tilwen today, and he said the following, &#8220;You&#8217;ll have to earn your [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Originally, as you all well know, I had intended on just continuing abstaining from ranked games, but it seems that the time has come for me to return to ranked games. What spurred this sudden change of ideas?<br />
Well, I was talking to Tilwen today, and he said the following, &#8220;You&#8217;ll have to earn your true rank soon so that you can no longer just say that you won games because you are lucky that stronger players are underestimating you since you have a 6k next to your name.&#8221;<br />
As I sat there struck by his comment, other players&#8217; comments about my true rank began to flood into my head.<br />
&#8220;Oh man&#8230; are people starting to see me as a sandbagger?!&#8221;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>(o.O)</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">For those who don&#8217;t know what sandbagging is, it&#8217;s purposely lowering your rank so that you can easily win. Definitely not my definition of enjoyment.</p>
<p>Starting off my return to ranked games has been rough though: four straight losses. It was so unbelievably frustrating at the time because I had just spent the last month playing against stronger players and actually managing to win in even games. So to lose consecutively to players that are supposedly around my &#8220;fake 6k&#8221; rank has been rather depressing. Although why I&#8217;m losing is not a mystery to me, it is due to one thing and one thing only: my ego.<br />
More on this later&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1637</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ranked Games: To Play or Not to Play&#8230;</title>
		<link>/ranked-games-to-play-or-not-to-play/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2013 23:04:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ranked games]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=1599</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[That is the question. I&#8217;ve been fortunate enough to make some incredible friends since my return to go, and I was quite surprised to find that many were curious about when I would finally play a ranked game again. To start, I&#8217;m shocked that I didn&#8217;t try to play a ranked game the moment the [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>That is the question.<br />
I&#8217;ve been fortunate enough to make some incredible friends since my return to go, and I was quite surprised to find that many were curious about when I would finally play a ranked game again.<br />
To start, I&#8217;m shocked that I didn&#8217;t try to play a ranked game the moment the clock struck midnight on New Years Eve. Yet, more than three days later, I&#8217;m sitting here with three free games under my belt and not a ranked game in sight. So the question is, what am I waiting for?<br />
In all honesty, I think part of me is torn between returning to ranked games and continuing my study method for an additional month. On one hand, I&#8217;m really curious how much growth I&#8217;ve undergone since my <a title="Ranked Games Retreat" href="//ranked-games-retreat/">ranked game sabbatical in December</a>. On the other hand, I&#8217;m thinking that it might be more exciting to continue as I have and see where I am in another month! xD After all, I need to get as strong as I can possibly get before the <a title="North American Go Convention!!!" href="//north-american-go-convention/">North American Go Convention</a>!!!<br />
And the other thing that I have to remember is that I am getting thrashed on Tygem and WBaduk at 6k or below, so in actuality, I might not have grown as much as I am hoping I did. So for now, looks I&#8217;m going to continue sticking to league games and continuing my training!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1599</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
