<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>tsumego &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/tsumego/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>WGW37: Tesuji More Useful Than Tsumego?</title>
		<link>/wgw37-tesuji-more-useful-than-tsumego/</link>
		<comments>/wgw37-tesuji-more-useful-than-tsumego/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2014 11:15:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Weekly Go Wednesday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[amazing moves]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[awe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[getting stronger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hikaru no go]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meijin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tesuji]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tsumego]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5039</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Weekly Go Wednesday, Issue #37 Last Friday, I mentioned an article that was shared with me on how to improve at go by Lynx. According to conventional wisdom, the one piece of advice that everyone seem to agree upon is that studying life and death is critical to getting stronger. And to be honest, it&#8217;s [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 style="text-align: center;">Weekly Go Wednesday, Issue #37</h2>
<p>Last <a title="Friday Go Forward: Week 58" href="//friday-go-forward-week-58/">Friday</a>, I mentioned an <a title="Lynx's How to Improve at Go" href="http://shobia.com/w/How_to_Improve_at_Go">article</a> that was shared with me on how to improve at go by Lynx. According to conventional wisdom, the one piece of advice that everyone seem to agree upon is that studying life and death is critical to getting stronger. And to be honest, it&#8217;s something I never really questioned. However, after reading Lynx&#8217;s article, I was confronted with an eye-opening question: <strong>Is studying tesuji more useful than tsumego? </strong><br />
After a lot of thought,  I would have to concur  with Lynx&#8217;s perspective. In fact, it is one of the key components to breaking the glass ceiling when trying to gain that next stone. However, because the masses constantly spout how important life and death is, it is often forgotten in all the noise.<br />
<span style="line-height: 1.5em;">Now now, before you grab your pitchforks and torches, hear me out won&#8217;t you?</span><br />
<span id="more-5039"></span><br />
To start, I will go ahead and address probably the strongest argument against Lynx&#8217;s theory: What is the use of tesuji if you die everywhere?<br />
True. If your life and skills are so abysmal that you are slaughtered around the board, I agree with you in that tesuji will not do you much good. However, the reality of the situation is that most games don&#8217;t consist of groups dying all over the board (unless the rank is horribly imbalanced). And though this can partially be attributed to people studying life and death, my personal experience has shown me that the bottom line is that <em>it is really hard to kill groups in go</em>.<br />
Though people might not realize it, I think that players will inevitably learn about life and death as they play. Why do I say this? Because whenever your group dies, it is usually pretty traumatic. Who can remember that time when they thought their corner was alive and then died in a magnificent burst of flames? I know I can recount it on multiple occasions. And what happens when you die? Well usually you might go back to figure out how you could&#8217;ve avoided it. After all, who likes dying?<br />
On top of that, let&#8217;s not forget the fact that players constantly miss tesuji in their games. It is usually very obvious to players who are much stronger, but unless someone is having their game reviewed by such a player, how many people are going to spend time going over their game to figure out the numerous tesuji they missed? Highly unlikely. They are way more likely to just move on and play another game.<br />
In addition, no matter how peaceful a player you are, you are eventually going to get into fights on the board. I&#8217;m sure there are kifu that exists where no one challenged each other at all, but I&#8217;m pretty sure they only exist at the beginner level since they aren&#8217;t aware they are capable of invading and living. And when it comes to fighting, there is no better weapon than being better at tesuji than your opponent.<br />
Who remembers this scene?<br />
<figure id="attachment_5114" style="width: 422px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/wgw37tesuji01.png"><img class=" wp-image-5114" alt="wgw37tesuji01" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/wgw37tesuji01.png?resize=422%2C312" width="422" height="312" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Ring any bells? [Credit: Hikaru No Go Anime]</figcaption></figure><figure id="attachment_5115" style="width: 384px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/wgw37tesuji02.png"><img class=" wp-image-5115" alt="wgw37tesuji02" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/wgw37tesuji02.png?resize=384%2C291" width="384" height="291" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">How about this one? [Credit: Hikaru no Go Anime]</figcaption></figure><figure id="attachment_5116" style="width: 384px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/wgw37tesuji03.png"><img class=" wp-image-5116" alt="wgw37tesuji03" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/wgw37tesuji03.png?resize=384%2C291" width="384" height="291" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Still no? [Credit: Hikaru no Go Anime]</figcaption></figure>Many of you probably figured it out after the second screenshot, but the answer for those who couldn&#8217;t remember is: Episode 56, &#8220;After a Millennium Comes an Answer.&#8221;<br />
Anyhow, was this a move that dealt with life and death? Did Sai&#8217;s incredible move kill the Meijin&#8217;s group? No. It was a brilliant tesuji that made all spectators watch in amazement. And in fact, if you think about it, most of the moves that are met with astonishment and awe in the show are usually tesuji. They are all about how brilliant that connection was, or how this peep is an excellent forcing move that allows XYZ tesuji to work.<br />
Finally, I want to remind you that Lynx&#8217;s point is <strong><em>not</em></strong> to burn all your tsumego books and never life and death. Instead, she&#8217;s simply trying to remind us of how important tesuji are when it comes to gaining that next stone. So the next time you are thinking about what to study, I hope that you&#8217;ll consider making some time to study tesuji in your busy schedule. It&#8217;ll definitely be worth your while in the long run.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/wgw37-tesuji-more-useful-than-tsumego/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>12</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">5039</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Book Review: Graded Go Problems for Dan Players &#8211; Vol. 1</title>
		<link>/book-review-graded-go-problems-dan-players-vol-1/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2014 12:15:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[collection]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[go problems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kiseido]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life and death]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reading]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tsumego]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=4735</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Graded Go Problems for Dan Players: Volume One &#8211; 300 Life-and-Death Problems (5-kyu to 3-dan) Description: This is the first volume of the continuing series to the popular &#8220;Graded Go Problems for Beginners.&#8221; This first book is focused on providing life-and-death techniques that are foundational to developing stronger reading abilities as players try to climb [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/02/ggpdpv1cover.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-4736" alt="ggpdpv1cover" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/02/ggpdpv1cover.jpg?resize=288%2C373" width="288" height="373" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">Graded Go Problems for Dan Players: Volume One &#8211; 300 Life-and-Death Problems (5-kyu to 3-dan)</h2>
<p><strong>Description:</strong> This is the first volume of the continuing series to the popular &#8220;Graded Go Problems for Beginners.&#8221; This first book is focused on providing life-and-death techniques that are foundational to developing stronger reading abilities as players try to climb their way into dan status.<br />
<span id="more-4735"></span><br />
[expand title=&#8221;Book Details&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
[table]
Title, GGPDP: Volume One &#8211; 300 Life-and-Death Problems (5-kyu to 3-dan)<br />
Series, Graded Go Problems for Dan Players (GGPDP)<br />
Compiled by, Masaru Aoki and Hirokazu Sato<br />
Translator, Richard Bozulich<br />
Publisher, <a href="http://www.kiseido.com/">Kiseido</a><br />
Published, &#8220;November 2009&#8243;<br />
Language, English<br />
ISBN, 978-4-906574-61-2<br />
Length, 232 pages<br />
Problems, 300 problems<br />
[/table]
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Table of Content&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Translator&#8217;s Preface</li>
<li>Glossary of Go Terms Used in this Book</li>
<li>300 Life and Death Problems (#1-300)</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Before I Read This Book&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
As an enthusiast of the &#8220;Graded Go Problems for Beginners&#8221; series, I have to say that I was ecstatic when I heard about this series. After all, every kyu player dreams of making it to the big dan league and being able to solve &#8220;dan level&#8221; problems. And even though I got myself a copy of this book quite a while ago, this book seemed quite daunting to me for some time due to the fact that I just felt I wasn&#8217;t ready for &#8220;dan&#8221; problems. Anyhow, I&#8217;m glad I finally got around to reading it so that you can hear my thoughts on the book itself.<br />
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;My Review&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221; expanded=&#8221;true&#8221;]
Perhaps my favorite aspect about the entire &#8220;Graded Go Problems&#8221; series as a whole is the extremely clean format. For those who don&#8217;t know what I&#8217;m talking about, every page that contains the problems is divided into four clean and even rectangles. Secondly, the numbering, diagram, directions, and even hints are all in universal places so that once you get exposed to the format, you&#8217;ll never wonder where to look next. And last but not least, the solutions are never exposed on the same page (aka you can&#8217;t see the solution as you&#8217;re trying to solve the problem). And thankfully, Graded Go Problems for Dan Players continues that tradition.<br />
One of the new things I noticed with this series is that they added an actual rank estimation for the problem difficulty. So a few examples of this might include: &#8220;Solve at a glance = 4-kyu, Solve within five minutes = 3-dan, etc.&#8221; While this is rather neat since you feel a sense of accomplishment if you&#8217;re able to solve it within the allotted time-frame, it&#8217;s important to realize that these rank estimations are a bit arbitrary. Just because you&#8217;re able to solve a few dan level problems at a glance does not necessarily mean you are &#8220;dan&#8221; level (whether it&#8217;s reading ability or playing ability). If you&#8217;re able to solve the whole book at a glance though, then it goes without saying you are way stronger than a dan player. xD<br />
When it comes to the solutions, they have a set standard format for how solutions are displayed and approached. In terms of basic format, every problem gets three solution diagrams. This generally includes the correct variation, an alternate variation / continuation of the correct variation, and an incorrect variation. In addition, there is usually at least a sentence to two explaining each of the variations in order to help the reader understand what&#8217;s going on.<br />
If there were to be any complaint about this series, it would probably be that the problems are not segmented into different techniques. However, I would remind the reader that the purpose of this series is to provide a collection of high-quality problems. As a result, the problems would be an assortment of different problems as opposed to a hierarchy of problems broken down by techniques. If you&#8217;re looking for problems categorized in such a fashion, you might benefit from checking out the Level Up Series along with Life and Death Problems 1 Basics by Robert Jasiek.<br />
Overall, I think that this series is destined for the same greatness as the &#8220;Graded for Go Problems for Beginners&#8221; when it comes to high quality problems that are displayed in an easy to read format. Definitely a must-have for any player serious about practicing their reading and looking for ways to keep honing their ability. Highly recommended!<br />
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Synopsis&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<strong>What did I enjoy about the book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Continues to provide the easy to read format you come to love from &#8220;Graded Go Problems for Beginners.&#8221;</li>
<li>Attempts to provide accurate rank difficulty estimations for problems through the time it takes to solve it.</li>
<li>Lots of high-quality problems that you can rely on without worrying about a mistake in the solution.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What did I gain from reading this book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Exposure to a lot of new techniques or moves I would have never considered when solving life and death.</li>
<li>Reassurance that my reading abilities have been improving.</li>
<li>Realization that I still had a ways to go before I could consider myself having &#8220;dan-level&#8221; reading.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What is the format of the book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>You get a set of problems and then when you turn the page you get the respective solutions (so that they are not within the same reading area). Very easy to follow and read.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What aspect can be improved on?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Nothing. I really think this book is perfect as it stands.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Is this book easy to read?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Absolutely. Very clear and concise.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Bottom Line</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>Great problem set for players 5 kyu and stronger.</li>
<li>Continues to uphold the quality and ease of reading you come to expect from the &#8220;Graded Go Problems&#8221; series.</li>
<li>Highly recommended for anyone looking to take the next steps to raising their reading ability to &#8220;dan&#8221; level!</li>
</ol>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Recommended For&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Players 5-kyu and stronger.</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Where Can I Buy It?&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Kiseido &#8211; <a href="http://kiseido.com/go_books.htm#K15">$25</a> (shipping and handling not included)</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Other Books in This Series&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;lastExpandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>GGPDP &#8211; Volume One: 300 Life-and-Death Problems (5-kyu to 3-dan)</li>
<li>GGPDP &#8211; Volume Two: 300 Tesuji Problems (5-kyu to 3-dan)</li>
<li>GGPDP &#8211; Volume Three: 300 Joseki Problems (1-dan to 3-dan)</li>
<li>GGPDP &#8211; Volume Four: 300 Life-and-Death Problems (4-dan to 7-dan)</li>
<li>GGPDP &#8211; Volume Five: 300 Tesuji Problems (4-dan to 7-dan)</li>
<li>GGPDP &#8211; Volume Six: Joseki Problems (TBD)</li>
<li>GGPDP &#8211; Volume Seven: 256 Opening and Middle Game Problems (1-dan to 7-dan)</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
<p style="text-align: center;"><em><strong>Last Updated on March 2nd, 2014</strong></em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">4735</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Monday Go Meditation: Game 43</title>
		<link>/monday-go-meditation-game-43/</link>
		<comments>/monday-go-meditation-game-43/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2014 12:15:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Kifu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Monday Go Meditation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[black]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[resignation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tsumego]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[victory]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=4589</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Introduction For this week&#8217;s meditation, I am featuring my first long game that I played after being on break from them for a long time. It&#8217;s an interesting game that illustrates how to properly chase and harrass a weak group while taking profit and learning to restrain the urge to kill. In addition, I have [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 style="text-align: center;">Introduction</h2>
<p>For this week&#8217;s meditation, I am featuring my first long game that I played after being on break from them for a long time. It&#8217;s an interesting game that illustrates how to properly chase and harrass a weak group while taking profit and learning to restrain the urge to kill.<br />
In addition, I have started integrating questions into the game review to hopefully add a more dynamic aspect to the game reviews and make them more enjoyable for you and give you some practice as well. And just to be clear, the questions and answers come from my abilities and understanding of the game; so there is definitely room for debate on the answers.<br />
Hope you enjoy this new feature and enjoy the review!<a href="//wp-content/uploads/2014/02/2014.02.17-MGM-43.sgf"><br />
</a><br />

<div id='glift_display1' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display1","sgf":"http:\/\/bengozen.com\/\/wp-content\/uploads\/2014\/02\/2014.02.17-MGM-43.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='//wp-content/uploads/2014/02/2014.02.17-MGM-43.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">[download label=&#8221;Download Kifu&#8221;]//wp-content/uploads/2014/02/2014.02.17-MGM-43.sgf[/download]
<h2 style="text-align: center;"><strong>One Point Lesson</strong></h2>
<p style="text-align: center;">Learn to relish in taking profit over killing a group is essential to getting stronger.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><em>A special thanks goes out to my friend Nate who gave me the encouragement and words of support needed to finally get me back into playing long games again.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/monday-go-meditation-game-43/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>18</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">4589</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Book Review: Essential Life &#038; Death 2</title>
		<link>/book-review-essential-life-death-2/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2013 09:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[korean style]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life and death]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[problems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reading]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[school]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[training]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tsumego]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[workbook]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=2895</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Description: Essential Life &#38; Death 2 is part of the Essential Life &#38; Death Series that is used as workbooks in private go schools in Korea. Though it might be seen as an addendum to the Level Up Series, it certainly can be used as a standalone product for anyone looking to study life and [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/06/eldv2cover.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2896" alt="eldv2cover" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/06/eldv2cover.jpg?resize=300%2C406" width="300" height="406" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><br />
<strong>Description:</strong> <em>Essential Life &amp; Death 2</em> is part of the Essential Life &amp; Death Series that is used as workbooks in private go schools in Korea. Though it might be seen as an addendum to the Level Up Series, it certainly can be used as a standalone product for anyone looking to study life and death.<br />
<span id="more-2895"></span><br />
[expand title=&#8221;Book Details&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
[table]
Title, Essential Life &amp; Death 2<br />
Author, Lee Jae-Hwan<br />
Translators, Lee Seong-Geun &amp; Daniela Trinks<br />
Publisher, <a href="http://www.baduktopia.com/">Baduktopia</a><br />
Published, &#8220;July 8th, 2009&#8243;<br />
Language, English<br />
ISBN, 978-89-90965-94-3<br />
Length, 168 Pages<br />
[/table]
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Table of Content&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ol>
<li>Tiger&#8217;s Mouth Vital Point</li>
<li>Vital Point of Eye Shapes</li>
<li>Using Seonsu (Sente)</li>
<li>Making a Sacrifice</li>
<li>Miai (Paired Moves) Tesuji</li>
<li>Playing Dansu (Atari) Fails</li>
<li>Beware of a Pae (Ko) 1</li>
<li><strong>1st Review</strong></li>
<li>Using Jachung</li>
<li>Extending the Eye Space</li>
<li>Under the Stones 1</li>
<li>First Line Tiger&#8217;s Mouth 1</li>
<li>1-2 Vital Point 1</li>
<li>Try to Find the Vital Point 1</li>
<li>Large Diagonal Vital Point 1</li>
<li><strong>2nd Review</strong></li>
<li>Where to Reduce the Eye Space</li>
<li>Large Knight&#8217;s Vital Point</li>
<li>Vital Point to Make a False Eye</li>
<li>False Eye After Placement 1</li>
<li>Using a Sacrifice to Make a False Eye</li>
<li>How to Make a False Eye</li>
<li>False Eye After Placement 2</li>
<li><strong>3rd Review</strong></li>
<li><strong></strong>Finding the Vital Point 1</li>
<li>Finding the Vital Point 2</li>
<li>Finding the Vital Point 3</li>
<li>Finding the Vital Point 4</li>
<li>Finding the Vital Point 5</li>
<li>Finding the Vital Point 6</li>
<li>Center of Symmetry</li>
<li>Finding the Vital Point<strong> 7 </strong></li>
<li>Large Diagonal Vital Point 1</li>
<li><b>4th Review</b></li>
<li>Using the Suicide-Rule</li>
<li>Using a Sacrifice</li>
<li>Under the Stones 2</li>
<li>Using Pae (Ko)</li>
<li>Using Miai (Paired Moves)</li>
<li>Wedging-in Tesuji</li>
<li>Using One Eye versus No Eye</li>
<li>Using a Throw-in</li>
<li><strong>5th Review</strong></li>
<li>Playing Inside at the Vital Point 1</li>
<li>Playing Inside at the Vital Point 2</li>
<li>Playing Inside at the Vital Point 3</li>
<li>Jachung using Vital Point</li>
<li>False Eye after Placement 3</li>
<li>First Line Tesuji</li>
<li>Where to Make a Tiger&#8217;s Mouth</li>
<li>Monkey Jump</li>
<li><strong>6th Review</strong></li>
<li>Life &amp; Death with no Outside Liberties</li>
<li>Life &amp; Death with an Outside Liberty</li>
<li>According to the Throw-in 1</li>
<li>According to the Throw-in 2</li>
<li>Beware of Bent 4 in the Corner</li>
<li>Bent 4 in the Corner</li>
<li>Placement (Playing Inside)</li>
<li>Spinning Around</li>
<li><strong>7th Review</strong></li>
<li>Using Connection</li>
<li>Using Double-Pae (Ko)</li>
<li>Using Jachung</li>
<li>Using a Weak Point</li>
<li>1-2 Vital Point 2</li>
<li>Center of Symmetry</li>
<li>Diagonal Move Tesuji 1</li>
<li>Diagonal Move Tesuji 2</li>
<li><strong>8th Review</strong></li>
<li>Loose Connection</li>
<li>Where to Hane</li>
<li>False Eye After Placement 4</li>
<li>Try to Find the Vital Point 2</li>
<li>Beware of a Pae (Ko) 2</li>
<li>Making a Seki in Sente</li>
<li>First Line Tiger&#8217;s Mouth 2</li>
<li>False Eye After Reduction</li>
<li><strong>9th Review</strong></li>
<li>Big Eye Shapes Can Die!</li>
<li>Using a Weak Point 2</li>
<li>Excellent Sequence</li>
<li>First Line Tiger&#8217;s Mouth 3</li>
<li>One Eye by Two Hane</li>
<li>Tesuji to Make a Pae (Ko)</li>
<li><strong>10th Review</strong></li>
<li><strong>Final Test</strong></li>
</ol>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Synopsis&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221; expanded=&#8221;true&#8221;]
<ol>
<li>You can expect the same quality of problems from the first volume.</li>
<li>A great way for players to drill their life and death skills.</li>
<li>Though I had a relatively easy time with the first volume, the problems in this book started to pose some difficulty for me.</li>
</ol>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Before I Read This Book&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<strong>My Abilities</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>I&#8217;ve studied my fair share of life and death and can confidently say that I have a SDK (single digit kyu) level of life and death.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>My Perspective</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>After finishing the first volume, I was expecting this book to be rather easy to do as well.</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;My Review&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221; expanded=&#8221;true&#8221;]
<strong>What did I enjoy about the book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>They have no reservation in terms of making you drill the same concept repeatedly.</li>
<li>There are so many concepts and shapes in this book that makes it very valuable.</li>
<li>The review sections (e.g., quizzes) and tests do a great job helping you determine if you actually learned the lessons prior.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What did I gain from reading this book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>A broader perspective on the different variations that can arise from life and death postiions.</li>
<li>A better grasp on techniques used to either kill or save a group.</li>
<li>The problems in this book actually posed some difficulty for me at times. Being that this is the second book, it didn&#8217;t take long for me to realize how weak my life and death skills really are.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What style of teaching does the book use?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Curriculum Style
<ul>
<li>Content is organized into lessons, topics, or themes in order to facilitate learning.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Teaching Mechanism:
<ul>
<li>Practice problems</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What aspect can be improved on?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>If I had to request one thing, it&#8217;s that I was hoping that the difficulty of the problems would be more gradual. The difficulty of the problems increased faster than I was expecting. Though this should be taken with a grain of salt since I have a feeling this is just an indicator of how weak my reading abilities are instead of it being the book&#8217;s problem.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Is this book easy to read?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Yes. Unless you can&#8217;t read English, it really doesn&#8217;t get any simpler.</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;In Comparison to Similar Books&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
[expandsub1 title=&#8221;1001 Life and Death Problems&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;cBookTitle&#8221;]
Compared to <a title="Book Review: 1001 Life and Death Problems" href="//book-review-1001-life-and-death-problems/">1001 Life and Death Problems</a>, this series does a better job hand-holing players new to life and death through the basic shapes and variations. On the other hand, I would say that in terms of polishing a player&#8217;s life and death skills, 1001 Life and Death Problems is still highly recommended. So to clarify, neither one trumps the other. Both can provide great value to a player&#8217;s life and death abilities.<br />
[/expandsub1]
[expandsub2 title=&#8221;Elementary Go Series, Volume 4 &#8211; Life and Death&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;cBookTitle&#8221;]
While <a title="Book Review: Life and Death" href="//book-review-life-and-death/">Life and Death</a> does a great job providing a broad survey of different shapes through explanations and accompanying practice problems, this series uses the &#8220;learn it through experience&#8221; methodology. Though they may overlap on a good deal of material, I believe that they complement one another and would both be of great use to serious players wanting to improve their life and death.<br />
[/expandsub2]
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Recommended For&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Players looking to improve their life and death skills.</li>
<li>People who prefer to learn through experience rather than explanations.</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Where Can I Buy It?&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Yellow Mountain Imports &#8211; <a title="Yellow Mountain Import Purchase Link" href="https://www.ymimports.com/p-1414-essential-life-death-2-10-5-kyu.aspx#.UeAJdkGvPzw">$13.00</a> USD (shipping &amp; handling not included)</li>
<li>Baduktopia &#8211; Contact them at info@baduktopia.com to request pricing and shipping costs.</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Other Books in This Series&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;lastExpandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li><a title="Book Review: Essential Life &amp; Death 1" href="//book-review-essential-life-death-1/">Essential Life and Death 1</a></li>
<li>Essential Life and Death 3</li>
<li>Essential Life and Death 4</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
<p style="text-align: center;"><em><strong>Last Updated on July 13th, 2013</strong></em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2895</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Book Review: Life and Death</title>
		<link>/book-review-life-and-death/</link>
		<comments>/book-review-life-and-death/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2013 09:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[groups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kill]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life and death]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reading]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[safety]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[save]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tsumego]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=3098</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Life and Death Description: In this volume of the Elementary Go Series, Davies teaches common shapes that players will encounter in their games along with practice problems to train the reader&#8217;s life and death skills. [expand title=&#8221;Book Details&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;] [table] Title, Life and Death (Volume 4) Series, Elementary Go Series Author, James Davies Publisher, Kiseido [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/06/egslifeanddeathcover.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3099" alt="egslifeanddeathcover" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/06/egslifeanddeathcover.jpg?resize=300%2C443" width="300" height="443" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">Life and Death</h2>
<p><strong>Description: </strong>In this volume of the Elementary Go Series, Davies teaches common shapes that players will encounter in their games along with practice problems to train the reader&#8217;s life and death skills.<br />
<span id="more-3098"></span><br />
[expand title=&#8221;Book Details&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
[table]
Title, Life and Death (Volume 4)<br />
Series, Elementary Go Series<br />
Author, James Davies<br />
Publisher, Kiseido<br />
Published, 1st Edition &#8211; December 1975 | 2nd Edition &#8211; August 1996<br />
Language, English<br />
ISBN, 978-4-906574-13-0<br />
Length, 160 Pages<br />
[/table]
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Table of Content&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ol>
<li>Introduction</li>
<li>Unsettled Three</li>
<li>Six Die, Eight Live</li>
<li>Four- and Five-Space Eyes</li>
<li>Rabbity Six</li>
<li>One-Space Notchers</li>
<li>Shortage of Liberties</li>
<li>Two-Space Notchers</li>
<li>An Eye in the Interior</li>
<li>Three-Space Notchers</li>
<li>False Eyes and Placement Techniques</li>
<li>The Door Group is Dead</li>
<li>Incomplete Shapes</li>
<li>Review Problems</li>
<li>To Make One Eye</li>
<li>Half Eyes</li>
<li>Bent Four in the Corner</li>
<li>The One-Two Points, Etc.</li>
<li>Placement: Attack and Defense</li>
<li>Throw-Ins</li>
<li>The L Group</li>
<li>The First L+1 Group</li>
<li>The Second L+1 Group</li>
<li>The L+2 Group</li>
<li>The Tripod Group</li>
<li>The J Groups</li>
<li>Hane for Ko</li>
<li>The Long L Group</li>
<li>Seki in the Corner</li>
<li>The Carpenter&#8217;s Square</li>
<li>The Weak Carpenter&#8217;s Square</li>
<li>More Corner Positions</li>
<li>Live or Link Up</li>
<li>Threat to Capture</li>
<li>Under the Stones</li>
<li>The Difference a Liberty Makes</li>
<li>Building Eye Shape</li>
</ol>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Synopsis&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221; expanded=&#8221;true&#8221;]
<ol>
<li>A great overview on a lot of different shapes that players can definitely benefit from.</li>
<li>Not a good introductory book for life and death.</li>
<li>Requires a higher reading ability level for the practice problems than I was anticipating.</li>
</ol>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Before I Read This Book&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<strong>My Abilities</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Having worked through other life and death books, I am confident enough to say that I have a SDK (single digit kyu) understanding of life and death.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>My Perspective</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>I was looking forward to getting exposed to a lot of basic life and death shapes. In addition, I was hoping to get a bit of practice on the different shapes so I could be a lot more confident on my life and death abilities when I finished the book.</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;My Review&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221; expanded=&#8221;true&#8221;]
<strong>What did I enjoy about the book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>There are so many shapes that you get to learn about!</li>
<li>On top of that, these shapes are ones that actually occur quite frequently in games! Case and point, I actually ran into a J shape soon after I finished the book.</li>
<li>There are a lot of &#8220;what is the status of this group&#8221; problems.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What did I gain from reading this book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Exposure to a lot of new shapes that I never even considered life and death shapes in the past.</li>
<li>Better understanding of the weaknesses in various shapes.</li>
<li>New ideas regarding how the opponent would/should actually respond in certain life and death scenarios.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What style of teaching does the book use?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Textbook Approach
<ul>
<li>Organized in a curriculum format that reflects the learning style one might normally find in school.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Primary Learning Mechanism:
<ul>
<li>Explanations with example diagrams</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Other Learning Mechanisms:
<ul>
<li>Practice problems</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What aspect can be improved on?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Though the fact that it uses &#8220;what is the status of this group&#8221; problems is a good thing for the most part, I feel that this is counter-productive to anyone learning life and death for the first time since status problems can actually be rather difficult for players who are not accustomed to reading multiple rather complex variations in life and death situations.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Is this book easy to read?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Yes. Davies&#8217; writing style is easy to understand and his conversational style makes for a fun read. In addition, almost every diagram is accompanied by a short line or paragraph explaining the position.</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;In Comparison to Similar Books&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
[expandsub1 title=&#8221;1001 Life and Death Problems&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;cBookTitle&#8221;]
<a title="Book Review: 1001 Life and Death Problems" href="//book-review-1001-life-and-death-problems/">1001 Life and Death Problems</a> is much more appropriate for players looking for an introduction to life and go. It does a great job providing the building blocks for being able to see the variations that are found in Davies&#8217; Life and Death.<br />
[/expandsub1]
[expandsub2 title=&#8221;Essential Life &amp; Death Series&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;cBookTitle&#8221;]
The Essential Life &amp; Death Series takes a more gradual approach with life and death and provides the reader with ample opportunities to practice. However, it does not contain the explanations that you get with Davies&#8217; Life and Death, so they complement one another very well.<br />
[/expandsub2]
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Recommended For&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Players looking for a reference on numerous shapes that are frequently encountered in games.</li>
<li>Players who have read other life and death books and are looking to expand their knowledge and test their skills.</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Where Can I Buy It?&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>GoGameGuru &#8211; <a title="Go Game Guru Purchase Link" href="http://shop.gogameguru.com/life-and-death/?acc=e4da3b7fbbce2345d7772b0674a318d5">$17.99</a> USD (shipping &amp; handling not included)</li>
<li>Kiseido &#8211; <a title="Kiseido Purchase Link" href="http://kiseido.com/go_books.htm">$18.00</a> USD (shipping &amp; handling not included)</li>
<li>SmartGo Books &#8211; <a title="SmartGo Book Link" href="http://www.smartgo.com/books.htm">$9.99</a> USD (e-Book for iPad &amp; iPhone Only)</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Other Books in This Series&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;lastExpandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li><a title="Book Review: In the Beginning" href="//book-review-in-the-beginning/">Elementary Go Series, Volume 1 &#8211; In the Beginning</a></li>
<li><a title="Book Review: 38 Basic Joseki" href="//book-review-38-basic-joseki/">Elementary Go Series, Volume 2 &#8211; 38 Basic Joseki</a></li>
<li><a title="Book Review: Tesuji" href="//book-review-tesuji/">Elementary Go Series, Volume 3 &#8211; Tesuji</a></li>
<li><a title="Book Review: Attack and Defense" href="//book-review-attack-and-defense/">Elementary Go Series, Volume 5 &#8211; Attack and Defense</a></li>
<li><a title="Book Review: The Endgame" href="//book-review-the-endgame/">Elementary Go Series, Volume 6 &#8211; The Endgame</a></li>
<li><a title="Book Review: Handicap Go" href="//book-review-handicap-go/">Elementary Go Series, Volume 7 &#8211; Handicap Go</a></li>
</ul>
[/expand]
<p style="text-align: center;"><em><strong>Last Updated on July 10th , 2013</strong></em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/book-review-life-and-death/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3098</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Book Review: Essential Life &#038; Death 1</title>
		<link>/book-review-essential-life-death-1/</link>
		<comments>/book-review-essential-life-death-1/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2013 09:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[korean style]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life and death]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[progressive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[school like training]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tsumego]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=2886</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Description: Essential Life &#38; Death 1 is part of the Essential Life &#38; Death Series that is used as workbooks in private go schools in Korea. Though it might be seen as an addendum to the Level Up Series, it certainly can be used as a standalone product for anyone looking to study life and [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/06/eldv1cover.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2887" alt="eldv1cover" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/06/eldv1cover.jpg?resize=300%2C408" width="300" height="408" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><br />
<strong>Description:</strong> <em>Essential Life &amp; Death 1</em> is part of the Essential Life &amp; Death Series that is used as workbooks in private go schools in Korea. Though it might be seen as an addendum to the Level Up Series, it certainly can be used as a standalone product for anyone looking to study life and death.<br />
<span id="more-2886"></span><br />
[expand title=&#8221;Book Details&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
[table]
Title, Essential Life &amp; Death 1<br />
Author, Lee Jae-Hwan<br />
Translators, Lee Seong-Geun &amp; Daniela Trinks<br />
Publisher, <a href="http://www.baduktopia.com/">Baduktopia</a><br />
Published, &#8220;July 8th, 2009&#8243;<br />
Language, English<br />
ISBN, 978-89-90965-93-6<br />
Length, 168 Pages<br />
[/table]
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Table of Content&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ol>
<li>One Eye by Tiger&#8217;s Mouth</li>
<li>One Eye by Pushing Ahead</li>
<li>One Eye by Stretching</li>
<li>Two Birds with One Stone</li>
<li>Beware of the 3-Point-Eye Space</li>
<li>Making the 3-Point Eye Space</li>
<li>Taking the Weak Point</li>
<li>Choking the Weak Point</li>
<li><strong>1st Review</strong></li>
<li>Making a Straight Four</li>
<li>Making a Bent four</li>
<li>Making a Twisted Four</li>
<li>Use Dead Stones to Make a Straight Four</li>
<li>Use Dead Stones to Make a Bent Four</li>
<li>Use Dead Stones to Make a Twisted Four</li>
<li>Making a Dead Four</li>
<li>Making a 5-Point-Eye Shape</li>
<li><strong>2nd Review</strong></li>
<li>Tiger&#8217;s Mouth Vital Point</li>
<li>Playing Inside at the Vital Point</li>
<li>Vital Point First</li>
<li>Finding the Vital Point 1</li>
<li>The Center of Symmetry</li>
<li>The 1-2 Vital Point</li>
<li><strong>3rd Review</strong></li>
<li>False Eye by Throwing-in Twice</li>
<li>False Eye by Raising the Throw-in</li>
<li>False Eye by Miai (Paired Moves)</li>
<li>False Eye by Cutting</li>
<li>False Eye by Underneath Attachment</li>
<li>False Eye by Crawling Out</li>
<li><strong>4th Review</strong></li>
<li>Using a Snapback</li>
<li>Using a Chokchoksu</li>
<li>Using a Sacrifice</li>
<li>Using a Sente (Seonsu)</li>
<li>Using Jachung</li>
<li>Using the Suicide-Rule</li>
<li>Using Miai (Paired Moves) 1</li>
<li>Making Seki (Dual Life) 1</li>
<li><strong>5th Review</strong></li>
<li>Block to Extend the Eye Space</li>
<li>Hane to Extend the Eye Space</li>
<li>Stretch to Extend the Eye Space</li>
<li>Throw-in to Reduce the Eye Space</li>
<li>Hane to Reduce the Eye Space</li>
<li>Push to Reduce the Eye Space</li>
<li><strong>6th Review</strong></li>
<li>Playing Inside (Placement)</li>
<li>Loose Block</li>
<li>Loose Connection</li>
<li>Finding the Vital Point 2</li>
<li>Using Sacrificed Stones</li>
<li>Where to Make a Tiger&#8217;s Mouth</li>
<li>Belly Attachment</li>
<li><strong>7th Review</strong></li>
<li>Large Diagonal Spin-Around</li>
<li>One-Point-Spin-Around</li>
<li>Cut to Spin-Around</li>
<li>Wedge-in to Spin-Around</li>
<li>Throw-in 1</li>
<li>Throw-in 2</li>
<li>False Eye by Using Jachung 1</li>
<li>False Eye by Using Jachung 2</li>
<li><strong>8th Review</strong></li>
<li>Beware of a False Eye</li>
<li>Beware of Jachung</li>
<li>False Eye after Reduction</li>
<li>Using Miai (Paired Moves) 2</li>
<li>Monkey Jump 1</li>
<li>Monkey Jump 2</li>
<li>Extending the Eye Space</li>
<li>Using a Weak Point</li>
<li><strong>9th Review</strong></li>
<li>Making Seki (Dual Life) 2</li>
<li>6 Die, 8 Live</li>
<li>4 Die, 6 Live</li>
<li>2nd Line Life &amp; Death</li>
<li>Beware of a Pae (Ko)</li>
<li>Living by Pae (Ko)</li>
<li>Capturing by Pae (Ko)</li>
<li><strong>10th Review</strong></li>
<li><strong>Final Test</strong></li>
</ol>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Synopsis&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221; expanded=&#8221;true&#8221;]
<ol>
<li>A workbook-based approach to teaching life and death.</li>
<li>A great way for players to drill their life and death skills.</li>
<li>A good introductory book to learning and experiencing life and death problems.</li>
</ol>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Before I Read This Book&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<strong>My Abilities</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>I&#8217;ve studied my fair share of life and death and can confidently say that I have a SDK (single digit kyu) level of life and death.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>My Perspective</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>I was hoping for very easy problems that would help polish my basic life and death skills.</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;My Review&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221; expanded=&#8221;true&#8221;]
<strong>What did I enjoy about the book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>They have no reservation in terms of making you drill the same concept repeatedly.</li>
<li>The concept of using seki to save your group is used very often from the very beginning.</li>
<li>The review sections (e.g., quizzes) and tests do a great job helping you determine if you actually learned the previous lessons.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What did I gain from reading this book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Polished my basic life and death skills.</li>
<li>Improved my ability to see seki as an option when solving life and death problems.</li>
<li>Realization that I had a long way to go for life and death.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What style of teaching does the book use?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Curriculum Style
<ul>
<li>Content is organized into lessons, topics, or themes in order to facilitate learning.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Teaching Mechanism:
<ul>
<li>Practice problems</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What aspect can be improved on?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>No complaints here!</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Is this book easy to read?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Yes. Unless you can&#8217;t read English, it really doesn&#8217;t get any simpler.</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;In Comparison to Similar Books&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
[expandsub1 title=&#8221;1001 Life and Death Problems&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;cBookTitle&#8221;]
Compared to <a title="Book Review: 1001 Life and Death Problems" href="//book-review-1001-life-and-death-problems/">1001 Life and Death Problems</a>, this series does a better job hand-holing players new to life and death through the basic shapes and variations. On the other hand, I would say that in terms of polishing a player&#8217;s life and death skills, <a title="Book Review: 1001 Life and Death Problems" href="//book-review-1001-life-and-death-problems/">1001 Life and Death Problems</a> is still highly recommended. So to clarify, neither one trumps the other. Both can provide great value to a player&#8217;s life and death abilities.<br />
[/expandsub1]
[expandsub2 title=&#8221;Elementary Go Series, Volume 4 &#8211; Life and Death&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;cBookTitle&#8221;]
While <a title="Book Review: Life and Death" href="//book-review-life-and-death/">Life and Death</a> does a great job providing a broad survey of different shapes through explanations and accompanying practice problems, this series uses the &#8220;learn it through experience&#8221; methodology. Though they may overlap on a good deal of material, I believe that they complement one another and would both be of great use to serious players wanting to improve their life and death.<br />
[/expandsub2]
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Recommended For&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Players looking to improve their life and death skills.</li>
<li>People who prefer to learn through experience rather than explanations.</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Where Can I Buy It?&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Yellow Mountain Imports &#8211; <a href="https://www.ymimports.com/p-1413-essential-life-death-1-15-10-kyu.aspx#.Ua-kqUCvP2s">$13.00</a> USD (shipping &amp; handling not included)</li>
<li>Baduktopia &#8211; Contact them at info@baduktopia.com to request pricing and shipping costs.</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Other Books in This Series&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;lastExpandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Essential Life and Death 2</li>
<li>Essential Life and Death 3</li>
<li>Essential Life and Death 4</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
<p style="text-align: center;"><em><strong>Last Updated on June 12th, 2013</strong></em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/book-review-essential-life-death-1/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>11</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2886</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Book Review: All About Ko</title>
		<link>/book-review-all-about-ko/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2013 09:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ko]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reference]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tsumego]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=2796</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Overall Rating: 8 / 10 Ponnuki Basic Information Title: Mastering the Basics, Volume 6: All About Ko Author: Rob can Zeijst and Richard Bozulich Publisher: Kiseido Publication Date: September 2007 Number of Problems: 121 Problems Page Length: 250 pages Synopsis A solid book that serves as a great reference on ko while providing problems and example games. Appropriate for [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/05/mtbsv6cover.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2828" alt="mtbsv6cover" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/05/mtbsv6cover.jpg?resize=300%2C422" width="300" height="422" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></h2>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">Overall Rating: 8 / 10 Ponnuki</h2>
<h3>Basic Information</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Title:</strong> Mastering the Basics, Volume 6: All About Ko</li>
<li><strong>Author: </strong>Rob can Zeijst and Richard Bozulich</li>
<li><strong>Publisher: </strong>Kiseido</li>
<li><strong>Publication Date: </strong>September 2007</li>
<li><strong>Number of Problems:</strong> 121 Problems</li>
<li><strong>Page Length:</strong> 250 pages</li>
</ul>
<h3>Synopsis</h3>
<ul>
<li>A solid book that serves as a great reference on ko while providing problems and example games.</li>
<li>Appropriate for 1 dan and stronger.</li>
<li>Recommended for serious players who <strong><em>really</em> </strong>want to study ko.</li>
</ul>
<p><span id="more-2796"></span></p>
<h3>What I Expected</h3>
<ul>
<li>A thorough explanation of ko and introduction of new ideas I never thought of with ko.</li>
<li>Explanations on determining the value of ko.</li>
<li>Problems to illustrate the different aspects of ko.</li>
</ul>
<h3>What You Can Expect</h3>
<ul>
<li><span style="line-height: 13px;">A good introduction to a lot of different concepts involved with ko battles.</span></li>
<li>Best explanation for determining the value of ko that I&#8217;ve seen thus far.</li>
<li>Problems and example games that help to illustrate the different concepts introduced in the first half.</li>
</ul>
<h3>My Thoughts as a 5 Kyu</h3>
<p>To begin, I&#8217;d like to clarify that I was not able to fully study and absorb all the material in this book. There are an array of reasons for this, but the primary one being that I have very little motivation to actually learn all the details about ko since I feel that I still have a wide gap in the rest of my go knowledge that mastery of ko would not be very rewarding at this point in time.<br />
For those who have looked at the Table of Contents, it is very clear that that Zeijst and Bozulich both took great care to make sure just about every aspect of ko was covered. Granted, while some of the sections are rather short (e.g., a few pages), the explanation are concise and clear enough that the brevity of the section will not hamper your learning ability.<br />
Finally, this is the first book I&#8217;m recommending for dan players and above. There is a really big reason for this: mastering ko battles is <em>utterly useles</em>s for kyu players unless they already have a solid understanding of everything else already (e.g., positional judgment, attacking and defending properly, direction of play, etc.). And based on what I&#8217;ve heard from stronger players, kyu players would be dan level if they already had a solid grasp of the other fundamentals of the game.<br />
If you really want to get this book however, I would recommend simply reading the explanations on the various aspects of ko; but don&#8217;t spend an exorbitant amount of time on the problems.</p>
<h3>Table of Content</h3>
<ol>
<li>Preface</li>
<li>Some Important Terms and Concepts</li>
<li>A Glossary of Japanese Terms Related to Ko</li>
<li>The Two Ko Rules</li>
<li>Chapter One: Ko in Action</li>
<li>Chapter Two: The Value of a Ko</li>
<li>Chapter Three: The Value of a Ko Threat</li>
<li>Chapter Four: There is No Ko in the Opening</li>
<li>Chapter Five: Adjacent Ko Threats</li>
<li>Chapter Six: Be the First to Take the Ko</li>
<li>Chapter Seven: Flower-Viewing Kos</li>
<li>Chapter Eight: Maximizing the Number of Ko Threats</li>
<li>Chapter Nine: Ko Threats that Lose Points</li>
<li>Chapter Ten: Invalid Ko Threats</li>
<li>Chapter Eleven: Creating Ko Threats</li>
<li>Chapter Twelve: Using Ko to Make Sabaki</li>
<li>Chapter Thirteen: Double and Triple Kos</li>
<li>Chapter Fourteen: Approach-Move Kos</li>
<li>Chapter Fifteen: Two-and Three-Stage Kos</li>
<li>Chapter Sixteen: The Ten-Thousand Year Ko</li>
<li>Chapter Seventeen: Bent Four in the Corner</li>
<li>Chapter Eighteen: Super Kos</li>
<li>Chapter Nineteen: The Carpenter&#8217;s Square</li>
<li>Chapter Twenty: Problems and Example GAmes</li>
<li>Appendix: Further Reading</li>
</ol>
<h3>Recommended Vendors:</h3>
<ol>
<li>Kiseido &#8211; <a title="Kiseido Order Form" href="http://www.kiseido.com/go_books.htm">$25.00</a> (S&amp;H not included)</li>
</ol>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Last updated June 9th, 2013</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2796</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Book Review: 1001 Life and Death Problems</title>
		<link>/book-review-1001-life-and-death-problems/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2013 09:00:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fundamentals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[go problems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life and death]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tsumego]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=1553</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Overall Rating: 5 / 5 Ponnuki Basic Information Title: Mastering the Basics, Volume 2 &#8211; One Thousand and One Life-and-Death Problems Authors: Compiled and edited by Richard Bozulich Publisher: Kiseido Publication Date: February 2002 Page Length: 244 pages Number of Problems: 1001 problems (what else did you expect? =D) Synopsis New and refreshing approach to teaching life and death. Appropriate [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/04/mtb2cover.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2694" alt="mtb2cover" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/04/mtb2cover.jpg?resize=300%2C450" width="300" height="450" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">Overall Rating: 5 / 5 Ponnuki</h2>
<h3>Basic Information</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Title:</strong> Mastering the Basics, Volume 2 &#8211; One Thousand and One Life-and-Death Problems</li>
<li><strong>Authors: </strong>Compiled and edited by Richard Bozulich</li>
<li><strong>Publisher: </strong>Kiseido</li>
<li><strong>Publication Date: </strong>February 2002</li>
<li><strong>Page Length:</strong> 244 pages</li>
<li><strong>Number of Problems</strong>: 1001 problems (what else did you expect? =D)</li>
</ul>
<h3>Synopsis</h3>
<ul>
<li>New and refreshing approach to teaching life and death.</li>
<li>Appropriate for 12 kyu and stronger.</li>
<li>Recommended for casual players.</li>
</ul>
<p><span id="more-1553"></span></p>
<h3>Detailed Review</h3>
<h4>Readability &#8211; 8 / 10</h4>
<p>The directions for the problems don&#8217;t get any simpler. You have one of two directions: Black to kill or Black to live. This can be slightly confusing for those who wish for more specific directions whether life means seki or not; but this is more accurate to what players must do in their actual games. In addition, the explanation are on the shorter side in order to accommodate the large number of problems. Due to the lack of variations, the readability of the book is rather difficult since there will be times where you are unsure of why your answer is wrong. However, since players purchasing this book are aiming to master the basics and progress into intermediate and hard life and death problems, the format of the book is a great stepping stone for doing so.</p>
<h4>Content Quality &#8211; 10 / 10</h4>
<p>The content quality is primarily boosted by the way that the problems are categorized. You start with one move problems (to kill or live), and then work your way up to three move problems and then five move problems. As a result, each section is carefully designed to meet those requirements and allow players to get a much better grasp of life and death concepts before jumping to something more advanced. Very high marks for this categorization method.</p>
<h4>Final Thoughts</h4>
<p>This book is not for the faint-hearted. 1,001 problems is a lot more difficult than it seems and it can get tiring at times. However, I cannot stress enough how great this book is at giving players a really good structure for practicing and reinforcing basic life and death skills. It may not cover every life and death problem category that exists out there, but it focuses on the important ones that you will generally see at the beginner and intermediate level. In addition, it gives players great practice in increasing the number of moves they are able to see in their head. So if you&#8217;re looking to focus on life and death problems that provide a challenge that won&#8217;t bore you to death, this is the book for you.</p>
<h4>Table of Contents</h4>
<ol>
<li>Preface</li>
<li>Some Important Terms and Concepts</li>
<li>Part One &#8211; One-move problems &#8211; Black to live</li>
<li>Part Two &#8211; One-move problems &#8211; Black to kill</li>
<li>Part Three &#8211; Three-move problems &#8211; Black to live</li>
<li>Part Four &#8211; Three-move problems &#8211; Black to kill</li>
<li>Part Five- Five-move problems &#8211; Black to live</li>
<li>Part Six- Five-move problems &#8211; Black to kill</li>
</ol>
<h4>Recommended Vendors:</h4>
<ol>
<li>Kiseido &#8211; <a title="Kiseido Order Form" href="http://www.kiseido.com/go_books.htm">$21.00</a> (S&amp;H not included)</li>
</ol>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Last updated May 14th, 2013 &#8211; 5 kyu</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1553</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Book Review: 501 Opening Problems</title>
		<link>/book-review-501-opening-problems/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2013 23:30:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beginning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[opening]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[principles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[problems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tsumego]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=2635</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Overall Rating: 4 / 5 Ponnuki Basic Information Title: Mastering the Basics, Volume 1 &#8211; Five Hundred and One Opening Problems Authors: Richard Bozulich in collaboration with Rob van Zeijst Publisher: Kiseido Publication Date: August 2002 Page Length: 256 pages Number of Problems: 501 Synopsis A great basic book about opening problems that utilizes proverbs as directions instead of vague [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/04/mtb1cover.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2636" alt="mtb1cover" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/04/mtb1cover.jpg?resize=300%2C427" width="300" height="427" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">Overall Rating: 4 / 5 Ponnuki</h2>
<h3>Basic Information</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Title:</strong> Mastering the Basics, Volume 1 &#8211; Five Hundred and One Opening Problems</li>
<li><strong>Authors: </strong>Richard Bozulich in collaboration with Rob van Zeijst</li>
<li><strong>Publisher: </strong>Kiseido</li>
<li><strong>Publication Date: </strong>August 2002</li>
<li><strong>Page Length:</strong> 256 pages</li>
<li><strong>Number of Problems</strong>: 501</li>
</ul>
<h3>Synopsis</h3>
<ul>
<li>A great basic book about opening problems that utilizes proverbs as directions instead of vague statements.</li>
<li>Appropriate for 10 kyu and stronger.</li>
<li>Recommended for serious players.</li>
</ul>
<p><span id="more-2635"></span></p>
<h3>Detailed Review</h3>
<h4>Readability &#8211; 9 / 10</h4>
<p>The directions and explanations in this book are rather in depth for the number of problems in the book. While it may go over some players&#8217; head if they are not familiar with opening concepts, the explanations are long enough that players of the appropriate level will understand it fully while newer players will at least get some exposure to new ideas.</p>
<h4>Content Quality &#8211; 10 / 10</h4>
<p>One of my favorite aspects about this book is that their directions consist of principles like &#8220;Neutralize your opponent&#8217;s thickness while establishing a base for yourself&#8221; in order to give you a better idea of how to approach the problem. There are more principles than I can count on both hands and they are applied to a number of different scenarios. As a result, this book earns a perfect score since the reader is forced to think strategically in addition to figuring out the right move.</p>
<h4>Final Thoughts</h4>
<p>Since this book is part of the series geared toward helping players master the basics, I have found that <em>Five Hundred and One Opening Problems</em> does a great job exposing the player to a lot of different opening concepts and principles. I personally wish there was a bit more structure as to helping the players truly grasp each principle before moving on to other principles, but it is a great start for any player looking to get a better understanding of the opening.</p>
<h4>Table of Contents</h4>
<ol>
<li>Preface</li>
<li>Some Important Terms and Concepts</li>
<li>Introduction</li>
<li>How to Use This Book</li>
<li>501 Opening Problems</li>
</ol>
<h4>Recommended Vendors:</h4>
<ol>
<li>Kiseido &#8211; <a title="Kiseido Order Form" href="http://www.kiseido.com/go_books.htm">$21.00</a> (S&amp;H not included)</li>
<li>SmartGo Books (eBook) &#8211; <a href="http://www.smartgo.com/booksbycategory.htm">$8.99</a> (Apple users only)</li>
</ol>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Last updated May 14th, 2013 &#8211; 5 kyu</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2635</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Yuan Zhou Monthly Workshop</title>
		<link>/yuan-zhou-monthly-workshop-2/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2013 22:30:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[black]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[even]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lee changho]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[park junghwan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[resignation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tsumego]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[victory]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[workshop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yuan zhou]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=1650</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Yesterday, I had the pleasure of attending another one of Yuan Zhou&#8216;s Monthly Workshops! We started off with a life and death problem that is called &#8220;hunting the 6 stone bird.&#8221; Apparently it&#8217;s a very old problem that has been around for a long time, for those wondering what the shape looks like. For those [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday, I had the pleasure of attending another one of <a title="Yuan Zhou's Website" href="http://www.zhouyuan.com/">Yuan Zhou</a>&#8216;s Monthly Workshops!<br />
We started off with a life and death problem that is called &#8220;hunting the 6 stone bird.&#8221; Apparently it&#8217;s a very old problem that has been around for a long time, for those wondering what the shape looks like. For those who would like to try it out for themselves, here it is below:<br />
<figure id="attachment_1663" style="width: 250px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/01/6stonebird.png"><img class="size-full wp-image-1663" alt="6stonebird" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/01/6stonebird.png?resize=250%2C250" width="250" height="250" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Black to play.</figcaption></figure>
Afterwards, I got to hear a very captivating  review for one of <a title="Lee Chang Ho's Page" href="http://senseis.xmp.net/?YiChangHo">Lee Changho</a> 9p Vs. <a title="Park Jung Hwan's Page" href="http://senseis.xmp.net/?ParkJungHwan">Park Junghwan</a> 9p games in the most recent Ing Cup World Go Championship. It was one that was full of full of suspense, excitement, and a capturing battle on epic proportions that made Park Junghwan the decisive victor.<br />
As I listened to Yuan Zhou review the game, there were a few things that really struck me:<br />
<span id="more-1650"></span></p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Professionals pay particular attention to their weak groups</strong>. They almost never let a weak group go unattended for more than a move or two.</li>
<li><strong>Professionals never play follow the leader.</strong> They try to figure out what their opponent is trying to do, and then usually come up with a move to interrupt the flow of their opponent&#8217;s game.</li>
<li><strong>Professional games tend to steer away from killing groups.</strong> The reasons lies in the fact that it is very difficult to kill a group and you usually end up sacrificing a lot of points in the process of attempting to do so.</li>
</ol>
<p>In addition, one of the biggest takeaways I had from the entire workshop is <strong>how incredibly important life and death is</strong>. I mean, sure, we all know that life and death is &#8220;important,&#8221; but I think that most players brush it off as a tedious chore that gets in the way of their game. And while I will be sure to write an article further detailing my new found appreciation for life and death, I leave you with this thought: Imagine the possibilities if you could live wherever you invaded/reduced. Wouldn&#8217;t every game become far more simpler?<br />
After the review, we had lunch and played a game with one another. As I looked back on my game, I believe that the reverse komi (-7.5 points) caused my opponent to take more risks than he needed to. In addition, our ranks are most likely about equal, so I believe that the game was rather lopsided to begin with. With that in mind, I do think that my play overall was rather poor and still shows a lack of my attention to the fundamentals of strong players.<br />

<div id='glift_display2' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display2","sgf":"http:\/\/bengozen.com\/\/wp-content\/uploads\/2013\/01\/2013.01.14-Yuan-Zhou-Monthly-Workshop.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='//wp-content/uploads/2013/01/2013.01.14-Yuan-Zhou-Monthly-Workshop.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center">[download label=&#8221;Download Kifu&#8221;]//wp-content/uploads/2013/01/2013.01.14-Yuan-Zhou-Monthly-Workshop.sgf[/download]
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1650</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
