<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>playing &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/playing/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>Experience on the Battlefield</title>
		<link>/experience-on-the-battlefield/</link>
		<comments>/experience-on-the-battlefield/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2014 11:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Weekly Go Wednesday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[battlefield]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[experience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[games]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[more]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[playing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[studying too much]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=10</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Weekly Go Wednesday, Issue #41 As many of you are aware, I have been known to prioritize studying and have had no qualms sacrificing playing games in order to do so. My rationale at the time was quite simple: Because I felt like I was always on a time crunch, reading books, studying problems, or [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 style="text-align: center;">Weekly Go Wednesday, Issue #41</h2>
<figure id="attachment_5339" style="width: 494px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2012/10/Keybladesandwarriors.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-5339" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2012/10/Keybladesandwarriors.jpg?resize=494%2C371" alt="Credit to Kingdom Hearts 3 Trailer" width="494" height="371" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Screenshot from <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Q5j8lQ9_9Cc">Kingdom Hearts 2 Secret Ending</a></figcaption></figure>
As many of you are aware, I have been known to prioritize studying and have had no qualms sacrificing playing games in order to do so. My rationale at the time was quite simple: Because I felt like I was always on a time crunch, reading books, studying problems, or even watching videos seemed to be better suited to my lifestyle. 15 minutes here&#8230; 5 minutes there&#8230; That way I could keep &#8220;improving&#8221; without the huge time commitment. Right?<br />
Well, maybe only half right. While I might have picked up a thing or two along the way, my experience at the <a title="1st Washington Open Baduk Championship — Part I" href="//1st-washington-open-baduk-championship-part/">1st Washington Baduk Open Championship</a> was rather traumatic. After getting my butt kicked twice in a row after the first round and deep introspection, I realized I needed to play more. So in light of that realization, I thought it only appropriate to write about the importance of experience on the battlefield.<br />
<span id="more-10"></span><br />
The reason I spent so long focusing on studying instead of playing was for the following reasons:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>&#8220;I will only play long games.&#8221;</strong> &#8211; I forget when I came to this conclusion, but I thought that any game less than 30 minutes main time would be &#8220;too short&#8221; for me. Therefore&#8230;</li>
<li><strong>&#8220;Don&#8217;t have enough time.&#8221;</strong> &#8211; Since 30 min main time games took about 1.5 hours to 2 hours, I felt that I never had that block of time to play.</li>
<li><strong>&#8220;I can study anywhere.&#8221;</strong> &#8211; I&#8217;ve never been a huge fan of playing on my mobile phone, so playing games wasn&#8217;t as convenient as studying books / problems.</li>
</ol>
<p>I mean, sure, I played a few games here and there; but I didn&#8217;t play consistently and definitely did not play as seriously as I might have if I played ranked games. So to no one&#8217;s surprise, my stamina at the tournament was just awful.<br />
After talking with Myung and learning that most Korean players actually play with 10 minute main time, it made me realize that my mandate of only playing &#8220;long games&#8221; was ridiculous and would only stunt my growth. And since I&#8217;ve made the change to play with shorter time settings, it&#8217;s made a huge difference for me.<br />
Whether you like it or not, your skills are only as good as they are on the battlefield. It&#8217;s irrelevant if you can solve dan level problems on your cell phone if you keep making basic mistakes in your actual games.<br />
No amount of book reading or problem solving can replace the invaluable experience of playing actual games, so get out there and play! Brace yourself for the biting wind of intense and competitive play as you charge into the fray to temper your blade. Charge!!!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/experience-on-the-battlefield/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>33</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">10</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Maintaining a Higher Quality of Learning</title>
		<link>/maintaining-higher-quality-learning/</link>
		<comments>/maintaining-higher-quality-learning/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2013 01:51:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[change]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[improvement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[playing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[revision]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=4047</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[So my resolution to play one game a day has ultimately fallen through. As time went on, my games began deteriorating in quality and each game began to feel more like a chore that I needed to hurry and finish instead of a learning experience. After feeling like this for a few days, I decided [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_4048" style="width: 400px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/09/quality-assurance.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-4048" alt="Credit to MediaWhiz" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/09/quality-assurance.jpg?resize=400%2C293" width="400" height="293" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Credit to <a href="http://www.mediawhiz.com/trust-quality-score-for-quality-results-2">MediaWhiz</a></figcaption></figure>
So my resolution to play one game a day has ultimately fallen through. As time went on, my games began deteriorating in quality and each game began to feel more like a chore that I needed to hurry and finish instead of a learning experience. After feeling like this for a few days, I decided to that I needed to re-examine what I was doing before I started developing bad habits. Instead of just stopping the idea as a whole however, I decided to revise it to the following: <strong>Play 1 game of go / thoroughly review one of your previous games per day.</strong><br />
As an active blogger, I face some challenges when it comes to things like generating content. One of the pieces of content that people seem to like are the game reviews. However, I found that trying to find time to play one game a day every day was making it difficult for me to find time to review my games. In addition, even though it doesn&#8217;t normally take too long for some people to review their games, I have been trying to make my reviews much more thorough and explain each move as I go. So as you might guess, it takes me a lot longer to review games than one might normally take.<br />
By doing this, I hope to not only reinforce my own understanding of the game; but to also make the reviews more useful to readers of various levels. In addition, by allowing myself the option to choose between playing and reviewing, I am hoping I will be able to maintain a higher quality of learning for myself while generating content for the blog. And for someone with a crazy schedule like me, being able to save that kind of time will do wonders for the other aspects of my life. With that said, hopefully my revised discipline inspires some of you to possibly take a similar route with your study as well. =)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/maintaining-higher-quality-learning/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>10</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">4047</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Finding Time for One Game a Day</title>
		<link>/finding-time-one-game-day/</link>
		<comments>/finding-time-one-game-day/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2013 20:16:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[consistently]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[experience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finding time]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[getting stronger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[one game a day]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[playing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[time]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=3981</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[As many of you are aware, I recently started a discipline of playing at least one game a day. And while I am happy to report that I have been keeping up with it, it occurred to me that there are many people out there who would probably like to attempt something similar; but decide [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/09/findingtime.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-3985" alt="findingtime" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/09/findingtime.jpg?resize=270%2C270" width="270" height="270" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></p>
<p>As many of you are aware, I recently started a discipline of playing at least one game a day. And while I am happy to report that I have been keeping up with it, it occurred to me that there are many people out there who would probably like to attempt something similar; but decide not to due to assuming that it would be too &#8220;time consuming.&#8221; So, I thought that I would go ahead and write about my experience on finding time for one game a day.<br />
<span id="more-3981"></span><br />
When I tried playing blitz (e.g., only 5 periods of 10 second byoyomi) in order to satisfy my &#8220;one game a day,&#8221; I found that the game was more of a blur than an experience and felt like I didn&#8217;t gain anything. After all, blitz games are more about intuition than anything else. On the other hand, when I tried to play a game of typical tournament length (e.g., 30 min main time), I would find my games taking anywhere from an hour to two (which any working person who wants any semblance of a life would agree is death). Therefore, after some experimenting with different time settings, I have found that 10 minutes main time and 3x 30 second byoyomi is about right since it strikes a nice balance between intuition and thinking while not taking too much time out of my day.<br />
Some might quote me on how I once stated that even 20 minute main time games were too short for me; however, the key difference between my analysis then and now is the fact that my focus used to be giving myself the most optimal conditions for winning a game. However, I have come to learn that that approach was too slow. I am fully aware and accept the fact that I will make many mistakes and lose many games as a result of not being able to think every move thoroughly, but the consistent practice and application is something that I am hoping will be beneficial in the long run. After all, the goal with this discipline is not to win; but to gain more experience while not putting a huge strain on your time.<br />
So for those who tend to find themselves studying instead of playing, I ask that you give this habit a shot. Whether it&#8217;s just one game every 3 days or just once a week, go out there, get your feet wet and just play. I don&#8217;t care if it&#8217;s under a secret account that you hide away from the rest of the world, but the important thing is that you do it. That way, when the time comes for you to take the plunge and participate in a tournament, you&#8217;ll feel a lot more comfortable with playing a game and have a much better chance of showing what you&#8217;ve been learning instead of losing because you are rusty from playing.<br />
At the end of the day, no matter how good you are at the various aspects of go (i.e., fuseki, joseki, tesuji, life and death, endgame, etc.), you are only as good as your ability to transition between these skills during a game. The faster you are at moving between them, the better your analysis will be and the stronger you will inevitably be. And no matter what anyone else says, there is nothing that can train this ability better than playing games. So what are you waiting for, get out there and play some go!<br />
<em>For anyone who is wondering where I am playing my daily games, I alternate between KGS and Tygem depending on my mood. Lately, I have been more partial to Tygem since it&#8217;s really easy to find a game and I get to play against players much stronger than me. You are welcome to follow me on my alternate account (that I created awhile ago for the 5 dan Tygem training frozensoul suggested to me): zenblade.  </em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/finding-time-one-game-day/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3981</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
