<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>how to deal with a troll &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/how-to-deal-with-a-troll/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>&#034;Play Against a Troll and Win!&#034; Achievement Complete!</title>
		<link>/play-against-a-troll-and-win-achievement-complete/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2012 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kifu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[achievement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how to deal with a troll]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kifu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[troll]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weiqi]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=31</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[ANNOUNCEMENT: All the games will now come with full commentary in order to minimize the complication of having to flip back and forth between the blog post and the game. I will do my best to diligently put down any variations I saw and why I played the moves that I did. So please be [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>ANNOUNCEMENT: All the games will now come with full commentary<del> in order to minimize the complication of having to flip back and forth between the blog post and the game</del>. I will do my best to diligently put down any variations I saw and why I played the moves that I did. So please be sure to <del>visit the link and then</del> let me know your thoughts! Enjoy! </strong><br />
This was a pretty scary game for me. I know I&#8217;ve been playing stronger opponents in the ASR League in even matches, but for some reason playing a ranked game against a 3k gave me the jitters. And I didn&#8217;t go looking for this game, this guy challenged me. Looking back on it, I&#8217;m pretty sure he was trying to play against weaker players so he could feel all big and mighty. Too bad he came out the loser&#8230;.<br />
<span id="more-31"></span><br />

<div id='glift_display1' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display1","sgf":"http:\/\/bengozen.com\/\/wp-content\/uploads\/2012\/09\/2012.09.20-Play-Against-a-Troll.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='//wp-content/uploads/2012/09/2012.09.20-Play-Against-a-Troll.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">[download label=&#8221;Download Kifu&#8221;]//wp-content/uploads/2012/09/2012.09.20-Play-Against-a-Troll.sgf[/download]
<p>This is definitely a game that I&#8217;m certainly proud to call my own. In addition, I had never really experienced playing against a troll until this game. If you want a glimpse as to what I&#8217;m talking about, you can see it in the kifu (more profanity and name calling occurs afterwards, but you&#8217;ll get the gist of it based on what I left in the record).<br />
I think this is a game that any players below 10k might find useful. So please check it out and hopefully you&#8217;ll learn something new from my game!<br />
As a final note, for players who have never encountered trolls before and have no idea how to deal with them properly, here is some advice from my personal experience today</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">1. <strong>Do not stoop to their level</strong> &#8211; In other words, don&#8217;t curse. Don&#8217;t insult. Nada. Nothing. Zip. Otherwise you can forget about reporting them to an admin and gaining any sympathy.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">2. <strong>Report it to an admin</strong> &#8211; This is particularly recommended when your opponent has either escaped and/or is threatening to drag the game on till the end of time by using byoyomi forever&#8230;. And if you&#8217;re wondering how to find an admin on KGS, they have a star symbol next to their username.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">3. <strong>Vent about it with a friend, and then move on</strong> &#8211; Thankfully I had frozensoul there at the time, who saw the debacle go down when it happened, and he helped me through it and thus I&#8217;ve come out unscathed. But seriously, once you&#8217;ve vented, don&#8217;t let the troll impact your joy and happiness in playing go. Completely not worth it.</p>
<p>That being said, I hope you guys will enjoy the commentary and the new format. Till next time!<br />
<del>In case anyone is wondering, it seems that the new updated template for Blogger seems to override the code for embedding Eidogo into the blog posts, so that&#8217;s the reason I&#8217;ve had to resort to linking out onto Eidogo. Sorry for the inconvenience!</del></p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">31</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
