<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>Websites &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/reviews/websites/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>My Experience with YSD &#8211; S9 &#8211; Part 2</title>
		<link>/experience-ysd-s9-part-2/</link>
		<comments>/experience-ysd-s9-part-2/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2014 15:33:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kifu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Websites]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yunguseng dojang]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5515</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Part I &#8211; Part II &#8211; Part III Overview With one month of Yunguseng Dojang (YSD) in my pocket, I was ready to take on this next month with a whole new perspective. However, this month would not be the bright new sunshine that I thought it would be. Lectures &#38; Homework For this month, the three [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><a title="My Experience with YSD — S9 — Part 1" href="//experience-ysd-s9-part-1/">Part I</a> &#8211; <strong>Part II</strong> &#8211; Part III</p>
<h2 id="overview">Overview</h2>
<p>With one month of <a title="Yunguseng Dojang Official Site" href="http://www.yunguseng.com/">Yunguseng Dojang</a> (YSD) in my pocket, I was ready to take on this next month with a whole new perspective. However, this month would not be the bright new sunshine that I thought it would be.<br />
<span id="more-5515"></span></p>
<h2 id="lecturesamphomework">Lectures &amp; Homework</h2>
<p>For this month, the three lecture topics were:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://ayd.yunguseng.com/videos/index.php?id=1219">Analyze the most often played patterns: Star point chapter</a></li>
<li><a href="http://ayd.yunguseng.com/videos/index.php?id=1256">Analyze the most often played patterns: 3–4 point chapter</a></li>
<li><a href="http://ayd.yunguseng.com/videos/index.php?id=1296">Approach to the 4–4 enclosed corner</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Though I didn’t get a chance to watch all the lectures, the material that I did watch and study contained very pertinent information in common patterns that typically appear in games.</p>
<h2 id="mygames">My Games</h2>
<h3 id="round6" style="text-align: center;">Round 6</h3>
<p><strong>Preliminary Thoughts</strong> &#8211; With my first match being against my friend nadoss, I was a little nervous since I always feel kind of weird when playing a friend in a competitive nature where something is at stake (i.e., our rank in YSD). In addition, I knew that nadoss could play at a level higher than his rank, so I was trying hard to remember not to take him lightly.<br />

<div id='glift_display1' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display1","sgf":"http:\/\/bengozen.com\/\/wp-content\/uploads\/2014\/07\/YSD-S9-Round6.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='//wp-content/uploads/2014/07/YSD-S9-Round6.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">[download label=&#8221;Download Kifu&#8221;]//wp-content/uploads/2014/07/YSD-S9-Round6.sgf[/download]
<p><strong>After the Game</strong> &#8211; While I managed to win, it was a victory of mixed feelings. On the one hand, I was glad to win the first round of month 2, but on the other hand, I did not feel like I played as well I could have.<br />
<strong>After the Review</strong> &#8211; Overall I wasn’t criticized too much for my play, but there were certainly mistakes here and there. I think the only thing I did well was being able to keep a whole board focus for some of the critical points in the game. However, this is not something I feel any pride in because there is a 5 stone difference between us anyways.</p>
<h3 id="round7" style="text-align: center;">Round 7</h3>
<p><strong>Preliminary Thoughts</strong> &#8211; This week I’m playing a 5 kyu. For some reason, playing even games against players with a lower rank than me by 2 stones or more makes me nervous. I guess I’m worried that I’ll get overconfident and underestimate my opponent, and then lose!! Haha. Ah well, just have to remember to play the best moves I possibly can. As long as I do that, I’m hoping I’ll have no regrets.<br />

<div id='glift_display2' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display2","sgf":"http:\/\/bengozen.com\/\/wp-content\/uploads\/2014\/07\/YSD-S9-Round7.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='//wp-content/uploads/2014/07/YSD-S9-Round7.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">[download label=&#8221;Download Kifu&#8221;]//wp-content/uploads/2014/07/YSD-S9-Round7.sgf[/download]
<p><strong>After the Game</strong> &#8211; The game ended up boiling down to a huge capturing race. It wasn’t necessary, but I got it in my head that it was time for White to die and I nearly killed myself in the process. Completely unnecessary and a poor decision on my part. On top of that, I even proudly played an empty triangle because I thought it was the firmest way to kill. <em>hangs head in shame</em><br />
<strong>After the Review</strong> &#8211; Inseong essentially confirmed my thoughts on the game. In fact, if anything there was probably more negative things to say about the game than positive. I was just fortunate that my slack moves were not punished properly. I really need to work on my mindset when playing people a couple stones or more weaker than I am…</p>
<h3 id="round8" style="text-align: center;">Round 8</h3>
<p><strong>Preliminary Thoughts</strong> &#8211; Prior to playing this game, I went on a 5 game losing streak* that very day. I was in the worst of moods and clearly on tilt. So as I geared up to play the 4k of our group, part of me flinched at the idea since my last loss was to a 4k as well. And I know that my opponent was no ordinary 4k, so as I prepared to challenge him to our match, I couldn’t help but feel some dread at adding a 6th loss to my day.<br />
*<em>And if you’re wondering how bad it was, my rank dropped from 2k to 4k. Yup. That bad.</em><br />

<div id='glift_display3' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display3","sgf":"http:\/\/bengozen.com\/\/wp-content\/uploads\/2014\/07\/YSD-S9-Round8.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='//wp-content/uploads/2014/07/YSD-S9-Round8.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">[download label=&#8221;Download Kifu&#8221;]//wp-content/uploads/2014/07/YSD-S9-Round8.sgf[/download]
<p><strong>After the Game</strong> &#8211; I can’t believe I won. When I was counting towards the end, I was pretty sure I was behind by like 10 points (although I will admit I completely forgot I had komi, but nonetheless I would have still been behind according to my rough estimates). While a relief in one respect, it definitely felt like a growing moment as the game was very different from my normal aggressive game. It was surprisingly calm.<br />
<strong>After the Review</strong> &#8211; Overall the review went pretty well. I missed a couple of key points that would have been pretty bad for me if my opponent was able to see it at the time; but there wasn’t anything overly critical. So all in all, I’m pretty happy with the result of the game and my ability to stay in control till the very end (considering how bent up I was at the time).</p>
<h3 id="round9" style="text-align: center;">Round 9</h3>
<p><strong>Preliminary Thoughts</strong> &#8211; Tonight’s opponent is one that I was rather worried about because he had an atypical playing style. In summary, he was very comfortable using 5–3 as one of his opening moves. Being as how I have little experience with it, I was admittedly worried. So while I did try to read up on 5–3 a little bit, I didn’t feel as prepared as I would have liked before playing this game.<br />

<div id='glift_display4' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display4","sgf":"http:\/\/bengozen.com\/\/wp-content\/uploads\/2014\/07\/YSD-S9-Round9.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='//wp-content/uploads/2014/07/YSD-S9-Round9.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">[download label=&#8221;Download Kifu&#8221;]//wp-content/uploads/2014/07/YSD-S9-Round9.sgf[/download]
<p><strong>After the Game</strong> &#8211; Losing the game was rough because it meant that I was not guaranteed a promotion anymore. In addition, I thought that I was in control for a good portion of the game; but ended up giving up away too much in the center and lost. Sigh. Frustrated for sure…<br />
<strong>After the Review</strong> &#8211; Sometimes the most frustrating thing is knowing you were right about being in control for a good portion of the game. And then when you make one single error that goofs up your entire advantage…. Argh! Makes you just want to throw your hands up in disbelief at your own incompetence… Although on an interesting note, I was very close to discovering a tesuji that would have allowed me to win the game. So that&#8217;s pretty cool.</p>
<h3 id="round10" style="text-align: center;">Round 10</h3>
<p><strong>Preliminary Thoughts</strong> &#8211; Once again, I was put in the position of having my final match be the determining factor between whether I get promoted or not. Sigh. And on top of that, I was fighting a slump so the pressure was not helping at all…<br />

<div id='glift_display5' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display5","sgf":"http:\/\/bengozen.com\/\/wp-content\/uploads\/2014\/07\/YSD-S9-Round10.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='//wp-content/uploads/2014/07/YSD-S9-Round10.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">[download label=“Download Kifu”]//wp-content/uploads/2014/07/YSD-S9-Round10.sgf[/download]
<p><strong>After the Game</strong> &#8211; I lost… Once again… I choked at the final moment and loss. Just no words at this time. Can’t even stay for the review because of how frustrated I am with my go.<br />
<strong>After the Review</strong> &#8211; It wasn’t until a few days later that I finally sat down to watch the review. To my surprise, sabum-nim actually had mostly positive things to say about my gameplay. Granted, in the end my opponent triumphed and destroyed me; but at least the game wasn’t hopeless. So while I was really bummed out after the game, I’m at least glad that the review wasn’t as horrible as I thought it would be.</p>
<h2 id="finalthoughts">Final Thoughts</h2>
<p>This has been a rough month for me, but a lot of it has to do with other factors and not so much with YSD itself. The YSD games certainly showed my decline and poor play over the month, but they are certainly not to blame. At the bare minimum, I am at least grateful to Inseong for his reviews and insights so that I can patch up my mistakes and continue getting stronger. Here’s to hoping next month is better.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a title="My Experience with YSD — S9 — Part 1" href="//experience-ysd-s9-part-1/">Part I</a> &#8211; <strong>Part II</strong> &#8211; Part III</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/experience-ysd-s9-part-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">5515</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>My Experience with YSD &#8211; S9 &#8211; Part 1</title>
		<link>/experience-ysd-s9-part-1/</link>
		<comments>/experience-ysd-s9-part-1/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2014 11:15:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kifu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Websites]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[anatoly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brian]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[commentary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dojang]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kifu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[league]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oren]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sauk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[season 9]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yunguseng]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5395</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Part I &#8211; Part II &#8211; Part III Overview Prelude: Out of respect to Sabum-nim (i.e., In-seong), the lessons learned are kept to a minimum since it is paid content and I do not want to infringe on that in any way, shape, or form. The game reviews also only contain highlights of concise highlights instead of my normal detailed [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>Part I</strong> &#8211; <a title="My Experience with YSD — S9 — Part 2" href="//experience-ysd-s9-part-2/">Part II</a> &#8211; Part III</p>
<h2>Overview</h2>
<p><em>Prelude: Out of respect to Sabum-nim (i.e., In-seong), the lessons learned are kept to a minimum since it is paid content and I do not want to infringe on that in any way, shape, or form. The game reviews also only contain highlights of concise highlights instead of my normal detailed reviews since I would inadvertently write about what Sabum-nim taught in the review (which would essentially replicate his lecture). </em><br />
As a new member to the <a title="Yunguseng Dojang Official Site" href="http://www.yunguseng.com/">Yunguseng Dojang</a> (YSD) during Season 9 of 2014, I was assigned to League A as my starting league (this is the highest league possible in the American division). I wasn&#8217;t sure what I was to expect, but I was excited at the prospect at being part of a formal training program.<br />
<span id="more-5395"></span></p>
<h2>Lectures &amp; Homework</h2>
<p>For this month, the three lecture topics were:</p>
<ol>
<li><a href="http://ayd.yunguseng.com/videos/index.php?id=1138">Knight move across attachment / Break the dog&#8217;s face / Indirect defense</a></li>
<li><a title="1-3-5 Opening Link" href="http://ayd.yunguseng.com/videos/index.php?id=1156">1-3-5 opening</a></li>
<li><a title="All About 3-3 Invasion Link" href="http://ayd.yunguseng.com/videos/index.php?id=1174">All about 3-3 invasion</a></li>
</ol>
<p>Overall, I felt that Sabum-nim was very good at selecting topics that were relevant to his students. After watching his student&#8217;s play their games, he would often notice trends that were occurring and would then select lecture topics to address them.<br />
In addition, the lectures were much more valuable if you could attend them in person because he made them interactive. There were usually numerous examples to show what he was trying to illustrate and to give the students a chance to show whether or not they understood what was being taught.<br />
Unfortunately, I was didn&#8217;t end up participating in the second aspect of lectures which were the homework (which consists of taking what you learned in the lecture and applying it to your own games). I&#8217;m sure I could come up with some bogus excuse for why I couldn&#8217;t do it, but it was my own fault and I plan to do every homework next month.<br />
Finally, another thing cool thing that Sabum-nim does is a lecture series that highlights the most important points from the games played that week (from both Europe and America division). It&#8217;s a cool series that has a lot of concise highlights and cool techniques that came up in actual games.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: left;">My Games</h2>
<h3 style="text-align: center;">Round 1</h3>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>Preliminary Thoughts</strong> &#8211; As this was the first game I would play in YSD, I felt a lot of pressure to try and play the best go I possibly could. To top it off, my opponent was known as one of the strongest players in the league, so I was more anxious than I would&#8217;ve liked. And so one of the things I did was to play out the game on a real board simultaneously. By doing so, I was hoping it would calm me down.</p>

<div id='glift_display6' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display6","sgf":"http:\/\/bengozen.com\/\/wp-content\/uploads\/2014\/06\/YSD-S9-Round1.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='//wp-content/uploads/2014/06/YSD-S9-Round1.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">[download label=&#8221;Download Kifu&#8221;]//wp-content/uploads/2014/06/YSD-S9-Round1.sgf[/download]
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>After the Game</strong> &#8211; Playing the game out on a real board ended up helping me calm down, but it also led to me being more adventurous/experimental and to also lose on time. When the pop-up flashed, &#8220;bengozen loses on time,&#8221; I sat there flustered as I tried to collect myself in thinking that at least I played a good game.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>After the Review</strong> &#8211; Turns out I was wrong on all counts. Not only was I not complimented on my play, but I was shown how badly I should have lost. I made numerous mistakes and deserved to lose (even regardless of time). Sigh. Definitely did not make the good impression I wanted to make on Sabum-nim.</p>
<h3 style="text-align: center;">Round 2</h3>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>Preliminary Thoughts</strong> &#8211; Since my last game was so disastrous, I was eager to yet again prove myself. Similar to the first match however, my opponent was considered one of the strongest players in the league as well, so there was a bit of pressure to try and do well against the veteran.</p>

<div id='glift_display7' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display7","sgf":"http:\/\/bengozen.com\/\/wp-content\/uploads\/2014\/06\/YSD-S9-Round2.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='//wp-content/uploads/2014/06/YSD-S9-Round2.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">[download label=&#8221;Download Kifu&#8221;]//wp-content/uploads/2014/06/YSD-S9-Round2.sgf[/download]
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>After the Game</strong> &#8211; Though I lost my Round 1 game in part due to experimenting, I still ended up doing it again this round. And just like before, I lost again. I was really starting to doubt my abilities as a player and whether I even belonged in League A.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>After the Review</strong> &#8211; Similar to the Round 1, I didn&#8217;t play particularly well this game either. The only reprieve that I got was that the game resulted in a fun reading problem on the bottom that Sabum-nim liked. Otherwise than that though, I was still feeling pretty crappy about my performance so far.</p>
<h3 style="text-align: center;">Round 3</h3>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>Preliminary Thoughts</strong> &#8211; Seeing as how I had lost my last two games, I had much lower expectations of myself this time around. I really had no idea if I was going to win. If anything, I was simply hoping I wouldn&#8217;t play another game that would add another mark of disappointment to Sabum-nim&#8217;s impression of me.</p>

<div id='glift_display8' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display8","sgf":"http:\/\/bengozen.com\/\/wp-content\/uploads\/2014\/06\/YSD-S9-Round3.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='//wp-content/uploads/2014/06/YSD-S9-Round3.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">[download label=&#8221;Download Kifu&#8221;]//wp-content/uploads/2014/06/YSD-S9-Round3.sgf[/download]
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>After the Game</strong> &#8211; The game was still a rather weird one for me. Still a lot more experimenting than I necessarily would have wanted, but it seemed I was not destined to play games that were in my comfort range. Luckily for me though, I was able to secure an advantage early on that allowed me to win the game.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>After the Review</strong> &#8211; Though this was my first win for YSD, the review still felt a bit mediocre for me overall. What I remember feeling like is that I was really only able to win because of my opponent&#8217;s overplay early on. Otherwise however, it wasn&#8217;t a particularly good game for me either.</p>
<h3 style="text-align: center;">Round 4</h3>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>Preliminary Thoughts</strong> &#8211; I was unable to make the original time scheduled for Round 4, but I was lucky that my opponent could reschedule to the prior Sunday. Unfortunately, unlike my previous games, I was unable to play in a focused state of mind because I was at a local Starbucks and had a lot of other work needed to be done. So I was unable to give this game my all like I normally would.</p>

<div id='glift_display9' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display9","sgf":"http:\/\/bengozen.com\/\/wp-content\/uploads\/2014\/06\/YSD-S9-Round4.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='//wp-content/uploads/2014/06/YSD-S9-Round4.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">[download label=&#8221;Download Kifu&#8221;]//wp-content/uploads/2014/06/YSD-S9-Round4.sgf[/download]
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>After the Game</strong> &#8211; After my opponent resigned, I breathed a sigh of relief; but I was not terribly proud of the game that I had just played. After looking back over it, it was a haphazard game that I was lucky to win only because my opponent made a mistake and I got away with a few overplays that allowed me to reverse the game in my favor. So even though I won, it felt more like I had loss since my play was rather disappointing.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>After the Review</strong> &#8211; Continuing the trend of being a disappointment, Sabum-nim was quick to show how I was able to get away with numerous overplays in order to win the game. &#8220;This wasn&#8217;t supposed to work. And then that wasn&#8217;t supposed to work.&#8221; Although this time around, I knew that my play was rather abysmal since I was unable to give it my all at the time; so I was accepting of his criticism.</p>
<h3 style="text-align: center;">Round 5</h3>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>Preliminary Thoughts</strong> &#8211; With my record at 2-2, my ability to stay in League A rested on this final match. And so the pressure was particularly high for this game since I was unsure if I would be able to pull it off and the idea of being demoted terrified me. On top of all of that, it was against a friend who I&#8217;ve gotten to know quite well over the last few weeks, so it was a mixed bag of emotions as we dove into the epic clash that would determine my fate.</p>

<div id='glift_display10' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display10","sgf":"http:\/\/bengozen.com\/\/wp-content\/uploads\/2014\/06\/YSD-S9-Round5.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='//wp-content/uploads/2014/06/YSD-S9-Round5.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">[download label=&#8221;Download Kifu&#8221;]//wp-content/uploads/2014/06/YSD-S9-Round5.sgf[/download]
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>After the Game</strong> &#8211; After clicking the resign button, I knew my fate was sealed. I was rather downtrodden, but there was a part of me that actually felt really good about the game. Unlike the other games, though I was <a title="My First Demotion" href="//first-demotion/">wrestling with disappointment of demotion at the time</a>, I actually felt like this game was something I could actually be proud of.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>After the Review </strong>&#8211; Finally, after four weeks of being a disappointment, I felt like I was finally able to play a game that Sabum-nim actually approved of. Of course as expected, I made a number of mistakes, but it felt like maybe I had finally played a game worthy of Sabum-nim&#8217;s time and energy. And on top of that, I felt start to awaken inside of me as a result of that game; but more on that later.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: left;">Final Thoughts</h2>
<p style="text-align: left;">When I first learned about how YSD worked, I have to admit that I thought 5 games a month would be a piece of cake. In reality, it is actually more difficult than it sounds since the games often take more than 90 minutes to complete and are scheduled. And well, you all know how life likes to get in the way of things. Nonetheless, I was really grateful that the program spurred us on to play more since that was one of my weaker areas at the time.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">As I look back at my thoughts after the reviews, I just wanted to clarify that Sabum-nim is really not an overly harsh or mean teacher. He simply tells it as it is without sugar-coating things since his goal is to teach you where your mistakes are and not to coddle you. In addition, it&#8217;s important to keep in mind that a major component to how I felt after each review derives from the fact that I am extremely self-critical of myself. So what else could you expect from someone rubbing salt into their own wounds? Haha.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">And though I was more disappointed and frustrated about being demoted to League B than I probably should have been, my exposure to League A was a great experience to show the gaps in my skills as a go player. I don&#8217;t know what is in store for me in League B, but I look forward to the challenge of climbing back up to League A. Until next month!</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>Part I</strong> &#8211; <a title="My Experience with YSD — S9 — Part 2" href="//experience-ysd-s9-part-2/">Part II</a> &#8211; Part III</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/experience-ysd-s9-part-1/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>17</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">5395</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Review: BadukTV by GoGameGuru</title>
		<link>/review-baduktv-gogameguru/</link>
		<comments>/review-baduktv-gogameguru/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2013 01:01:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Websites]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[baduktv]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[channel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[english]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gogameguru]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tv]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=4062</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;m happy to announce that I have finally gotten the opportunity to sign up for GoGameGuru&#8217;s (GGG) BadukTV English service! Needless to say, I am thrilled with it! I&#8217;ve only made it through two lessons in their &#8220;Becoming a 5 Kyu&#8221; video series and I am loving it! Not only am I learning a lot, but [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;m happy to announce that I have finally gotten the opportunity to sign up for <a href="http://gogameguru.com/baduk-tv/">GoGameGuru&#8217;s (GGG) BadukTV English</a> service! Needless to say, I am thrilled with it! I&#8217;ve only made it through two lessons in their &#8220;Becoming a 5 Kyu&#8221; video series and I am loving it! Not only am I learning a lot, but it&#8217;s really incredible to be able to watch material that is not game commentary and actually aimed at weak players like me!!!! Ahhh!!! So wonderful!!!!<em><br />
</em><br />
Now, before I go into why I think <a href="http://gogameguru.com/baduk-tv/">BadukTV by GGG</a> is awesome, let me clarify something. Some of you got a chance to watch a BadukTV video that I <a title="Watching BadukTV for the First Time" href="//watching-baduktv-first-time/">posted recently</a>, but I want to remind everyone that <strong>they are completely different services.</strong> The BadukTV English that I posted is from the BadukTV channel that features English speakers and is currently free. BadukTV from GGG on the other hand, is a paid service that focuses on providing popular Korean BadukTV episodes that have English subtitles.<strong><br />
</strong><br />
&#8220;Wait wait wait Ben. Why the hell would I pay for something when I can get it for free?&#8221;<br />
Well it&#8217;s actually quite simple:</p>
<ol>
<li>The problem with free material is that you never know when you&#8217;re going to get new material and whether or not it&#8217;s even going to be helpful to you.</li>
<li>There is no guarantee that the quality of material will be up to par.</li>
<li>The material is most likely going to be more advanced than the typical kyu player will be able to really handle.</li>
</ol>
<p>In other words, let me ask you this: How many videos or lectures have you seen out there that is a lecture series with titles like &#8220;Becoming 5 Kyu&#8221; or &#8220;Level Up to 3 Kyu&#8221;?<br />
<a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/10/thats-what-i-thought.gif"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-4067" alt="thats what i thought" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/10/thats-what-i-thought.gif?resize=245%2C180" width="245" height="180" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><br />
Let&#8217;s face it. There are plenty of material out there with strong players reviewing professional games and trying to go through the variations. And sure, <a href="http://gogameguru.com/baduk-tv/">BadukTV from GGG</a> has those lectures too for stronger players; however, when it comes to videos of professionals lecturing on material that&#8217;s relevant to kyu players who are anxious to get stronger, the Western hemisphere is lacking in this area and BadukTV by GGG helps to fill that empty void many of us long for.<br />
And just in case I haven&#8217;t sold you on their English service, they also have:</p>
<ol>
<li>BadukTV OnDemand &#8211; TV programs that you can stream whenever you want. They don&#8217;t all have subtitles, but like someone reminded me, go transcends all language barriers and you might find yourself understanding more than you expected!</li>
<li>BadukTV Live &#8211; Watch BadukTV live as if you had it as part of your cable service!</li>
<li>BadukTV Mobile &#8211; Watch BadukTV programs right from your mobile device!</li>
</ol>
<p>Bottom line: If you&#8217;re one of those people who wished that that the Western hemisphere could have a channel dedicated to go, you definitely need to check this out. They are providing an incredible service and I hope you&#8217;ll join me in supporting them in their efforts! Be sure to check out their site <a href="http://gogameguru.com/baduk-tv/">here</a> for more information!<br />
PS. And if you have any other questions about the service, please don&#8217;t hesitate to leave a comment below or <a title="Contact" href="//contact/">contact me</a> and I&#8217;ll be sure to answer your questions to the best of my ability!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/review-baduktv-gogameguru/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">4062</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Website Review: Go Teaching Ladder</title>
		<link>/website-review-go-teaching-ladder/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2012 17:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Websites]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[free]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[game reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lessons]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[teaching]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=1316</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Rating: 4 /5 Ponnuki Synopsis: A fantastic resource for game reviews when you don&#8217;t have time for real-time reviews. It&#8217;s FREE!!!! The reviews are not instantaneous, but what you&#8217;d expect from a volunteer based service? Detailed Review: GoTeachingLadder is a fantastic resource for players want to have their games reviewed. As it is a completely [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2012/12/goteachingladdermainpage.png"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-1317" title="Go Teaching Ladder Main Page" alt="Go Teaching Ladder Main Page Screenshot" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2012/12/goteachingladdermainpage.png?resize=497%2C364" width="497" height="364" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></h2>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">Rating: 4 /5 Ponnuki</h2>
<h3 style="text-align: left;">Synopsis:</h3>
<ul>
<li>A fantastic resource for game reviews when you don&#8217;t have time for real-time reviews.</li>
<li>It&#8217;s FREE!!!!</li>
<li>The reviews are not instantaneous, but what you&#8217;d expect from a volunteer based service?</li>
</ul>
<h3 style="text-align: left;">Detailed Review:</h3>
<p style="text-align: left;"><a title="Go Teaching Ladder Website" href="http://gtl.xmp.net/">GoTeachingLadder</a> is a fantastic resource for players want to have their games reviewed.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">As it is a completely volunteer based service, one cannot expect the same level of reviews that you might receive from strong players online; but this does not diminish the value of this website.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">The process for submitting a game for review is very simple:</p>
<ol>
<li>Click the link for submitting a game.</li>
<li>Fill out the form.</li>
<li>Verify that the information is correct.</li>
<li>Submit your request.</li>
<li>Enjoy your game review when you receive it!</li>
</ol>
<p>One of the things about GTL that makes it so effective is the fact that they allow you to ask specific questions about your game so that you can be sure those aspects are given the attention you desire. If it weren&#8217;t for this aspect, the value of the reviews would be diminished greatly.<br />
The only downside to this resource is the fact that the wait time can be up to a couple weeks at a time depending on your reviewer. While you should expect nothing less from a volunteer based site, this can diminish the value of the game reviews since you may not quite remember the lessons as vividly as shortly after the game.<br />
For more information and common questions, visit their FAQ page <a title="Go Teaching Ladder FAQ" href="http://gtl.xmp.net/about/faq">here</a>!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1316</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>New Incredible Go Resource: BadukMovies!!!</title>
		<link>/new-incredible-go-resource-badukmovies/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 10 Nov 2012 13:10:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Websites]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[badukmovies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[videos]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=1095</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hey everyone. I just discovered a brand new go resource that got me so excited I had to post about it instantly! It&#8217;s called BadukMovies and is made by Peter Brouwer 6D and Kim Ouweleen 4D and looks like a magnificent wealth of information. I will put up a detailed review for the site in the future, [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hey everyone. I just discovered a brand new go resource that got me so excited I had to post about it instantly!<br />
It&#8217;s called BadukMovies and is made by Peter Brouwer 6D and Kim Ouweleen 4D and looks like a magnificent wealth of information. I will put up a detailed review for the site in the future, but at the bare minimum I wanted to let you guys know about this site first!</p>
<h1 style="text-align: center;"><a title="Baduk Movies" href="http://www.badukmovies.com/">BadukMovies</a></h1>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1095</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Website Review: Tel&#039;s Go Notes</title>
		<link>/website-review-tels-go-notes/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2010 00:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Websites]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=83</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Review: Tel&#8217;s Go Notes is an excellent website that serves as an amazing companion to the interactive Go tutorials that exist out there on the web.  It&#8217;s purpose is to provide a one stop solution to clarify a lot of mental misconceptions.  A very simple example of this is: What is the object of the [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="https://i1.wp.com/4.bp.blogspot.com/_R3zwHD97QhU/TKsy3RIf08I/AAAAAAAAAR8/LlBK4IZEu-M/s1600/telsgonotes.jpg" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="46" src="https://i1.wp.com/4.bp.blogspot.com/_R3zwHD97QhU/TKsy3RIf08I/AAAAAAAAAR8/LlBK4IZEu-M/s320/telsgonotes.jpg?resize=320%2C46" width="320" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></div>
<div style="font-family: inherit; text-align: center;">
<div style="text-align: left;">
<div style="margin: 0px;"><u><b><span style="font-size: small;">Review:</span></b></u></div>
<div style="margin: 0px;"><u><b><span style="font-size: small;"><br /></span></b></u></div>
<div style="margin: 0px;"><a href="http://www.telgo.com/">Tel&#8217;s Go Notes</a> is an excellent website that serves as an amazing companion to the interactive Go tutorials that exist out there on the web.  It&#8217;s purpose is to provide a one stop solution to clarify a lot of mental misconceptions.  A very simple example of this is: What is the object of the game?  Many of you will scoff at this question and say &#8220;Territory&#8230; duh,&#8221; but when we look over your games you&#8217;ll find that you actually spend significantly more time trying to kill your opponent&#8217;s stones than build territory.  (This is not a terrible thing, but it&#8217;s something you&#8217;ll need to eventually grow out of).</div>
<div style="margin: 0px;"></div>
<div style="margin: 0px;">Tel does an excellent job of taking a lot of basic concepts and explaining them in a simple and straightforward manner.  This is one of the best websites to quickly get a great overview of topics such as <a href="http://www.telgo.com/Minimal.htm">life and death</a>, <a href="http://www.telgo.com/territory/Territory.html">elementary territory building</a>, and <a href="http://www.telgo.com/connections/connections.html">what makes a &#8220;good&#8221; connection</a>.  To be honest, even a number of the beginner books I purchased don&#8217;t cover such topics nearly as well (in terms of clarity and just the right amount of explanation).</div>
<div style="margin: 0px;"></div>
<div style="margin: 0px;">In terms of criticisms, I only have two (and they are just slight nuances).  First, the diagrams (particularly on the home page) are kind of small for my liking.  They get the job done, but I think they can definitely be larger.  For sections such as &#8220;what is a ladder,&#8221; an embedded sgf file would remove the necessity for all those diagrams.  Second, I think the navigability of the site is a little tough.  My suggestion would be to have navigation bars on the top and bottom of the site in order to ease maneuvering around the website.  Again these are but slight nuances in light of a great website.</div>
</div>
</div>
<div style="font-family: inherit;">
<div style="margin: 0px;"></div>
</div>
<div style="font-family: inherit;">
<div style="margin: 0px;"><b><u>Synopsis</u>:</b></div>
<div style="margin: 0px;"><b><br /></b></div>
<div style="margin: 0px;">Although we have plenty of sites trying to teach Go, this one is a one-stop website for beginners that will provide what you need without filtering through a bunch of advanced concepts.  Top notch. </div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">83</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Website Review: Empty Triangle</title>
		<link>/website-review-empty-triangle/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2010 22:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Websites]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=106</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Screenshot of Empty Triangle&#8216;s Home Page Review: Please turn your attention to one of the most awesome Go related artwork that exists out there.  As you peruse through E3A, you&#8217;ll find the characters humorous and absolutely relatable as you progress in Go.  The layout is simple and unique with the artistic nature of chidori.  Nothing [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: center;">
<div style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_R3zwHD97QhU/TJU2EGvbqBI/AAAAAAAAANM/gCDBZTCpkbE/s1600/empty+triangle+home+page.png" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="240" src="https://i2.wp.com/3.bp.blogspot.com/_R3zwHD97QhU/TJU2EGvbqBI/AAAAAAAAANM/gCDBZTCpkbE/s320/empty+triangle+home+page.png?resize=320%2C240" width="320" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></div>
<p></div>
<div style="text-align: center;">Screenshot of <a href="http://www.emptytriangle.com/">Empty Triangle</a>&#8216;s Home Page</div>
<p><b>Review:</b></p>
<p>Please turn your attention to one of the most awesome Go related artwork that exists out there.  As you peruse through E3A, you&#8217;ll find the characters humorous and absolutely relatable as you progress in Go.  The layout is simple and unique with the artistic nature of chidori.  Nothing much more needs to be said, so go check it out!</p>
<p>Some favorites&#8230;</p>
<div style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_R3zwHD97QhU/TJU36TO-jMI/AAAAAAAAANU/DOgn2R-rTRY/s1600/e3a+lost+again.jpg" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="640" src="https://i2.wp.com/3.bp.blogspot.com/_R3zwHD97QhU/TJU36TO-jMI/AAAAAAAAANU/DOgn2R-rTRY/s640/e3a+lost+again.jpg?resize=380%2C640" width="380" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></div>
<div style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.emptytriangle.com/archive/6">#006 Completely lost again</a></div>
<div style="clear: both; text-align: center;"></div>
<div style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_R3zwHD97QhU/TJU4ATpzS3I/AAAAAAAAANc/AbOYpgEo2Z0/s1600/e3a+snowsuji.jpg" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="640" src="https://i0.wp.com/4.bp.blogspot.com/_R3zwHD97QhU/TJU4ATpzS3I/AAAAAAAAANc/AbOYpgEo2Z0/s640/e3a+snowsuji.jpg?resize=410%2C640" width="410" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></div>
<div style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.emptytriangle.com/archive/45">#045 snowsuji</a></div>
<div style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_R3zwHD97QhU/TJU4FKZMslI/AAAAAAAAANk/nMpDhNGevv4/s1600/e3a+weakness.jpg" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="400" src="https://i1.wp.com/4.bp.blogspot.com/_R3zwHD97QhU/TJU4FKZMslI/AAAAAAAAANk/nMpDhNGevv4/s400/e3a+weakness.jpg?resize=375%2C400" width="375" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></div>
<div style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.emptytriangle.com/archive/show/49">#049 weakness</a></div>
<div style="clear: both; text-align: center;"></div>
<div style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_R3zwHD97QhU/TJj47-o-aXI/AAAAAAAAAOU/15PJncR9vYk/s1600/e3a+skill.jpg" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="331" src="https://i0.wp.com/4.bp.blogspot.com/_R3zwHD97QhU/TJj47-o-aXI/AAAAAAAAAOU/15PJncR9vYk/s400/e3a+skill.jpg?resize=400%2C331" width="400" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></div>
<div style="text-align: center;"></div>
<div style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.emptytriangle.com/archive/show/58">#058 skill</a></div>
<div style="text-align: center;"></div>
<p><b>Synopsis: </b></p>
<p>I absolutely love this site and recommend to anyone playing Go!  Can&#8217;t wait till the shop is up!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">106</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Website Review: Sensei&#039;s Library</title>
		<link>/website-review-senseis-library/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2010 12:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Websites]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=120</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Review: Sensei&#8217;s Library is Go&#8217;s wiki database.  It encompasses pretty much any Go information that you could possibly want.  It has a lot of great tips and is great for players of all levels and types.  Since it&#8217;s a collaborative website, the clarity of the information is not always as consistent.  This is not a [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="https://i1.wp.com/3.bp.blogspot.com/_R3zwHD97QhU/TId7nh-vrVI/AAAAAAAAAIg/0JKvirwh37c/s1600/senseislib.png" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="65" src="https://i0.wp.com/3.bp.blogspot.com/_R3zwHD97QhU/TId7nh-vrVI/AAAAAAAAAIg/0JKvirwh37c/s320/senseislib.png?resize=320%2C65" width="320" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></div>
<div style="clear: both; text-align: center;"></div>
<div style="text-align: left;"><b>Review:</b></div>
<div style="text-align: left;">Sensei&#8217;s Library is Go&#8217;s wiki database.  It encompasses pretty much any Go information that you could possibly want.  It has a lot of great tips and is great for players of all levels and types.  Since it&#8217;s a collaborative website, the clarity of the information is not always as consistent.  This is not a huge problem though, since most of the articles I&#8217;ve perused through so far have been pretty solid.</p>
<p>My favorite part is the fact that if there is ever a term in the article that is confusing, they generally have already anticipated such confusion and hyperlink it to its definition.  And trust me, I&#8217;ve been confused plenty of times (e.g. shicho (a ladder)&#8230; ponnuki (the diamond shape made from a one stone capture)&#8230;.).</p>
</div>
<div style="text-align: left;"><b>Conclusion:</b></div>
<div style="text-align: left;"></div>
<div style="text-align: left;">Sensei&#8217;s Library will definitely be on my list for places to hit whenever I&#8217;m confused or don&#8217;t know where a term is, and it should be in your repertoire as well.</div>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">120</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Website Review: The Interactive Way to Go</title>
		<link>/website-review-the-interactive-way-to-go/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 22 Aug 2010 21:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Websites]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=143</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Rating: 5 / 5 Ponnuki Synopsis: Presents information in a simple and easy to understand method for brand new players. Utilizes interactive diagrams to help reinforce what you&#8217;re learning. Available in 30+ languages. It&#8217;s FREE!!!! The best online tutorial available online for players! Detailed Review: Prior to discovering The Interactive Way to Go by Hiroki [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2010/08/interactivegomainpage.png"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-1291" title="Interactive Go Website" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2010/08/interactivegomainpage-1024x692.png?resize=512%2C346" alt="Interactive Go Website Screenshot" width="512" height="346" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></p>
<h2 style="clear: both; text-align: center;">Rating: 5 / 5 Ponnuki</h2>
<h3 style="clear: both; text-align: left;">Synopsis:</h3>
<div style="clear: both; text-align: left;">
<ul>
<li>Presents information in a simple and easy to understand method for brand new players.</li>
<li>Utilizes interactive diagrams to help reinforce what you&#8217;re learning.</li>
<li>Available in 30+ languages.</li>
<li>It&#8217;s FREE!!!!</li>
<li>The best online tutorial available online for players!</li>
</ul>
<h3>Detailed Review:</h3>
</div>
<div style="text-align: left;">
Prior to discovering <a title="The Interactive Way to Go English Site" href="http://playgo.to/iwtg/en/">The Interactive Way to Go</a> by Hiroki Mori, I had attempted to read various articles on the rules of go here and there; but none of them ever really made sense to me and this inevitably delayed my discovery of how incredible this game is. Fortunately for me, I eventually stumbled upon this treasure trove that allowed me to finally jump head first into the world of go.<br />
To start, the website&#8217;s strength is in its simplicity. The technological requirements are minimal and do not require any fancy computer hardware in order to use it. As a result, one should not expect an extremely flashy website with fancy animations everywhere. In addition, it has a simple user interface that makes it easily accessible to practically any user.<br />
In regards to its content, this is the best aspect of this site because it takes you to the ABSOLUTE basics. It takes a step-by-step approach to teach you the concepts and does a fantastic job simplifying a majority of go terminology into concise sentences that are easy to understand. In case you are not aware, the lowest go rank is considered to be 30 kyu. This rank assumes that you already have an idea of basic concepts like atari, ladders, and so forth. With this tutorial, you start out as a mere 50 kyu, so one can deduce that this tutorial spares no effort in catching you up to speed! Another aspect that I really appreciate about this website is its step-by-step approach.<br />
Like any other good tutorial, this site does not hesitate to utilize diagrams to further illustrate its concepts. However, what makes this tutorial truly shine are the interactive problems. As if the explanations and diagrams were not already sufficient, these interactive problems are embedded into the lesson so that to further illustrate his point and reinforce what you are learning.<br />
<figure id="attachment_1295" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2010/08/interactivegoproblem.png"><img class="size-full wp-image-1295" title="Interactive Go Problem Screenshot" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2010/08/interactivegoproblem.png?resize=310%2C345" alt="" width="310" height="345" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Interactive Problem Screenshot</figcaption></figure>
<p style="text-align: center;">
<p>While it may be frustrating at times since the answers are not given, I assure you that the solutions actually exist. Whenever you get stuck, I would recommend going over the written explanation and diagrams again before using trial and error to figure out the solution.<br />
Bottom line: <a title="The Interactive Way to Go English Site" href="http://playgo.to/iwtg/en/">The Interactive Way to Go</a> is a top notch tutorial that every player who even has a remote interest in learning go should check out!
</div>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Last updated December 6th, 2012 (Rank: 6 kyu)</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">143</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
