<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>dempsey roll &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/dempsey-roll/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>On a Losing Streak&#8230; But It&#039;s Not All Bad</title>
		<link>/on-a-losing-streak-but-its-not-all-bad/</link>
		<comments>/on-a-losing-streak-but-its-not-all-bad/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2013 01:46:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chinese opening]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dempsey roll]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[losing streak]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[silver lining]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=3687</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[So as some of you might have noticed, I&#8217;ve been playing a lot more games recently. However, it seems I am on a losing streak; but it&#8217;s not all bad since it means I&#8217;m back in experimental mode. My rank has even dropped down to 6k it seems, but this is partially due to the [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>So as some of you might have noticed, I&#8217;ve been playing a lot more games recently. However, it seems I am on a losing streak; but it&#8217;s not all bad since it means I&#8217;m back in experimental mode. My rank has even dropped down to 6k it seems, but this is partially due to the fact that I haven&#8217;t played enough ranked games where I actually have time to think. So I really don&#8217;t give much credence to my rank drop.<br />
I know for most people, the losing streak plus rank drop is enough to go on a rampage and think about quitting the game. In actuality though, I have found it&#8217;s really important to focus on the cause of the loss instead of the loss itself. Perhaps it&#8217;s simple reading error? Or perhaps just a rigid approach to the game. Either way, I always find comfort knowing that I have the capability to make a change in my game if I choose. It&#8217;s just a matter of swallowing my pride and a willingness to overcome the obstacles that stand in my way.<br />
On a separate note, I have kept true to my promise on sealing away the Chinese Opening. It has yet to make an appearance even though I am on a losing streak. However, I am not tempted in the slightest to bring it back out yet. After all, for those who read Hajime no Ippo, I feel like the Chinese Opening is kind of like my &#8220;Dempsey Roll.&#8221; I am quite skilled at utilizing it to great effectiveness; but there&#8217;s been so much study on it that I must seal it away for now. Once I patch up my other weaknesses though, I have a feeling that I will be able to unleash something fearsome when I finally break the seal on it.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/on-a-losing-streak-but-its-not-all-bad/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3687</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
