<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>kaz &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/kaz/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>Kaz&#039;s Go School is Finally Here!</title>
		<link>/kazs-go-school-finally/</link>
		<comments>/kazs-go-school-finally/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2014 16:33:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[getting stronger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kaz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lessons]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online go school]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=4513</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Kaz&#8217;s Online Go School is finally here! For those who don&#8217;t know about Kaz, I discovered him from his site (http://www.kazsensei.com)/ a couple of years ago and have been waiting for his website to become fully live and functional. The website is a bit hard to navigate, but after going through it, I thought that [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kaz&#8217;s Online Go School is finally here! For those who don&#8217;t know about Kaz, I discovered him from his site (<a href="http://www.kazsensei.com/">http://www.kazsensei.com/</a>) a couple of years ago and have been waiting for his website to become fully live and functional. The website is a bit hard to navigate, but after going through it, I thought that it would be great if I ever got a chance to learn from him. So after waiting for a couple of years, I am psyched to tell you that the opportunity is finally here!<br />
So for those curious about this online go school, let me start with this: <strong>The first session of Kaz&#8217;s Online Go School is 8 classes for only $6 USD.</strong> Now that I have your attention, here&#8217;s my elevator pitch for the school.</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>His teaching style emphasizes teaching amateur players who are adults which is quite unique!</strong> In fact, he states in his ad that the range of players he normally teaches is 30 to 70+ years old and talks about how teaching children is very different from teaching adults! So in other words, it sounds like he has a lot of experience working with amateur players (which is precisely what many of us need).</li>
<li><strong>Kaz will generate a text for student&#8217;s to study after each lesson.</strong> It&#8217;s great to get online reviews and such, but I think it&#8217;s great that Kaz will also be generating offline content for students to study as well in order to reinforce the concepts learned from the last lesson.</li>
<li><strong>You get 8 two-hour group lessons with Kaz for only $6 USD.</strong> This is such an incredible value and such a great deal if anyone has done even the slightest bit of research on the other online schools available. For those who haven&#8217;t, one of the most popular online go schools charges about $135 a month. So yeah. &#8216;Nuff said.</li>
</ol>
<p>Bottom line: I think any player who has even been remotely interested in participating in an online go school needs to do this. There is just no reason for why you shouldn&#8217;t give this a shot for $6 USD. It&#8217;s seriously an incredible deal.<a href="//wp-content/uploads/2014/01/Kaz-Go-Problem-Set.zip"><br />
</a><br />
For more details on his school, you can find it here <a href="//wp-content/uploads/2014/01/Kaz’s-Online-Go-School.pdf">Kaz’s Online Go School (PDF)</a>. I took the liberty of taking his email and updating some of the language and structure in order to make it easier to find the information you need. And for those interested in the free problems set that he attached to his email, you can download it [download label=&#8221;here&#8221;]//wp-content/uploads/2014/01/Kaz-Go-Problem-Set.zip[/download].<br />
And just in case it isn&#8217;t clear, I have already paid my $6 and will definitely be participating in this. Let me know if you guys have any other questions and I&#8217;ll do my best to answer them. Hope to see you in class!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/kazs-go-school-finally/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">4513</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Book Review: Get Strong at Joseki 3</title>
		<link>/book-review-get-strong-joseki-3/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2013 20:25:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bozulich]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[get strong]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[joseki]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kaz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kiseido]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[star point]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=3972</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Get Strong at Joseki 3 Description: In the fourth volume of the Get Strong at Go Series, Bozulich and Kazunari familiarizes the reader with 10 josekis that commonly occur around the star point, how to handle them in regards to their variations, choosing the correct joseki given the whole board, and how to play after [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/09/getstrongv4cover.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3973" alt="getstrongv4cover" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/09/getstrongv4cover.jpg?resize=280%2C400" width="280" height="400" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">Get Strong at Joseki 3</h2>
<p><strong>Description:</strong> In the fourth volume of the Get Strong at Go Series, Bozulich and Kazunari familiarizes the reader with 10 josekis that commonly occur around the star point, how to handle them in regards to their variations, choosing the correct joseki given the whole board, and how to play after the joseki is completed. A great book for players who want a better grasp on joseki as a whole.<br />
<span id="more-3972"></span><br />
[expand title=&#8221;Book Details&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
[table]
Title, Get Strong at Joseki 3 (Vol. 4)<br />
Series, Get Strong at Go Series<br />
Author, Richard Bozulich &amp; Furuyama Kazunari<br />
Publisher, <a href="http://www.kiseido.com/">Kiseido</a><br />
Published, &#8220;First Printing May 1996 | Second Printing August 2008&#8243;<br />
Language, English<br />
ISBN, 987-4-906574-54-4<br />
Length, 208 Pages<br />
Problems, 194 Problems<br />
[/table]
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Table of Content&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Preface</li>
<li>Introduction &#8211; Ten Basic Joseki</li>
<li>Problems Part One &#8211; Joseki Variations (Problems 1-116)</li>
<li>Problems Part Two &#8211; Choosing the Right Joseki (117-140)</li>
<li>Problems Part Three &#8211; How to Play After the Joseki (141-194)</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Before I Read This Book&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
As I mentioned before in the previous two volumes (<a title="Book Review: Get Strong at Joseki 1" href="//book-review-get-strong-at-joseki-1/">GTAJ1</a> &amp; <a title="Book Review: Get Strong at Joseki 2" href="//book-review-get-strong-joseki-2/">GTAJ2</a>), joseki is not a real strength of mine. While I have become aware of some common ones due to experience using them or making mistakes, learning joseki has always been a bit of a challenge for me. With this final volume though, I was really looking forward to seeing star point joseki be featured.<br />
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Synopsis&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<strong>What did I enjoy about the book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>I really liked the fact that Bozulich &amp; Kazunari included joseki that are not commonly found in resources like Josekipedia. An example of this include the high one space double approach.</li>
<li>I enjoy the fact that Bozulich &amp; Kazunari includes some common trick plays and how to handle them.</li>
<li>The problems contain variations on different scenarios that really help acclimate the reader to seeing how just one slight chance in the sequence can completely change the outcome.</li>
<li>There is a whole section devoted to choosing joseki in regards to the entire board.</li>
<li>Proper attention is given to how to play once a joseki is finished.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What did I gain from reading this book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>A realization that there is a lot more to start point joseki than I was aware.</li>
<li>A better understanding of some of the reasons behind why certain joseki are played.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What is the format of the book?</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>Similar to the <a title="Book Review: Get Strong at Joseki 1" href="//book-review-get-strong-at-joseki-1/">GTSAJ1</a> and <a title="Book Review: Get Strong at Joseki 2" href="//book-review-get-strong-joseki-2/">GTSAJ2</a>, there is an introduction section that familiarizes the reader with the featured joseki in the book. Afterwards, the rest are practice problems accompanied by their solutions to help the reader gain a better grasp on the joseki.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>What aspects can be improved on?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>No complaints here!</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Is this book easy to read?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Yes and no. The explanations are short and concise for those who are familiar with much of go strategy and its terminology. For those who might be unfamiliar with things such as a &#8220;severe pincer&#8221; or how moves are &#8220;pressuring another group&#8221; might find it a little hard to comprehend.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Bottom Line</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>Excellent format for players to familiarize themselves with some common star point joseki along with some not so common ones as well.</li>
<li>Gives great practice for trying to see the board as a whole instead of localized sequences.</li>
<li>A fantastic way for players to gain a better handle on using joseki instead of simply memorizing them.</li>
</ol>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;My Review&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221; expanded=&#8221;true&#8221;]
As with the previous volumes, I was very pleased overall with the quality of problems in this book. Bozulich &amp; Kazunari continued to live up to my expectations and did a great job with the star point joseki featured in this book. Just like before though, I found that the first section regarding joseki variations was still quite difficult for me to work through. To be clear though, Bozulich acknowledges that this will be common for many players at first due to unfamiliarity with the material. So it&#8217;s nothing to fret about.<br />
The favorite part of my book is still the section on &#8220;Choosing the Right Joseki and Playing the Right Joseki&#8221; since it is geared toward getting to the reader to take into account the whole board when making their decision. This is a wonderful change of scenery from the narrow perspective that players often practice on (such as focusing on just a corner or two groups for life and death). Definitely the best section of the entire series.<br />
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Recommended For&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ol>
<li>Players looking to study some common (and a couple uncommon) star point joseki and its application to actual board positions.</li>
</ol>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Where Can I Buy It?&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>GoGameGuru &#8211; <a title="Get Strong at Joseki 3 GoGameGuru Purchase Link" href="http://shop.gogameguru.com/get-strong-at-joseki-3/?acc=e4da3b7fbbce2345d7772b0674a318d5">$20.99</a> USD (shipping and handling not included)</li>
<li>Kiseido &#8211; <a title="Kiseido Purchase Form" href="http://www.kiseido.com/go_books.htm">$21.00</a> USD (shipping and handling not included)</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Other Books in This Series&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;lastExpandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li><a title="Book Review: Get Strong at the Opening" href="//book-review-get-strong-at-the-opening/">Get Strong at the Opening</a></li>
<li><a title="Book Review: Get Strong at Joseki 1" href="//book-review-get-strong-at-joseki-1/">Get Strong at Joseki 1</a></li>
<li><a title="Book Review: Get Strong at Joseki 2" href="//book-review-get-strong-joseki-2/">Get Strong at Joseki 2</a></li>
<li>Get Strong at Joseki 3</li>
<li>Get Strong at Invading</li>
<li>Get Strong at Tesuji</li>
<li>Get Strong at the Endgame</li>
<li>Get Strong at Life and Death</li>
<li>Get Strong at Handicap Go</li>
<li>Get Strong at Attacking</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
<p style="text-align: center;"><em><strong>Last Updated on September 14th, 2013.</strong></em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3972</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
