<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>Journal &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/journal/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>The Important Thing to Remember</title>
		<link>/the-important-thing-to-remember/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=6321</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hey everyone. As I&#8217;m sure you&#8217;ve noticed, the weekly posts have not gotten to the point where they are coming out weekly just yet. And to be honest, while I found that initially discouraging, I had to remind myself that the important thing to remember is that go is now a part of my regular [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hey everyone. As I&#8217;m sure you&#8217;ve noticed, the weekly posts have not gotten to the point where they are coming out weekly just yet. And to be honest, while I found that initially discouraging, I had to remind myself that the important thing to remember is that go is now a part of my regular life.</p>
<p>What does this mean exactly?</p>
<ul>
<li>I&#8217;m doing tsumego daily. The amount varies from time to time, but it&#8217;s usually a small batch of ten to twenty-five at a time</li>
<li>Much to the chagrin of my good friend Nate, I&#8217;m playing correspondence games which allows me to going a long time without playing a game.</li>
<li>I walk by my go board that I set up by my desk and occasionally play out a professional game when I need to get out of my head a bit.</li>
</ul>
<p>It&#8217;s not perfect, but it&#8217;s a hell a lot better than before when I would get discouraged from starting the blog up again cause I couldn&#8217;t keep up the pace I used to. After all, as many go players will tell you, this journey is an endless one. So if you remember anything, it&#8217;s that that the name of the game is progress and nothing else.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">6321</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Return to Tengen</title>
		<link>/return-to-tengen/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 00:30:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=6283</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s been well over fifteen months, but it seems it was time for me to come back from the abyss. And I have to say, it feels good to be back. First Things First I wanted to start by apologizing for leaving the blog in the state that it was before I left. In my [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s been well over fifteen months, but it seems it was time for me to come back from the abyss. And I have to say, it feels good to be back.</p>
<p><span id="more-6283"></span></p>
<h2>First Things First</h2>
<p>I wanted to start by apologizing for leaving the blog in the state that it was before I left. In my previous attempt to leave the WordPress ecosystem, I ended up breaking a lot of old functionality and caused a bit of a mess. I&#8217;m not quite sure how I&#8217;ll be going about fixing it at this time, but know that it&#8217;s a priority of mine to do so in the coming months.</p>
<h2>Why I&#8217;m Back</h2>
<p>To be honest, I&#8217;ve always been keeping an eye on the go world from afar. So it never really left my mind, but part of me always wondered when it would be time to return to the game.</p>
<p>For all those who have read my blog and commented while I was gone, thank you for those little reminders of how much I enjoyed running this blog. Each question and comment certainly helped to slowly pull me back.</p>
<p>That said, I think the straw that broke the camel&#8217;s back was seeing the announcement for <a href="http://www.gocongress.org/">Go Congress</a> 2018. As it just so happens, it&#8217;s happening pretty close to where I live. So I couldn&#8217;t help but look back at my old Go Congress posts and it brought back a wave of nostalgia that made me consider whether I would try to attend it this year.</p>
<p>As you might guess, I&#8217;m most likely going to be attending it this year. Haha.</p>
<h2>Final Thoughts</h2>
<p>My plan for now is to start fixing the infrastructure that made it difficult for me to blog at the time of the redesign. I&#8217;ll try to and post as often as I can, but until the infrastructure is fixed, I know that will serve as a pretty major impediment for me.</p>
<p>Until then, hope everyone has been well and I look forward to talking and playing with you all again! And if you have any pressing features that you think I should fix sooner rather than later, please let me know!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">6283</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Back to My Roots</title>
		<link>/back-to-my-roots/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2016 20:29:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=6286</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[As some of you may have heard, GoGameGuru published a post today that talks about going back to its roots. And while I&#8217;d never compare my work to the accomplishments of David and his team, the post resonated with me. When I first started this blog, I saw it as a way to track my [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As some of you may have heard, <a href="https://gogameguru.com/roots/">GoGameGuru published a post today</a> that talks about going back to its roots. And while I&#8217;d never compare my work to the accomplishments of David and his team, the post resonated with me.</p>
<p><span id="more-6286"></span></p>
<p>When I first started this blog, I saw it as a way to track my progress and as a journal for people to read. Over time, I tested out different ideas: Monday Go Meditation, Thursday Go Tygem, Friday Go Forward, etc. And not to mention, I was in graduate school and had way more free time on my hands than I do now.</p>
<p>There is and always will be a part of me that wishes I could devote all my time and energy to go. Upon reflection, that idealistic desire of being all or nothing has been my problem all along. And this not only applies to go, but other things in my life as well.</p>
<p>If life is the 19&#215;19 board we are all so familiar with, I realized that the boundaries are not static nor permanent. It would be much simpler if things would stay the same, but that&#8217;s not how my life is. As someone who always seeks new experiences, it&#8217;s only natural that my interests are diverse. What was once a corner I thought I had complete control over can become center territory with an exposed side ready to come under attack at any point.</p>
<p>To clarify though, I&#8217;m not saying that my weekly posts will never return; but they&#8217;ll be on hiatus for a while. Or well, at least while I&#8217;m putting back the foundation of this blog together.</p>
<p>So until then, look forward to a return of organic posts that sprout from random thoughts and encounters in go!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">6286</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Off In Development World&#8230;</title>
		<link>/off-in-development-world/</link>
		<comments>/off-in-development-world/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2015 23:07:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5990</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[As some of you are aware, I&#8217;ve gone off the deep end into the software development world. I&#8217;ll be taking a longer sabbatical than anticipated; but you&#8217;ll still be able to catch me for a game of go or discussion on things you can do to progress! So feel free to email me whenever and [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As some of you are aware, I&#8217;ve gone off the deep end into the software development world. I&#8217;ll be taking a longer sabbatical than anticipated; but you&#8217;ll still be able to catch me for a game of go or discussion on things you can do to progress! So feel free to email me whenever and draw me out to a game on KGS whenever, because I could sure use the distraction.<br />
Meanwhile, best of luck to everyone on their games and their progress. I definitely look forward to seeing how much everyone has grown by the time I come back! Ganbatte!<br />
P.S. If you&#8217;d like to keep up with what I&#8217;m up to, I&#8217;ve created a new <a href="http://www.twitter.com/bencodezen">Twitter</a> devoted to my development and UX exploits. Until then everyone!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/off-in-development-world/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">5990</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Encountering My First Chess Advocate</title>
		<link>/encountering-my-first-chess-advocate/</link>
		<comments>/encountering-my-first-chess-advocate/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2015 01:19:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chess vs go]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[enjoyment]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5984</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Today at work I was talking to my co-worker and was scoffed at when he found out I played go. &#8220;Who plays go?!&#8221; he exclaimed. I tried to then jump into a mini-speech on its complexity; but he shut me down pretty quickly by dismissing me and saying that chess was much more complex and [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Today at work I was talking to my co-worker and was scoffed at when he found out I played go.<br />
&#8220;Who plays go?!&#8221; he exclaimed.<br />
I tried to then jump into a mini-speech on its complexity; but he shut me down pretty quickly by dismissing me and saying that chess was much more complex and the only reason why go is as &#8220;mysterious&#8221; as it seems to be is because it essentially hasn&#8217;t had the same exposure here in the Western world. And given enough time, it would be clear that chess was clearly the harder game.<br />
To be honest, I was rather baffled and shocked. I had encountered my fair share of chess vs go arguments, but this was the first time I&#8217;d encountered it in person (and with such vigor as well). Sadly I was too shaken by the encounter to really try and convince him otherwise. (To give some context, he is very intelligent and is extremely knowledgeable about a lot of things. So in other words, I wasn&#8217;t going to win him over with any sort of uplifting speech about go.)<br />
As I sit here thinking about it, I do want to write about my personal take on the chess vs go debate and why I chose go; but that is for another time. For now, what I will say is that I think that trying to argue that one is superior over another is like saying one is better off learning one instrument over another. You can spend all day arguing over minutiae of how one instrument might give better coordination than another; but what really matters at the end of the day is as simple as which one gives you real joy. And if you have that, that is enough to make one thing better for you than another.<br />
Just my two cents.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/encountering-my-first-chess-advocate/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>38</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">5984</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hello Again with GoKibitz</title>
		<link>/hello-again-with-gokibitz/</link>
		<comments>/hello-again-with-gokibitz/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2015 17:17:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Commentaries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kifu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[9x9]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[black]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[even]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gokibitz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[opponent 1d]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[resign]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[victory]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5974</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hey everyone. Just wanted to let you know I&#8217;m still alive and well. Been getting into some really interesting projects these past few weeks and have been really pondering what I can do with blogging again since I miss doing it. And as someone who hates it when a regular blogger just drops out of [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hey everyone. Just wanted to let you know I&#8217;m still alive and well. Been getting into some really interesting projects these past few weeks and have been really pondering what I can do with blogging again since I miss doing it. And as someone who hates it when a regular blogger just drops out of the blogosphere, you can rest assured that I won&#8217;t ever just leave the blog hanging in the event I need to close up shop for awhile.<br />
In terms of what I&#8217;ve been up to, I&#8217;ve been tinkering again with daily regimens and playing games via <a title="Dragon Go Server" href="http://www.dragongoserver.net/">DGS</a> and <a title="Online Go Server" href="http://www.online-go.com/">OGS</a> while concurrently juggling a new job and trying to learn a ton of new skills. I&#8217;ve gone all the way back down to the very basics of doing only 10 life and death problems a day. They&#8217;re not hard in any sense of the word, but they help me to keep a connection to the world of go.<br />
And as a special treat for those who miss my reviews, I&#8217;ve decided to try reviewing one of my 9&#215;9 games that I played recently on GoQuest via an awesome new social kifu reviewing software called <a title="GoKibitz" href="http://www.gokibitz.com/">GoKibitz</a> that a close friend and long time rival built himself. So I hope you enjoy the review and I will try and post again soon!<br />
UPDATE: Apparently all my comments got lost in the abyss of the internet&#8230;. Oy vey&#8230; I&#8217;ll try and get another version up soon&#8230;.<br />
<iframe id="gokibitz-mkYiGH8c" style="width: 100%; min-height: 500px; display: block; border: 10px solid snow;" src="//gokibitz.com/kifu/mkYiGH8c" width="300" height="150"></iframe><script src="//gokibitz.com/embed/mkYiGH8c"></script></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/hello-again-with-gokibitz/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>13</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">5974</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Happy Chinese New Year 2015!</title>
		<link>/happy-chinese-new-year-2015/</link>
		<comments>/happy-chinese-new-year-2015/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2015 22:03:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5966</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[First and foremost, my apologies for disappearing out of the blue like that. Though it would not have been my preference, a number of things came up that forced me to put go on the back burner for a little bit. On the upside though, I will be starting a new job in a couple of weeks [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cny2015.jpeg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5967" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cny2015.jpeg?resize=225%2C225" alt="cny2015" width="225" height="225" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><br />
First and foremost, my apologies for disappearing out of the blue like that. Though it would not have been my preference, a number of things came up that forced me to put go on the back burner for a little bit. On the upside though, I will be starting a new job in a couple of weeks and plan to start getting back to go.<br />
Hope everyone is doing well.<br />
Happy Chinese New Year!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/happy-chinese-new-year-2015/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>14</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">5966</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Giving DGS Another Shot</title>
		<link>/giving-dgs-another-shot/</link>
		<comments>/giving-dgs-another-shot/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2015 15:21:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5963</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I’ve decided to give Dragon Go Server another shot. While I had some issues with it in the past, I’m ready to approach it again from a more calm approach. In other words, I won’t be in a rush to make my move or finish games. Instead, I’ll view each move as a problem for [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I’ve decided to give <a title="Dragon Go Server" href="http://www.dragongoserver.net/index.php">Dragon Go Server</a> another shot. While I had some issues with it in the past, I’m ready to approach it again from a more calm approach. In other words, I won’t be in a rush to make my move or finish games. Instead, I’ll view each move as a problem for me to solve. No more, no less. So go ahead and send your challenges. I await them in anticipation!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/giving-dgs-another-shot/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>26</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">5963</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Retrospective on 2014</title>
		<link>/retrospective-2014/</link>
		<comments>/retrospective-2014/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 13:02:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5958</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hey everyone. Sorry that I’ve been MIA for a while. As you might have guessed, I’ve been caught up with work along with the many obligations that come with the holiday season. Lots of late nights, running errands, cooking, cleaning, etc. While I haven’t been able to blog as much as I would like, I [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hey everyone. Sorry that I’ve been MIA for a while. As you might have guessed, I’ve been caught up with work along with the many obligations that come with the holiday season. Lots of late nights, running errands, cooking, cleaning, etc.<br />
While I haven’t been able to blog as much as I would like, I couldn’t bear the thought of ending 2014 without some sort of retrospective.<br />
In terms of how the year has gone, it has been a rather introspective one that was fraught with a lot of anxieties and insecurities that plagued me subconsciously. Though it’s rather unfortunate that it took me so long to identify the issue at hand, it has been an important discovery that has allowed me to start fixing a lot of different aspects in my life. So once again, I have another thing to add on to the list of reasons I’m thankful that go is in my life.<br />
And while the standard practice is to make big overtures about what the next year will bring, I think I’ll take a page from modesty this time around. No grand gestures of blogging everyday or playing 100 games in a month. Instead, I’ll just let you know what I have in mind for next year:</p>
<ol>
<li>Actually play games and not just study.</li>
<li>Find a groove that works for my blogging. I know what I want ideally, but it’s time I found the right balance for consistency.</li>
</ol>
<p>With that said and done, I also want to take the time to thank everyone for their support of the blog. Your comments and words of advice and encouragement have been key in helping me persist through times of difficulty. I hope that you all have a great New Years Eve and will have an even better 2015. Till next year!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/retrospective-2014/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">5958</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Stirring the Embers Once Again&#8230;</title>
		<link>/stirring-embers/</link>
		<comments>/stirring-embers/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2014 02:34:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kifu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[go seigen]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5949</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[As many of you are aware, the legendary Go Seigen passed away on November 30th. I’ve been wracking my brain for a way to properly honor him, but it is still eluding me. To help the process out, I decided that it would be a good start working through my collection of his games again. [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/12/2014-12-10-Go-Seigen.jpg"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-5950 " src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/12/2014-12-10-Go-Seigen-300x225.jpg?resize=394%2C256" alt="2014-12-10 Go Seigen" width="394" height="256" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><br />
As many of you are aware, the legendary Go Seigen passed away on November 30th. I’ve been wracking my brain for a way to properly honor him, but it is still eluding me. To help the process out, I decided that it would be a good start working through my collection of his games again. As I played through his game (above), I started to feel the embers begin to catch flame again.<br />
I also had the opportunity to play with fellow blogger RisingStar today. It was a friendly game with a 9 stone handicap. And while the mere thought of playing that kind of game would have scared me a week ago, it was surprisingly calming and fun. Sometimes I feel like I get in these moves where the game just seems to make sense. Moves flow easily and there is a serenity that keeps you level headed at all times. This was one of those games.<br />
The game record is below, but there will most likely be a MGM on it in the future.<br />
[wgo]http://box2018.temp.domains/~bengozen/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/2014.12.10-bengozen-risingstar-9h.sgf[/wgo]
<p style="text-align: center;">[download label=&#8221;Download Kifu&#8221;]//wp-content/uploads/2014/12/2014.12.10-bengozen-risingstar-9h.sgf[/download]
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/stirring-embers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>10</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">5949</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
