<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>consistency &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/consistency/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>Friday Go Forward: Week 70</title>
		<link>/friday-go-forward-week-70/</link>
		<comments>/friday-go-forward-week-70/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2014 23:39:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Progress Reports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[consistency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[progress]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[report]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[slow and steady wins the race]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5552</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Overview This week has been very sparse in terms of study and playing, but extremely heavy in regards to writing (if you didn’t notice with the Weekly Go Wednesday article). And though my time has been a bit more biased towards writing, I don’t think any of you are complaining. Haha. It’s taken some time [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="overview">Overview</h2>
<p>This week has been very sparse in terms of study and playing, but extremely heavy in regards to writing (if you didn’t notice with the Weekly Go Wednesday article). And though my time has been a bit more biased towards writing, I don’t think any of you are complaining. Haha.<br />
It’s taken some time to break into my productivity system, but the cogs and wheels are starting to mesh together better now. I’m much more aware of where my time is going along with how I’m progressing as a whole in life now. Whole board thinking. See that?<br />
I’m looking forward to when my entire system works effortlessly and I can really amp up my go training. No matter though. Slow and steady wins the race.</p>
<h2 id="trainingregimen">Training Regimen</h2>
<ul>
<li>Work on go for at least 10–15 minutes a day.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="games">Games</h2>
<ul>
<li><a title="KGS Website" href="http://www.gokgs.com/">KGS</a> &#8211;  1 game</li>
<li><a title="Dragon Go Server - BenGoZen's Profile" href="http://www.dragongoserver.net/userinfo.php?uid=60385">DGS</a> &#8211; 6 ongoing games</li>
<li><a title="Online Go Server - BenGoZen's Profile" href="http://online-go.com/user/view/549/BenGoZen">OGS</a> &#8211;  7 ongoing games</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="books">Books</h2>
<ul>
<li><a title="Book Review: Get Strong at Tesuji" href="//book-review-get-strong-tesuji/"><em>Get Strong at Tesuji</em></a> by Richard Bozulich</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="lessonslearned">Lessons Learned</h2>
<ul>
<li>It doesn’t matter if you make mistakes during your game because your opponent is just as likely to make mistakes if not bigger ones. So don’t be too hard on yourself during a game because you’ll only be making yourself more vulnerable than necessary.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/friday-go-forward-week-70/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">5552</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Friday Go Forward: Week 69</title>
		<link>/friday-go-forward-week-69/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2014 15:03:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Progress Reports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[consistency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[efficiency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[long term]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[scrivener]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5496</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Overview I swear my training regimen is getting shorter with each week that goes on by, but in all fairness, I am working on developing a system that focuses on consistency over a long period of time as opposed to having my life be extremely skewed towards one direction or another based on how I [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="overview">Overview</h2>
<p>I swear my training regimen is getting shorter with each week that goes on by, but in all fairness, I am working on developing a system that focuses on consistency over a long period of time as opposed to having my life be extremely skewed towards one direction or another based on how I feel. Of course, this doesn’t mean that I’m only doing that much every day, but it’s my bare minimum requirement per day.<br />
One of the things I’ve been working on throughout the week is designing a better blogging system. I was currently working directly out of WordPress and collecting notes where I could here and there, but it wasn’t a very efficient system and took up quite a bit of time. To my luck, in the process of me restructuring other aspects of my life (i.e., time management, project management, finances, etc.), I actually stumbled across <a title="Scrivener Official Page" href="http://www.literatureandlatte.com/scrivener.php">Scrivener</a> and have been testing out recently. I’m still in the trial period, but I have to say that this tool is really quite impressive for serious writers out there. It’s starting to really help me get my thoughts together and allow me to blog more effectively.<br />
Another thing that I want to mention is that after next week’s Friday Go Forward, I will most likely be pushing out these progress reports to Saturday since they are more status updates than anything else and can be scheduled ahead of time. I’ve found it to be near impossible to blog on Saturday, so this will add a consistent content item to Saturday while allowing me to blog about more personal things on Friday if I want to.<br />
Finally, I plan on releasing an online document that will allow you to check my training and efforts in go in real time! By doing so, you can get a real detailed look at what I’m doing since status reports are generally more an overview than anything else. Hopefully this will be of interest to some of you, but if not, at least it will be another artifact to track my progress and possible analysis in the future.<br />
With all that said, hope all those living in the US have a great 4th of July weekend! See you all next week.</p>
<h2 id="trainingregimen">Training Regimen</h2>
<ul>
<li>Work on go for at least 10–15 minutes a day.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="games">Games</h2>
<ul>
<li><a title="KGS Website" href="http://www.gokgs.com/">KGS</a> &#8211;  3 games</li>
<li><a title="Dragon Go Server - BenGoZen's Profile" href="http://www.dragongoserver.net/userinfo.php?uid=60385">DGS</a> &#8211; 6 ongoing games</li>
<li><a title="Online Go Server - BenGoZen's Profile" href="http://online-go.com/user/view/549/BenGoZen">OGS</a> &#8211;  5 ongoing games</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="books">Books</h2>
<ul>
<li><a title="Book Review: Get Strong at Tesuji" href="//book-review-get-strong-tesuji/"><em>Get Strong at Tesuji</em></a> by Richard Bozulich</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="videos">Videos</h2>
<ul>
<li><a title="Yunguseng Dojang - Season 9 - 2nd Month - 5th Round Reviews" href="http://ayd.yunguseng.com/videos/index.php?id=1287">YSD 2nd Month 5th Round Reviews</a></li>
</ul>
<h2 id="lessonslearned">Lessons Learned</h2>
<ul>
<li>I’m still bad at framing moves in terms of how many points / potential it can provide when playing games.</li>
<li>I need to start trusting my instinct more. Apparently it is correct more often than I give it credit for.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">5496</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Boxing and Go</title>
		<link>/boxing-and-go/</link>
		<comments>/boxing-and-go/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2013 16:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[boxing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[consistency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fundamentals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[improving]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[menu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[training]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=3794</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;ve recently taken an interest in boxing, and I have to say that the more I study it, the more I can&#8217;t help but see similarities between boxing and go. Here are a few off the top of my head: There are two players in each match. Regardless of how badly each player might want [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_3796" style="width: 400px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/08/Boxing-Sport-Latest-HD-Wallpaper-3.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-3796" alt="Credit to CrazyThemes" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/08/Boxing-Sport-Latest-HD-Wallpaper-3.jpg?resize=400%2C225" width="400" height="225" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Credit to CrazyThemes</figcaption></figure>
I&#8217;ve recently taken an interest in boxing, and I have to say that the more I study it, the more I can&#8217;t help but see similarities between boxing and go. Here are a few off the top of my head:</p>
<ol>
<li>There are two players in each match.</li>
<li>Regardless of how badly each player might want to win, there can only be one victor at the end of the match.</li>
<li>Exchanging blows with your opponent is inevitable and necessary for a good match.</li>
<li>There are different styles of boxing that seem analogous the go styles as well (e.g., technician/point counter, infighter/fighting, etc.).</li>
</ol>
<p>But most importantly of all, <strong>those who rise to the top are those who are instinctively faithful to the fundamentals</strong>.<br />
After all, look at any boxer&#8217;s training regimen and what are you going to find? Running, jump rope, shadow boxing, combinations, sparring. Repeat. Repeat. Repeat. There might be a few deviations occasionally depending on what muscle groups they need to build for certain techniques, but the training menu almost always consists of the fundamentals. And what does a fight primarily consist of? The basics: jab, cross, hook, uppercut, jab, jab&#8230;<br />
So how is this relevant to go? Well, one topic that I know runs rampant throughout the community is the idea of getting stronger (especially for kyu players who want to reach dan level). And as I begin to study boxing, I can&#8217;t help but wonder what a go players training menu should look like? I mean sure, everyone will say do life and death problems, but that advice is so incredibly generic and subject to interpretation (as to how to study it) that I would guarantee that many players have gone astray and become frustrated with their progress because they couldn&#8217;t figure out what to do to keep getting better.<br />
I know that no one has a magical formula for getting better at go; but I think that there is more wisdom that can be offered from my study of boxing in terms of trying to discover better guidelines for designing a training menu for go. After all, it&#8217;s not about knowing the most complicated joseki or knowing the common trick plays, but to instead constantly improve the fundamentals.<br />
More on this as I continue researching and testing out different things&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/boxing-and-go/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>11</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3794</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Friday Go Forward: Week 15</title>
		<link>/friday-go-forward-week-15/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2013 09:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Progress Reports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[back from vacation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[consistency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[treading lightly]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=2677</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Overview As this is my first week back since my vacation, it has been a relatively light week that has consisted of me trying to get my feet wet again in the world of go. Like I mentioned before in a previous post, I&#8217;m working on hard on really gaining a better understanding of what [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>Overview</h2>
<p>As this is my first week back since my vacation, it has been a relatively light week that has consisted of me trying to get my feet wet again in the world of go. Like I mentioned before in a previous post, I&#8217;m working on hard on really gaining a better understanding of what I&#8217;m capable of maintaining consistently without burnout.<br />
Playing ranked games has been a little weird and disappointing since I can&#8217;t seem to hold my own at the moment, but I&#8217;m trying not to let it bother me too much since I am a bit rusty and loss through very clear and obvious mistakes. So as long as I work hard to become more disciplined about how I play each move, my games should improve without much effort.</p>
<h2>Games</h2>
<ul>
<li><span style="line-height: 13px;">KGS &#8211; 6 games ( 2 wins : 4 losses )</span></li>
<li>DGS &#8211; 2 ongoing games</li>
<li>Nova &#8211; 4 ongoing games</li>
</ul>
<h2>Training</h2>
<ul>
<li><span style="line-height: 13px;">20 tsumego problems each day.</span></li>
<li>Worked on <em>Mastering the Basics: 501 Tesuji Problems</em>.</li>
<li>Started on <em>Mastering the Basics: The Basics of Go Strategy</em>.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Lessons Learned</h2>
<ol>
<li>Avoid blitz games and games 25 minutes or less since I am a thinker. Fast games will come when my fundamentals are more solid.</li>
<li>Really need to stop the bad habit of &#8220;Let&#8217;s play here and see what happens.&#8221;</li>
<li>Got to keep working on thinking of games as if I&#8217;m playing myself.</li>
</ol>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2677</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Keep Studying Interesting</title>
		<link>/how-to-keep-studying-interesting/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2013 09:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Weekly Go Wednesday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bored]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[consistency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entertaining]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[exploring]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fun]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[studying]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[topics of interest]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=2548</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Weekly Go Wednesday, Issue #25 Whether you like it or not, studying is one of the most important aspects of getting stronger at go. While some players are able to simply learn everything through playing and reviewing, this is often reliant on stronger players or even simple luck of figuring out what is wrong with [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 style="text-align: center;">Weekly Go Wednesday, Issue #25</h2>
<figure id="attachment_2631" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/04/wgw25.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-2631" alt="Credit to Gagful" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/04/wgw25.jpg?resize=300%2C252" width="300" height="252" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Credit to <a href="http://www.gagful.com/uploads/2012_9/1347619043_studying_gag.jpg">Gagful</a></figcaption></figure>
Whether you like it or not, studying is one of the most important aspects of getting stronger at go. While some players are able to simply learn everything through playing and reviewing, this is often reliant on stronger players or even simple luck of figuring out what is wrong with your moves or thinking process. As a result, there is no telling how fast you will improve.<br />
Unfortunately, this is one of the most dreaded aspects of trying getting stronger for most players. After all, it reminds us of our school days where homework and projects were a drag and no one ever wanted to do them. So, as the last installment of Weekly Go Wednesday (at least for the time being), I thought it would be best to leave you with my thoughts on how you can keep your study of go interesting so that you can continue to climb the ranks.<br />
<span id="more-2548"></span><br />
In order to help make studying more interesting, we must start by giving ourselves the right mindset when thinking about studying. Although the image jokes about how studying ends with the word &#8220;dying,&#8221; one should not view studying as a dreaded chore; but instead as <strong>an opportunity to explore topics of interest</strong>. By doing so, one no longer thinks of the cumbersome tasks that lie ahead; but will instead look forward to each studying session.<br />
Once you have the right mindset, here are some tips that I use to help keep myself motivated to consistently study go:<br />
<strong>1. Only study things that are of interest to <em>you</em>.</strong> As much as everyone goes on about how important life and death is, if that subject bores you to tears, don&#8217;t do it. Study whatever else makes <em>you</em> happy and makes the game enjoyable. That might be attacking, joseki, tesuji, fuseki, endgame, whatever. Although it might seem like you are neglecting other areas, I have found that those other areas eventually become topics of interest as you gain a greater understanding of the game.<br />
<strong>2. Follow a couple of professional players that you are fans of. </strong>It&#8217;s much more fun studying professional games when you are rooting for your favorite player or trying to understand why your pro played the way he did. In addition, the emotional attachment you have to your favorite player winning or losing will make the things you learn stick that much more in your brain. And if you don&#8217;t know which professionals to follow, two easy names that I would recommend starting with are <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gu_Li">Gu Li</a> and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lee_Sedol">Lee Sedol</a>.<br />
<strong>3. Keep your study sessions short.</strong> If the study sessions are too long, it can cause you to study more infrequently and procrastinate study sessions since you&#8217;ll always have the excuse, &#8220;I don&#8217;t have enough time.&#8221; It&#8217;s better to cut your studying in chunks in order to allow more material to be dispersed over time which inadvertently marinates in your brain and has more time to be absorbed into your actual play.<br />
Best of luck in your studies and pursuit of the next stone. Till next time!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2548</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
