<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>tenuki &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/tenuki/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>Must Tenuki For a While</title>
		<link>/must-tenuki/</link>
		<comments>/must-tenuki/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2014 03:25:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[break]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pause]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tenuki]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5560</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[As some of you might have noticed, I’ve been pretty MIA for a while. One of the major events that happened last week was I moved out to a new apartment. And for those who know what it’s like to move, you know how much of a monstrosity that can be when it comes to [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As some of you might have noticed, I’ve been pretty MIA for a while. One of the major events that happened last week was I moved out to a new apartment. And for those who know what it’s like to move, you know how much of a monstrosity that can be when it comes to sorting, packing, and cleaning.<br />
The move came at a rather funny time in my life as it happened to be a perfect representation of how I’ve been deconstructing my own life lately as well. Reassessing what I’m trying to do and where all my time and energy is being placed. On one hand, everything is a gigantic mess and it’s difficult at times to figure out what I’m trying to do in all this chaos. However, I have confidence that it will work out for the best.<br />
As I’m reassessing my strategy for my life, it should come as no surprise that I’ve had to reassess how I’ve been approaching my study of go as well. I’ll be honest in that I have not been happy at all with my numerous training regimens and have felt like I’ve lost focus. In fact, my Yunguseng match which was rescheduled for today was the first time I even looked at anything go related at all in the past few days. It was quite a weird feeling.<br />
So while I would love to continue the momentum I had going with the blog, I’m putting a hold on all the weekly articles and game commentary in order to give myself time to really sort through things. So I hope you’ll forgive me as I must tenuki for a while as I try and figure out what my whole board strategy for my life is.<br />
I’ll be sure to drop in and update you on my thoughts and progress, so no need to worry that I’m simply dropping off the face of the planet. I’ll still be around.<br />
Hope that all is well with everyone.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/must-tenuki/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>10</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">5560</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Monday Go Meditation: Game 46</title>
		<link>/monday-go-meditation-game-46/</link>
		<comments>/monday-go-meditation-game-46/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2014 11:15:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Kifu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Monday Go Meditation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ignoring]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tenuki]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[victory]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[white]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=4725</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Introduction For this week&#8217;s go meditation, one of the primary themes of this game is trying to recognize when it&#8217;s worth it to respond to your opponent and when you should ignore your opponent. Throughout the game, there are numerous times where responding to my opponent locally would not have technically have been &#8220;wrong,&#8221; but [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 style="text-align: center;">Introduction</h2>
<p>For this week&#8217;s go meditation, one of the primary themes of this game is trying to recognize when it&#8217;s worth it to respond to your opponent and when you should ignore your opponent. Throughout the game, there are numerous times where responding to my opponent locally would not have technically have been &#8220;wrong,&#8221; but it would have been difficult on the board as a whole if I simply let my opponent get sente to play where he wanted. So be sure to pay attention to when I respond and why I have no problem doing so, but then it is equally important to note when I ignore my opponent and tenuki. Hope you enjoy!<a href="//wp-content/uploads/2014/03/2014.03.10-MGM-46.sgf"><br />
</a><br />

<div id='glift_display1' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display1","sgf":"http:\/\/bengozen.com\/\/wp-content\/uploads\/2014\/03\/2014.03.10-MGM-46.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='//wp-content/uploads/2014/03/2014.03.10-MGM-46.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">[download label=&#8221;Download Kifu&#8221;]//wp-content/uploads/2014/03/2014.03.10-MGM-46.sgf[/download]
<h2 style="text-align: center;"><strong>One Point Lesson</strong></h2>
<p style="text-align: center;">Unless it&#8217;s a matter of life and death, you can ignore your opponent a lot more often than you realize.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/monday-go-meditation-game-46/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">4725</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
