<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>goals &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/goals/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>Friday Go Forward: Week #5</title>
		<link>/friday-go-forward-week-5/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 14:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Progress Reports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[goals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hajime no ippo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[surpass]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=2030</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Games KGS &#8211; 3 games ( 2 win : 1 loss ) Real Life &#8211; 2 games ( 1 win : 1 loss ) Tsumego Essential Life &#38; Death (Vol. 2) &#8211; Pages 82 &#8211; 87 Other Elementary Go Series, Volume 3 &#8211; Tesuji &#8211; Pages 1 &#8211; 22 Dictionary of Basic Joseki, Volume 1 &#8211; [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 style="text-align: left;">Games</h2>
<ul>
<li>KGS &#8211; 3 games ( 2 win : 1 loss )</li>
<li>Real Life &#8211; 2 games ( 1 win : 1 loss )</li>
</ul>
<h2>Tsumego</h2>
<ul>
<li><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Essential Life &amp; Death (Vol. 2)</span> &#8211; Pages 82 &#8211; 87</li>
</ul>
<h2>Other</h2>
<ul>
<li><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Elementary Go Series, Volume 3 &#8211; Tesuji</span> &#8211; Pages 1 &#8211; 22</li>
<li><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Dictionary of Basic Joseki, Volume 1</span> &#8211; Pages 1 &#8211; 15</li>
</ul>
<h2>Thoughts</h2>
<p>Although I haven&#8217;t played as much as I might have liked, this week has been pretty interesting in terms of the various activities I&#8217;ve had going on. My go studying has taken on more flavors and variety, which has greatly increased my enjoyment of what I&#8217;m learning. In addition, it feels as if I&#8217;m starting to think less and less of winning, which is something I hope to ingrain permanently into my being. There are a number of reasons due to this spark of an epiphany. One that I will mention in particular is from <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fighting_Spirit_(manga)">Hajime no Ippo</a>.<br />
The line comes from a scene after the main character, Ippo, manages to win against a boxer who&#8217;s goal was to become like his idol. When analyzing what happened and why Ippo won (even though he was an underdog), the idol said:</p>
<blockquote><p>It was the result of different goals between the challengers. Those who try to reach and those who try to surpass.</p></blockquote>
<p>Although I&#8217;ve heard similar lines to this before, it was rather profound to me when I read it (perhaps due to the emotional attachment to characters and the story). And to be honest, I think there&#8217;s a lot of truth in there. Because in actuality, my goal is not to simply reach shodan; but to surpass it entirely.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2030</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lightbulb&#8230;..</title>
		<link>/lightbulb/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2010 01:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[goals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mistakes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[private lesson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yuan zhou]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=110</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[So I had my second private lesson today, and I have to say I felt like such an idiot as we were going over my games. It&#8217;s funny how blatantly obvious my idiotic decisions and rationales are when pointed out. I&#8217;m still falling into the typical traps of a new player (e.g. focusing on local [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div style="clear: both; text-align: left;">
So I had my second private lesson today, and I have to say I felt like such an idiot as we were going over my games. It&#8217;s funny how blatantly obvious my idiotic decisions and rationales are when pointed out. I&#8217;m still falling into the typical traps of a new player (e.g. focusing on local areas, having no purpose, wishful thinking, etc.) Argh&#8230;. I think I&#8217;m going to have to come up with a handout for beginning Go players to look over once a day to help them out.<br />
One of the most critical aha moments that went off in my head today is the fact that I don&#8217;t and can&#8217;t quite read ahead worth crap. It&#8217;s definitely one of the reasons that I make the poor plays that I do. This is probably one of the reasons I hate half of the books that I&#8217;ve reviewed so far. They have so many complicated diagrams, but in reality there is probably more substance since they are probably assuming you can read it out in your head no problem. So far, I&#8217;ve been actually replaying variations on an actual board. This is useful to an extent, but I have to be able to play the simulations out in my head.<br />
As I mentioned at the beginning of this month, I&#8217;m trying to break the double digit kyu (DDK) by October 8th. It probably is near impossible to do so, but here&#8217;s my crazy game plan:</p>
<ol>
<li>Finish the following books:
<ul>
<li><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Opening Theory Made Easy</span> by Otake Hideo 9 dan</li>
<li><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Whole Board Thinking in Joseki &#8211; Volume One</span> by Yi-Lun Yang</li>
<li><span style="text-decoration: underline;">One Thousand and One Life-and-Death Problems</span> by Richard Bozulich</li>
<li><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Understanding Dan Level Play</span> by Yuan Zhou</li>
<li><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Tesuji</span> by James Davies</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Replay 25 moves of a professional game (that has commentary) everyday.</li>
<li>Play one serious game (not a bot) everyday where I don&#8217;t rush and try my hardest.</li>
</ol>
<p>It&#8217;s like my teacher said, &#8220;It&#8217;s not hard to rise levels at the stage you&#8217;re at, you just have to stop doing all these irrational and inefficient moves.&#8221; Time to topple over these obstacles.
</p></div>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">110</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Journal Log #1</title>
		<link>/journal-log-1/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2010 11:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[20k]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[goals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new to kgs]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=128</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Sorry it took so long everyone, but I will now start adding my own anecdotes on my journey. As you all may have seen, I&#8217;ve been busy writing various reviews and reading as fast as I possibly can while still maintaining my life. The time has come&#8230; all the beginning quests have been completed&#8230; and [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sorry it took so long everyone, but I will now start adding my own anecdotes on my journey. As you all may have seen, I&#8217;ve been busy writing various reviews and reading as fast as I possibly can while still maintaining my life.<br />
The time has come&#8230; all the beginning quests have been completed&#8230; and it is time to leave the home village where I have spent my beginnings. Let us overview my stats.<br />
<span id="more-128"></span><br />
I&#8217;m currently ranked at 20 kyu (according to KGS), which to me is not very strong at all. In a few days, it will have been a month. So I&#8217;m curious as to a more accurate measurement of my skills, but alas that will do me little good. In the past, I&#8217;ve made it a point to try and play on equal grounds with the Bots available on KGS. Yeah&#8230;. I think that was a bad decision.<br />
Plenty of people think that playing a computer develops bad habits in a player. I couldn&#8217;t agree more. I will say however, that the quality of play does improve one you get pass the 20-30 kyu computers. The computers tend to make semi-automatic plays and won&#8217;t realize they&#8217;re trapped (e.g. ladders). Above 20 kyu the play improves but is still a bit robotic.<br />
In terms of how my games have progressed, you are always more than welcome to browse the KGS Archives for Zenix &#8211; month of August. To sum it up, my very first 19&#215;19 game on KGS was a loss of 312.5 points to a player who did not have a rank. (For those who do not understand the magnitude of that loss, there are 361 points available assuming no stones are placed down.) My games continued down a lot of resignations and losses of gigantic proportions (e.g. +132.5 and +296.5). I would even lose to bots that were technically weaker than me.<br />
Where am I now? It seems that with just a little under a month of Go under my belt, I&#8217;ve managed to compete on relatively even ground with LibertyBot [14k] (I win with about a 30-40 point margin) even though I make some egregious errors sometimes. So not too shabby&#8230; but I got a long way to go.<br />
Where do I think I&#8217;m headed next? Assuming I can maintain all other aspects of my life pretty well, let&#8217;s shoot for the moon shall we?<br />
<strong>September&#8217;s Goal: I&#8217;m going to rise to a strength of a single digit kyu within a month.</strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">128</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
