<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>zen &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/zen/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>Losing Sight of My Go</title>
		<link>/losing-sight-go/</link>
		<comments>/losing-sight-go/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2014 23:05:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kifu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[2k opponent]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[anti-zen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[attached to winning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[black]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[long game]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[selfish]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shameful]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[undo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[w+resign]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zen]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5480</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Today I played a game against a 2k as Black (with 45 min main time settings). It&#8217;s been a long time since I&#8217;ve played a game with such long time settings where the opponent actually used up most of his/her time. In fact, it was a little nerve wracking because the quality of the moves [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Today I played a game against a 2k as Black (with 45 min main time settings). It&#8217;s been a long time since I&#8217;ve played a game with such long time settings where the opponent actually used up most of his/her time. In fact, it was a little nerve wracking because the quality of the moves were quite different. Far less impulsive ones and much more proper moves that were given a lot of thought. I felt I had decent control of the game for the most part, but started losing control of it towards the later half of the middle game. Around this time, my opponent misclicks.<br />
At first I was thrilled to see the mistake, but then the undo request instantly popped up and I was confronted with the conflicting decision as to wheter I should give him the undo or not. Long story short, he was supposed to gain about 8 points in sente, but misclicked and put his own stones in atari so that I could capture them instead, save my stones, and gain a few points myself.<br />

<div id='glift_display1' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display1","sgf":"http:\/\/bengozen.com\/\/wp-content\/uploads\/2014\/06\/2014.06.24-Losing-Sight-of-My-Go.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='//wp-content/uploads/2014/06/2014.06.24-Losing-Sight-of-My-Go.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">[download label=&#8221;Download Kifu&#8221;]//wp-content/uploads/2014/06/2014.06.24-Losing-Sight-of-My-Go.sgf[/download]
<p>For 95% of spectators out there, the answer is crystal clear: it was an obvious misclick. In that moment however, though I&#8217;m ashamed to say it, I wanted to win so badly that I tried to brush off his undo and play on. I tried to resolve my cognitive dissonance by telling myself that it was his fault that he misclicked. Not my problem. Within a few moves however, I woke to my senses and realized how pitiful I was being. So I resigned in order to try and pick up what little self-respect I had left.<br />
The reason I&#8217;m writing about this is because I realized I have become too caught up in winning. Even though my name was created with the idea that I had found zen in go, I think that it has become so far from the truth (especially as of late). With each game recently, any sense of calmness or zen has been consistently disturbed by the notion of winning or losing. And with each game, I am concerned that I am losing sight of my go.<br />
This ends now. I don&#8217;t care if I have to drop ten stones to get back to it, but I&#8217;m going to put the pieces that started this blog back together: Ben + Go + Zen.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/losing-sight-go/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>15</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">5480</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pursuing Zen Under Siege</title>
		<link>/pursuing-zen-siege/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2013 23:36:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[risky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[siege]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zen]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=4281</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;ve been thinking a lot about life lately something about myself. For those who know me in real life, it&#8217;s probably safe to say that I can get a little overly excited about something most people would consider mundane. It&#8217;s not because I was deprived as a child or anything; but I believe that each [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve been thinking a lot about life lately something about myself. For those who know me in real life, it&#8217;s probably safe to say that I can get a little overly excited about something most people would consider mundane. It&#8217;s not because I was deprived as a child or anything; but I believe that each day should be lived to the fullest and that every moment we have is something to be excited about.<br />
The downside, however, is that while I am able to keep my emotions and mental state very positive for a majority of the time, one wrong misstep can throw me into a weird limbo where I kind of just fall off the deep end. And whether I like it or not, this is clearly reflected in my go. So in order to try and train my ability to be calm and collected, I decided to do the one thing I generally advise against: playing blitz games.<br />
With the time pressure and the fact that I tend to take my losses in blitz pretty hard (due to the fact that I often lose due to a stupid mistake as opposed to actually being weaker than my opponent), this approach is essentially the equivalent of trying to achieve enlightenment in the middle of a war zone. It&#8217;s not that it&#8217;s impossible, but it&#8217;s pretty risky and could be dangerous for my go. However, I know that trying to take any other route will probably delay my ability to overcome this hurdle.<br />
See you on the other side.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">4281</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Confidence is Worth Two Stones</title>
		<link>/confidence-worth-two-stones/</link>
		<comments>/confidence-worth-two-stones/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2013 17:59:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[confidence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stop being negative]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zen]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=4059</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Last week, I was playing a game when other players started showing up to watch the game. My opponent then remarked, &#8220;Everyone is here to see me lose.&#8221; And then I promptly replied, &#8220;You&#8217;ve got it wrong. They&#8217;re here to see me lose.&#8221; Though it was said in a joking manner that was also supposed to [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_4111" style="width: 400px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/10/confidence-building.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-4111" alt="Credit to treeofknowledge" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/10/confidence-building.jpg?resize=400%2C300" width="400" height="300" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Credit to <a href="http://www.treeof.com/confidence-building/">treeofknowledge</a></figcaption></figure>
Last week, I was playing a game when other players started showing up to watch the game. My opponent then remarked, &#8220;Everyone is here to see me lose.&#8221; And then I promptly replied, &#8220;You&#8217;ve got it wrong. They&#8217;re here to see me lose.&#8221; Though it was said in a joking manner that was also supposed to be humble, it wasn&#8217;t until after the game that a comment made by a visitng dan player struck me: &#8220;Confidence is worth two stones.&#8221;<br />
It got me thinking about my whole approach to the game, or perhaps life in general. With the way I&#8217;ve been brought up, it&#8217;s expected that one be humble and not be cocky or overconfident. However, I started to wonder whether or not I ended up taking this mentality too far and becoming self-deprecating instead. In other words, even though I would say things like, &#8220;No no, I&#8217;m a weak player&#8221; as a way of being humble; I may have actually been planting seeds of doubt in myself this entire time.<br />
Now to be clear, I&#8217;m not saying that one should prance around saying how they&#8217;ll win every game and rub it in their opponent&#8217;s faces. &#8220;Look at me! I&#8217;m so great!&#8221; I mean sure, sometimes the cockiness works as a placebo effect and some people end up becoming &#8220;stronger,&#8221; but then everyone thinks you&#8217;re an asshole and that is way worse than being a weak player. So instead, I will stop using negative statements and stop worrying about what other people think.<br />
With each stone I play, I will simply aim to play the best go that I can. That is all that matters.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/confidence-worth-two-stones/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">4059</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Friday Go Forward: Week 19</title>
		<link>/friday-go-forward-week-19/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2013 09:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Progress Reports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lots of training]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zen]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=2921</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Overview This has been an interesting week that was fraught with frustration, but paired with deep introspection that yielded something valuable for me as a whole. Although it took me some time to realize, there was a growing tendency for me to rush in both Go and my life in general. So, I am grateful [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>Overview</h2>
<p>This has been an interesting week that was fraught with frustration, but paired with deep introspection that yielded something valuable for me as a whole. Although it took me some time to realize, there was a growing tendency for me to rush in both Go and my life in general. So, I am grateful that go has once again provided an avenue for me to improve my life as a whole once again. Beginning the path back to zen will have a number of butterfly effects, but I have a feeling they will be far from regrettable. =)</p>
<h2>Games</h2>
<ul>
<li><span style="line-height: 13px;">KGS &#8211; 4 games (2 wins : 2 losses)</span></li>
<li>DGS &#8211; 1 ongoing game</li>
<li>Nova &#8211; 2 ongoing games</li>
</ul>
<h2>Training</h2>
<ul>
<li><span style="line-height: 13px;">Finished <em>Essential Life &amp; Death: Vol. 1 </em>and started<em> Vol. 2</em>.</span></li>
<li>Finished reading <em>The Chinese Opening</em> by Yuan Zhou.</li>
<li>Started working on <em>Attacking and Defending Moyos </em>by Zeijst and Bozulich.</li>
<li>Started reading <em>Modern Master Games, Vol. 1 </em>by Zeijst and Bozulich.</li>
<li>Started working on <em>Positional Judgment </em>by Cho Chikun.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Lessons Learned</h2>
<ol>
<li>If I feel like I am strapped for time or rushed before I even start a game, it&#8217;s probably best to not even bother playing.</li>
<li>To refrain from kyu tunnel vision, I need to look at the board with fresh eyes after every move.</li>
</ol>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2921</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Losing Sight of Zen</title>
		<link>/losing-sight-of-zen/</link>
		<comments>/losing-sight-of-zen/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2013 22:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[calmness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zen]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=2953</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In case this isn&#8217;t apparent, this is a 2-D drawing. And also, do you spot what I see? xD Late last night, I had written about the fact that my go has become a race to the finish line. I realize that I was probably not the most articulate since I was about to pass [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_2954" style="width: 413px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/06/moiillusions.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-2954" alt="moiillusions" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/06/moiillusions.jpg?resize=413%2C310" width="413" height="310" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Credit to <a href="http://www.moillusions.com/">moillusions</a> for the illustration and frozensoul for finding it.</figcaption></figure>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>In case this isn&#8217;t apparent, this is a 2-D drawing. And also, do you spot what I see? xD</em></p>
<p>Late last night, I had written about the fact that my go has become a race to the finish line. I realize that I was probably not the most articulate since I was about to pass out, but upon further reflection this morning, I realized that my problem actually is rooted in the fact that I have lost sight of my zen (aka my center of calm).<br />
Whenever I play a move, I realized that I am always in a hurry to see what my opponent plays next. In fact, it&#8217;s almost as if I&#8217;m trying to play a blitz game in a game that&#8217;s supposed to have a main time of 20 minutes or more. As a result, autopilot moves show up and failure to consider global effects arise again and again.<br />
Bottom line: I need find my center again. Otherwise, this will quickly spiral out of control and my go will become a reckless monster beyond saving. This ends today.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/losing-sight-of-zen/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2953</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Paranoid Go</title>
		<link>/paranoid-go/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2013 21:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[haphazard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lack of focus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[obstacle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[paranoid go]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zen]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=2640</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[As you know, I have been in a rather &#8220;meh&#8221; mood when it comes to playing go. It&#8217;s not so much that I&#8217;ve lost interest in the game, but I found my play style becoming very scattered and ugly. It wasn&#8217;t until recently that frozensoul helped to shed light on the issue and told me [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As you know, I have been in a rather &#8220;meh&#8221; mood when it comes to playing go. It&#8217;s not so much that I&#8217;ve lost interest in the game, but I found my play style becoming very scattered and ugly. It wasn&#8217;t until recently that frozensoul helped to shed light on the issue and told me that I have entered a &#8220;paranoid go&#8221; phase. My moves are played haphazardly and often lack a sense of focus and purpose. Although I once wrote of this roadblock as being a &#8220;mood&#8221; issue, it seems that it may actually be a rather large obstacle that I must overcome.<br />
In order to mediate this, I have taken a big step back from playing and have re-incorporated studying professional games into my routine. The aim of doing this is to try and unlock my paranoia of letting my opponents have any ideal opening or framework which often caused me to overextend myself which then resulted in my resignation.<br />
At this point in my journey, my abilities seem to fluctuate rather violently depending on my opponent and their play style. This is unacceptable for me, since I despise the idea that the player I am becoming is one that is blatantly weak to certain styles and then overpowering against others. My go should shine on its own regardless of who my opponent is. And to clarify, this does not mean I think I will win all of my games; but instead, I want all of my games to be interesting and something I can be proud to show to anyone.<br />
So while I am currently lost out in the sea paranoid go, when I find my way back onto the path of zen go: opponents beware. =)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2640</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
