<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>not rushing &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/not-rushing/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>The 6k Screwup</title>
		<link>/the-6k-screwup/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2013 22:30:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[not rushing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[progress]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[taking your time]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=1726</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[When I decided to return to ranked games, I will have to be honest in that I expected my graph to just shoot up. In fact, I&#8217;ve even developed a reputation in the ASR League for being a &#8220;3k Killer.&#8221; So it should obviously follow that any even games with 6 and 7 kyus should [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When I decided to return to ranked games, I will have to be honest in that I expected my graph to just shoot up. In fact, I&#8217;ve even developed a reputation in the ASR League for being a &#8220;3k Killer.&#8221; So it should obviously follow that any even games with 6 and 7 kyus should be something I can win in my sleep right? <em><b>WRONG!</b></em><br />
For those who don&#8217;t follow me on KGS, you&#8217;ll notice that my rank graph is well&#8230; a bit different from what I imagined it would be. xD<br />
<figure id="attachment_1731" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/01/rank2.png"><img class="size-full wp-image-1731" alt="rank2" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/01/rank2.png?resize=300%2C184" width="300" height="184" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Notice how it drops at the end? Twice?!</figcaption></figure>
Like anyone else, I was really frustrated by my progress. I mean, why was I having such a difficult time beating 6-7ks when I actually managed to beat stronger players in even games from time to time? I tried to make all kinds of excuses: the stronger players were underestimating me, my opponents were just lucky I made mistakes, I was in an off mood, etc. But after I realized how those were all just external attributions for things I had control over, I decided to look inward for the answer.<br />
<span id="more-1726"></span><br />
After some soul searching, I realized that the question I needed to ask myself was: Why are my ASR games so vastly different from my ranked games?<br />
At first, I thought that it might be because ranked games carried more pressure and so forth. While that may carry some validity, I know that it can&#8217;t be the excuse for my poor play against 6-7ks. I had to find an answer that I would be happy with. So the most obvious thing to do was compare my ranked games and my free games on ASR League.<br />
When I did, I noticed the following trends:</p>
<ul>
<li>ASR games represented a calm style that has proven quite formidable against stronger opponents.</li>
<li>Ranked games were extremely aggressive and resulted in either large wins or losses.</li>
<li>If I lost a ranked game, I would feel compelled to keep playing in an effort to &#8220;redeem&#8221; myself.&#8221;</li>
<li>This usually led to me accepting games that averaged around 10 &#8211; 15 minutes main time in order to get a quick win.</li>
<li>I usually played ranked games when procrastinating other work I should have been doing.</li>
<li>I never felt bad about losing a game where I was able to give my full efforts into each move.</li>
</ul>
<h3 style="text-align: center">EUREKA! ALL MY PROBLEMS CAN BE TRACED TO ONE THING: TIME.</h3>
<p>Here&#8217;s why:</p>
<ol>
<li>Since my nature is already prone to getting into massive fights, having the time pressure only exasperates my bad habit.</li>
<li>If I have a bitter loss, then the aggressive tendency gets worse and I start playing games with even shorter time frames.</li>
<li>The shorter time frames make me more frantic and I end up playing moves that I &#8220;think&#8221; will work out, but any closer inspection would prove otherwise.</li>
</ol>
<p>As a result, I resolve to have the minimum requirements when I play: 30 minutes main time with at least 3 periods of 30 second byoyomi.* Anything shorter than that has a good chance to throw me off course. And until I have reinforced the fundamentals in every fiber, I will stick with these guidelines in order to prevent myself from self-destructing.**After all, every game I play is a game that I can be proud of, regardless of whether I win or lose.<br />
*For other players, I would recommend a bare minimum of 20 minutes main time because 10 minutes really ends up being more like blitz than anything else.<br />
**The one exception to this rule will be my Tygem 5-dan experiment. =D</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1726</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
