<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>free games &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/free-games/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>Free Game Zen</title>
		<link>/free-game-zen/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2012 17:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kifu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[3k]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[defeat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[even game]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[free games]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[resignation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[white]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=1364</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[When I decided to go on a ranked game sabbatical, I will tell you right now that I doubted my own abilities to follow through on it. If I could relate it to a person&#8217;s diet, it is as if a carnivore  tries to go vegetarian for a month. For most people, the thought is [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When I decided to go on a ranked game sabbatical, I will tell you right now that I doubted my own abilities to follow through on it. If I could relate it to a person&#8217;s diet, it is as if a carnivore  tries to go vegetarian for a month. For most people, the thought is incredibly daunting and seemingly impossible. Just like ranked games, I wasn&#8217;t sure whether it was entirely possible to go a whole month without playing a single ranked game; but here I am, Day 17, and the differentiation between ranked and free games has become a faint blur. I will be the first to admit that this will not be permanent, but I think this new perspective has allowed my go to be far more creative than before.<br />
The other benefit to playing these free games is that the obsession with winning and losing has also begun to diminish. Most of my games are even games against players that are at least 3 stones stronger, so getting demolished constantly seems to have been good for my go soul. =) On top of it all, when winning and losing becomes more of an afterthought, I find that my games are far more interesting and expand on my current abilities.<br />
Still not convinced? Well, then let me direct your attention to a game I played with a 3k. Hope you enjoy!<br />

<div id='glift_display1' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display1","sgf":"http:\/\/bengozen.com\/\/wp-content\/uploads\/2012\/12\/2012.12.17-Free-Game-Zen.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='//wp-content/uploads/2012/12/2012.12.17-Free-Game-Zen.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"> [download label=&#8221;Download Kifu&#8221;]//wp-content/uploads/2012/12/2012.12.17-Free-Game-Zen.sgf[/download]
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1364</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>So Far So Good&#8230;</title>
		<link>/so-far-so-good/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2012 22:48:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[free games]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[getting stronger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the next horizon]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=1349</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Contrary to my previous attempts at abstaining from ranked games, I&#8217;m happy to report that I have kept to that promise thus far. I won&#8217;t say that it hasn&#8217;t been difficult, since I can&#8217;t help but stare at the numerous opponents I could be playing. Nevertheless, the free games that I&#8217;ve been playing have helped [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Contrary to my previous attempts at abstaining from ranked games, I&#8217;m happy to report that I have kept to that promise thus far. I won&#8217;t say that it hasn&#8217;t been difficult, since I can&#8217;t help but stare at the numerous opponents I could be playing. Nevertheless, the free games that I&#8217;ve been playing have helped to abate that desire. In addition, I&#8217;m also very happy to report that my apprehensiveness at playing White has diminished significantly since that <a title="Resistant to Playing White" href="//resistant-to-playing-white/">last post</a>.<br />
In regards to my study, I&#8217;ve been working on studying more on shapes and how to attack properly. The free games have been great because they allow me to experiment with the concepts I&#8217;ve been exposing myself to, and as always, having stronger players review my games afterwards give me a better sense of how far off the mark I am when attempting to apply X Y Z principles.<br />
As I&#8217;ve began to enter the realm of mid-SDK ranks, I am beginning to see that the terrain of each game has begun to deviate from the go I was familiar with before in the lower kyu. For example, many games in the past were often determined by large captures. Nowadays, I have noticed that failure to take direction of play and whole board strategy into consideration generally ends poorly for me. It&#8217;s not to say that my reading abilities are good enough as they stand, but the other intricacies of the game (e.g., leaving behind aji on purpose, solid knowledge of joseki, etc.) will soon become critical to master if I am to take the next step.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1349</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
