<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>desire to win &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/desire-to-win/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>The Desire to Win &#8211; Part 2</title>
		<link>/the-desire-to-win-part-2/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2012 15:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[baduk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[desire to win]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[go]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weiqi]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=28</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I have to admit that the responses that I received yesterday from my post have certainly made me reconsider my position from yesterday&#8217;s post, but ultimately I think it is more of a paradigm shift than necessarily regretting my decision to resign. For those of you who have never seen this video, please take 20 [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I have to admit that the responses that I received yesterday from my post have certainly made me reconsider my position from yesterday&#8217;s post, but ultimately I think it is more of a paradigm shift than necessarily regretting my decision to resign.<br />
For those of you who have never seen this video, please take 20 seconds and watch this unbelievable and tragic event happen to a professional 9-dan.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='720' height='405' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/qt1FvPxmmfE?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;fs=1&#038;autohide=2&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;wmode=transparent' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;'></iframe>
<p><em>Can you imagine? Playing a professional game on live television as a professional 9-dan and then putting yourself in self-atari? Although you have to admit, the man handled himself quite well and his reaction was quite priceless.</em><br />
<span id="more-28"></span><br />
That being said, the reason for the second part of this post is due to a friend of mine, Justin, who commented on a distinction that I had not really considered: <strong>the competitive setting</strong>. For those who would like to read about his personal experience with both sides of the regretful win/loss, see his comment in <a title="The Desire to Win – Part 1" href="//the-desire-to-win-part-1/">Part 1 of this topic</a>.<br />
Although I may have declared that all games should be won with as much honor as possible, I was not fair in considering the many aspects that go contains.<br />
Like anything else in life, as much as we may try to make the right decisions, we are human and are prone to our mistakes. I recognize that the first post of this topic argued to &#8220;do the right thing,&#8221; but that does not take into account the fact that <strong>luck and mistakes are just as much a part of go as it is in anything else</strong>.<br />
Last night, my friend Nate said it best when he told me that, &#8220;<strong>In some regards, the basic notion of trying to catch up in a game is to hope that your opponent will make a slack move or even a mistake.</strong>&#8221; Those words really struck me and as a result, I&#8217;m sitting here re-evaluating the stance I had taken just hours ago.<br />
As Justin stated, competitive go is a completely different setting. Each win is coveted by every player. <strong>Your opponents will take advantage of every slack move, and they will punish you for your mistakes.</strong> Do not err in thinking that the &#8220;honorable win&#8221; will draw any sympathy from your opponents.<br />
Ultimately, for my own experience, the decision to resign is still not a regrettable one. While improving your rank may be arguably &#8220;competitive,&#8221; I would argue it&#8217;s more a casual thing where there is very little at stake except your ego and pride. (<em>Granted, some people would say that a person&#8217;s ego and pride is extremely important. I fall into the camp where I think ego and pride is overrated</em>.)<br />
When the time comes to tournament/competitive play however, I have every intention of winning with everything I have that day&#8230; and that includes skill, luck, and even my opponent&#8217;s mistake(s). Otherwise, I plan on winning with my strength alone, because that is the basis where our pursuit to become one stone stronger will ultimately come from.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">28</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Desire to Win &#8211; Part 1</title>
		<link>/the-desire-to-win-part-1/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2012 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kifu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[baduk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[desire to win]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[go]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weiqi]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=29</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Today, I am writing about a more solemn topic that I know most people would shy away from posting on. However, I believe that this post touches on something that almost every go player will encounter along their journey: the desire to win. It is a difficult topic for me to write at the moment [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Today, I am writing about a more solemn topic that I know most people would shy away from posting on. However, I believe that this post touches on something that almost every go player will encounter along their journey: <strong>the desire to win</strong>. It is a difficult topic for me to write at the moment since the disappointing kifu is fresh off the board, but by doing so I hope to capture a vulnerability that we all feel at one point or another.<br />
<span id="more-29"></span><br />
In terms of what I mean when I say the desire to win, I&#8217;m not just talking about the simple desire for victory. After all, most people enjoy winning and the feeling of doing so. Instead, I&#8217;m talking about the type of desperation to win that you lose your rationale and even if you somehow manage to win, it&#8217;s the type of win that eats away at you because you know you didn&#8217;t really deserve it.<br />
For <span style="text-decoration: underline;">Hikaru no Go</span> fans, the following scene should be familiar.<br />
<figure id="attachment_466" style="width: 392px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2012/09/hikaru83_06.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-466" title="Hikaru No Go - Chapter 83" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2012/09/hikaru83_06.jpg?resize=392%2C640" alt="" width="392" height="640" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Hikaru No Go &#8211; Chapter 83</figcaption></figure>
Who could possibly forget how tortured Hikaru felt afterwards? After all, is there really any honor or joy that can really come from a win like this?</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">The game record for today is precisely that kind of win.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">
<div id='glift_display1' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display1","sgf":"http:\/\/bengozen.com\/\/wp-content\/uploads\/2012\/09\/2012.09.27-The-Desire-to-Win.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='//wp-content/uploads/2012/09/2012.09.27-The-Desire-to-Win.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">[download label=&#8221;Download Kifu&#8221;]//wp-content/uploads/2012/09/2012.09.27-The-Desire-to-Win.sgf[/download]
<p>For those who don&#8217;t have time to see the game record and the commentary, it essentially consists of me trying to win a capture race where I&#8217;m about six moves behind. And it wasn&#8217;t a complicated race, my group was two moves away from death. Ultimately, my opponent&#8217;s overconfidence caused him to actually lose his entire group.<br />
Now he still thought he was going to win, so he played it out to the end; but when he realized he was short 3.5 points, he left the game &#8220;for obvious reasons.&#8221;<br />
At first, I tried justifying to myself that I deserved that win. After all, it was my opponent&#8217;s cockiness and carelessness that led him to the situation&#8230;. serves him right&#8230;. right? I didn&#8217;t want to lose&#8230; I wanted my rank to go up&#8230; why should I give up my win for his mistake&#8230;.<br />
So in regards to the results of the game, technically, I did win with a +3.5 margin. After some thought and in the midst of drafting this post, I came to a realization. <strong>Even though most people would have viewed their opponent escaping as a frustrating event that might have even demanded the attention of an admin since the game had been played out to the very end, this should instead be looked as an opportunity for me to do the right thing.</strong><br />
Many people would say that the lessons in Go are parallel to those in life, and this is precisely one of those moments. <strong>Everything in life can ultimately be boiled down to which perspective you choose to take. And in the end, it is precisely these choices that lead us down the various paths we call our life.</strong><br />
Faced with a major crossroad, I decided to do the right thing: I resigned. If I let an admin or the system eventually force the game in my favor, that would be a permanent mark that I would never be able to change. By resigning, my spirit is at rest and I can move forward without the guilt.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Update: This post has now become a two-part post in order to account for some great points that were brought up. <a title="The Desire to Win – Part 2" href="//the-desire-to-win-part-2/">Read The Desire to Win &#8211; Part 2 here</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">29</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
