<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>reckless &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/reckless/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>Impulsive Recklessness</title>
		<link>/impulsive-recklessness/</link>
		<comments>/impulsive-recklessness/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2013 20:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bad habits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[impulsive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[obstacle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reckless]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=3850</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Last night I had the pleasure of playing fellow go twitter friend goBum. For our first game against one another, I thought it was exciting and a lot of fun. Afterwards though, we were severely reminded of the numerous mistakes that occurred throughout the game. Of the two of us though, I would have to say [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Last night I had the pleasure of playing fellow go twitter friend <a href="http://www.twitter.com/gobum">goBum</a>. For our first game against one another, I thought it was exciting and a lot of fun. Afterwards though, we were severely reminded of the numerous mistakes that occurred throughout the game. Of the two of us though, I would have to say that my play was probably the most shameful. Haha. And if you&#8217;re wondering what kind of moves I&#8217;m talking about, I mean the whole gamut of making empty triangles that are thank you moves along with playing impulsive moves that are the equivalent of passing. Needless to say, I got what I deserved when it came to verbal bashing. Haha. xD<br />
Since I&#8217;m a glutton for punishment, I decided to also show the game to sensei today. As I expected, the feedback wasn&#8217;t much better from his end either. Haha. However, he pointed out a critical flaw in my play: I still play from a pressured player mindset. In other words, I get so entangled in myself that I fail to analyze the board correctly. I fail to separate myself from what is happening on the board. Instead of calm analysis of what&#8217;s going on, any slight deviation from what I expected led to me feeling like it as a personal failure instead of a simple change on the board to be accounted for. As a result, the impulsive and reckless moves that plague my game are inevitable.<br />
To separate myself from the game when I play&#8230; What a cumbersome obstacle I have in my way&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/impulsive-recklessness/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3850</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
