<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>pro &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/pro/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>Book Review: Fight Like a Pro &#8211; The Secrets of Kiai</title>
		<link>/book-review-fight-like-a-pro-the-secrets-of-kiai/</link>
		<comments>/book-review-fight-like-a-pro-the-secrets-of-kiai/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2013 09:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fighting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[innovative]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kiai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[resistance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spirit]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=3586</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Fight Like a Pro &#8211; The Secrets of Kiai Description: In the final installment of the Mastering the Basics Series, Zeijst and Bozulich bring the first significant effort to trying to put the concept of kiai on paper. In this book, you will find 16 fighting games by some of the world&#8217;s strongest players from [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/07/mtbsv8cover.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3587" alt="Mastering the Basics 8 Cover" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/07/mtbsv8cover.jpg?resize=300%2C444" width="300" height="444" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">Fight Like a Pro &#8211; The Secrets of Kiai</h2>
<p><strong>Description:</strong> In the final installment of the Mastering the Basics Series, Zeijst and Bozulich bring the first significant effort to trying to put the concept of kiai on paper. In this book, you will find 16 fighting games by some of the world&#8217;s strongest players from Korean, China, and Japan along with problems to give the reader practice at trying to figure out the &#8220;kiai move.&#8221; This book can be seen a culmination of everything that the reader has been learning throughout the series and will be a classic in go literature.<br />
<span id="more-3586"></span><br />
[expand title=&#8221;Book Details&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
[table]
Title, Fight Like a Pro &#8211; The Secrets of Kiai (Volume 8)<br />
Series, Mastering the Basics Series<br />
Author, Rob van Zeijst &amp; Richard Bozulich<br />
Publisher, <a href="http://www.kiseido.com/">Kiseido</a><br />
Published, &#8220;December 2012&#8243;<br />
Language, English<br />
ISBN, 978-4-906574-78-0<br />
Length, 282 Pages<br />
[/table]
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Table of Content&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ol>
<li>What is kiai?</li>
<li>Kiai and komi</li>
<li>Fear and kiai</li>
<li>Psychological warfare</li>
<li>Players featured in these games</li>
<li>Tournaments in which the games were played</li>
<li>Game One: Wang Yuhui vs. Kim Seong-ryong</li>
<li>Game Two: Yuki Satoshi vs. Takao Shinji</li>
<li>Game Three: Kobayashi Satoru vs. O Meien</li>
<li>Game Four: Yuki Satoshi vs. Hane Naoki</li>
<li>Game Five: Li He vs. Fan Yunruo</li>
<li>Game Six: Takao Shiji vs. Cho U</li>
<li>Game Seven: Iyama Yuta vs. Yoda Norimoto</li>
<li>Game Eight: Chang Hao vs. Yi Se-tol</li>
<li>Game Nine: Gu Li vs. Weon Seong-chin</li>
<li>Game Ten: Gu Li vs. Weon Seong-chin</li>
<li>Game Eleven: Pak Cheong-sang vs. Hane Naoki</li>
<li>Game Twelve: Gu Li vs. Chang Hao</li>
<li>Game Thirteen: Liu Xing vs. Chang Hao</li>
<li>Game Fourteen: Yi Ch&#8217;ang-ho vs. Qiu Jun</li>
<li>Game Fifteen: Pak Yeong-hun vs. Kong Jie</li>
<li>Game Sixteen: O Meien vs. Miyazawa Goro</li>
<li>Mastering the Basics</li>
</ol>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Before I Read This Book&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<strong>My Abilities</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Of the various styles that exists in go, I&#8217;m pretty sure most people would agree that mine leans towards fighting. However, my attacks and fighting abilities are still rather wild, ineffective and often misdirected.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>My Perspective</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>As my style naturally leans towards fighting, I was sold the moment I saw &#8220;fight like a pro.&#8221; Based on the trends of the series, I was hoping to see the principles behind fighting and then a bunch of practice problems to hone my fighting skills.</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Synopsis&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<strong>What did I enjoy about the book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>There are problems that allows players to guess what the kiai move was.</li>
<li>There is a short section at the beginning explaining some of the philosophy and background behind what kiai really is.</li>
<li>Whenever an idea like &#8220;Black cutting there would be disastrous, so he avoided it,&#8221; you can be sure that there will be a diagram to illustrate and prove it to the reader.</li>
<li>I really enjoyed getting to see analysis on professional games by some of the most well known players (i.e., Gu Li, Lee Changho, Lee Sedol, etc.) in today&#8217;s go scene.</li>
<li>They had a blitz game!!! It was epic!!!</li>
<li>Though difficult to understand at times, Zeijst and Bozulich do an incredible job breaking down professional games to an understandable level.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What did I gain from reading this book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>A better understanding of what kiai is and how to use kiai in my own games.</li>
<li>Realization that kiai is not equivalent to starting random fights, trying desperately to kill something, or starting a fight that endangers the life of one of your groups. Instead, they are very calculated moves that are meant to open up opportunities to make a comeback or disrupt the opponent&#8217;s plans.</li>
<li>Insight into what goes into a professional&#8217;s decision and what I can do myself to try and apply it to my own games.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What is the format of this book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>After a short introduction on what kiai is and its significance in go, the book is universally structured as a game review. Each chapter will start with what colors each respective player had (for the featured game) followed by how much komi was played, the amount of time each player had, and where and when it was played. Then, as one might expect with any game review, there are the accompanying diagrams of the actual kifu (broken out in chunks at a time) along with variations along the way. The one refreshing aspect that gives the reader a break from simply reading are the questions that Zeijst and Bozulich pose along the way (e.g., &#8220;Where do you think Black played in response to 34?&#8221;).</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What aspect can be improved on?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>This is extremely nit-picky, but what would have made each game kifu complete is if the ruleset that was used in each game was included. Again, super super minor; but something that would have been nice to have.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Is this book easy to read?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>For the most part, the book is very easy to follow and understand. The diagrams are never too long. In addition, Zeijst and Bozulich take each game at a pretty steady pace so that weaker players like myself have an opportunity to think through certain important moves instead of just rushing through the kifu. A word of caution though, the explanations can be a little advanced at times; but this is also what is part of its charm since I can look forward to learning more when I read it again in the future.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Bottom Line</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>A very comprehensive application of all the fundamentals you learn from the rest of the series along with other books as well.</li>
<li>Contains a great collection of games from current professionals (e.g., Gu Li, Lee Sedol, etc.), which is always a treat!</li>
<li>The focus of the book is more on kiai and not fighting techniques.</li>
<li>A pioneer in go literature on the topic of kiai that amateur players will definitely come to appreciate in the years to come.</li>
</ol>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;My Review&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221; expanded=&#8221;true&#8221;]
One of the things I really enjoyed about this book is the fact though the explanations can be difficult to comprehend at times, the diagrams are usually only a few moves long and really allows the reader to take the game in bite sizes.<br />
In addition, I really like how Zeijst and Bozulich takes great care in ensuring that their statements are backed up by a variations. An example of this would be like, &#8220;The commonsense move of Black A would be disastrous.&#8221; Once they make a statement like this, there is almost always a diagram to show why. Whether you can fully grasp it is a whole different matter, but the proof is there.<br />
Finally, though there were a number of times where I felt lost and unable to quite comprehend the severity of what was going on, I definitely felt something awaken inside of me after playing through all the kifus in this book. And even though I didn&#8217;t end up learning &#8220;fighting principles,&#8221; the lesson and multiple demonstrations of true kiai through the games of many strong professionals I have come to respect has truly been an eye opening experience.<br />
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Recommended For&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Players who have a thorough understanding of the fundamentals introduced in the previous Mastering the Basics series.</li>
<li>Players who enjoy reviewing professional games and having the games broken down to them while learning about kiai.</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Where Can I Buy It?&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Kiseido &#8211; <a title="Kiseido Purchase Link" href="http://kiseido.com/go_books.htm">$25.00</a> USD (shipping and handling not included)</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Other Books in This Series&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;lastExpandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li><a title="Book Review: 501 Opening Problems" href="//book-review-501-opening-problems/">Mastering the Basics, Volume 1 &#8211; 501 Opening Problems</a></li>
<li><a title="Book Review: 1001 Life and Death Problems" href="//book-review-1001-life-and-death-problems/">Mastering the Basics, Volume 2 &#8211; 1001 Life and Death Problems</a></li>
<li><a title="Book Review: Making Good†Shape" href="//book-review-making-good-shape/">Mastering the Basics, Volume 3 &#8211; Making Good Shape</a></li>
<li><a title="Book Review: 501 Tesuji Problems" href="//book-review-501-tesuji-problems/">Mastering the Basics, Volume 4 &#8211; 501 Tesuji Problems</a></li>
<li><a title="Book Review: The Basics of Go Strategy" href="//book-review-the-basics-of-go-strategy/">Mastering the Basics, Volume 5 &#8211; The Basics of Go Strategy</a></li>
<li><a title="Book Review: All About†Ko" href="//book-review-all-about-ko/">Mastering the Basics, Volume 6 &#8211; All About Ko</a></li>
<li><a title="Book Review: Attacking and Defending Moyos" href="//book-review-attacking-and-defending-moyos/">Mastering the Basics, Volume 7 &#8211; Attacking and Defending Moyos</a></li>
<li>Mastering the Basics, Volume 8 &#8211; Fight Like a Pro &#8211; The Secrets of Kiai</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
<p style="text-align: center;"><em><strong>Last Updated on September 4th, 2013</strong></em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/book-review-fight-like-a-pro-the-secrets-of-kiai/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3586</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pro Event at the Japanese Embassy</title>
		<link>/pro-event-at-the-japanese-embassy/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2013 21:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kifu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[4p]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[japanese]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[narumi osawa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[professional]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rengo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartgo]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=2299</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[On April 2nd, 2013, I had the honor of being able to attend a professional go event that featured Narumi Osawa (4p) and was hosted by the Japanese Embassy in Washington D.C. It was a free event that consisted of a short talk designed for beginners, a simultaneous game against Narumi, and a lecture/review on [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/04/japanembassy.jpg"><img alt="japanembassy" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/04/japanembassy.jpg?resize=300%2C225" width="300" height="225" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></p>
<p>On April 2nd, 2013, I had the honor of being able to attend a professional go event that featured Narumi Osawa (4p) and was hosted by the Japanese Embassy in Washington D.C. It was a free event that consisted of a short talk designed for beginners, a simultaneous game against Narumi, and a lecture/review on one of the games.<br />
<span id="more-2299"></span><br />
For those who don&#8217;t know Narumi, here is a short biography on her.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/04/narumi-osawa.jpg"><img alt="narumi osawa" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/04/narumi-osawa.jpg?resize=208%2C303" width="208" height="303" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></p>
<ul>
<li>Born in Saitama Prefecture, Japan on May 22nd, 1976.</li>
<li>Became professional 1-dan in 1998, promoted to 2-dan in 1999, 3-dan in 2003, and 4-dan in 2009.</li>
<li>Won the Women’s Kakusei Title（女流鶴聖戦） in 1999 and 2003, and the Women’s JAL Title（JAL女流早碁戦）in 2005.</li>
<li>Participated in the 16th Asian Tournament as a member of the Japanese National Team.</li>
</ul>
<p>Being as the event was in D.C. on a weekday night, I made sure to pad extra time for any possible metro delays or my own inability to find the place. Luckily I did, because even though I arrived about half an hour early, it took me walking into two different buildings before I finally found the Japanese Embassy.<br />
In all honesty, I was a little skeptical as to how many people would be able to attend since it was in D.C. and on a Tuesday. For those who don&#8217;t live in the area, traffic can be crazy when trying to get into the city during rush hour; but I was pleasantly surprised to see that a lot of people showed up! On top of that, there were actually a number of beginners who came as well! It was certainly very uplifting to see so many people attend.<br />
<figure style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/04/japanembassy5.jpg"><img alt="japanembassy5" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/04/japanembassy5.jpg?resize=300%2C225" width="300" height="225" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">As you can see, the place is filled with people!</figcaption></figure>
When the time came to meet Narumi, I was a little more nervous than usual because I knew that she didn&#8217;t speak very much English. Fortunately, there was a translator that helped to facilitate some basic conversation between her and I regarding how strong I was. One of the interesting questions I got from her was what we considered beginners to be in terms of rank. I responded that we considered beginners to be anywhere from 30-20k. As she nodded to acknowledge my statement, I couldn&#8217;t help but be reminded of how most players in Asia probably only recognize dan as an actual rank. Haha.<br />
When it came time for the event to start, we were still short on boards and missing the demonstration board. Narumi was quick on her feet however, and she suggested that the beginners form two teams and she would comment on the game as they played. After a little bit of shuffling around, two teams of five were formed and play began. Here are some photographs from the beginner event:<br />
<figure style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/04/japanembassy2.jpg"><img alt="japanembassy2" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/04/japanembassy2.jpg?resize=300%2C400" width="300" height="400" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">The two kids here are choosing for color.<br />Side Note: It was exciting when we found out that the boy is an elementary student who aspires to be a professional player!</figcaption></figure>
<figure style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/04/japanembassy3.jpg"><img alt="japanembassy3" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/04/japanembassy3.jpg?resize=300%2C225" width="300" height="225" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Each player was permitted 3 moves before letting the next player rotate in.</figcaption></figure>
<figure style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/04/japanembassy4.jpg"><img alt="japanembassy4" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/04/japanembassy4.jpg?resize=300%2C225" width="300" height="225" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Narumi Osawa (4p) explaining a concept to the audience.</figcaption></figure>
<p style="text-align: left;">Afterwards, in order to try and accommodate the number of players, Narumi thought it would be best to have people play rengo (e.g, pair go) against her. So without hesitation, I asked my friend Gurujeet to join me in the battle to try and survive against a professional. As neither Gurujeet nor I have played much pair go, it was approached with fun and adventure as we played a game that was not necessarily our best, but certainly yielded a rather interesting game. =)</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Due to time constraints and the need to move on to the next part of the event, we were unable to finish the game in its entirety. (Although in all honesty, both Gurujeet and I were already preparing to say &#8220;I resign&#8221; in Japanese anyways. xD) To my surprise however, Narumi wanted me show our game on the demonstration board for her commentary. Needless to say, I was happy to do so (and silently thanking SmartGo again for always being there in my time of need for a solid kifu app).</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">When I got up on the stage, it felt a little surreal to think that I was the person helping the professional put stones on the demonstration board. I mean, I&#8217;ve seen it on videos a ton of times, but to actually be the one doing it! So cool! And to top it all off, it was my game as well!</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">As I stood up there listening to Narumi explain various aspects of our game in Japanese, for the first time ever, I felt go transcend the language barrier. I know that sounds really odd, but even though I have practically no knowledge of Japanese, I felt as if I could understand the core concept of each of her messages as she spoke and moved stones around. Call me crazy, but it was an incredible experience.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">The following is the game record from that night with any commentary from Narumi clearly marked.</p>

<div id='glift_display1' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display1","sgf":"http:\/\/bengozen.com\/\/wp-content\/uploads\/2013\/04\/2013.04.04-Pro-Event-at-the-Japanese-Embassy.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='//wp-content/uploads/2013/04/2013.04.04-Pro-Event-at-the-Japanese-Embassy.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">[download label=&#8221;Download Kifu&#8221;]//wp-content/uploads/2013/04/2013.04.04-Pro-Event-at-the-Japanese-Embassy.sgf[/download]
<p style="text-align: left;">Well, with that night, I have played a go pro from each of the major countries: Korea, China, Japan, and Taiwan! Woot! Now onwards to grow my collection of pro games!</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2299</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>North American Go Convention &#8211; Day 1</title>
		<link>/north-american-go-convention-day-1/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 22:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kifu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[6d]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[joanne missingham]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nagc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[north american go convention]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tournament]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=1895</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Introduction &#8212; Day 1 &#8212; Day 2 &#8212; Day 3 &#8212; Day 4 &#8212; Day 5 &#8212; Conclusion The day got off to a rather dreary start as I spent about an hour in rainy traffic trying to make my way down to the event. After grabbing a quick bite to eat, I found myself standing [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><a title="North American Go Convention!!!" href="//north-american-go-convention/">Introduction</a><strong> &#8212; Day 1</strong> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 2" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-2/">Day 2</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 3" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-3/">Day 3</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 4" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-4/">Day 4</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 5" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-5/">Day 5</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Conclusion" href="//north-american-go-convention-conclusion/">Conclusion</a></p>
<p>The day got off to a rather dreary start as I spent about an hour in rainy traffic trying to make my way down to the event. After grabbing a quick bite to eat, I found myself standing outside the building wondering how to get in. There was construction going on and with all the doors locked down I was running around trying to figure out how to get in for about 10 minutes. Thankfully someone was kind enough to let me in on their way out.<br />
As I rode the elevator up to the 9th floor, I was a little anxious as I expected a bit of a crowd since I was running late. Although I think the real concern for me was missing the opportunity to play a teaching/game with the professionals. When I arrived however, there were only around six to eight people in the waiting area. For those who aren&#8217;t aware, the North American Go Convention (NAGC) is a two part convention that started out in New Jersey and made its way down to DC. With the traffic and crummy weather, the bus was unfortunately running late and thus everything was pushed back. So all my rushing to get there on time was for naught. xD On the upside, it gave me a chance to settle down and catch my breath.<br />
While sitting in the waiting area, I couldn&#8217;t help but overhear as people were talking about their strengths and how long they&#8217;d been studying. There were a few Korean players and a couple Chinese players. The two younger players (around my age) had apparently started studying when they were around 5 years old and were 7 dan and 4 dan respectively. You can only imagine how I felt when I realized that I was the only kyu player in the room. Haha.<br />
As if things couldn&#8217;t get worse, one of the moms asked me later on how strong I was. After all the conversation in the room about how the children were dans and had started studying go since they were young, I think she just naturally expected me to say I was X dan. When I responded that I was 6 kyu, she gave me a quizzical look as if she had never heard of the rank. In fact, someone even asked, &#8220;So wait, is 6 kyu higher than 1 kyu?&#8221;<br />
&#8220;Dear lord,&#8221; I thought, &#8220;They don&#8217;t even recognize the kyu levels.&#8221; *hangs head in shame*<br />
<span id="more-1895"></span><br />
Of course, all you can do is really laugh as you realize how vast the world of go is and how strong people are.<br />
Anyhow, we eventually moved into the tournament room and I had the pleasure of catching up with Yuan Zhou while we waited. In addition, I played a friendly game with a someone who told me he had not played in a while. In terms of evaluating his strength, I could tell that he was no pushover and probably even stronger than me. So much for letting him take black. =D It was a fun game and it would&#8217;ve been interesting to see how it ended. Before we could really get into the middle game fighting though, we were happy to stop our game since <a href="http://senseis.xmp.net/?JoanneMissingham">Joanne Missingham</a> arrived!<br />
<figure id="attachment_1918" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/02/joannemissingham.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1918" alt="Joanne Missingham (Hei Jia Jia) 6P" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/02/joannemissingham.jpg?resize=300%2C200" width="300" height="200" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Joanne Missingham (Hei Jia Jia) 6P</figcaption></figure>
The next thing I know, I was sitting before her as I was about to play my second professional simultaneous game. Earlier that night, I had learned that the Chinese word for dan is pronounced dee and the Chinese word for kyu is jee. So when she came around, everyone else had told her their rank in Chinese, I decided to do the same. Due to my nervousness however, I ended up saying &#8220;6 dee&#8221; instead of &#8220;6 jee.&#8221; You can only imagine my surprise when she only told me to put down 2 stones when she told the other dans to put down three. Hahaha. After realizing what had happened, I quickly got her attention as I was like, &#8220;Wait wait! I&#8217;m 6 kyu! Not 6 dan!!&#8221; xD<br />
Even though this is not my first time playing a professional, it still blew my mind as to how strong professionals are. Their adherence to the fundamentals and unwavering will to exploit weaknesses and determine these things in matters of seconds is astonishing. Definitely awe-inspiring. I only hope that one day I will amount to even 10% of what they are.<br />
Below is the game record for my game with Joanne Missingham (6P). Due to the event starting late however, I didn&#8217;t really get a chance to discuss the game much with her. On the upside, I did get a couple of comments from her to clarify a few areas that I was positive caused my downfall. =)<br />

<div id='glift_display2' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display2","sgf":"http:\/\/bengozen.com\/\/wp-content\/uploads\/2013\/02\/2013.02.14-NAGC-Day-1.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='//wp-content/uploads/2013/02/2013.02.14-NAGC-Day-1.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">[download label=&#8221;Download Kifu&#8221;]//wp-content/uploads/2013/02/2013.02.14-NAGC-Day-1.sgf[/download]
<p>And for those who don&#8217;t happen to follow my twitter, the day ended with a bit of a hitch. You see, I followed the signs for visitors to park in the garage. Lo and behold, you can imagine my surprise when I came down to the garage to get my car and saw the garage doors shut. I thought I was going to be stranded outside for the rest of the night. Hahaha. But luckily I found a way into the garage and then eventually got out. Lesson learned for the next two nights!</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a title="North American Go Convention!!!" href="//north-american-go-convention/">Introduction</a><strong> &#8212; Day 1</strong> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 2" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-2/">Day 2</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 3" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-3/">Day 3</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 4" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-4/">Day 4</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 5" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-5/">Day 5</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Conclusion" href="//north-american-go-convention-conclusion/">Conclusion</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1895</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
