<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>tesuji &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/tesuji/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>Friday Go Forward: Week 59</title>
		<link>/friday-go-forward-week-59/</link>
		<comments>/friday-go-forward-week-59/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2014 11:15:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Progress Reports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life and death]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[risingstar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tesuji]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tournament]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[washington open]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5041</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Overview After trying to go through my training regimen from last week, I realized I was getting bored of practicing the same problems over and over again. And while my intentions were good (since my goal was to make all the problems instinctive), interest and motivation trumps that so I&#8217;ve moved on to more interesting [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 style="text-align: left;">Overview</h2>
<p>After trying to go through my training regimen from last week, I realized I was getting bored of practicing the same problems over and over again. And while my intentions were good (since my goal was to make all the problems instinctive), interest and motivation trumps that so I&#8217;ve moved on to more interesting topics to change it up for now. And especially after giving thought to the notion that <a title="WGW37: Tesuji More Useful Than Tsumego?" href="//wgw37-tesuji-more-useful-than-tsumego/">tesuji is more important than life and death</a>, I really wanted to start studying tesuji once again.<br />
On another note, in case anyone missed it, the <a title="Nova Go Club Tournaments Website" href="http://www.novagoclub.org/tournaments">Washington Open</a> is happening this weekend. Yours truly will be attending and competing/participating in whatever I can do. So you can definitely look forward to a series of posts on the event. I&#8217;m a little nervous because I haven&#8217;t really been playing as much as I should have, but I&#8217;ll have to brush that aside and just go to have as much fun as I can. If I can play really interesting games, then I will consider this event to be a success. See you all next week!<br />
PS. In case you didn&#8217;t know, fellow go player Risingstar just started his own <a title="RisingStar's Blog" href="http://gosimplycomplex.blogspot.com/">blog</a>, so be sure to check it out and support him as we try and bolster go&#8217;s presence online!</p>
<h2>Training Regimen</h2>
<ul>
<li><b>Life and Death Problems </b>
<ul>
<li>Book: Jump Level Up 5</li>
<li>Frequency: Daily</li>
<li>Task: 10 minutes working through problems</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong><span style="line-height: 1.5em;">Tesuji Problems</span></strong>
<ul>
<li><span style="line-height: 1.5em;"> Book: Graded Go Problems for Dan Players (Vol. 2) &#8211; 300 Tesuji Problems</span></li>
<li>Frequency: Daily</li>
<li>Task: 10 minutes working through problems</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h2>Games</h2>
<ul>
<li><a title="KGS Website" href="http://www.gokgs.com/">KGS</a> &#8211;  3 games</li>
<li><a title="Pandanet-IGS Official Site" href="http://pandanet-igs.com/communities/pandanet">IGS</a> &#8211; 2 games</li>
<li><a title="Dragon Go Server - BenGoZen's Profile" href="http://www.dragongoserver.net/userinfo.php?uid=60385">DGS</a> &#8211; 5 ongoing games</li>
<li><a title="Online Go Server - BenGoZen's Profile" href="http://online-go.com/user/view/549/BenGoZen">OGS</a> &#8211;  2 ongoing games</li>
</ul>
<h2>Books</h2>
<ul>
<li>Jump Level Up 5</li>
<li>Graded Go Problems for Dan Players (Vol. 2) &#8211; 300 Tesuji Problems</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/friday-go-forward-week-59/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">5041</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>WGW37: Tesuji More Useful Than Tsumego?</title>
		<link>/wgw37-tesuji-more-useful-than-tsumego/</link>
		<comments>/wgw37-tesuji-more-useful-than-tsumego/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2014 11:15:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Weekly Go Wednesday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[amazing moves]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[awe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[getting stronger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hikaru no go]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meijin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tesuji]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tsumego]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5039</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Weekly Go Wednesday, Issue #37 Last Friday, I mentioned an article that was shared with me on how to improve at go by Lynx. According to conventional wisdom, the one piece of advice that everyone seem to agree upon is that studying life and death is critical to getting stronger. And to be honest, it&#8217;s [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 style="text-align: center;">Weekly Go Wednesday, Issue #37</h2>
<p>Last <a title="Friday Go Forward: Week 58" href="//friday-go-forward-week-58/">Friday</a>, I mentioned an <a title="Lynx's How to Improve at Go" href="http://shobia.com/w/How_to_Improve_at_Go">article</a> that was shared with me on how to improve at go by Lynx. According to conventional wisdom, the one piece of advice that everyone seem to agree upon is that studying life and death is critical to getting stronger. And to be honest, it&#8217;s something I never really questioned. However, after reading Lynx&#8217;s article, I was confronted with an eye-opening question: <strong>Is studying tesuji more useful than tsumego? </strong><br />
After a lot of thought,  I would have to concur  with Lynx&#8217;s perspective. In fact, it is one of the key components to breaking the glass ceiling when trying to gain that next stone. However, because the masses constantly spout how important life and death is, it is often forgotten in all the noise.<br />
<span style="line-height: 1.5em;">Now now, before you grab your pitchforks and torches, hear me out won&#8217;t you?</span><br />
<span id="more-5039"></span><br />
To start, I will go ahead and address probably the strongest argument against Lynx&#8217;s theory: What is the use of tesuji if you die everywhere?<br />
True. If your life and skills are so abysmal that you are slaughtered around the board, I agree with you in that tesuji will not do you much good. However, the reality of the situation is that most games don&#8217;t consist of groups dying all over the board (unless the rank is horribly imbalanced). And though this can partially be attributed to people studying life and death, my personal experience has shown me that the bottom line is that <em>it is really hard to kill groups in go</em>.<br />
Though people might not realize it, I think that players will inevitably learn about life and death as they play. Why do I say this? Because whenever your group dies, it is usually pretty traumatic. Who can remember that time when they thought their corner was alive and then died in a magnificent burst of flames? I know I can recount it on multiple occasions. And what happens when you die? Well usually you might go back to figure out how you could&#8217;ve avoided it. After all, who likes dying?<br />
On top of that, let&#8217;s not forget the fact that players constantly miss tesuji in their games. It is usually very obvious to players who are much stronger, but unless someone is having their game reviewed by such a player, how many people are going to spend time going over their game to figure out the numerous tesuji they missed? Highly unlikely. They are way more likely to just move on and play another game.<br />
In addition, no matter how peaceful a player you are, you are eventually going to get into fights on the board. I&#8217;m sure there are kifu that exists where no one challenged each other at all, but I&#8217;m pretty sure they only exist at the beginner level since they aren&#8217;t aware they are capable of invading and living. And when it comes to fighting, there is no better weapon than being better at tesuji than your opponent.<br />
Who remembers this scene?<br />
<figure id="attachment_5114" style="width: 422px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/wgw37tesuji01.png"><img class=" wp-image-5114" alt="wgw37tesuji01" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/wgw37tesuji01.png?resize=422%2C312" width="422" height="312" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Ring any bells? [Credit: Hikaru No Go Anime]</figcaption></figure><figure id="attachment_5115" style="width: 384px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/wgw37tesuji02.png"><img class=" wp-image-5115" alt="wgw37tesuji02" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/wgw37tesuji02.png?resize=384%2C291" width="384" height="291" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">How about this one? [Credit: Hikaru no Go Anime]</figcaption></figure><figure id="attachment_5116" style="width: 384px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/wgw37tesuji03.png"><img class=" wp-image-5116" alt="wgw37tesuji03" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/wgw37tesuji03.png?resize=384%2C291" width="384" height="291" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Still no? [Credit: Hikaru no Go Anime]</figcaption></figure>Many of you probably figured it out after the second screenshot, but the answer for those who couldn&#8217;t remember is: Episode 56, &#8220;After a Millennium Comes an Answer.&#8221;<br />
Anyhow, was this a move that dealt with life and death? Did Sai&#8217;s incredible move kill the Meijin&#8217;s group? No. It was a brilliant tesuji that made all spectators watch in amazement. And in fact, if you think about it, most of the moves that are met with astonishment and awe in the show are usually tesuji. They are all about how brilliant that connection was, or how this peep is an excellent forcing move that allows XYZ tesuji to work.<br />
Finally, I want to remind you that Lynx&#8217;s point is <strong><em>not</em></strong> to burn all your tsumego books and never life and death. Instead, she&#8217;s simply trying to remind us of how important tesuji are when it comes to gaining that next stone. So the next time you are thinking about what to study, I hope that you&#8217;ll consider making some time to study tesuji in your busy schedule. It&#8217;ll definitely be worth your while in the long run.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/wgw37-tesuji-more-useful-than-tsumego/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>12</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">5039</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Book Review: Basic Techniques of Go</title>
		<link>/book-review-basic-techniques-go/</link>
		<comments>/book-review-basic-techniques-go/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2013 23:35:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[endgame]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[handicap go]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[opening]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tesuji]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=4253</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Basic Techniques of Go Description: This book can be considered a broad coverage of the following: opening principles, lots of handicap go advice, brief survey of tesujis, and a brief survey of endgame. The material is quite dense and contrary to what many descriptions say about this book, I vehemently disagree with the recommending this [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/10/basictechniquesofgocover.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-4254" alt="basictechniquesofgocover" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/10/basictechniquesofgocover.jpg?resize=288%2C407" width="288" height="407" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">Basic Techniques of Go</h2>
<p><strong>Description:</strong> This book can be considered a broad coverage of the following: opening principles, lots of handicap go advice, brief survey of tesujis, and a brief survey of endgame. The material is quite dense and contrary to what many descriptions say about this book, I vehemently disagree with the recommending this book for beginners. It is suited for intermediate to advanced players. Beginners steer clear of this book!<br />
<span id="more-4253"></span><br />
[expand title=&#8221;Book Details&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
[table]
Title, Basic Techniques of Go<br />
Author, Haruyama Isamu 9P and Nagahara Yoshiaki 6P<br />
Edited by, Richard Bozulich<br />
Publisher, Kiseido<br />
Published, &#8220;First Printing, Feb. 1969 | Tenth Printing, Nov. 2002&#8243;<br />
Language, English<br />
ISBN, 4-906574-02-5<br />
Length, 172 Pages<br />
[/table]
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Table of Content&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Preface to the Third Edition</li>
<li>Technial Terms</li>
<li>Chapter One
<ul>
<li>Principles of Even-Game Openings
<ul>
<li>Opening Moves</li>
<li>Corner Enclosures</li>
<li>Approach Moves</li>
<li>Proper Timing of Enclosures, Approach Moves, and Extensions</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>How to Play Handicap Go</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Chapter Two
<ul>
<li>The Nine-Stone Handicap and the Attach-and-Extend Joseki</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Chapter Three
<ul>
<li>Six Stone Handicap Opening Strategy
<ul>
<li>White&#8217;s Capping Strategy</li>
<li>Invading the Sides</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Chapter Four
<ul>
<li>Four-Stone Handicap and the One-Space Jump Joseki</li>
<li>The One-Space Jump in Four-Stone Handicap Openings
<ul>
<li>The Pincer</li>
<li>Double Approach Moves</li>
<li>Double Pincer</li>
<li>The Attachment</li>
<li>Capping</li>
<li>The Invasion</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Chapter Five
<ul>
<li>A Survey of Tesuji
<ul>
<li>Tesuji Problems</li>
<li>Answer to the Tesuji Problems</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Chapter Six
<ul>
<li>The Endgame
<ul>
<li>Counting the Size of a Territory</li>
<li>Sente Endgame</li>
<li>Coutning the Size of an Endgame Play</li>
<li>Endgame Tesujis</li>
<li>Endgame Problems</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Appendix</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Before I Read This Book&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
I bought this book way back when I started go. I felt like I was completely lost when I first tried to read it, so here I am a couple years later trying to read it once more. What I was expecting when I bought it was a book on a broad coverage of techniques one would find with go. Now that I am much stronger and more experienced, I am still hoping for a survey of techniques along with clarification on their usage.<br />
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;My Review&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221; expanded=&#8221;true&#8221;]
When I first opened this book, I was a little surprised to be greeted by a chapter on opening theory. After all, this is a book on technique is it not? I recognize that selecting the correct opening move is a &#8220;technique&#8221; in a sense, but in my mind I was thinking more along the lines of haengma (i.e., the movement of the stones) or something else.<br />
With that aside though, the first chapter does cover quite a bit regarding the opening. While this is good in one sense, I still found it to be a bit dense and cannot imagine any beginner trying to work through this and achieve much success.<br />
And the next thing I know, the book is going full blown into handicap go coverage. All I could think when I kept reading was, &#8220;EH?!&#8221; I understand that these handicap go principles and techniques being described might seem &#8220;basic,&#8221; but even as a single digit kyu, even I was raising my eyebrows as I was trying to figure out what was going on. The diagrams were often rather complicated and required multiple readings just to get a sense of what was going on. After you work through a rather substantial amount of handicap go material, you finally get to the tesuji section.<br />
Here, I finally got a sense of what I was hoping for. A broad survey of different techniques used in different situations. With each tesuji, there is a brief explanation along with an example and an obvious variation or two that players might question. So while some of the material in here was a bit advanced and hard to grasp based on simple reading, this felt more like the book I was looking for when purchasing this book. And for those wondering about the problems, they are overall intermediate level and not very beginner friendly.<br />
For the last chapter, the reader is introduced to the importance of endgame. And while I would consider myself to at least be moderately versed when it comes to endgame, this was a rather tough section for me to work through. I can only imagine what it would be like for someone who had little to no exposure on endgame. Definitely not an easy chapter at all.<br />
Overall, I would divide the book into the following categories: 10% Opening Principles, 40% Handicap Go, 30% Tesuji, and 20% Endgame. And as such, I find that it is not quite aptly named as &#8220;Basic Techniques of Go&#8221; since there was far more handicap go than I think is appropriate for beginners. And not to mention, what about life and death? That deserves attention in here as well if it is going to be titled &#8220;Basic Techniques of Go.&#8221;<br />
In regards to its overall difficulty, it really does feel as if the reader needs to already have a decent grasp of the material in order to truly understand and digest the contents of this book. To be clear though, I am by no means saying that the content in this book is bad. Quite the contrary in fact, there is a lot of information considering how short the book is. It&#8217;s just that its rather dense for beginner/intermediate players.<br />
So if you fall into the category of beginner/intermediate players looking to get stronger, I do not recommend this book for you. Instead, I recommend checking out the Mastering the Basics series from Kiseido as a better alternative.<br />
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Synopsis&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<strong>What did I enjoy about the book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>There is a lot of information on handicap go.</li>
<li>They did do a pretty nice job surveying some common tesuji.</li>
<li>There were problems to accompany the tesuji and endgame section.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What did I gain from reading this book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Due to the dense material, I can&#8217;t say I really gained anything from this first reading.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What aspect(s) can be improved on?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>In all honesty, I don&#8217;t feel that it would be very fair for me to criticize the book at the moment since I feel that its content is generally out of reach for me. The one thing I will say is that the title is a little misleading to the unsuspecting player. Otherwise, I will save my comments for when I am able to better comprehend the book.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Is this book easy to read?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>As a mid to high single digit kyu, I felt that it was rather difficult to read due to the level of discussion that occurred in the book. However, if one could easily follow the level of content in this book, the English is rather straightforward and should be pretty easy to work through.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Bottom Line</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>Content is essentially 10% opening principles, 40% handicap go, 30% tesuji, and 20% endgame.</li>
<li>Better suited to players already familiar with the content in the book. In other words, NOT for beginners.</li>
<li>If you&#8217;re a beginner/intermediate player looking to get stronger, check out the Mastering Basics series instead.</li>
</ol>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Recommended For&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Intermediate/advanced players looking for additional material to study.</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Where Can I Buy It?&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Kiseido &#8211; <a href="http://kiseido.com/go_books.htm">$18</a> (shipping and handling not included)</li>
<li>SmartGo Books &#8211; <a href="http://gobooks.com/">$8.99</a> (iOS Devices Only)</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
<p style="text-align: center;"><em><strong>Last Updated on November 3rd, 2013</strong></em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/book-review-basic-techniques-go/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">4253</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Book Review: Get Strong at Tesuji</title>
		<link>/book-review-get-strong-tesuji/</link>
		<comments>/book-review-get-strong-tesuji/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2013 11:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bozulich]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[get strong]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kiseido]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tesuji]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=4014</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Get Strong at Tesuji Description: In the sixth volume of the Get Strong at Go Series, Bozulich has compiled a fantastic set of tesuji problems that focus on developing a player&#8217;s intuition through practicing lots of easier problems. Though there are a few intermediate/hard problems dispersed throughout the book, this is a great book for [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/09/getstrongv6.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-4015" alt="getstrongv6" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/09/getstrongv6.jpg?resize=280%2C400" width="280" height="400" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">Get Strong at Tesuji</h2>
<p><strong>Description:</strong> In the sixth volume of the Get Strong at Go Series, Bozulich has compiled a fantastic set of tesuji problems that focus on developing a player&#8217;s intuition through practicing lots of easier problems. Though there are a few intermediate/hard problems dispersed throughout the book, this is a great book for players of all levels (especially beginnger and intermediate levels).<br />
<span id="more-4014"></span><br />
[expand title=&#8221;Book Details&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
[table]
Title, Get Strong at Tesuji<br />
Series, Get Strong at Go Series<br />
Author, Richard Bozulich<br />
Publisher, <a href="http://www.kiseido.com/">Kiseido</a><br />
Published, &#8220;First Printing September 1996 | Second Printing June 2006&#8243;<br />
Language, English<br />
ISBN, 4-906574-56-4<br />
Length, 184 Pages<br />
Problems, 534 Problems<br />
[/table]
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Table of Content&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Preface</li>
<li>Some Important Terms and Concepts</li>
<li>Tesuji Problems</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Before I Read This Book&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
Besides the common tesuji that everyone learns when they first start out playing (i.e., snapback, crane&#8217;s nest, etc.), I would have to say that I did not feel like I knew that many tesuji. In addition, I always found it very difficult to identify tesuji in the middle of an actual game. So I was hoping that this book would give me a better foothold in identifying tesuji in common shapes and positions that might arise in my games.<br />
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Synopsis&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<strong>What did I enjoy about the book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Problems have a difficulty rating to inform the players how hard the problem is.</li>
<li>The problem set is overall very accommodating to beginner and intermediate players. In fact, a few of the &#8220;advanced&#8221; problems could be even be solved by a high SDK with some ease.</li>
<li>There is a nice repetition of techniques (that are dispersed throughout the book) to allow for excellent reinforcement of the technique.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What did I gain from reading this book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>A greater comfort level with tesuji as a whole.</li>
<li>Increased confidence in my ability to identify tesuji in positions that once were obscure to me.</li>
<li>Renewed faith in my ability to eventually go back and attempt <a title="Book Review: 501 Tesuji Problems" href="//book-review-501-tesuji-problems/">501 Tesuji Problems</a> once again.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What is the format of the book?</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>A set of problems followed by their solutions and explanation. Repeat. Repeat. Repeat.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>What aspects can be improved on?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>No complaints here!</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Is this book easy to read?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Yes. Explanations and solutions are short and clear cut. In addition, the diagrams are not complicated, so the solutions are easy to follow.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Bottom Line</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>Though I was skeptical of the book at first, this book is actually very accessible to beginner and intermediate players (though a bit more towards intermediate players) who want to practice tesuji.</li>
<li>Provides a lot of opportunities for practice and reinforcement of common tesuji techniques.</li>
<li>Continues the quality of content you come to expect from the &#8220;Get Strong at Series&#8221; and is well worth the money.</li>
</ol>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;My Review&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221; expanded=&#8221;true&#8221;]
As some of you are aware, when I tried to work my way through <a title="Book Review: 501 Tesuji Problems" href="//book-review-501-tesuji-problems/">Mastering the Basics: 501 Tesuji Problems</a>, I had an incredibly difficult time getting through it (for whatever reason I stil cannot identify). And since I always thought that the &#8220;Get Strong at Series&#8221; would be considered a more advanced level than the &#8220;Mastering the Basics Series,&#8221; I was a little worried about what I might encounter. Luckily for me though, I did not let my dread delay me any longer and I am so glad that I finally got opened it up!<br />
Get Strong at Tesuji continues the tradition of being a problem book that centers around giving readers numerous opportunities to practice their skills. The problems are not categorized in any particular manner, but a new aspect to the design (that I found very helpful) is the usage of stars in order to designate the problems difficulty. The problems ranged from 1 star (easy) to 4 stars (difficult). The book primarily consists of 1 star and 2 star problems, an occasional 3 star problem, and only a handful of 4 star problems towards the very end. And for those who might be wondering how difficult the 3 star problems are, I am approximately 4 kyu at this time and found them to be manageable. So based on that analysis, it should be pretty clear that the book is actually very accessible to beginner and intermediate players.<br />
Though there is no introductory section on the techniques that are used in the book, something that I want to remind readers out there is that the concept of tesuji is to find a move that works in your favor no matter how your opponent responds. Though some techniques can be neatly categorized and labelled, it would be impossible to collectively explain every technique that might ever arise in your game. So at the end of the day, the best way to build one&#8217;s ability to find and identify tesuji is to be exposed to more ideas and examples that already exist.<br />
Overall, I am very pleased with the quality of content and level of problems that this book provided. Although I wouldn&#8217;t necessarily give this book to someone who is 20 kyu, I would highly recommend this book to any player who has had some basic knowledge to tesuji and is looking for a book on tesuji that will not overwhelm them with overly difficult problems.<br />
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Recommended For&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ol>
<li>Players looking to improve their basic abilities in identifying and using tesuji.</li>
</ol>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Where Can I Buy It?&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>GoGameGuru &#8211; <a title="Get Strong at Tesuji GoGameGuru Purchase Link" href="http://shop.gogameguru.com/get-strong-at-tesuji/?acc=e4da3b7fbbce2345d7772b0674a318d5">$20.99</a> USD (shipping and handling not included)</li>
<li>Kiseido &#8211; <a title="Kiseido Purchase Form" href="http://www.kiseido.com/go_books.htm">$21.00</a> USD (shipping and handling not included)</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Other Books in This Series&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;lastExpandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li><a title="Book Review: Get Strong at the Opening" href="//book-review-get-strong-at-the-opening/">Get Strong at the Opening</a></li>
<li><a title="Book Review: Get Strong at Joseki 1" href="//book-review-get-strong-at-joseki-1/">Get Strong at Joseki 1</a></li>
<li><a title="Book Review: Get Strong at Joseki 2" href="//book-review-get-strong-joseki-2/">Get Strong at Joseki 2</a></li>
<li><a title="Book Review: Get Strong at Joseki 3" href="//book-review-get-strong-joseki-3/">Get Strong at Joseki 3</a></li>
<li>Get Strong at Invading</li>
<li>Get Strong at Tesuji</li>
<li>Get Strong at the Endgame</li>
<li>Get Strong at Life and Death</li>
<li>Get Strong at Handicap Go</li>
<li>Get Strong at Attacking</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
<p style="text-align: center;"><em><strong>Last Updated on September 28th, 2013</strong></em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/book-review-get-strong-tesuji/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">4014</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Book Review: Tesuji</title>
		<link>/book-review-tesuji/</link>
		<comments>/book-review-tesuji/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2013 15:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[clever moves]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[problems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tactics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tesuji]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tesujis]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=2997</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Tesuji Description: In this volume of the Elementary Go Series, Davies lays out the some basic tesuji that every player should learn along with practice problems and different contexts for teach tesuji. [expand title=&#8221;Book Details&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;] [table] Title, Tesuji (Volume 3) Series, Elementary Go Series Author, James Davies Publisher, Kiseido Published, 1st Edition April 1975 &#124; [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/06/egstesujicover.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3096" alt="egstesujicover" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/06/egstesujicover.jpg?resize=300%2C438" width="300" height="438" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">Tesuji</h2>
<p><strong>Description: </strong>In this volume of the Elementary Go Series, Davies lays out the some basic tesuji that every player should learn along with practice problems and different contexts for teach tesuji.<br />
<span id="more-2997"></span><br />
[expand title=&#8221;Book Details&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
[table]
Title, Tesuji (Volume 3)<br />
Series, Elementary Go Series<br />
Author, James Davies<br />
Publisher, Kiseido<br />
Published, 1st Edition April 1975 | Eighth Edition June 2010<br />
Language, English<br />
ISBN, 978-4-906574-12-2<br />
Length, 200 Pages<br />
[/table]
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Table of Content&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ol>
<li>Reading</li>
<li>Capture the Cutting Stones</li>
<li>Amputate the Cutting Stones</li>
<li>Ko</li>
<li>When Liberties Count</li>
<li>Linking Groups Together</li>
<li>Into Enemy Territory</li>
<li>Escape</li>
<li>Sacrifice to Gain Tempo</li>
<li>Tesuji for Attack</li>
<li>How to Connect</li>
<li>Making Shape</li>
<li>Ignore the Atari</li>
<li>Double-Threat Tesuji</li>
<li>Challenge Problems</li>
</ol>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Synopsis&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221; expanded=&#8221;true&#8221;]
<ol>
<li>Great introduction to tesujis since the chapters are short and the explanations are concise.</li>
<li>Problems are a bit advanced for players learning tesuji, but should be viewed as exposure material instead of a test of knowledge.</li>
<li>Reminds me of an abridged textbook where it covers a lot of material and organized in an intuitive format that helps to give context to the tesujis being presented.</li>
</ol>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Before I Read This Book&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<strong>My Abilities</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>This is my second time reading the book; but besides having a decent grasp of the three most basic tesujis: snapbacks, ladders, and nets, I would have to say that my ability to find tesuji is rather weak.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>My Perspective</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>When I first got this book, I was really hoping to get exposed to a lot of different tesujis along with some context as to how they were being used. For example, this tesuji is good for connecting stones.</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;My Review&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221; expanded=&#8221;true&#8221;]
<strong>What did I enjoy about the book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Tesujis are presented in contexts such as &#8220;amputate the cutting stone&#8221; that help to show how tesujis can be utilized for multiple purposes. For example, the squeeze tesuji is presented in both &#8220;amputate the cutting stone&#8221; and &#8220;making shape.&#8221;</li>
<li>The chapters are written in a concise manner with just enough diagrams to make it a short read while illustrating everything very clearly.</li>
<li>There are always practice problems after every tesuji they introduce.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What did I gain from reading this book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>A better grasp on tesujis as a whole.</li>
<li>New ideas regarding how tesujis can be utilized for multiple purposes.</li>
<li>Slightly improved reading ability.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What style of teaching does the book use?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Textbook Approach
<ul>
<li>Organized in a curriculum format that reflects the learning style one might normally find in school.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Primary Learning Mechanism:
<ul>
<li>Explanations with example diagrams</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Other Learning Mechanisms:
<ul>
<li>Practice problems</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What aspect can be improved on?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>I would have liked to see more introductory problems for each tesuji since there was no predicting how complicated the problems would be at the end of each chapter.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Is this book easy to read?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Yes. With its short and concise chapters and explanations, it is usually pretty easy to finish a section within a chapter in 5-10 minutes.</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Recommended For&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Players looking for a book to start learning about tesujis.</li>
<li>Players looking to reinforce their knowledge of tesujis.</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Where Can I Buy It?&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>GoGameGuru &#8211; <a title="Go Game Guru Purchase Link" href="http://shop.gogameguru.com/tesuji/?acc=e4da3b7fbbce2345d7772b0674a318d5">$17.99</a> USD (shipping &amp; handling not included)</li>
<li>Kiseido &#8211; <a title="Kiseido Purchase Link" href="http://kiseido.com/go_books.htm">$18.00</a> USD (shipping &amp; handling not included)</li>
<li>SmartGo Books &#8211; <a title="SmartGo Book Link" href="http://www.smartgo.com/books.htm">$9.99</a> USD (e-Book for iPad &amp; iPhone Only)</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Other Books in This Series&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;lastExpandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li><a title="Book Review: In the Beginning" href="//book-review-in-the-beginning/">Elementary Go Series, Volume 1 &#8211; In the Beginning</a></li>
<li><a title="Book Review: 38 Basic Josekis" href="//book-review-38-basic-josekis/">Elementary Go Series, Volume 2 &#8211; 38 Basic Josekis</a></li>
<li><a title="Book Review: Life and Death" href="//book-review-life-and-death/">Elementary Go Series, Volume 4 &#8211; Life and Death</a></li>
<li><a title="Book Review: Attack and Defense" href="//book-review-attack-and-defense/">Elementary Go Series, Volume 5 &#8211; Attack and Defense</a></li>
<li><a title="Book Review: The Endgame" href="//book-review-the-endgame/">Elementary Go Series, Volume 6 &#8211; The Endgame</a></li>
<li><a title="Book Review: Handicap Go" href="//book-review-handicap-go/">Elementary Go Series, Volume 7 &#8211; Handicap Go</a></li>
</ul>
[/expand]
<p style="text-align: center;"><em><strong>Last Updated on July 6th, 2013</strong></em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/book-review-tesuji/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2997</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Book Review: 501 Tesuji Problems</title>
		<link>/book-review-501-tesuji-problems/</link>
		<comments>/book-review-501-tesuji-problems/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2013 09:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mastering the basics series]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[not worth your time]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tesuji]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=2702</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Overall Rating: 6 / 10 Ponnuki Basic Information Title: Mastering the Basics, Volume 4 &#8211; Five Hundred and One TesujiProblems Author: Compiled and Written by Richard Bozulich Publisher: Kiseido Publication Date: October 2005 Page Length: 292 pages Number of Problems: 501 Synopsis My least favorite of the entire series so far. Lacked the explanations that makes the series so [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/05/mtb4cover.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2703" alt="mtb4cover" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/05/mtb4cover.jpg?resize=300%2C436" width="300" height="436" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></h2>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">Overall Rating: 6 / 10 Ponnuki</h2>
<h3>Basic Information</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Title:</strong> Mastering the Basics, Volume 4 &#8211; Five Hundred and One TesujiProblems</li>
<li><strong>Author: </strong>Compiled and Written by Richard Bozulich</li>
<li><strong>Publisher: </strong>Kiseido</li>
<li><strong>Publication Date: </strong>October 2005</li>
<li><strong>Page Length:</strong> 292 pages</li>
<li><strong>Number of Problems</strong>: 501</li>
</ul>
<h3>Synopsis</h3>
<ul>
<li>My least favorite of the entire series so far.</li>
<li>Lacked the explanations that makes the series so great.</li>
<li>Appropriate for 5 kyu and stronger.</li>
</ul>
<p><span id="more-2702"></span></p>
<h3>What I Expected</h3>
<ul>
<li>A section explaining various tesujis along with a few easy problems in each section to get your brain moving.</li>
<li>A problem section that consisted of an assortment of the tesujis from the first portion of the book.</li>
</ul>
<h3>What You Can Expect</h3>
<ul>
<li><span style="line-height: 13px;">Problems along with their usual solutions, but that is all.</span></li>
</ul>
<h3>My Thoughts as a 5 Kyu</h3>
<p>When I first reviewed this book, I will admit that my initial findings were rather negative since I was really disappointed in the fact that it did not follow the same structure that the other books in the series had. As a result, you will have to forgive me for knocking it down a few pegs.<br />
The book delivers on the promise that you will practice a lot of problems in hopes of training your brain to find tesujis without being told what to do. While I understand the merits in this approach, I still firmly believe that the book would be far more effective if it kept to the format of the Mastering the Basics series.<br />
So if you&#8217;re looking for a book that gives explanations and guidance on tesujis, this is definitely not the book for you. On the other hand, if you want a book of pure tesuji problems, then you&#8217;ve come to the right place.</p>
<h4>Table of Content</h4>
<ol>
<li>Preface</li>
<li>A Glossary of Tesujis Used in this Book</li>
<li>Some Important Terms and Concepts</li>
<li>501 Tesuji Problems</li>
</ol>
<h4>Recommended Vendors:</h4>
<ol>
<li>Kiseido &#8211; <a title="Kiseido Order Form" href="http://www.kiseido.com/go_books.htm">$21.00</a> (S&amp;H not included)</li>
<li>SmartGo Books (eBook) &#8211; <a href="http://www.smartgo.com/booksbycategory.htm">$8.99</a> (Apple users only)</li>
</ol>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Last updated June 28th, 2013</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/book-review-501-tesuji-problems/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>60</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2702</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Book Review: Lessons in the Fundamentals of Go</title>
		<link>/book-review-lessons-in-the-fundamentals-of-go/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2013 14:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[basics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fundamentals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[getting stronger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kageyama]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lessons]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shape]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tesuji]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=1393</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Overall Rating: 5 / 5 Ponnuki Basic Information Title: Lessons in the Fundamentals of Go Author: Toshiro Kageyama 7-dan Translator: James Davies Publisher: Kiseido Publication Date: May 1978 Page Length: 272 pages Synopsis A hybrid of theoretical/conceptual explanations along with problems to illustrate the ideas. While may seem advance, Kageyama&#8217;s personality really shines through and makes [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/03/lessonsinthefundamentalsofgocover.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2181" alt="lessonsinthefundamentalsofgocover" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/03/lessonsinthefundamentalsofgocover.jpg?resize=248%2C400" width="248" height="400" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></h2>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">Overall Rating: 5 / 5 Ponnuki</h2>
<h3>Basic Information</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Title:</strong> Lessons in the Fundamentals of Go</li>
<li><strong>Author: </strong>Toshiro Kageyama 7-dan</li>
<li><strong>Translator:</strong> James Davies</li>
<li><strong>Publisher: </strong>Kiseido</li>
<li><strong>Publication Date: </strong>May 1978</li>
<li><strong>Page Length:</strong> 272 pages</li>
</ul>
<h3>Synopsis</h3>
<ul>
<li>A hybrid of theoretical/conceptual explanations along with problems to illustrate the ideas.</li>
<li>While may seem advance, Kageyama&#8217;s personality really shines through and makes this such an interesting read (regardless of your level).</li>
<li>Appropriate for 20 kyu and stronger.</li>
<li>Recommended for all types of players.</li>
</ul>
<p><span id="more-1393"></span></p>
<h3>Detailed Review</h3>
<h4>Readability &#8211; 10 / 10</h4>
<p>When it comes to readability, I&#8217;m not sure there&#8217;s a single go book out there that can outclass Kageyama&#8217;s ability to show his humorous and delightful personality through his writing. There is almost never a dull moment in this book. Often times, he will seem to be going off on a tangent (like baseball), but he will always find a way to bring it back full circle to emphasize one of his points. His pragmatic and straight forward advice is something that every go player can make use of, regardless of how strong you desire to be. In fact, even if we set aside the actual treasure trove of go advice that is in this book, I would argue that the entertainment value of his writing makes the book worth every penny.</p>
<h4>Content Quality &#8211; 10 / 10</h4>
<p>Although this is not your classic tsumego book, it does have a similar style to the <a href="http://senseis.xmp.net/?ElementaryGoSeries">Elementary Go Series</a> where there are a few problems at the end of most chapters. In addition, I will be the first to admit that some of these problems are rather difficult and can be discouraging if you are under the impression you need to be able to solve them the first time you see them. In fact, the value of this book lies in its ability to expose you to so many different concepts and ideas. Considering the size of the book and the how short each of the chapters are, the amount of content he covers is nothing short of incredible.</p>
<h4>Final Thoughts</h4>
<p>Although this is my third time reading the book, and it still has not lost a bit of its charm. I continue to learn something new every time I read it, and never fail to crack a smile when Kageyama goes on one of his rants about how amateur players always try to find shortcuts to reading ladders. Nonetheless, this is truly a classic that I believe will never be outdated. So do yourself a favor, and if you are going to only have a small collection of go books, this is definitely one you will want to have.</p>
<h4>Table of Contents</h4>
<ol>
<li>Chapter 1: Ladders and Nets</li>
<li>Chapter 2: Cutting and Connecting</li>
<li>Chapter 3: The Stones Go Walking</li>
<li>Chapter 4: The Struggle to Get Ahead</li>
<li>Chapter 5: Territory and Spheres of Influence</li>
<li>Interlude: Lecturing on NHK-TV</li>
<li>Chapter 6: Life and Death</li>
<li>Chapter 7: How to Study Joseki</li>
<li>Chapter 8: Good Shape and Bad</li>
<li>Chapter 9: Proper and Improper Moves</li>
<li>Chapter 10: Tesuji: The Snap-Back; Shortage of Liberties; The Spiral Latter; The Placement; The Attachment; Under the Stones</li>
<li>Chapter 11: Endgame Pointers</li>
<li>Appendix: Game Commentary: Beating the Meijin</li>
</ol>
<h4>Recommended Vendors:</h4>
<ol>
<li>Amazon &#8211; <a title="Amazon Purchase Link" href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/4906574289/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=4906574289&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=be09a-20">$18.00</a> (S&amp;H not included)</li>
<li>GoGameGuru- <a title="GoGameGuru Purchase Link" href="http://shop.gogameguru.com/lessons-in-the-fundamentals-of-go/?acc=e4da3b7fbbce2345d7772b0674a318d5">$17.99</a> (S&amp;H not included)</li>
<li>Kiseido &#8211; <a title="Kiseido Order Form" href="http://www.kiseido.com/go_books.htm">$18.00</a> (S&amp;H not included)</li>
</ol>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Last updated March 8th, 2013 &#8211; 6 kyu</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1393</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Stronger-Player-Suji</title>
		<link>/stronger-player-suji/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2013 14:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Weekly Go Wednesday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[don't be afraid]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[growing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stronger players]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tesuji]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=1691</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Weekly Go Wednesday, Issue #15 I recently had the pleasure of discussing a game with frozensoul and DeepSnow, when DeepSnow said something that made me laugh: &#8220;I count on kyu players to outread themselves.&#8221; &#8211; DeepSnow While it was funny at the moment, it didn&#8217;t take long before the truth of the statement dawned on [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 style="text-align: center;"><em>Weekly Go Wednesday, Issue #15</em></h2>
<figure id="attachment_1770" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/01/wgw15.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1770" alt="Credit to ptblank" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/01/wgw15.jpg?resize=300%2C240" width="300" height="240" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Credit to <a href="http://ptblank.deviantart.com/art/Magic-Hat-191955649">ptblank</a></figcaption></figure>
<p style="text-align: left;">I recently had the pleasure of discussing a game with frozensoul and DeepSnow, when DeepSnow said something that made me laugh:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;I count on kyu players to outread themselves.&#8221; &#8211; DeepSnow</p></blockquote>
<p>While it was funny at the moment, it didn&#8217;t take long before the truth of the statement dawned on me.<br />
For those wondering what he is talking about, DeepSnow is referring to the tendency of kyu players to automatically play conservative moves in anticipation of some crazy tesuji (even though it doesn&#8217;t exist).<br />
There are two primary reasons for why players do this:<br />
<span id="more-1691"></span><br />
<strong>#1. They have had a traumatic experience where something they thought worked gets demolished by a stronger player.</strong><br />
You have to realize that <em><strong>every</strong></em> player knows what this feels like. It sucks when it happens to you, but I am sure that there has been more than one occasion where you played a move that was not supposed to work but getting away with it with a big smile on your face. And to be honest, it&#8217;s not so much that our original move was flawed; but our inability to properly punish a bad play ends up getting us in trouble. The simplest example would be someone accidentally dying in a life and death situation when they were supposed to live. Therefore, the way to combat that is not to lose any edge on the moves that you play, but to put more thought into the possible follow-up moves so that there is nothing to regret at the end of the game.<br />
<strong>#2. The fact that their opponent has a higher rank makes them assume that their opponent&#8217;s reading is better.</strong><br />
Here&#8217;s the thing though, just because your opponent has a higher rank than you doesn&#8217;t mean that their reading is that much more miraculous than yours. In fact, stronger players often make overplays that can lead to their utter demise if the correct response is given. On top of that, they often play these kinds of moves in anticipation of you playing a sub-optimal move in response so that they can gain momentum. Unfortunately, we often let them get away with these overplays for fear of getting into a fight with them and losing big.<br />
So when you are playing against stronger players, keep the following in mind:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Play moves that you understand.</strong> In other words, you should be have an idea as to how you see the follow-ups playing out. You should never feel pressured to play &#8220;higher level moves&#8221; since you are playing a stronger player. Sticking with what you understand will allow you to learn from your mistakes and grow instead of being like, &#8220;Well that was a move that just looked right.&#8221;</li>
<li><strong>Only get into fights that you believe you can win.</strong> Do not cut and fight because you don&#8217;t know what else to do. Getting cut up into multiple weak groups is precisely what your opponent wants. It&#8217;s not that you shouldn&#8217;t fight, but you should definitely pick your battles carefully.</li>
<li><strong>Most importantly of all, your opponent is human too.</strong> Regardless of how strong your opponent is, they are not perfect and are capable of making mistakes as well. In fact, keeping a cool head and a calm approach could be the edge you need to take them by surprise.</li>
</ol>
<p>Hope that this advice helps to keep your head on a little straighter the next time you play a stronger opponent. And if there&#8217;s anything that you&#8217;ve found that helps you when playing against stronger players, please be sure to share!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1691</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
