<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>return &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/return/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>Taking It One Day at a Time</title>
		<link>/taking-one-day-time/</link>
		<comments>/taking-one-day-time/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2014 19:42:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[one step at a time]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[return]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[simple yet effective]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5564</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[With the U.S. Go Congress quickly approaching, it only seemed appropriate that it be high time that I returned back to go. And to be honest, it couldn’t have happened a moment sooner. Over the past couple of weeks, I’ve taken some serious time to truly re-evaluate how my time and energy have been spent [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>With the U.S. Go Congress quickly approaching, it only seemed appropriate that it be high time that I returned back to go. And to be honest, it couldn’t have happened a moment sooner.<br />
Over the past couple of weeks, I’ve taken some serious time to truly re-evaluate how my time and energy have been spent and whether my efforts were helping me move towards a larger goal in life. As a result, I cut back on almost everything and spent a lot of time thinking and testing out new approaches to my time, my energy, and my life in general.<br />
For a while, I had a hard time figuring out how I was going to work go back into my life. After all, it was a highly time consuming activity that I had begun to feel frustrated with since I felt like my game had gone to crap. Nevertheless, I knew that the problem wasn’t the game; but that the problem was me.<br />
I won’t go into great detail about my thought processes and the various choices I’ve made along the way since it would end up making my post sound like some sort of productivity blog. However, the important thing is that I have found a way to bring go back into my life. It will be a much simpler approach than before and not nearly so haphazard, which I hope will be effective in the long run.<br />
As for the blog, I will take a similar approach to my study of the game and approach it with a simple yet effective method instead of trying to do ten different things at once. So if you’ll bear with me for a bit, I’ll be testing out different tactics for consistent blogging while slowly reviving popular posts like Monday Go Meditation once I have a handle on things again.<br />
With that said, I’m happy to be back and look forward to what the future holds!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/taking-one-day-time/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>14</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">5564</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Back from Hong Kong</title>
		<link>/back-hong-kong/</link>
		<comments>/back-hong-kong/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2014 01:04:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hong kong]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[return]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=4829</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hey everyone. I just got back from Hong Kong yesterday. So while I&#8217;d love to write all about my Hong Kong trip, I&#8217;ll need to finish catching up before doing so. But overall, the trip went well and I got to spend a bit of time really fine tuning my approach to go along with [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hey everyone. I just got back from Hong Kong yesterday. So while I&#8217;d love to write all about my Hong Kong trip, I&#8217;ll need to finish catching up before doing so. But overall, the trip went well and I got to spend a bit of time really fine tuning my approach to go along with having the pleasure of visiting the Hong Kong Go Association. More on that later though. Hope you all are doing well!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/back-hong-kong/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">4829</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Slow and Steady Return</title>
		<link>/a-slow-and-steady-return/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2013 21:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[im back]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new approach]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[return]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=2683</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[While I already miss the awesome weather, incredible scenery (aka awesome beaches with super clear water), and not to mention amazing food, I am glad to be back! When I first left for my vacation, I thought that I would be itching to get back into go. To my surprise, it is still taking me [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>While I already miss the awesome weather, incredible scenery (aka awesome beaches with super clear water), and not to mention amazing food, I am glad to be back!<br />
When I first left for my vacation, I thought that I would be itching to get back into go. To my surprise, it is still taking me awhile to really get back into my routine. I&#8217;m still feeling a little apprehensive; but on the upside, I am starting to feel excited at the prospect of playing again! So, good news on that end!<br />
In the past, I used to come off of these breaks with an intent on studying like there was no tomorrow. This time though, I intend on taking it one step at a time and really figuring out where my groove is with studying and playing. My goal is to become the strongest player I can possibly be. If these last couple years have taught me anything, it  is that consistency is the best route to doing so. So I&#8217;m hoping that I can avoid burnout with this slower, but hopefully more solid approach.<br />
I apologize for not having a Monday Go Meditation ready for this week, but it seems that it may be a little bit before I get that back up and running since I&#8217;m out of games that have good material for a review. Just more motivation for me to finally start playing ranked games on KGS again. =)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2683</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>I am back.</title>
		<link>/i-am-back/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2012 20:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[back from sabbatical]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[return]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=42</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[That&#8217;s right. Lo and behold. I have emerged from my hermit hole away from the go world and have now returned! Looking forward to posting here again. Be sure to leave a comment if you&#8217;re still following or still play go!]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>That&#8217;s right. Lo and behold. I have emerged from my hermit hole away from the go world and have now returned! Looking forward to posting here again. Be sure to leave a comment if you&#8217;re still following or still play go!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">42</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
