<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>one step at a time &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/one-step-at-a-time/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>Taking It One Day at a Time</title>
		<link>/taking-one-day-time/</link>
		<comments>/taking-one-day-time/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2014 19:42:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[one step at a time]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[return]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[simple yet effective]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5564</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[With the U.S. Go Congress quickly approaching, it only seemed appropriate that it be high time that I returned back to go. And to be honest, it couldn’t have happened a moment sooner. Over the past couple of weeks, I’ve taken some serious time to truly re-evaluate how my time and energy have been spent [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>With the U.S. Go Congress quickly approaching, it only seemed appropriate that it be high time that I returned back to go. And to be honest, it couldn’t have happened a moment sooner.<br />
Over the past couple of weeks, I’ve taken some serious time to truly re-evaluate how my time and energy have been spent and whether my efforts were helping me move towards a larger goal in life. As a result, I cut back on almost everything and spent a lot of time thinking and testing out new approaches to my time, my energy, and my life in general.<br />
For a while, I had a hard time figuring out how I was going to work go back into my life. After all, it was a highly time consuming activity that I had begun to feel frustrated with since I felt like my game had gone to crap. Nevertheless, I knew that the problem wasn’t the game; but that the problem was me.<br />
I won’t go into great detail about my thought processes and the various choices I’ve made along the way since it would end up making my post sound like some sort of productivity blog. However, the important thing is that I have found a way to bring go back into my life. It will be a much simpler approach than before and not nearly so haphazard, which I hope will be effective in the long run.<br />
As for the blog, I will take a similar approach to my study of the game and approach it with a simple yet effective method instead of trying to do ten different things at once. So if you’ll bear with me for a bit, I’ll be testing out different tactics for consistent blogging while slowly reviving popular posts like Monday Go Meditation once I have a handle on things again.<br />
With that said, I’m happy to be back and look forward to what the future holds!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/taking-one-day-time/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>14</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">5564</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Trying to Put the Pieces Back Together</title>
		<link>/trying-put-pieces-back-together/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2014 15:55:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kifu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dojang]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[journey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[one step at a time]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[progress]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yunguseng]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5545</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I played the second round of my Yunguseng match tonight. To be honest, it was a game of mixed feelings. Though I hate to admit it, I&#8217;m not quite out of my slump yet. I could definitely feel it as I started getting antsy when the game began. I started being negative and worried that [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I played the second round of my Yunguseng match tonight. To be honest, it was a game of mixed feelings. Though I hate to admit it, I&#8217;m not quite out of my slump yet. I could definitely feel it as I started getting antsy when the game began. I started being negative and worried that I would lose again. Yet on the other hand, there were moments where I managed to give my game some life as I surged forth with a desire to attack and try to harass my opponent&#8217;s group with as much vigor as I could muster up.<br />

<div id='glift_display1' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display1","sgf":"http:\/\/bengozen.com\/\/wp-content\/uploads\/2014\/07\/YSD-S9-Round12.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='//wp-content/uploads/2014/07/YSD-S9-Round12.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">[download label=&#8221;Download Kifu&#8221;]//wp-content/uploads/2014/07/YSD-S9-Round12.sgf[/download]
<p>It was a bit weird being in this bi-polar/gray area of feeling like my go was rather aimless, having it spring back to life, making bad moves where I was completely off with my reading, and then having lively energy again. Then again I guess this is all part of trying to put the pieces together again. They don&#8217;t quite fit together at the moment, but I&#8217;m optimistic that they will become whole once again.<br />
And though I would normally be concerned with how fast it would take or when it would happen, I’ve realized that doing so will not do me any good. I’ll just keep working on my weaknesses and play to the best of my ability. Everything will fall into place in due time.<br />
PS. There won&#8217;t be any detailed commentary for this game, but I just wanted to mention that there are quite a number of mistakes and overplays in this game. So in case anyone wants to point out things like my lower left corner was supposed to die and so forth, no worries, got it all in the review.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">5545</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Friday Go Forward: Week 16</title>
		<link>/friday-go-forward-week-16/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2013 09:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Progress Reports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[boxing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[handicap go]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[one step at a time]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[patience]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=2720</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Overview In case it wasn&#8217;t apparent to everyone, this week has been entirely centered around boxing analogies along with handicap go. There hasn&#8217;t been as many ranked games as I might have liked, but the amount of go I&#8217;ve been playing/studying seems to be harmonizing much better with the rest of my life. Still fine [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>Overview</h2>
<p>In case it wasn&#8217;t apparent to everyone, this week has been entirely centered around boxing analogies along with handicap go. There hasn&#8217;t been as many ranked games as I might have liked, but the amount of go I&#8217;ve been playing/studying seems to be harmonizing much better with the rest of my life. Still fine tuning a number of things, but just glad to not feel overwhelemed by go anymore.</p>
<h2>Games</h2>
<ul>
<li><span style="line-height: 13px;">KGS &#8211; 2 games (2 wins : 0 losses)</span></li>
<li>DGS &#8211; 2 ongoing games</li>
<li>Nova &#8211; 3 ongoing games</li>
</ul>
<h2>Training</h2>
<ul>
<li><span style="line-height: 13px;">20 tsumego problems each day.</span></li>
<li>Worked <em>Mastering the Basics: The Basics of Go Strategy</em>.</li>
<li>Started reading <em>Kage&#8217;s Secret Chronicles of Handicap Go.</em></li>
</ul>
<h2>Lessons Learned</h2>
<ol>
<li>When attacking, strike at the vital points while maintaining strength and not overextending yourself.</li>
<li>It&#8217;s okay to let things live or give your opponents points, as long as you are getting more in return.</li>
<li>Don&#8217;t over think your moves in turn based go. Rather than spend hours staring at the screen trying to make the perfect move, you will learn and gain more by playing more games and learning from your mistakes.</li>
</ol>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2720</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
