<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>b+resign &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/bresign/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>Monday Go Meditation: Game 62</title>
		<link>/monday-go-meditation-game-62/</link>
		<comments>/monday-go-meditation-game-62/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2014 11:15:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Kifu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Monday Go Meditation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[3k opponent]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[b+resign]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[black]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[commentary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kifu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[review]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5471</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Introduction About a week ago, there was a bit of discussion about the importance of endgame. Now while I would never even begin to propose that endgame is not important or can&#8217;t make a huge difference, I was saying how I didn&#8217;t think studying it would serve kyu players as much as say dan players. Ironically, [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 style="text-align: center;">Introduction</h2>
<p>About a week ago, there was a bit of discussion about the importance of endgame. Now while I would never even begin to propose that endgame is not important or can&#8217;t make a huge difference, I was saying how I didn&#8217;t think studying it would serve kyu players as much as say dan players.<br />
Ironically, the game featured this week was played shortly after the discussion and happened to feature endgame as the shining star of the game. In addition, this game is also a good example of competing moyos and how critical points in shape and boundaries can make a huge difference in the resulting outcome. Hope you enjoy this review!<br />

<div id='glift_display1' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display1","sgf":"http:\/\/bengozen.com\/\/wp-content\/uploads\/2014\/06\/2014.06.30-MGM-62.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='//wp-content/uploads/2014/06/2014.06.30-MGM-62.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">[download label=&#8221;Download Kifu&#8221;]//wp-content/uploads/2014/06/2014.06.30-MGM-62.sgf[/download]
<h2 style="text-align: center;"><strong>One Point Lesson</strong></h2>
<p style="text-align: center;">When you&#8217;re really behind, your only hope is to complicate the game and push your opponent&#8217;s abilities to the absolute limit.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span id="more-5471"></span></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">Game Summary</h2>
[table colwidth=&#8221;50|140|375|375&#8243; colalign=&#8221;center|center|center|center&#8221;]
no,Category,Good,Bad<br />
1,Opening,<strong>Move 11</strong> &#8211; Decisively ignoring White&#8217;s extension to play on the right inside seemed like the correct move.,<strong>Move 35</strong> &#8211; This was a bad move that allowed White to get a nice result on the upper right.<br />
2,Attack and Defense,<strong>Move 111</strong> &#8211; Ignoring White to defend my group was an important step to giving me a chance to make a comeback.,<strong>Move 80</strong> &#8211; Letting White attack my group like this was very painful. It could have been awful if White had continued his attack.<br />
3,Shape,<strong>Move 147</strong> &#8211; Being able to find this point in the midst of near death was another proud moment for me.,<strong>Move 48</strong> &#8211; Letting White get this shape point was unbelievably painful.<br />
4,Strategy,<strong>Move 115</strong> &#8211; Ignoring White&#8217;s approach on my corner to try and reverse the game was importantly to try and reverse the game.,<strong>Move 47</strong> &#8211; Trying to take the corner instead of expanding my moyo was a pretty big mistake.<br />
5,Overall Reading,<strong>Move 151</strong> &#8211; Being able to read out this attachment almost instantly was a proud moment for me.,<strong>Move 63</strong> &#8211; This was so painfully obvious to my opponent. Should have saved it for later.<br />
6,Endgame,<strong>Move 161</strong> &#8211; Taking my sente to connect here is probably what eventually pushed my opponent to resign later.,<strong>Move 86</strong> &#8211; Seeing White fly into my area like that was so painful. It nearly ended the game.<br />
[/table]
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/monday-go-meditation-game-62/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>24</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">5471</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Monday Go Meditation: Game 61</title>
		<link>/monday-go-meditation-game-61/</link>
		<comments>/monday-go-meditation-game-61/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2014 11:15:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Kifu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Monday Go Meditation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[3k opponent]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[b+resign]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[commentary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kifu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reboot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[update]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[white]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5470</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Introduction This week marks the reboot of the Monday Go Meditation (MGM) series! In the spirit of continuous improvement, I felt it was time to give this series an upgrade in order to continue striving for the perfect weekly column for my game reviews. Here are some enhancements that I have made: All MGM&#8217;s will now [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 style="text-align: center;"><strong>Introduction</strong></h2>
<p>This week marks the reboot of the Monday Go Meditation (MGM) series! In the spirit of continuous improvement, I felt it was time to give this series an upgrade in order to continue striving for the perfect weekly column for my game reviews. Here are some enhancements that I have made:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>All MGM&#8217;s will now include the game summary table. </strong>After doing the <a title="Thursday Go Tygem: Game 07" href="//thursday-go-tygem-game-07/">Thursday Go Tygem</a> series for a bit, it seemed that the table was a popular aspect of it since it allowed me to provide a broad overview of the game in the event you don&#8217;t have time to go through the entire game. As a result, I felt it would be a great addition to MGM.</li>
<li>A<strong>ll games featured here will be 2 weeks old at the most.</strong> One thing I noticed is that the games being posted were starting to be a few weeks if not a month old, which is not good since it does not reflect my current progress as a player. Though this makes it a little harder for me since I can&#8217;t prepare as many game reviews in advance, I am confident this change will make this weekly column much more viable.</li>
<li><strong>The commentary will also be taking on a more &#8220;stream of consciousness&#8221; type narrative</strong> in order to provide more context in terms of how I was feeling throughout the game and the emotions and thoughts I wrestled with. As a result, the game reviews will not be heavily focused on explaining things in depth or showing numerous variations since that is more of a teaching-oriented type review (which I do plan on featuring here in the future, but don&#8217;t feel it&#8217;s appropriate for MGM).</li>
</ol>
<p>So in light of all that, this week&#8217;s game features an even game against a 3k that I played last week before going on my losing streak. Haha. It&#8217;s a great game that illustrates how emotions can really cloud your judgment when it comes to the actual board position and how you&#8217;re really doing.<br />
As always, it would be greatly appreciated if you could let me know what you think about these new changes. Hope you enjoy the review!<br />

<div id='glift_display2' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display2","sgf":"http:\/\/bengozen.com\/\/wp-content\/uploads\/2014\/06\/2014.06.23-MGM-61.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='//wp-content/uploads/2014/06/2014.06.23-MGM-61.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">[download label=&#8221;Download Kifu&#8221;]//wp-content/uploads/2014/06/2014.06.23-MGM-61.sgf[/download]
<h2 style="text-align: center;"><strong>One Point Lesson</strong></h2>
<p style="text-align: center;">Using emotions to judge whether you are ahead or behind is typically a recipe for poor decision making.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span id="more-5470"></span></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;"><strong>Game Summary</strong></h2>
[table colwidth=&#8221;50|140|375|375&#8243; colalign=&#8221;center|center|center|center&#8221;]
no,Category,Good,Bad<br />
1,Opening, <strong>Move 24:</strong> This move really gave me a nice advantage in the opening. See game commentary for a more in-depth explanations., <strong>Move 19:</strong> I’m not sure that I handled Black’s response here correctly. Perhaps the tenuki was a mistake.<br />
2,Attack and Defense, <strong>Move 50:</strong> This diagonal jump was a new move I tried that seemed to do a great job keeping pressure on Black., <strong>Move 58:</strong> This move was too defensive and failed to keep pressure on Black.<br />
3,Shape, Nothing worth mentioning., <strong>Move 64:</strong> Not connecting and letting Black push through to connect his groups together was a travesty.~~<strong>Move 52:</strong> The hane was bad and left too many cutting points for me to worry about later.<br />
4,Strategy, <strong>Move 44:</strong> Leaving the cutting point to play continue my expansion of the top seemed to work out well overall., <strong>Move 86-88:</strong> The push and cut was a risky play since Black had a number of forcing moves to counter the strategy.<br />
5,Overall Reading, Nothing to brag about since most sequences I read out usually had one fatal flaw that was luckily overlooked by my opponent., <strong>Move 76-85:</strong> This sequence was shameful since it was a result of wishful thinking and only made things worse.<br />
6,Endgame, <strong>Move 120:</strong> Ignoring Black’s move to start my own endgame sequence was a proud moment for me.,<strong> Move 104:</strong> This jump may not be as big as I thought. Perhaps blocking at M2 would have been better.<br />
[/table]
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/monday-go-meditation-game-61/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>10</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">5470</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Thursday Go Tygem: Game 06</title>
		<link>/thursday-go-tygem-game-06/</link>
		<comments>/thursday-go-tygem-game-06/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2014 11:15:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Kifu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thursday Go Tygem]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[b+resign]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[black]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[commentary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[korean]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[opponent 1d]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tygem]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5366</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Introduction This opponent was a unique one since he thought longer than I did and took his time. He actually ended up in byoyomi early on in the game and used most of his byoyomi time which is really weird for Tygem since most players I&#8217;ve encountered play pretty quickly and I&#8217;m the one usually [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 style="text-align: center;">Introduction</h2>
<p>This opponent was a unique one since he thought longer than I did and took his time. He actually ended up in byoyomi early on in the game and used most of his byoyomi time which is really weird for Tygem since most players I&#8217;ve encountered play pretty quickly and I&#8217;m the one usually running out of time. Overall though, I felt that I was in control for most of the game. Hopefully you&#8217;ll agree! And if I&#8217;m totally wrong, please let me know!<br />

<div id='glift_display3' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display3","sgf":"http:\/\/bengozen.com\/\/wp-content\/uploads\/2014\/06\/2014.06.12-TGT-06.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='//wp-content/uploads/2014/06/2014.06.12-TGT-06.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">[download label=&#8221;Download Kifu&#8221;]//wp-content/uploads/2014/06/2014.06.12-TGT-06.sgf[/download]
<h3 style="text-align: center;">Game Summary</h3>
[table colwidth=&#8221;50|140|375|375&#8243; colalign=&#8221;center|center|center|center&#8221;]
no,Category,Good,Bad<br />
1,Opening,<strong>Move 9-11</strong>: Ignoring White in the upper left was good in that I did not unnecessarily strengthen my opponent by trying to struggle.,&#8221;Other than the inconsistency of Move 21, I don’t see any egregious errors in regards to the opening.&#8221;<br />
2,Middle Game,<strong>Move 39-63</strong>: It felt like I did a good job attacking White while gaining nice 4th line territory on the right.,Can’t see any major mistakes at the moment.<br />
3,Fighting,Overall the fighting seemed to be in my favor most of the game. Nothing terribly complicated.,Didn’t see any real weaknesses in my fighting this game.<br />
4,Endgame,<strong>Move 219</strong>: Ignoring White’s atari at M1 to make an extra point showed I was not making automatic moves and trying to look for bigger plays.,<strong>Move 164</strong>: Letting what get the diagonal here first was rough.<br />
5,Overall Reading,<strong>Move 121</strong>: I was proud to be able to read out this attachment and know it could not be cut without some loss to White.,<strong>Move 70</strong>: I could sense there was double cut aji here but failed to read it out properly.<br />
6,Strategy,<strong>Move 81</strong>: Sacrificing the F3 group in exchange for breaking up the left side seemed to show good judgment.,&#8221;<strong>Move 21</strong>: Though successful, the 3-3 invasion seems to be contrary to my initial plan at making a moyo. So negative points for inconsistency.&#8221;<br />
[/table]
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/thursday-go-tygem-game-06/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">5366</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
