<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>crushed by sdks &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/crushed-by-sdks/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>Happy Belated Halloween &#038; SDK&#039;s</title>
		<link>/happy-belated-halloween-sdks/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2010 14:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crushed by sdks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[halloween]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=52</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[So I know&#8230; where have I been over this past weekend? A myriad of events and things to do. A belated Happy Halloween to everyone on the blogosphere. Midterms are past now, and I managed to pull off an A- in the Data Analysis class and a 101% in the Applied Social class. Sweet. Moving [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>So I know&#8230; where have I been over this past weekend? A myriad of events and things to do. A belated Happy Halloween to everyone on the blogosphere. Midterms are past now, and I managed to pull off an A- in the Data Analysis class and a 101% in the Applied Social class. Sweet. Moving on to my Go progress, there is five more days before month three is up. As to how I&#8217;m doing, I just got off my winning streak and was promptly crushed by 10 kyus.<br />
In the first game, I let myself lose a capturing race&#8230; yeah I know&#8230; and then I regained composure and pressed my opponent flat but failed to kill the group in the middle. Not sure I really could have, but I tried anyhow and then loss a corner because I thought it would be intelligent to play out a ko.<br />
Second game, my corner was promptly taken over. Was going to resign since I wasn&#8217;t sure I could continue properly, but pushed through and actually saved the group&#8230; just to have it cut because I wasn&#8217;t paying attention to a shortage of liberties and let my opponent get to moves in. Resigned after that.<br />
So to all my Go players who are stuck in the DDKs, I think I may have figured out why I keep getting destroyed by any opponent 10k or better. They simply do the fundamentals a lot better than we do. What do I mean by that? They cut, connect, and think about most of their moves which simply allows better play.<br />
I really don&#8217;t think that I&#8217;m not at the SDK strength, it&#8217;s just that I&#8217;m failing at the fundamentals and letting my stronger opponents take advantage of my weaknesses. And since they know how to properly punish the mistakes most of the time, so it&#8217;s just miserable. If I leave just one cutting point open, they&#8217;ll rush in. Bleh&#8230; Once I surpass the DDK barrier, I&#8217;ll be sure to let you know how you can also blow past the DDK barrier.<br />
Do I think I&#8217;ll break the SDK barrier on KGS in 5 days? Absolutely not. I don&#8217;t have the time to play enough games to do so. Will I evolve my playing ability in these next five days? You can bet the farm on that sonny boy. =D</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">52</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
