<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>fear &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/fear/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>One-Space Low Pincer-Phobia</title>
		<link>/one-space-low-pincer-phobia/</link>
		<comments>/one-space-low-pincer-phobia/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2014 19:09:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[21st century dictionary of basic joseki]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fear]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[joseki]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[obstacles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[one space low pincer]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5941</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[As I’ve been starting to unravel the tightly wound knot that has been at the core of my fear to play games the way I used to, one of the things I noticed is that there is one joseki in particular that has played a major role in my discomfort at playing full games. Yup. [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As I’ve been starting to unravel the tightly wound knot that has been at the core of my fear to play games the way I used to, one of the things I noticed is that there is one joseki in particular that has played a major role in my discomfort at playing full games.<br />
<a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/12/one-space-low-pincer.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5942" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/12/one-space-low-pincer.png?resize=241%2C121" alt="one-space-low-pincer" width="241" height="121" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><br />
Yup. The one-space low pincer to the high-one space approach to the 3-4. Words cannot express how much I hated seeing that move played against me due to one simple fact: I have no idea how to properly play against it.<br />
Now of course, everyone will say there are plenty of resources online for me to look it up and study it. The issue however, is that I don’t find online resources terribly helpful in learning joseki and I haven’t quite figured out the best way that I learn joseki. Generally speaking, there are two primary approaches to it: (1) get a broad overview and keep playing, making mistakes and learning as you go, and (2) “memorize” all the different variations so you know how to get an even position (locally) about of the different variations.<br />
While I’m more of a fan of approach #1, I have to say that I’m still in pursuit of the hybrid of the two approaches. Of course, for anyone who has read up on getting stronger, the general advice is “learn joseki and then forget it immediately.” And though the wisdom in that statement is evident to me, I find that I am more comfortable and confident if I start with some sort of foundation before running off and exploring on my own.<br />
Since I’m not a huge fan of the online resources for learning joseki (at least the ones I’m aware of), I was fortunate enough to obtain a copy of the <em>21st Century Dictionary of Basic Joseki, Vol. 1 &amp; 2</em> recently (courtesy of Mr. Richard Bozulich) and plan to use it to finally resolve my fear of the one-space low pincer.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/one-space-low-pincer-phobia/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>26</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">5941</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fear</title>
		<link>/fear/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2010 16:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kifu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fear]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[getting stronger]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=56</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I recently wrote a post concerning being able to overcome the blade of your opponent.  To not fear it, but to step forth and dive into the abyss. As a manga reader, I&#8217;ve recently read the Fairy Tale chapter.  There is a scene where the protagonist (Natsu) faces an unsurmountable strength.  When confronted, Natsu normally [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I recently wrote a post concerning being able to overcome the blade of your opponent.  To not fear it, but to step forth and dive into the abyss.<br />
As a manga reader, I&#8217;ve recently read the Fairy Tale chapter.  There is a scene where the protagonist (Natsu) faces an unsurmountable strength.  When confronted, Natsu normally will not stop until he wins.  For the first time however, he admits defeat.  And just when he does, his opponent then says:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Fear is not &#8216;evil.&#8217; It is to know your own weakness.  If you know your weakness, people can become strong.&#8221; &#8211; Gildartz</p></blockquote>
<p>As much as I try to avoid it, failing to save a vital group that costs you the game is one that still gets me in a bad mood. See the following kifu to see. The game changers starts at Move 95.<br />
<span id="more-56"></span><br />

<div id='glift_display1' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display1","sgf":"http:\/\/bengozen.com\/\/wp-content\/uploads\/2010\/10\/2010.10.27-Fear.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='//wp-content/uploads/2010/10/2010.10.27-Fear.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
After reading this chapter though, I think I&#8217;ve taken another step forth along my path to becoming the strongest Go player I can be.  It&#8217;s true.  Losing a game can take quite a toll on a person&#8217;s mental stability, especially when the one mistake that cost you the game was your fault. Yet it is in these moments that you should not despair, for the realization of that weakness, whether it is a lack of reading, patience, or simple skill, will allow you to take the step in gaining strength.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">56</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
