<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>playing as white &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/playing-as-white/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>WGW 28: How to Play as White in 2 Stone Handicap Games</title>
		<link>/wgw-28-play-white-2-stone-handicap-games/</link>
		<comments>/wgw-28-play-white-2-stone-handicap-games/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 12:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Weekly Go Wednesday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[2 stones handicap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[playing as white]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=4348</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Weekly Go Wednesday, Issue #28 Welcome to a continuation of my series on how to play as White for beginner/intermediate players. Just like before, I would appreciate any additional insight from stronger players below to supplement my thoughts here. With that said, onwards we go: 2 stone handicap games. Concern #1: &#8220;Black has two corners!! [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 style="text-align: center;">Weekly Go Wednesday, Issue #28</h2>
<p>Welcome to a continuation of my series on how to play as White for beginner/intermediate players. Just like before, I would appreciate any additional insight from stronger players below to supplement my thoughts here. With that said, onwards we go: 2 stone handicap games.<br />
<strong>Concern #1: &#8220;Black has two corners!! Ahh!!! Must overplay like crazy to catchup!&#8221;</strong><br />
First and foremost, two star points does not equal two corners. Black just has two positions setup on the diagonal corners.  So stop panicking and breathe. What you have to remember is that it is only a 2 stone handicap. Yes. <em>Only two stones</em>. If you forgot what it means to give your opponent handicap stones, let me remind you: you are <em>stronger</em> than them. So play normally and establish your positions as you typically would.<br />
<strong>Concern #2: &#8220;But it&#8217;s TWO STONES!!!!!&#8221;</strong><br />
Yes. I heard you the first time; but let me remind you that the two stones you are so worried about is a double edged sword. As you know, people&#8217;s strength can fluctuate a stone or two depending on the time and day along with the style being used; so what that means to you is that you need to realize that your overplays have a pretty good chance of being punished properly. As a result, you need to remember to just play calmly. Your opponent&#8217;s mistake will show itself eventually.<br />
Similar to playing as White in even games, here are a few things to remember:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Be patient.</strong> Two stones might seem like a lot, but there it is not a huge barrier to overcome. Play solidly and wait for your opponent to make an overplay and then things will start to turn in your favor.</li>
<li><strong>Two stones can be a double-edged sword. </strong>This is particularly true of two stone handicap games because there is no saying whether or not you will be playing one stone weaker or your stone will be playing one stone stronger. So avoid huge overplays because there is a good chance that your opponent will be able to punish it properly.</li>
<li><strong>Feel honored to play as White.</strong> I have a feeling this piece of advice will be staying throughout this series, but you really should feel honored to have the opportunity to prove your strength as White.</li>
</ol>
<p>I hope that this helps! Please be sure to leave a comment below if you have any additional comments or questions!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/wgw-28-play-white-2-stone-handicap-games/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">4348</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>WGW 26: How to Play as White in Even Games</title>
		<link>/wgw-26-play-white-even-games/</link>
		<comments>/wgw-26-play-white-even-games/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2013 11:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Weekly Go Wednesday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[playing as white]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=4263</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Weekly Go Wednesday, Issue #26 A couple months ago, I had a request put in by fellow go player DecimoKing for an article on my advice on playing as White. This is the first part to a series of posts geared to provide some guidance to players who find themselves feeling burdened when playing White. [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 style="text-align: center;">Weekly Go Wednesday, Issue #26</h2>
<p>A couple months ago, I had a request put in by fellow go player DecimoKing for an article on my advice on playing as White. This is the first part to a series of posts geared to provide some guidance to players who find themselves feeling burdened when playing White. Although this is definitely geared more for beginner/intermediate players, I would appreciate any additional insight from stronger players below to supplement my thoughts here. With that said, let&#8217;s get started with the first scenario as White: even games.<br />
<strong>Concern #1: &#8220;Black is one move ahead! I feel like I&#8217;m behind when I&#8217;m playing White.&#8221;</strong><br />
The first thing to do is to breathe. Inhale. Exhale. Now, what you have to remember is that this is exactly why the komi system was created in the first place. It&#8217;s always very easy to forget that you have komi. In other words, you already start with points when Black starts with none! So if anyone should feel behind, it&#8217;s Black! xD<br />
<strong>Concern #2: &#8220;Black always gets these awesome moyos (i.e., frameworks) that are gigantic and fearsome!&#8221;</strong><br />
What you have to remember here is that you always have a choice of being more aggressive and breaking up Black&#8217;s formation early on in the game.* Will the game get more complicated? Yes. Will it involve a lot more fighting. Absolutely. However, what you have to determine for yourself is which situation do you hate more: a large moyo where you find yourself needing to invade and live or lose, or a game full of fighting that&#8217;s quite complicated.<br />
*The only framework that White can&#8217;t truly stop without ending up in a disadvantageous position is the sanrensei; but if that is what you hate playing against, then the issue is more about learning a counter strategy to sanrensei as opposed to worried about playing White.<br />
In summary, here are a few things to remember when playing White in even games:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Be patient.</strong> Remember that the komi system was designed to compensate for the first move advantage. If you let yourself get caught up in the illusion of being behind, you&#8217;ll find yourself rushing into dangerous situations that will put you at a disadvantage early in the game.</li>
<li><strong>You can always steer the game in a different direction.</strong> If you really hate frameworks like the Chinese Opening and don&#8217;t know any counter strategies to them, go ahead and interrupt the formation before it materializes (aka approach the corner instead of taking a corner for yourself).</li>
<li><strong>Feel honored to play as White.</strong> Don&#8217;t forget that in go, playing as White usually signifies that who is the stronger player. After all, what color do you play if you give your opponent handicap stones? =) So if your intention is to become the strongest player you can possibly be, shouldn&#8217;t White stones become your best friend? xD</li>
</ol>
<p>I hope that this helps and please be sure to leave a comment below if you have any questions or comments!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/wgw-26-play-white-even-games/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">4263</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Resistant to Playing White</title>
		<link>/resistant-to-playing-white/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2012 22:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[playing as white]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=1166</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In my entire go playing thus far, I never actually found a real preference for one color over another&#8230; until recently. I&#8217;m not sure if any other players share this concern with me, but I recently developed a resistance to playing White. As I sit here wondering how I got to this place, I can [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In my entire go playing thus far, I never actually found a real preference for one color over another&#8230; until recently.<br />
I&#8217;m not sure if any other players share this concern with me, but I recently developed a resistance to playing White. As I sit here wondering how I got to this place, I can only come up with the following possibilities:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><strong>#1. I have no control over how the opening will play out.</strong></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">Now this seems kind of childish, but I feel woefully unprepared to deal with the openings that my opponents tend to play. For example, a play that I know will always haunt me until I get familiar with it is the 3-4 opening. I have a vague idea as to how to deal with it, but I still feel at a loss when I think about it.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><strong>#2. I feel like I have to be more aggressive in order to nullify Black&#8217;s plans.</strong></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">I recognize that with komi White does not nearly have the disadvantage that it used to have, but the idea of being one move behind Black gets under my skin more than I&#8217;d like it to.</p>
<p>That being said, perhaps all of this irrationality stems from the fact that I&#8217;ve recently begun to finally grasp the strategy behind go. My whole board understanding has grown and as a result I have a better idea how things fit together, but I think a side effect of this is I started realizing how much I actually don&#8217;t understand.<br />
For those who aren&#8217;t aware, I have been working with the sanrensei for quite some time now and have developed quite a liking for it. Unfortunately though, sanrensei only really works as Black. I&#8217;ve tried playing sanrensei as White a few times, but the only times I win are when my opponents allow me to gain the initiative and outplay them tactically.<br />
I know that this adverse reaction to playing White will subside in the future, and perhaps one of the best remedies for it is to simply gain better understanding of the different counter strategies to the popular variations that Black generally plays. It&#8217;s a pity there isn&#8217;t a book out there that deals specifically with this subject matter. If there isn&#8217;t one when I&#8217;ve become much stronger and gained a better understanding of the strategic elements of White, you can be sure that I will be posting articles on it to help fill the void.<br />
One thing is for sure though, I want this feeling to disappear as soon as possible.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1166</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
