<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>go seigen &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/go-seigen/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>Stirring the Embers Once Again&#8230;</title>
		<link>/stirring-embers/</link>
		<comments>/stirring-embers/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2014 02:34:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kifu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[go seigen]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5949</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[As many of you are aware, the legendary Go Seigen passed away on November 30th. I’ve been wracking my brain for a way to properly honor him, but it is still eluding me. To help the process out, I decided that it would be a good start working through my collection of his games again. [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/12/2014-12-10-Go-Seigen.jpg"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-5950 " src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/12/2014-12-10-Go-Seigen-300x225.jpg?resize=394%2C256" alt="2014-12-10 Go Seigen" width="394" height="256" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><br />
As many of you are aware, the legendary Go Seigen passed away on November 30th. I’ve been wracking my brain for a way to properly honor him, but it is still eluding me. To help the process out, I decided that it would be a good start working through my collection of his games again. As I played through his game (above), I started to feel the embers begin to catch flame again.<br />
I also had the opportunity to play with fellow blogger RisingStar today. It was a friendly game with a 9 stone handicap. And while the mere thought of playing that kind of game would have scared me a week ago, it was surprisingly calming and fun. Sometimes I feel like I get in these moves where the game just seems to make sense. Moves flow easily and there is a serenity that keeps you level headed at all times. This was one of those games.<br />
The game record is below, but there will most likely be a MGM on it in the future.<br />
[wgo]http://box2018.temp.domains/~bengozen/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/2014.12.10-bengozen-risingstar-9h.sgf[/wgo]
<p style="text-align: center;">[download label=&#8221;Download Kifu&#8221;]//wp-content/uploads/2014/12/2014.12.10-bengozen-risingstar-9h.sgf[/download]
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/stirring-embers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>10</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">5949</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Discovering My &#034;Master Wu&#034;</title>
		<link>/discovering-master-wu/</link>
		<comments>/discovering-master-wu/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2014 01:21:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[first kyu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[go seigen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[master]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[master wu]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5391</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[As most of you know, I&#8217;ve spent my fair share of money on this game. Perhaps one of my craziest purchases as a beginner was The Complete Game Records of Go Seigen. Yup. I bought it in September 2010 when I was a mere 15k.  And though it may have seemed like the biggest waste of [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As most of you know, I&#8217;ve spent my fair share of money on this game. Perhaps one of my craziest purchases as a beginner was <a title="Amazon Purchase Link" href="http://www.amazon.com/dp/7500917260/?tag=mclambjavier999-20">The Complete Game Records of Go Seigen</a>. Yup. I bought it in <a title="BenGoZen September 2010 Archive" href="//2010/09/">September 2010</a> when I was a mere 15k.  And though it may have seemed like the biggest waste of money at the time, I can only smile as I think about how funny the world works sometimes.<br />
Since my first step onto the endless path of go, I have come to learn of many different professionals along with their various styles. And though I&#8217;ve come and gone between the various ones and learned from them, none of them ever really stuck with me. It&#8217;s not that I don&#8217;t admire their strength or am not a fan of them, but there was never one that stuck with me more than another.<br />
<span id="more-5391"></span><br />
For those who have read <a title="Book Review: First Kyu" href="//book-review-first-kyu/">First Kyu</a>, you might remember that Wook (the main character) studied endlessly from <em>Game Records of Wu</em>, which was the focal point of his study to become a professional. And as I was reading it again for like the fifth time, the following paragraph struck me.</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;One day during his fifth month in the mountains, Wook suddenly experienced higher understanding. It was during his eight time reviewing the game records of Master Wu. The experience was the go equivalent of Buddha under the tree, or Jesus after forty days in the wilderness.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Wook came to find his go through studying Master Wu*, similar to how Hikaru&#8217;s go is entrenched in Shusaku&#8217;s (ultimately Sai&#8217;s) go. And after reading that again, part of me wondered who my Master Wu would be. And as the fates would have it, my mind shot straight to my collection of Go Seigen books sitting on my bookshelf at my parent&#8217;s place.<br />
I know that the more popular historical figures that most people study are legends like Honinbo Shusaku, <a title="Kitani Minoru Sensei's Library's Page" href="http://senseis.xmp.net/?KitaniMinoru">Kitani Minoru</a>&#8216;s disciples, Lee Changho, and Lee Sedol because their style is much easier to understand and imitate. And in all honesty, I have tried to study most of them, but I never felt that inspiration that many people talk about when going through a professional&#8217;s games.<br />
I&#8217;ve been told countless times that Go Seigen is very difficult to imitate and requires an immensely strong reading ability for his style to work. Yet, as I sat down with the first volume and my board and stones, a feeling of awe and inspiration came over me as I started playing out the moves on the board. And in that moment, I could feel it deep down: Go Seigen is my Master Wu.<br />
<em>*Fun Trivia: Apparently speculation is that Master Wu in <a title="Book Review: First Kyu" href="//book-review-first-kyu/">First Kyu</a> actually refers to Go Seigen. I had absolutely no idea. Isn&#8217;t that crazy?!</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/discovering-master-wu/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>15</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">5391</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Book Review: Master Play &#8211; The Style of Go Seigen</title>
		<link>/book-review-master-play-style-go-seigen/</link>
		<comments>/book-review-master-play-style-go-seigen/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2013 13:12:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[go seigen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[playing style]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Slate & Shell]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yuan zhou]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=4028</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Master Play: The Style of Go Seigen Description: In the second volume of Yuan Zhou&#8217;s series &#8220;Master Play,&#8221; Zhou goes into the difficult to understand style of Go Seigen, the greatest player of the 20th century. While you might have issues making sense of Go Seigen&#8217;s games on your own, Zhou does a brilliant job demystifying [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/09/masterplaygoseigencover.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-4029" alt="masterplaygoseigencover" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/09/masterplaygoseigencover.jpg?resize=288%2C410" width="288" height="410" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">Master Play: The Style of Go Seigen</h2>
<p><strong>Description:</strong> In the second volume of Yuan Zhou&#8217;s series &#8220;Master Play,&#8221; Zhou goes into the difficult to understand style of Go Seigen, the greatest player of the 20th century. While you might have issues making sense of Go Seigen&#8217;s games on your own, Zhou does a brilliant job demystifying his moves and help you get a glimpse into the brilliant and innovative mind that Go Seigen posseses.<br />
<span id="more-4028"></span><br />
[expand title=&#8221;Book Details&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
[table]
Title, Master Play: The Style of Go Seigen<br />
Series, Master Play<br />
Author, Yuan Zhou<br />
Publisher, Slate &amp; Shell<br />
Published, &#8220;2008&#8221;<br />
Language, English<br />
ISBN, 1-932001-41-7<br />
Length, 83 Pages<br />
[/table]
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Table of Content&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>A Brief Biography of Go Seigen</li>
<li>An Early Demonstration of Go Seigen&#8217;s Power</li>
<li>Go Seigen in His Prime</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Before I Read This Book&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
When I first started playing go, I was not too keen on learning about professional go at the time. Yet there were two names that I already knew that were legendary: Shusaku and Go Seigen. Being the crazy person I am, I went ahead and acquired Go Seigen&#8217;s entire game collection (in Chinese). Needless to say it was a reckless decision and I did not even open it up for quite some time.<br />
Some time later on, I was excited to hear that Yuan Zhou had released a book on Go Seigen&#8217;s style. Seeing as how this book would be in English and I might actually be able to comprehend it, I went ahead and purchased it in hopes that I might finally be able to make use of the collection I bought years ago.<br />
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;My Review&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221; expanded=&#8221;true&#8221;]
When you first open the book, you are greeted with a fun little dialogue between Yuan Zhou and two amateur players (4 kyu and 1 dan respectively). In this conversation, Zhou inquires about what amateur players know about Go Seigen. After getting a basic gist of what they know, Zhou launches into a wonderful story-telling of Go Seigen biography and why he has become the legend he is known to be today. It is very entertaining and really helps to give context to a man that many speak so highly of. I personally feel that without this section, the book would not be complete.<br />
Now, in regards to the game commentaries, Zhou does a wonderful job of keeping the length of the diagrams to a minimum. It is usually easy to follow what Zhou is trying to illustrate. In addition, there are not too many variations to deter from the actual game. The goal of these commentaries serve more as an explanation of Go Seigen&#8217;s brilliance, as opposed to an in-depth discussion about go theory and technique, which really makes the book that much more enjoyable since professional go can often be difficult for amateurs to understand.<br />
As my first exposure to Yuan Zhou&#8217;s Master Play Series, I was very pleased with his ability to fit so much information in such a short book. I am looking forward to checking out the other ones in the future!<br />
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Synopsis&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<strong>What did I enjoy about the book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The biography of Go Seigen was very entertaining and informative.</li>
<li>The game commentaries focus on showing Go Seigen&#8217;s brilliance as opposed to go theory and technique.</li>
<li>It is very easy to read and work through.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What did I gain from reading this book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>A much better understanding of the legend known as Go Seigen.</li>
<li>An even greater respect for his style of go.</li>
<li>Greater interest in studying his other games.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What is the format of the book?</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>A biography of Go Seigen that is a few pages long and reads like a story.</li>
<li>Game commentaries that follow the standard structure of diagrams accompanied by their explanations.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>What aspect can be improved on?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>There is an extra &#8220;B&#8221; in the bottom diagram on Page 5.</li>
<li>Otherwise,</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Is this book easy to read?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Yes. The book was easy to read and work through.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Bottom Line</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>A fantastic introduction to Go Seigen and his legacy.</li>
<li>Contains two beautiful games that illustrate his ingenuity and brilliance.</li>
<li>Well worth the price of admission if you are interested in learning about Go Seigen and his style of go.</li>
</ol>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Recommended For&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Players who are interested in learning more about Go Seigen.</li>
<li>Players who are interested in reading in-depth but understandable commentaries of two of Go Seigen&#8217;s games.</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Where Can I Buy It?&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Slate &amp; Shell &#8211; <a href="http://www.slateandshell.com/SSYZ006.html">$15.50</a> (shipping and handling not included)</li>
<li>SmartGo Books &#8211; <a title="SmartGo Books" href="http://www.smartgo.com/books.htm">$4.99</a> USD (e-Book)</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Other Books in This Series&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;lastExpandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Master Play: The Style of Lee Changho</li>
<li>Master Play: The Style of Go Seigen</li>
<li>Master Play: The Style of Takemiya</li>
<li>Master Play: The Fighting Styles of Kato Masao &amp; Seo Bong Soo</li>
<li>Master Play: The Territorial Styles of Kitani Minoru &amp; Cho Chikun</li>
<li>Master Play: the Playing Style of Seven Top Pros</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
<p style="text-align: center;"><em><strong>Last Updated on September 25th, 2013</strong></em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/book-review-master-play-style-go-seigen/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">4028</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Go Seigen, Freedom and an AGA Online Tournament</title>
		<link>/go-seigen-freedom-aga-online-tournament/</link>
		<comments>/go-seigen-freedom-aga-online-tournament/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2013 15:18:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[aga]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[freedom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[go seigen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tournament]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=4034</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I recently finished Master Play: The Style of Go Seigen (Review coming soon!), and it has really given me a lot to think about in regards to the way I play go. For starters, though I&#8217;ve been familiar with the concept of professionals ignoring an area when there just aren&#8217;t any good moves to play, [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I recently finished <em>Master Play: The Style of Go Seigen</em> (Review coming soon!), and it has really given me a lot to think about in regards to the way I play go.<br />
For starters, though I&#8217;ve been familiar with the concept of professionals ignoring an area when there just aren&#8217;t any good moves to play, it wasn&#8217;t until I saw Go Seigen&#8217;s games till I realized how true this really was. In fact, not only did Go Seigen constantly resist giving in to his opponents; but he would also not hesitate to trade large sections of the board! And what made it even more mind-blowing, was that these areas he would sacrifice were places that were only a few moves away from solid territory!<br />
With that vivid illustration in mind, I couldn&#8217;t help but start to notice how stubborn kyu players get about hanging onto stones or territory. It&#8217;s as if once they&#8217;ve made a decision (i.e., I have declared the right side to be mine!), they will defend it to the end regardless of the fact that they are losing. Another example of this is I&#8217;ve noticed is: &#8220;Oh look, I&#8217;ve spent the time to play three stones here, even though they are now strategically useless, I must save it at all cost even though I will let my opponent walk right into my territory!&#8221; Granted, I realize that you must understand strategy and such to be able to walk away from some groups, but this seems to be a general trend that I&#8217;ve noticed.<br />
In addition, I think I may have started to internalize the idea of, &#8220;If you can&#8217;t find a good move, play somewhere else.&#8221; In other words, seeing Go Seigen&#8217;s game for the first time has really shocked me into realizing how much freedom there really is on the go board. Although a sequence might be considered sente or an area might seem large, it may not actually be from a whole board perspective or from another player&#8217;s strategy.<br />
I keep trying to bring this post to a nice closing statement, but it seems that this post is destined for random ramblings. It&#8217;s still a whirlwind of thoughts and emotions that I&#8217;m sorting through, but I guess that&#8217;s one of the benefits of having a blog right? A way for me to dump my thoughts and attempt to sort it out in the process. xD<br />
<a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/09/2013.09.22_AGA-Online-logo.jpg"><img class="aligncenter" alt="2013.09.22_AGA-Online-logo" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/09/2013.09.22_AGA-Online-logo.jpg?resize=468%2C60" width="468" height="60" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><br />
On an entirely different note, in case you haven&#8217;t heard about it, the <a href="http://www.usgo.org/">American Go Association (AGA)</a> has taken a big step towards establishing a presence online. Starting in October, there will be an <a href="http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/09/expanding-online-efforts-aga-launches-on-line-self-paired-tourney-on-kgs/">AGA Online Tournament</a> that will be used to help gather information and help them figure out the right way to proceed with online games in the future. And yes, I have already signed up! For more information, check out their post <a href="http://www.usgo.org/news/2013/09/expanding-online-efforts-aga-launches-on-line-self-paired-tourney-on-kgs/">here</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/go-seigen-freedom-aga-online-tournament/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">4034</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Feeling Like Go Seigen with a Mega-Fail</title>
		<link>/feeling-like-go-seigen-with-a-mega-fail/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2013 22:30:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kifu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[0.5 komi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[black]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[defeat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[even]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[go seigen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[resignation]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=1625</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s been awhile since I last posted a kifu on here, and for my first KGS game post for 2013, it is only fitting that I post this one. To give some background to this game, it&#8217;s been about five weeks since my friend Nate and I had the opportunity to play one another. So [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s been awhile since I last posted a kifu on here, and for my first KGS game post for 2013, it is only fitting that I post this one.<br />
To give some background to this game, it&#8217;s been about five weeks since my friend Nate and I had the opportunity to play one another. So the anticipation of the game was making me a little bit nervous since I&#8217;m quite sure that he&#8217;s stronger than his KGS rank. Nonetheless, I was excited at the opportunity to finally get to start the new year properly with a game with him.<br />
This game was a magnificent show of tenacity and fierce fighting spirit from both players (if I may say so). Both of us were unrelenting in trying to stay ahead and find a way to conclude the game in his favor. It took a whopping 1.5 hours, which was more than either of us was probably anticipating; but what an intense and awesome 1.5 hours.<br />
In regards to the blog post title, I felt like Go Seigen at certain points of the game because I was like, &#8220;Twenty points? Was that supposed to be mine? No matter! Here! Take it! Let me show you how that will dwarf in comparison to my attack!&#8221; On the other hand, this game is a mega-fail for me because of the fact that I lost my tenacity in the final move and failed to realize that the game was actually one move away from victory.<br />
I hope that you enjoy one of my craziest games to date.<br />

<div id='glift_display1' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display1","sgf":"http:\/\/bengozen.com\/\/wp-content\/uploads\/2013\/01\/2013.01.08-Go-Seigen-MegaFail.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='//wp-content/uploads/2013/01/2013.01.08-Go-Seigen-MegaFail.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center">[download label=&#8221;Download Kifu&#8221;]//wp-content/uploads/2013/01/2013.01.08-Go-Seigen-MegaFail.sgf[/download]
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1625</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
