<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>professional &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/professional/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>Monday Go Meditation: Game 68</title>
		<link>/monday-go-meditation-game-68/</link>
		<comments>/monday-go-meditation-game-68/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2014 11:15:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Commentaries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kifu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[4p]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[5 stones handicap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dahye lee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[professional]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[simul]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5897</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Introduction For this week’s meditation, we are going to be reviewing my first professional simul game from Go Congress! Through this game, you’ll get to witness the enduring strength of professionals in simul games. Even though the game looks overwhelmingly in Black’s advantage for a good portion of the game, it is in the middle [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>Introduction</h2>
<p>For this week’s meditation, we are going to be reviewing my first professional simul game from <a title="Go Congress 2014 — Day 1" href="//go-congress-2014-day-1/">Go Congress</a>! Through this game, you’ll get to witness the enduring strength of professionals in simul games. Even though the game looks overwhelmingly in Black’s advantage for a good portion of the game, it is in the middle game where their precise analysis becomes extremely evident.<br />
In case there are those wondering though, Dahye’s felt that I played well for most of the game; but as you’ll see in the game, an oversight on the security of my own groups was the ultimate reason for my demise. Hope that you enjoy the game!<br />
<span id="more-5897"></span><br />

<div id='glift_display1' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display1","sgf":"http:\/\/bengozen.com\/\/wp-content\/uploads\/2014\/10\/2014.10.27-MGM-68.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='//wp-content/uploads/2014/10/2014.10.27-MGM-68.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">[download label=&#8221;Download Kifu&#8221;]//wp-content/uploads/2014/10/2014.10.27-MGM-68.sgf[/download]
<h2>One Point Lesson</h2>
<p>Never let your guard down against a professional. NEVER!!!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/monday-go-meditation-game-68/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">5897</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Book Review: Commented Games by Lee Sedol: Volume 1</title>
		<link>/book-review-commented-games-lee-sedol-volume-1/</link>
		<comments>/book-review-commented-games-lee-sedol-volume-1/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2013 16:15:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[commentary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lee sedol]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[professional]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=3942</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Commented Games by Lee Sedol: Volume 1 &#8211; One Step Closer to the Summit Description: Described as many as the Korean version of Invincible, this series contains some of the most detailed commentaries that I have read thus far. In addition, it is evident that Lee Sedol (9P) and Lee Sena have worked work to [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/09/leesedolv1cover.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3946" alt="leesedolv1cover" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/09/leesedolv1cover.jpg?resize=293%2C400" width="293" height="400" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">Commented Games by Lee Sedol: Volume 1 &#8211; One Step Closer to the Summit</h2>
<p><strong>Description:</strong> Described as many as the Korean version of <em>Invincible</em>, this series contains some of the most detailed commentaries that I have read thus far. In addition, it is evident that Lee Sedol (9P) and Lee Sena have worked work to make the content accessible to both that beginner and intermediate players as well. This book not only goes into Lee Sedol&#8217;s thought on go strategy and his thoughts on the moves that occur; but also talks about his feelings and mental state during each game along with anecdotes from his journey to being one of the strongest go players in the world.<br />
<span id="more-3942"></span><br />
[expand title=&#8221;Book Details&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
[table]
Title, Commented Games by Lee Sedol: Volume 1 &#8211; One Step Closer to the Summit<br />
Series, Commented Games by Lee Sedol<br />
Author, Lee Sedol (9P) &amp; Lee Sena<br />
Translators, Daniela Trinks &amp; Lee Seong Keun<br />
Publisher, Baduktopia<br />
Published, &#8220;June 2012&#8243;<br />
Language, English<br />
ISBN, 978-89-90965-37-0<br />
Length, 319 Pages<br />
[/table]
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Table of Content&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Commentator&#8217;s Preface</li>
<li>Writer&#8217;s Preface</li>
<li>Chapter 1
<ul>
<li>The 8th Baedalwang Tournament, Title Match &#8211; Game 4 (Yoo Chang Hyuk 9P) vs. Lee Sedol 9P)</li>
<li>Episodes
<ul>
<li>First Encounter with Baduk</li>
<li>Baduk Study I</li>
<li>The Pizza Tree</li>
<li>Baduk Study II</li>
<li>Fetching Makgeolli</li>
<li>Father&#8217;s Tears</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Chapter 1 &#8211; Epilogue 1</li>
<li>Chapter 1 &#8211; Epilogue 2: The Challenger Determining Match</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Chapter 2
<ul>
<li>The 5th LG Cup International Tournament, Title Match &#8211; Game 3 (Lee Changho 9P vs. Lee Sedol 3P)</li>
<li>Episodes
<ul>
<li>Favorite Books and Movies</li>
<li>The Most Difficult Part of Baduk</li>
<li>Accompany</li>
<li>Playing Online</li>
<li>Competition and Mental Discipline</li>
<li>Improving Skills</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Chapter 2 &#8211; Epilogue</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Chapter 1
<ul>
<li>The 15th Fujitsu Cup, Final Round (Yoo Chang Hyuk 9P vs. Lee Sedol 3P)</li>
<li>Episodes
<ul>
<li>Baduk Style</li>
<li>Tournament Participation and Debts</li>
<li>A Game with Yoo Chang Hyuk 9P</li>
<li>Father&#8217;s Teaching Philosophy</li>
<li>Naming</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Chapter 3 &#8211; Epilogue</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Before I Read This Book&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
When I first began my journey as a go player, I bought Invincible and was excited at the prospect of working through all the games of one of the greatest go legends of all time, Shusaku. Although I&#8217;m sure the quality of information in it is incredible, the experience of trying to work through it was rather traumatic since it was so incredibly advanced. Needless to say, I learned the hard way how incredibly inaccessible professional commentaries can be.<br />
Around the time this book came out, I had just started being exposed to the modern professional go scene. Like most people, I gravitated toward the most well known and strongest players (i.e., Lee Changho, Lee Sedol, Gu Li, etc.). So Lee Sedol&#8217;s book came out and it was being hailed as the Korean version of &#8220;Invincible,&#8221; I was a little nervous at first. When I found out however that it was written to try and be accessible to beginner/intermediate players as well, let&#8217;s just say I couldn&#8217;t purchase the book fast enough.<br />
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;My Review&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221; expanded=&#8221;true&#8221;]
When I first started working through this book, one of the things that absolutely shocked me was how short the sequences were for each diagram. I was so used to other professional commentaries where game diagrams were often 10 moves or longer with such advanced discussions that this new approach was such a relief. In addition, since each game diagram is usually only a few moves long, the game discussion is broken down in far more detail and provides weaker players like myself an actual chance at learning something! In addition, at the end of each game, Lee Sedol highlights all of the important moments along with each game. This is something I had never encountered before and found it really helped me gain perspective on the game.<br />
And as if that weren&#8217;t enough already, the fact that every diagram is accompanied by Lee Sedol&#8217;s actual thoughts on the game along with intropsective thoughts on his mentality at the time makes the experience surreal. In fact, the only way I think that the game reviews could get any better would be if Lee Sedol himself were sitting with me one on one while going over his games and answering my questions. And yes, I&#8217;m being completely serious.<br />
In terms of my ability to understand the discussion about the variations however, I would have to say that there were times it was a bit difficult for me to follow. However, this is actually a really good thing since you will notice that I did not mention my eyes glazing over or anything. It&#8217;s just that it currently feels just slightly out of my reach, so I imagine that it won&#8217;t be too far in the future when I will be able to really appreciate all the discussion in the book.<br />
And finally, yes, it may take a long time before I&#8217;m able to fully comprehend the book in its entirety and apply it to my own games; but the fact is that I had an incredible time reading this book. The combination of learning about Lee Sedol&#8217;s perspective on go along with being able to get to know Lee Sedol as a person made the book an incredible experience. This will definitely be one of my favorites of all time and I am looking forward to revisiting it many times in my journey as a go player.<br />
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Synopsis&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<strong>What did I enjoy about the book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>When you first open the book, you are immediately greeted by colored pictures capturing some of Lee Sedol&#8217;s highlights in life. While this might seem irrelevant to some, I found that it added a really personal touch to the book since it felt as if I was looking through a scrapbook and getting to know Lee Sedol personally.</li>
<li>The introductory page for each game was immensely appreciated since it gave context as to the kind of game being played along with how high the stakes were.</li>
<li>The game commentary is extremely detailed and you get to hear Lee Sedol&#8217;s personal thoughts on both the go discussion along with his mentality at the time.</li>
<li>The way Lee Sedol highlights the important moments of each game is new and really helped to wrap up the game in a very thorough manner.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What did I gain from reading this book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>A much broader perspective on the game in regards to how to approach it.</li>
<li>The realization of just how important accurate reading is when it comes to go.</li>
<li>A new awareness of how often things can change and that trade-offs can occur at any time in the game.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>How is the book structured?</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>A one page introduction to the game with the following information:
<ul>
<li>Prize Money (1st Place)</li>
<li>Winner&#8217;s Purse (2nd Place)</li>
<li>Tournament Regulations (Time Allotted for Each Game)</li>
<li>Short summary of the tournament&#8217;s background and general structure.</li>
<li>The tournament pairing chart.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>A title page featuring:
<ul>
<li>A black and white picture from the actual game itself (with the respective players included).</li>
<li>The tournament and round that the game was played in.</li>
<li>The date that the game was played.</li>
<li>Indication of who played which color and what rank they were at the time.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>For the commentary portion of each chapter, each figure had the following structure:
<ol>
<li>A large kifu that made it easy to read and figure out where each move was.</li>
<li>Below each kifu was at least a few lines from Lee Sedol commenting on his mental state of mind or thoughts he was having at the time. This is not to be confused with go related commentary, since it is more of a psychological introspection than anything else.</li>
<li>Approximately a paragraph long of Lee Sedol&#8217;s explanation of what happened in the featured sequence and some of his thoughts on it (e.g., why he played the way he did, etc.).</li>
<li>As you can expect from any game review, the discussion of variations and numerous diagrams appear with each sequence.</li>
<li>At the end of each game, Lee Sedol goes through and summarizes the highlights of each game and discusses the importance of that moment.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>An epilogue of Lee Sedol&#8217;s thoughts of the tournament as a whole along with any thoughts he had about himself as a player and his psychological state at the time. In other words, it&#8217;s as if you got the opportunity to talk to Lee Sedol and hear his thoughts on the tournament. Extremely enjoyable to read.</li>
<li>Finally, spread throughout the chapters, players will also find anecdotes and random tidbits (called Episodes in the Table of Contents) about Lee Sedol that serve as an extremely enjoyable break.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>What aspect can be improved on?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>No complaints here!</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Is this book easy to read?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Yes. The tone of the book was primarily conversational that really helped alleviate any difficulty weaker players might normally have when reading a book with professional level commentary.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Bottom Line</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>The first book where a professional provides commentary that can be accessible by beginner and intermediate players (though a bit more towards intermediate players).</li>
<li>The format of the book makes for an incredible and unforgettable experience where the reader can be immersed in go and Lee Sedol&#8217;s thoughts while also getting to know him at the same time.</li>
<li>It takes professional level commentary to a level never seen before.</li>
<li>Worth every penny and more for the content and experience you get with it!</li>
</ol>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Recommended For&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Any players who are fans of Lee Sedol.</li>
<li>Players who have run into issues understanding professional commentaries in the past and are looking for a book that tries to bridge that gap.</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Where Can I Buy It?&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>GoGameGuru &#8211; <a title="Commented Games by Lee Sedol Volume 1 GoGameGuru Purchase Link" href="http://shop.gogameguru.com/commented-games-by-lee-sedol-1/?acc=e4da3b7fbbce2345d7772b0674a318d5">$42.00</a> (shipping and handling not included)</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Other Books in This Series&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;lastExpandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Commented Games by Lee Sedol: Volume 1 &#8211; One Step Closer to the Summit</li>
<li><a title="Book Review: Commented Games by Lee Sedol Volume 2" href="//book-review-commented-games-lee-sedol-volume-2/">Commented Games by Lee Sedol: Volume 2 &#8211; Dream to Be the Best</a></li>
<li>Commented Games by Lee Sedol: Volume 3 &#8211; TBD</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
<p style="text-align: center;"><em><strong>Last Updated on September 10th, 2013</strong></em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/book-review-commented-games-lee-sedol-volume-1/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3942</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Monday Go Meditation: Game 08</title>
		<link>/monday-go-meditation-game-08/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2013 09:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Monday Go Meditation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chinese opening]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[insei]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mirror go]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[professional]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=2573</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Introduction With my own games being rather all over the place lately, I decided to try something new and review a game that I had a chance to see live online. This is between an insei in China (Black) and a Chinese professional (White). Since the Chinese Opening is currently a big part of my [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 style="text-align: center;">Introduction</h2>
<p>With my own games being rather all over the place lately, I decided to try something new and review a game that I had a chance to see live online. This is between an insei in China (Black) and a Chinese professional (White). Since the Chinese Opening is currently a big part of my go, this game was the best choice since I got to see how stronger players not only utilize the Chinese Opening, but how they dealt with a mirror opening.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">
<div id='glift_display2' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display2","sgf":"http:\/\/bengozen.com\/\/wp-content\/uploads\/2013\/04\/2013.04.22-MGM-08.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='//wp-content/uploads/2013/04/2013.04.22-MGM-08.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">[download label=&#8221;Download Kifu&#8221;]//wp-content/uploads/2013/04/2013.04.22-MGM-08.sgf[/download]
<h2 style="text-align: center;"><strong>One Point Lesson</strong></h2>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>Having the ideal opening does not mean you have a won game.</strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2573</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pro Event at the Japanese Embassy</title>
		<link>/pro-event-at-the-japanese-embassy/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2013 21:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kifu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[4p]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[japanese]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[narumi osawa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[professional]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rengo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartgo]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=2299</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[On April 2nd, 2013, I had the honor of being able to attend a professional go event that featured Narumi Osawa (4p) and was hosted by the Japanese Embassy in Washington D.C. It was a free event that consisted of a short talk designed for beginners, a simultaneous game against Narumi, and a lecture/review on [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/04/japanembassy.jpg"><img alt="japanembassy" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/04/japanembassy.jpg?resize=300%2C225" width="300" height="225" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></p>
<p>On April 2nd, 2013, I had the honor of being able to attend a professional go event that featured Narumi Osawa (4p) and was hosted by the Japanese Embassy in Washington D.C. It was a free event that consisted of a short talk designed for beginners, a simultaneous game against Narumi, and a lecture/review on one of the games.<br />
<span id="more-2299"></span><br />
For those who don&#8217;t know Narumi, here is a short biography on her.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/04/narumi-osawa.jpg"><img alt="narumi osawa" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/04/narumi-osawa.jpg?resize=208%2C303" width="208" height="303" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></p>
<ul>
<li>Born in Saitama Prefecture, Japan on May 22nd, 1976.</li>
<li>Became professional 1-dan in 1998, promoted to 2-dan in 1999, 3-dan in 2003, and 4-dan in 2009.</li>
<li>Won the Women’s Kakusei Title（女流鶴聖戦） in 1999 and 2003, and the Women’s JAL Title（JAL女流早碁戦）in 2005.</li>
<li>Participated in the 16th Asian Tournament as a member of the Japanese National Team.</li>
</ul>
<p>Being as the event was in D.C. on a weekday night, I made sure to pad extra time for any possible metro delays or my own inability to find the place. Luckily I did, because even though I arrived about half an hour early, it took me walking into two different buildings before I finally found the Japanese Embassy.<br />
In all honesty, I was a little skeptical as to how many people would be able to attend since it was in D.C. and on a Tuesday. For those who don&#8217;t live in the area, traffic can be crazy when trying to get into the city during rush hour; but I was pleasantly surprised to see that a lot of people showed up! On top of that, there were actually a number of beginners who came as well! It was certainly very uplifting to see so many people attend.<br />
<figure style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/04/japanembassy5.jpg"><img alt="japanembassy5" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/04/japanembassy5.jpg?resize=300%2C225" width="300" height="225" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">As you can see, the place is filled with people!</figcaption></figure>
When the time came to meet Narumi, I was a little more nervous than usual because I knew that she didn&#8217;t speak very much English. Fortunately, there was a translator that helped to facilitate some basic conversation between her and I regarding how strong I was. One of the interesting questions I got from her was what we considered beginners to be in terms of rank. I responded that we considered beginners to be anywhere from 30-20k. As she nodded to acknowledge my statement, I couldn&#8217;t help but be reminded of how most players in Asia probably only recognize dan as an actual rank. Haha.<br />
When it came time for the event to start, we were still short on boards and missing the demonstration board. Narumi was quick on her feet however, and she suggested that the beginners form two teams and she would comment on the game as they played. After a little bit of shuffling around, two teams of five were formed and play began. Here are some photographs from the beginner event:<br />
<figure style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/04/japanembassy2.jpg"><img alt="japanembassy2" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/04/japanembassy2.jpg?resize=300%2C400" width="300" height="400" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">The two kids here are choosing for color.<br />Side Note: It was exciting when we found out that the boy is an elementary student who aspires to be a professional player!</figcaption></figure>
<figure style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/04/japanembassy3.jpg"><img alt="japanembassy3" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/04/japanembassy3.jpg?resize=300%2C225" width="300" height="225" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Each player was permitted 3 moves before letting the next player rotate in.</figcaption></figure>
<figure style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/04/japanembassy4.jpg"><img alt="japanembassy4" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/04/japanembassy4.jpg?resize=300%2C225" width="300" height="225" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Narumi Osawa (4p) explaining a concept to the audience.</figcaption></figure>
<p style="text-align: left;">Afterwards, in order to try and accommodate the number of players, Narumi thought it would be best to have people play rengo (e.g, pair go) against her. So without hesitation, I asked my friend Gurujeet to join me in the battle to try and survive against a professional. As neither Gurujeet nor I have played much pair go, it was approached with fun and adventure as we played a game that was not necessarily our best, but certainly yielded a rather interesting game. =)</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Due to time constraints and the need to move on to the next part of the event, we were unable to finish the game in its entirety. (Although in all honesty, both Gurujeet and I were already preparing to say &#8220;I resign&#8221; in Japanese anyways. xD) To my surprise however, Narumi wanted me show our game on the demonstration board for her commentary. Needless to say, I was happy to do so (and silently thanking SmartGo again for always being there in my time of need for a solid kifu app).</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">When I got up on the stage, it felt a little surreal to think that I was the person helping the professional put stones on the demonstration board. I mean, I&#8217;ve seen it on videos a ton of times, but to actually be the one doing it! So cool! And to top it all off, it was my game as well!</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">As I stood up there listening to Narumi explain various aspects of our game in Japanese, for the first time ever, I felt go transcend the language barrier. I know that sounds really odd, but even though I have practically no knowledge of Japanese, I felt as if I could understand the core concept of each of her messages as she spoke and moved stones around. Call me crazy, but it was an incredible experience.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">The following is the game record from that night with any commentary from Narumi clearly marked.</p>

<div id='glift_display3' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display3","sgf":"http:\/\/bengozen.com\/\/wp-content\/uploads\/2013\/04\/2013.04.04-Pro-Event-at-the-Japanese-Embassy.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='//wp-content/uploads/2013/04/2013.04.04-Pro-Event-at-the-Japanese-Embassy.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">[download label=&#8221;Download Kifu&#8221;]//wp-content/uploads/2013/04/2013.04.04-Pro-Event-at-the-Japanese-Embassy.sgf[/download]
<p style="text-align: left;">Well, with that night, I have played a go pro from each of the major countries: Korea, China, Japan, and Taiwan! Woot! Now onwards to grow my collection of pro games!</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2299</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
