<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>good shape &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/good-shape/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>Book Review: Making Good Shape</title>
		<link>/book-review-making-good-shape/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2013 22:30:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bad shape]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fundamentals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[getting stronger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good shape]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shape]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=1546</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Overall Rating: 5 / 5 Ponnuki Basic Information Title: Mastering the Basics, Volume 3 &#8211; Making Good Shape Authors: Rob van Zeijst and Richard Bozulich Publisher: Kiseido Publication Date: December 2002 Page Length: 206 pages Number of Problems: 245 Synopsis Gives players fantastic exposure to new concepts and ideas regarding shape. High quality content for a subject that has minimal [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2012/12/makingGoodShapeCover.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1670" alt="makingGoodShapeCover" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2012/12/makingGoodShapeCover.jpg?resize=300%2C407" width="300" height="407" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">Overall Rating: 5 / 5 Ponnuki</h2>
<h3>Basic Information</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Title:</strong> Mastering the Basics, Volume 3 &#8211; Making Good Shape</li>
<li><strong>Authors: </strong>Rob van Zeijst and Richard Bozulich</li>
<li><strong>Publisher: </strong>Kiseido</li>
<li><strong>Publication Date: </strong>December 2002</li>
<li><strong>Page Length:</strong> 206 pages</li>
<li><strong>Number of Problems</strong>: 245</li>
</ul>
<h3>Synopsis</h3>
<ul>
<li>Gives players fantastic exposure to new concepts and ideas regarding shape.</li>
<li>High quality content for a subject that has minimal literature compared to other concepts of go (e.g., life and death).</li>
<li>Any player who has a desire to get stronger and enter the realm of SDK&#8217;s should absolutely get this book.</li>
<li>A hybrid of theoretical/conceptual explanations along with problems to illustrate the ideas.</li>
<li>Appropriate for 15 kyu and stronger.</li>
<li>Recommended for serious players.</li>
</ul>
<p><span id="more-1546"></span></p>
<h3>Detailed Review</h3>
<h4>Readability &#8211; 9 / 10</h4>
<p>While a large portion of this book is focused on problems, the first chapter consists of explanations regarding shape concepts and theories. Overall, it is relatively easy to understand and read. It can be rather dense at times, but this is something you want from a book that is focused solely on a topic that doesn&#8217;t receive very much attention. Like any other tsumego book, the diagrams and solutions are quite straightforward. The only time I would imagine anyone would have any difficulty following the content would be at the end when example games are given. Then again, I always find those hard to follow and truly grasp anything from. So as a result, I&#8217;m not including it in the evaluation.</p>
<h4>Content Quality &#8211; 10 / 10</h4>
<p>As I mentioned before, this book consists of both a theoretical/conceptual part and a tsumego part. The theory section of the book is done remarkably well and deserves nothing but the highest of accolades in terms of collecting all the various insights on shape into one chapter. In addition, the tsumego section covers a wide variety of game positions that I have personally seen. This only helps to further drive home concepts that we are being exposed to. In addition, the explanations are quite detailed for a tsumego and does a good job covering typical responses that players might choose and why they are not very good.</p>
<h4>Final Thoughts</h4>
<p>Unlike typical tsumego books, approach this book as you would a theory based book. In other words, the goal of the book is being exposed to new concepts and not &#8220;solving the problem.&#8221; Spend a couple minutes or so on each one, but no more, since the solution is often (at least for me) different from what you can come up with. Once you&#8217;ve done that, flip over to the solution and see why the authors chose the answer they did.<br />
The reason for this approach is that your goal is to be exposed to new concepts and ideas regarding good shape. Although the format of the book may be in terms of &#8220;problems&#8221; and &#8220;solutions,&#8221; there is no true right or wrong. If anything, you should try to see it as &#8220;better&#8221; or &#8220;more efficient.&#8221; By approaching the book in this manner, you will gain far more and find it far less frustrating since you will not feel bad for not having the &#8220;right answer.&#8221;<br />
This is truly an amazing book that has so much value to players looking to further understand a concept that eludes many of us. Although I have technically &#8220;finished&#8221; the book, the theories and concepts are far from being fully integrated into my play. It is definitely is a book that I will be revisiting time and time again.</p>
<h4>Table of Contents</h4>
<ol>
<li>Preface</li>
<li>Some Important Terms and Concepts</li>
<li>Chapter One: The Efficiency of Stones</li>
<li>Chapter Two: Examples of Good Shape</li>
<li>Chapter Three: 245 Problems.</li>
<li>Chapter Four: Example Games</li>
</ol>
<h4>Recommended Vendors:</h4>
<ol>
<li>Amazon &#8211; <a title="Amazon Purchase Link" href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/4906574734/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=be09a-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=4906574734">$25.00</a> (S&amp;H not included)</li>
<li>Kiseido &#8211; <a title="Kiseido Order Form" href="http://www.kiseido.com/go_books.htm">$21.00</a> (S&amp;H not included)</li>
<li>SmartGo Books (eBook) &#8211; <a href="http://www.smartgo.com/booksbycategory.htm">$8.99</a> (Apple users only)</li>
</ol>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Last updated January 15th, 2012 &#8211; 6 kyu</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1546</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Book Review: Opening Theory Made Easy</title>
		<link>/book-review-opening-theory-made-easy/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2010 13:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good shape]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[opening theory]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[strategy]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=81</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Overall Rating: 5 / 5 Ponnuki Basic Information Title: Opening Theory Made Easy Author: Hitake Odeo, 9 dan Publication Date: October 1992 Page Length: 170 pages Synopsis The best introductory book to opening theory. Concise, easy to read, and easy to carry. Appropriate for 15 kyu and stronger. Recommended for any player with an interest [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2010/10/opening-theory-made-easy-cover.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-1495" alt="opening-theory-made-easy-cover" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2010/10/opening-theory-made-easy-cover.jpg?resize=206%2C288" width="206" height="288" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">Overall Rating: 5 / 5 Ponnuki</h2>
<h3><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Basic Information</span></h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Title: </strong>Opening Theory Made Easy</li>
<li><strong>Author: </strong>Hitake Odeo, 9 dan</li>
<li><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 1992</li>
<li><strong>Page Length: </strong>170 pages</li>
</ul>
<h3 style="text-align: left;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Synopsis</span></h3>
<ul>
<li style="text-align: left;">The best introductory book to opening theory.</li>
<li style="text-align: left;">Concise, easy to read, and easy to carry.</li>
<li style="text-align: left;">Appropriate for 15 kyu and stronger.</li>
<li style="text-align: left;">Recommended for any player with an interest in understanding the opening.</li>
</ul>
<div style="text-align: left;"><span id="more-81"></span></div>
<h3 style="text-align: left;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Detailed Review</span></h3>
<h4 style="text-align: left;">Readability &#8211; 9 / 10</h4>
<p>There are twenty chapters in this book, hence the twenty principles. Hideo does a fantastic job of reviewing basic principles of opening theory while keeping his responses short and concise. This makes it extremely easy to gain lots of exposure to various important concepts so that you can try implementing it in your games instead of being caught up in dense theory that will take ages before you see it appear in your game.</p>
<h4 style="text-align: left;">Content Quality &#8211; 9 / 10</h4>
<p style="text-align: left;">This is a book that delivers on exactly what the title says. Opening theory made easy. As if that wasn&#8217;t enough to get you excited, they have twenty one-line principles to simplify it even further. Every concept is explained within 5-10 pages including diagrams! This might seem short to some, but the key is gaining a solid grasp of the principles so that they appear in your play. The details regarding opening theory will be dealt with when you get to it.</p>
<h4 style="text-align: left;">Conclusion</h4>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Opening Theory Made Easy</span> is what <span style="text-decoration: underline;">In the Beginning</span> should have been. When a new player buys a book that says &#8220;in the beginning&#8221; and is the first volume in an &#8220;elementary&#8221; go series, you&#8217;d think that it would be simple to follow. For those who haven&#8217;t invested in this series, steer clear for now. If you&#8217;ve already purchased it, don&#8217;t worry about it. That book will be a nice book to study after you understand this one.<br />
This will definitely be a classic that I will re-read over and over again. Bravo Otake Hideo. This one will definitely go in the hall of fame in my library of Go books.<br />
In summary though, if you are even remotely interested in the opening theory of the game, this is THE book to buy. It&#8217;s portability and ease of reading will have you blowing through it in no time and learning a lot of crucial principles that will be critical to your growth in the game. Don&#8217;t delay! Buy it now!!!</p>
<h3 style="text-align: left;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Table of Contents</span></h3>
<ol>
<li>Chapter One &#8211; Fuseki Fundamentals
<ol>
<li>Corner enclosures aim at side extensions</li>
<li>Be flexible in deploying from the star-point</li>
<li>Find the right pincer</li>
<li>Have a counterplan to deal with invasions</li>
<li>The 5-4 stone aims at outside influence</li>
<li>The 4th line is the line of development, the 3rd line is the line of completion</li>
<li>Build box-like moyos</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>Chapter Two &#8211; Good Shape
<ol>
<li>Family feuds waste resources</li>
<li>Don&#8217;t permit a hane at the head of your stones</li>
<li>You can never catch up if you push from behind</li>
<li>The empty triangle is bad shape</li>
<li>The ponnuki is worth 30 points</li>
<li>Don&#8217;t atari automatically | Beginners Play Atari</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>Chapter Three &#8211; Strategy
<ol>
<li>Attack the opponent by stealing his base</li>
<li>Don&#8217;t attach against weak stones</li>
<li>Try to kill two birds with one stone</li>
<li>Use thickness to attack</li>
<li>Keep away from solid positions</li>
<li>Reduce a large moyo lightly</li>
<li>Don&#8217;t cling to stones that have served their purpose</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ol>
<h3 style="text-align: left;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Recommended Vendors</span></h3>
<ol>
<li>GoGameGuru &#8211; <a title="GoGameGuru Purchase Link for Opening Theory Made Easy" href="http://shop.gogameguru.com/opening-theory-made-easy/?acc=e4da3b7fbbce2345d7772b0674a318d5">$17.99</a> (S&amp;H not included)</li>
<li>Kiseido &#8211; <a title="Kiseido Purchase Link" href="http://www.kiseido.com/go_books.htm">$18.00</a> (S&amp;H not included)</li>
</ol>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>Last updated October 6th, 2010 &#8211; 15 kyu</em></strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">81</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
