<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>endgame &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/endgame/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>Book Review: Basic Techniques of Go</title>
		<link>/book-review-basic-techniques-go/</link>
		<comments>/book-review-basic-techniques-go/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2013 23:35:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[endgame]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[handicap go]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[opening]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tesuji]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=4253</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Basic Techniques of Go Description: This book can be considered a broad coverage of the following: opening principles, lots of handicap go advice, brief survey of tesujis, and a brief survey of endgame. The material is quite dense and contrary to what many descriptions say about this book, I vehemently disagree with the recommending this [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/10/basictechniquesofgocover.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-4254" alt="basictechniquesofgocover" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/10/basictechniquesofgocover.jpg?resize=288%2C407" width="288" height="407" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">Basic Techniques of Go</h2>
<p><strong>Description:</strong> This book can be considered a broad coverage of the following: opening principles, lots of handicap go advice, brief survey of tesujis, and a brief survey of endgame. The material is quite dense and contrary to what many descriptions say about this book, I vehemently disagree with the recommending this book for beginners. It is suited for intermediate to advanced players. Beginners steer clear of this book!<br />
<span id="more-4253"></span><br />
[expand title=&#8221;Book Details&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
[table]
Title, Basic Techniques of Go<br />
Author, Haruyama Isamu 9P and Nagahara Yoshiaki 6P<br />
Edited by, Richard Bozulich<br />
Publisher, Kiseido<br />
Published, &#8220;First Printing, Feb. 1969 | Tenth Printing, Nov. 2002&#8243;<br />
Language, English<br />
ISBN, 4-906574-02-5<br />
Length, 172 Pages<br />
[/table]
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Table of Content&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Preface to the Third Edition</li>
<li>Technial Terms</li>
<li>Chapter One
<ul>
<li>Principles of Even-Game Openings
<ul>
<li>Opening Moves</li>
<li>Corner Enclosures</li>
<li>Approach Moves</li>
<li>Proper Timing of Enclosures, Approach Moves, and Extensions</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>How to Play Handicap Go</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Chapter Two
<ul>
<li>The Nine-Stone Handicap and the Attach-and-Extend Joseki</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Chapter Three
<ul>
<li>Six Stone Handicap Opening Strategy
<ul>
<li>White&#8217;s Capping Strategy</li>
<li>Invading the Sides</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Chapter Four
<ul>
<li>Four-Stone Handicap and the One-Space Jump Joseki</li>
<li>The One-Space Jump in Four-Stone Handicap Openings
<ul>
<li>The Pincer</li>
<li>Double Approach Moves</li>
<li>Double Pincer</li>
<li>The Attachment</li>
<li>Capping</li>
<li>The Invasion</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Chapter Five
<ul>
<li>A Survey of Tesuji
<ul>
<li>Tesuji Problems</li>
<li>Answer to the Tesuji Problems</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Chapter Six
<ul>
<li>The Endgame
<ul>
<li>Counting the Size of a Territory</li>
<li>Sente Endgame</li>
<li>Coutning the Size of an Endgame Play</li>
<li>Endgame Tesujis</li>
<li>Endgame Problems</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Appendix</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Before I Read This Book&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
I bought this book way back when I started go. I felt like I was completely lost when I first tried to read it, so here I am a couple years later trying to read it once more. What I was expecting when I bought it was a book on a broad coverage of techniques one would find with go. Now that I am much stronger and more experienced, I am still hoping for a survey of techniques along with clarification on their usage.<br />
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;My Review&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221; expanded=&#8221;true&#8221;]
When I first opened this book, I was a little surprised to be greeted by a chapter on opening theory. After all, this is a book on technique is it not? I recognize that selecting the correct opening move is a &#8220;technique&#8221; in a sense, but in my mind I was thinking more along the lines of haengma (i.e., the movement of the stones) or something else.<br />
With that aside though, the first chapter does cover quite a bit regarding the opening. While this is good in one sense, I still found it to be a bit dense and cannot imagine any beginner trying to work through this and achieve much success.<br />
And the next thing I know, the book is going full blown into handicap go coverage. All I could think when I kept reading was, &#8220;EH?!&#8221; I understand that these handicap go principles and techniques being described might seem &#8220;basic,&#8221; but even as a single digit kyu, even I was raising my eyebrows as I was trying to figure out what was going on. The diagrams were often rather complicated and required multiple readings just to get a sense of what was going on. After you work through a rather substantial amount of handicap go material, you finally get to the tesuji section.<br />
Here, I finally got a sense of what I was hoping for. A broad survey of different techniques used in different situations. With each tesuji, there is a brief explanation along with an example and an obvious variation or two that players might question. So while some of the material in here was a bit advanced and hard to grasp based on simple reading, this felt more like the book I was looking for when purchasing this book. And for those wondering about the problems, they are overall intermediate level and not very beginner friendly.<br />
For the last chapter, the reader is introduced to the importance of endgame. And while I would consider myself to at least be moderately versed when it comes to endgame, this was a rather tough section for me to work through. I can only imagine what it would be like for someone who had little to no exposure on endgame. Definitely not an easy chapter at all.<br />
Overall, I would divide the book into the following categories: 10% Opening Principles, 40% Handicap Go, 30% Tesuji, and 20% Endgame. And as such, I find that it is not quite aptly named as &#8220;Basic Techniques of Go&#8221; since there was far more handicap go than I think is appropriate for beginners. And not to mention, what about life and death? That deserves attention in here as well if it is going to be titled &#8220;Basic Techniques of Go.&#8221;<br />
In regards to its overall difficulty, it really does feel as if the reader needs to already have a decent grasp of the material in order to truly understand and digest the contents of this book. To be clear though, I am by no means saying that the content in this book is bad. Quite the contrary in fact, there is a lot of information considering how short the book is. It&#8217;s just that its rather dense for beginner/intermediate players.<br />
So if you fall into the category of beginner/intermediate players looking to get stronger, I do not recommend this book for you. Instead, I recommend checking out the Mastering the Basics series from Kiseido as a better alternative.<br />
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Synopsis&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<strong>What did I enjoy about the book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>There is a lot of information on handicap go.</li>
<li>They did do a pretty nice job surveying some common tesuji.</li>
<li>There were problems to accompany the tesuji and endgame section.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What did I gain from reading this book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Due to the dense material, I can&#8217;t say I really gained anything from this first reading.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What aspect(s) can be improved on?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>In all honesty, I don&#8217;t feel that it would be very fair for me to criticize the book at the moment since I feel that its content is generally out of reach for me. The one thing I will say is that the title is a little misleading to the unsuspecting player. Otherwise, I will save my comments for when I am able to better comprehend the book.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Is this book easy to read?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>As a mid to high single digit kyu, I felt that it was rather difficult to read due to the level of discussion that occurred in the book. However, if one could easily follow the level of content in this book, the English is rather straightforward and should be pretty easy to work through.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Bottom Line</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>Content is essentially 10% opening principles, 40% handicap go, 30% tesuji, and 20% endgame.</li>
<li>Better suited to players already familiar with the content in the book. In other words, NOT for beginners.</li>
<li>If you&#8217;re a beginner/intermediate player looking to get stronger, check out the Mastering Basics series instead.</li>
</ol>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Recommended For&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Intermediate/advanced players looking for additional material to study.</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Where Can I Buy It?&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Kiseido &#8211; <a href="http://kiseido.com/go_books.htm">$18</a> (shipping and handling not included)</li>
<li>SmartGo Books &#8211; <a href="http://gobooks.com/">$8.99</a> (iOS Devices Only)</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
<p style="text-align: center;"><em><strong>Last Updated on November 3rd, 2013</strong></em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/book-review-basic-techniques-go/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">4253</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Importance of Endgame</title>
		<link>/the-importance-of-endgame/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2012 14:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kifu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[6k]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[black]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[defeat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[endgame]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[even game]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=1188</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[So for those who don&#8217;t play on KGS, I actually managed to climb back up to 6k and hang on to it (*knock on wood*). As it is everyday, I had an urge to play a ranked game and decided to play against an opponent who is actually more along the lines of 5k but [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>So for those who don&#8217;t play on KGS, I actually managed to climb back up to 6k and hang on to it (*knock on wood*). As it is everyday, I had an urge to play a ranked game and decided to play against an opponent who is actually more along the lines of 5k but recently got downgraded to 6k. Although I was resistant to playing him at first, I decided to plunge ahead since I planned on beating stronger opponents anyways.<br />
Let me just say this for the record: <strong>I never quite understood the importance of endgame until this game</strong>.<br />
I mean, sure, everyone &#8220;knows&#8221; that the endgame is important. As I look at the people around me however, I realized that <strong>most kyu players tend to disregard this aspect of go since most of their games are contingent upon big battles which often result in early resignations</strong>. With that in mind, how could you blame them for not paying more attention to endgame?<br />
As I&#8217;m approaching the mid-SDK range, the games that I have played have begun to take on a new form from the big battles I used to fight. While this makes me a bit nervous, this is part of the journey to becoming the strongest player I can possibly be.<br />
The following game is one that I think many of you would find quite interesting since it consists of a rather complicated capturing race and is a great example of why a player&#8217;s endgame skill can be the difference between victory or defeat.<br />

<div id='glift_display1' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display1","sgf":"http:\/\/bengozen.com\/\/wp-content\/uploads\/2012\/11\/2012.11.30-The-Importance-of-Endgame.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='//wp-content/uploads/2012/11/2012.11.30-The-Importance-of-Endgame.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">[download label=&#8221;Download Kifu&#8221;]//wp-content/uploads/2012/11/2012.11.30-The-Importance-of-Endgame.sgf[/download]
<p>While he ended up resigning due to the capturing race, in reality this game goes down as a defeat in my book. Had I been more careful about my endgame, I&#8217;m quite sure that I would have earned that victory fair and square; but it is clear that my reckless endgame actually cost me the game. This game has really humbled my opinion of my abilities and reminded me how critical it is to:</p>
<ol>
<li>Practice estimating the score so that I do not have a distorted view of the game.</li>
<li>Be more meticulous about my endgame moves since I only get a few opportunities to really practice it.</li>
<li>Continue to practice my reading abilities so that I do not get caught in liberty shortages due to misreading.</li>
</ol>
<p>Here&#8217;s to hoping I have learned my lesson.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1188</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
