<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>losing &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/losing/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>Friday Go Forward: Week 62</title>
		<link>/friday-go-forward-week-62/</link>
		<comments>/friday-go-forward-week-62/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2014 11:15:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Progress Reports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dojang]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[experimenting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[level up]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[losing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[territorial style]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yunguseng]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5250</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Overview This week has been a continuation of trying to get used to the new training regimen that I started last week. Believe it or not, I have been rather successful at playing more instead of solely focusing on studying. So in that regard, things are a success. On the other hand, I lost again [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 style="text-align: left;">Overview</h2>
<p>This week has been a continuation of trying to get used to the new training regimen that I started last week. Believe it or not, I have been rather successful at playing more instead of solely focusing on studying. So in that regard, things are a success.<br />
On the other hand, I lost again in my match this week for <a title="Yunguseng Dojang Official Website" href="http://www.yunguseng.com/">Yunguseng Dojang</a>. After some thought and introspection, I have come to the conclusion that my go has become very impatient lately. I try to complicate the game with every move while also experimenting with a territorial style that just ends up not working out for me. Sigh.<br />
Ah well. It has been fun experimenting with the territorial style. And who knows? Maybe this little detour of mine will help to patch up some of my weaknesses from my normal style. Guess we&#8217;ll have to see!</p>
<h2>Training Regimen</h2>
<ul>
<li>Spend about 50% of your time playing games.</li>
<li>Spend 10 minutes/day perusing a new book of go.</li>
<li>Spend 20 minutes/day diligently working on the Level Up series.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Games</h2>
<ul>
<li><a title="TygemGo Official Site" href="http://www.tygemgo.com/">Tygem</a> &#8211; 6 games</li>
<li><a title="IGS PandaNet Official Site" href="http://www.pandanet-igs.com/">IGS</a> &#8211; 2 games</li>
<li><a title="KGS Website" href="http://www.gokgs.com/">KGS</a> &#8211;  3 games</li>
<li><a title="Dragon Go Server - BenGoZen's Profile" href="http://www.dragongoserver.net/userinfo.php?uid=60385">DGS</a> &#8211; 5 ongoing games</li>
<li><a title="Online Go Server - BenGoZen's Profile" href="http://online-go.com/user/view/549/BenGoZen">OGS</a> &#8211; 3 ongoing games</li>
</ul>
<h2>Books</h2>
<ul>
<li><a title="Book Review: Level Up Review 1" href="//book-review-level-up-review-1/">Level Up Review 1</a></li>
<li><a title="Book Review: Level Up Review 2" href="//book-review-level-up-review-2/">Level Up Review 2</a></li>
<li>The Theory and Practice of Semeai</li>
</ul>
<h2>Lessons Learned</h2>
<ul>
<li>Patience is an important value when playing go.</li>
<li>When you have an overwhelming advantage, (1) don&#8217;t become overconfident and (2) don&#8217;t give your opponent a chance to turn it around.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/friday-go-forward-week-62/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">5250</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Getting Pulverized by Tygem Dans</title>
		<link>/getting-pulverized-tygem-dans/</link>
		<comments>/getting-pulverized-tygem-dans/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2014 01:53:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[korean players]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[losing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tygem]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5242</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I mentioned recently that I wanted to turn my attention Tygem because of how different the players are there. I tried explaining it to a friend a night or two ago but couldn&#8217;t find the right game to really illustrate it. Well, after talking with frozensoul today, I thought I&#8217;d fire up one of my [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I mentioned recently that I wanted to turn my attention Tygem because of how different the players are there. I tried explaining it to a friend a night or two ago but couldn&#8217;t find the right game to really illustrate it.<br />
Well, after talking with frozensoul today, I thought I&#8217;d fire up one of my old dan level accounts on Tygem and take a stab at playing on it again.<br />
Oy vey&#8230; the epitome of aggressiveness occurred tonight. Invade&#8230; fight&#8230;. invade&#8230; attach&#8230; die&#8230;. invade&#8230; fight&#8230; ahhhh&#8230;&#8230;<br />
I think I&#8217;ve lost like 5+ games in a row now. While I feel like I&#8217;m on a bit of an emotional tilt from getting pulverized game after game, I think it&#8217;s good medicine to offset my victory at the <a title="1st Washington Open Baduk Championship — Part II" href="//1st-washington-open-baduk-championship-part-ii/">Washington Baduk Open Championship</a>.<br />
Perhaps it&#8217;s the fact that I haven&#8217;t played much, or maybe it&#8217;s just that I&#8217;m really weak against Korean players. In fact, as I think back to the games I lost, I think the bottom line is that they were able to outfight me and play much sharper moves each time (which ended up killing me constantly). I tried to swing by with all my might, but it was like I was poking them with a sewing needle and then came down on me with a two handed axe.<br />
Ah well. They say to lose your first 100 games when you start playing right? Looks like I&#8217;ll be starting that exercise up again as I dive back into the war zone. *deep breath* See you on the other side.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/getting-pulverized-tygem-dans/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">5242</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>New Go Equipment and My Losing Streak</title>
		<link>/new-go-equipment-losing-streak/</link>
		<comments>/new-go-equipment-losing-streak/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2013 03:43:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[confronting my weakness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[en]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[equipment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gogameguru]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[losing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=4288</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[My GoGameGuru order came in!!! Woot woot!!! You can see everything I got in the picture (except the glass stones which are inside the bowls). There is so much to write about and review. Haha. However, since I do need a little bit of time to put the reviews together, the one thing I want [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/11/gogamegurustuff.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-4290" alt="gogamegurustuff" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/11/gogamegurustuff.jpg?resize=461%2C346" width="461" height="346" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></p>
<p>My <a href="http://shop.gogameguru.com/">GoGameGuru</a> order came in!!! Woot woot!!! You can see everything I got in the picture (except the glass stones which are inside the bowls). There is so much to write about and review. Haha. However, since I do need a little bit of time to put the reviews together, the one thing I want to recommend right away is the <a href="http://shop.gogameguru.com/folding-go-board/?acc=e4da3b7fbbce2345d7772b0674a318d5">Foldable Go Board</a>. The quality is incredible for the price and it&#8217;s definitely my favorite item of my entire order. So if you&#8217;re in the market for a foldable go board, don&#8217;t wait!<br />
On a more journalistic note, I&#8217;ve been on a losing streak lately. Interestingly enough however, I&#8217;m actually okay with it. The training to try and maintain zen in high pressure situations or even after losing has been tough; but I think it&#8217;s been doing me some good. In fact, I was even able to resign a game that I was winning (against a 5 kyu) since I had more pressing matters to attend to. And if you&#8217;re wondering why I think it&#8217;s an accomplishment, it&#8217;s because I never would have been able to do that in the past. I would have saw the game as rightfully mine to win and probably have been unable to walk away from it.<br />
As one might expect, my rank has been dropping left and right; but surprisingly enough, I&#8217;m actually okay with it. I&#8217;m not worried about whether or not the server thinks I&#8217;m stronger or not. I am taking on my weaknesses head on. It might make me lose a stone or two for now, but I think the benefit I will gain from this approach will be worth it. =)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/new-go-equipment-losing-streak/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">4288</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Perfectly Defeated&#8230;</title>
		<link>/perfectly-defeated/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2012 22:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[losing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[on tilt]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=1129</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[So over the past week, my rank on KGS actually went up to 6k and I managed to defend it properly against a 5k. Good news right? I&#8217;m back at 7k now. (-.-) How does that happen you might wonder? Losing four straight games in a row. That&#8217;s how. Haha. You know those times where [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>So over the past week, my rank on KGS actually went up to 6k and I managed to defend it properly against a 5k. Good news right? I&#8217;m back at 7k now. (-.-) How does that happen you might wonder? Losing four straight games in a row. That&#8217;s how. Haha.<br />
You know those times where no matter what you do (whether it&#8217;s fate or you just sabotaging yourself), you keep on losing? That&#8217;s me right now. Haha. I&#8217;ve gone through four straight losses and it&#8217;s been pretty pitiful.<br />
I lost my first match to in a relatively normal way. Not on tilt quite yet, and then I decide to challenge him to a rematch. And then I get excited when I think that his group is killable, and end up losing my entire corner early on in the game. There goes my second loss.<br />
From that point on though, it was like I was on a pure vengeful pursuit to win against him. I played him once again, and decisively won a number of key battles, and then I lose on time.<br />
As if that weren&#8217;t bad enough, I then go off and challenge another 6k. This match is going great, because he&#8217;s in a killing mood too but I&#8217;m managing to outread him for most of the game&#8230; and then I failed to realize one of my sequences put a big group in atari and then everything died&#8230;<br />
<a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2012/11/losingmeme.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-1131" title="Y u keep losing" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2012/11/losingmeme-300x225.jpg?resize=300%2C225" alt="why you keep losing meme" width="300" height="225" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>ARGHHHHHHHHHH!!!!!</strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1129</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
