<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>no cutting corners &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/no-cutting-corners/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>No More Cutting Corners</title>
		<link>/cutting-corners/</link>
		<comments>/cutting-corners/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2014 00:43:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[basics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dojang]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[level up]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[no cutting corners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[studying]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yunguseng]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5283</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Up till now, my go studies have been pretty sporadic. I may have read my fair share of books and watched my fair share of videos, but I would have to say that I really never spent the time and energy really absorbing them. Sure, I was exposed to lots of new concepts and ideas; [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Up till now, my go studies have been pretty sporadic. I may have read my fair share of books and watched my fair share of videos, but I would have to say that I really never spent the time and energy really absorbing them. Sure, I was exposed to lots of new concepts and ideas; but implementing them in my games was a whole different animal.<br />
After reading a <a title="What Was Nonsense Becomes Possible - Noseki" href="http://noseki.com/2014/05/08/what-was-nonsense-becomes-possible/">post</a> from fellow go blogger Noseki, I was inspired to take a new approach with my go studies by fully immersing myself in it. For example, in my game for <a title="Yunguseng Dojang" href="http://www.yunguseng.com/">Yunguseng Dojang</a>, I replayed every move on the real board and really took my time to absorb each and every move (which is the reason I ended up losing on time since I completely did not pay attention to my computer which was telling me I was running out of time).<br />
In addition, I&#8217;ve also revamped my primary study materials for books. I&#8217;m going back to the Level Up Series (starting with <a title="Book Review: Level Up Review 1" href="//book-review-level-up-review-1/">Level Up! Review 1</a> since I don&#8217;t have time to start all the way back at <a title="Book Review: Level Up 1" href="//book-review-level-up-1/">Level Up 1</a>) and working my way through it with extreme thoroughness. In other words, no solution whatsoever. I will work through every problem and solve it with absolute certainty before moving on.<br />
If I have any hope of becoming any stronger, I think that it&#8217;s finally time that I stopped cutting corners. The time for me to be knocking at the door of the dans is fast approaching, and I have no intention of letting myself be caught unawares when that time comes.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/cutting-corners/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">5283</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
