<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>blog &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/blog/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>Taking a Second Look at the Blog</title>
		<link>/taking-second-look-blog/</link>
		<comments>/taking-second-look-blog/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2014 21:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[content]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[revising]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[strategy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[update]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5462</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Lately I&#8217;ve been reconsidering what direction the blog has been heading in. Although it&#8217;s been great starting a new series and having content flow consistently, lately the blog has felt more like a newspaper or e-magazine of sorts instead of a personal journal. For example, the game reviews that are being published are now usually like [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lately I&#8217;ve been reconsidering what direction the blog has been heading in. Although it&#8217;s been great starting a new series and having content flow consistently, lately the blog has felt more like a newspaper or e-magazine of sorts instead of a personal journal. For example, the game reviews that are being published are now usually like a month behind where I am now, which can be confusing for you as a reader and also throws my blog into a weird clashing timeline.<br />
As a result, I&#8217;ve been thinking a lot about what I can do to fix that, and I&#8217;ve come up with the following items in order to better optimize my time and produce content that better fits my vision for the blog:<br />
Starting next week&#8230;</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Thursday Go Tygem will now be discontinued</strong> in order to pave way for #2 and #3.</li>
<li><strong>Monday Go Meditation is going to undergo a reboot</strong> with an updated format that takes some elements of Thursday Go Tygem and should improve the overall quality and value of the weekly column. In addition, I will be clearing out the queue in Monday Go Meditation in order to make way for current games and realign the blog with the games I&#8217;m currently playing as opposed to games I played weeks or even months ago.</li>
<li><strong>There will be a new post every weekday (i.e. Mon-Fri)</strong>. This might seem extreme and be a point of concern for some, but I&#8217;ve reached a new level of comfort with my blogging that should make this very viable. I&#8217;m hoping that this should help the blog start to return to its origins of being a chronicle of my journey (in real-time).</li>
</ol>
<p>In addition, you&#8217;ll start noticing little changes around the blog like new tagging or categories appear as I restructure the content in order to make it more user friendly, but those shouldn&#8217;t impact your reading experience on the blog much.<br />
Starting in July&#8230;</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>I&#8217;m going to update the format and change the schedule of Friday Go Forward </strong>&#8211; Although some don&#8217;t realize it, Friday Go Forward currently captures my progress from the last Friday afternoon/evening to the next Thursday evening since it gets published every Friday morning. In order to better capture my weekly progress, I will be changing it to Saturday so it fully captures that week. In addition, everyone&#8217;s feedback  was really helpful on figuring out next steps, so be on the lookout in the future for an improved format!</li>
</ol>
<p>Whew. Been meaning to unload that from my brain for some time. I&#8217;m hoping that you&#8217;ll like these new changes; but as always, please be sure to leave feedback in case I&#8217;m missing something or you see something I can do to improve what you&#8217;re seeing here on the blog. See you around!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/taking-second-look-blog/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">5462</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
