<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>weiqi &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/weiqi/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>Hong Kong Trip: Part 3 &#8211; Weiqi</title>
		<link>/hong-kong-trip-part-3/</link>
		<comments>/hong-kong-trip-part-3/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2014 15:50:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Cultural]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[go]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hong kong]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hong kong go association]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shiu lao shi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[souvenir]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trip]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weiqi]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=4956</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Part 1 — The Scenery   &#124;&#124;   Part 2 — The Food   &#124;&#124;   Part 3 — Weiqi Introduction After much waiting and anticipation, I&#8217;m happy to release the final post on my Hong Kong trip. Since we always save the best for last, it should come as no surprise to you that you had to wait till [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><a title="Hong Kong Trip: Part 1 — The Scenery" href="//hong-kong-trip-part-1/">Part 1 — The Scenery</a>   ||   <a title="Hong Kong Trip: Part 2 — The Food" href="//hong-kong-trip-part-2/">Part 2 — The Food</a>   ||   <em>Part 3 — Weiqi</em></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">Introduction</h2>
<p>After much waiting and anticipation, I&#8217;m happy to release the final post on my Hong Kong trip. Since we always save the best for last, it should come as no surprise to you that you had to wait till the very end to hear about my go adventures! Before we go on however, I just wanted to clarify a couple of things. (1) The title of this post was originally &#8220;Go,&#8221; but due to the fact that I was in Hong Kong, I felt it was only appropriate to title it &#8220;Weiqi.&#8221; (2) However, in order to ease the readability of my post, I will be using &#8220;go&#8221; in the text instead of &#8220;weiqi&#8221; for simple consistency with English go literature. With that said, onwards with my go adventure in Hong Kong!</p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">Part 3 &#8211; Weiqi</h2>
<p>As I&#8217;m sure some of you remember, I posted on <a title="Reddit Hong Kong Post" href="http://www.reddit.com/r/baduk/comments/2059yl/go_players_clubs_in_hong_kong/">reddit</a> and <a title="Preparing for My Hong Kong Trip" href="//preparing-hong-kong-trip/">here</a> before the trip to see if anyone was in the area. Most of the feedback I got from people was that I should visit the <a title="Hong Kong Go Association Website" href="http://www.hkga.org.hk/">Hong Kong Go Association (HKGA)</a>. I was a little saddened by the fact that I was unable to find anyone who lived locally online, but I knew that I couldn&#8217;t bear the idea of going all the way to Asia and not do a single go-related activity. So I promised myself that if I were to do anything for myself this trip, it would be to visit the HKGA.<br />
When we first arrived in Hong Kong, one of the things we did was to go to one of the shopping districts. And believe it or not, as I&#8217;m walking down the street, I see this across the street.<br />
<figure id="attachment_5043" style="width: 640px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-01.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-5043" alt="2014HKP3-01" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-01-1024x768.jpg?resize=640%2C480" width="640" height="480" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Wait&#8230; why does that cartoon character look like he&#8217;s doing something I&#8217;m terribly familiar with&#8230;</figcaption></figure>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span id="more-4956"></span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;">*blink*</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">*double blink*</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">*rubs eyes*</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">*squints at the bus ad*</p>
<figure id="attachment_5044" style="width: 640px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-02.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-5044" alt="2014HKP3-02" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-02-1024x768.jpg?resize=640%2C480" width="640" height="480" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Oh&#8230;. my&#8230;.. Sai!!!!!!</figcaption></figure>
Yep. It was an ad for go on a bus. No it wasn&#8217;t some special bus for the HKGA. It was just your normal run of the mill bus with an ad for HKGA. You have no idea how excited I was to see it at the time. Haha. I probably even looked a little crazy to the people around as I&#8217;m pointing excitedly and trying to tell my family to look at the epicness painted on the bus.<br />
Now if anyone has visited the HKGA website, you&#8217;ll notice that it&#8217;s entirely in Chinese without any English version. And while I may be able to read and write Mandarin, trying to read a web page full of Chinese is a huge struggle for me since my Chinese is still rather basic.<br />
One of the things I noticed on the site was that there were classes being held at night throughout the week. They would cost money, but that didn&#8217;t bother me since it would be a brand new experience for me. So I had my mom call them (because I can&#8217;t speak Cantonese), and we find out that the classes were not actually running at the time.<br />
When my mom told me that, I then asked if they had a time where local players would come and play. As you might imagine, I was envisioning the HKGA to be something like the Nihon Ki-in in Japan where there&#8217;s a go salon in the building with a bunch of people playing throughout the day. To my surprise and disappointment, the secretary told my mom that they didn&#8217;t have anything like that.<br />
I was pretty bummed to hear that. After all, would my epic go adventure in Hong Kong be reduced to simply visiting the HKGA and maybe taking a few pictures? All hope was nearly gone until the secretary told my mom that I could take private lessons if I wanted to.<br />
After some back and forth, I found out that my teacher would be an amateur who was around 6-7 dan. He could speak Mandarin and English as well, so language wouldn&#8217;t be an issue. The only obstacle in my way was that it would be about $100USD for a lesson.<br />
I wrestled with the decision for a while. After all, $100USD is not cheap by any stretch of the imagination. However, for those who don&#8217;t know me, I&#8217;m more of the seize life by the moment kind of person. Since I had no idea when I would go back to Hong Kong, I ultimately decided to schedule a lesson for the next day in the morning at 10:00AM.<br />
The next day, I woke up excited to embark on my go adventure. My mom asked if I knew where I was going, and I told her that I had the address (252 Hennessy Road; Wan Chai; Hong Kong) already. I had confirmed it via Google maps and also a redditor had also told me the same address. Just to be safe though, my family was kind enough to be willing to go with me (in case I needed help getting around), so off we went.<br />
<figure id="attachment_5045" style="width: 640px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-03.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-5045" alt="2014HKP3-03" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-03-1024x682.jpg?resize=640%2C426" width="640" height="426" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">In Hong Kong, this is the symbol for the metro / subway line. If you see this, there is one very close by.</figcaption></figure>
After grabbing breakfast, we found ourselves the nearest metro line and headed off towards 252 Hennessy Road; Wan Chai; Hong Kong.<br />
<figure id="attachment_5046" style="width: 640px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-04.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-5046" alt="2014HKP3-04" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-04-1024x768.jpg?resize=640%2C480" width="640" height="480" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">The metro system is also way better than DC. Look. They have a map with electronic LED&#8217;s to show you where you are and what stop is next. Brilliant!</figcaption></figure>
Because I didn&#8217;t want to be late, we arrived with plenty of time to spare (around 9:30AM).<br />
<figure id="attachment_5047" style="width: 640px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-05.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-5047" alt="2014HKP3-05" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-05-1024x768.jpg?resize=640%2C480" width="640" height="480" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Woohoo! Here we are! The Hong Kong Go Association at 252 Hennessy Road; Wan Chai; Hong Kong.</figcaption></figure>
After finding the location, I turned around to look for the doorway and was instead greeted by a kind of creepy looking entrance.<br />
<figure id="attachment_5048" style="width: 384px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-06.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-5048 " alt="2014HKP3-06" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-06-768x1024.jpg?resize=384%2C512" width="384" height="512" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Tell me I&#8217;m not the only one who thought this looked like a scene out of a horror movie like Saw or something&#8230;</figcaption></figure>
After buzzing and waiting around for 15-20 minutes, I got a little nervous as I was wondering whether or not the teacher had bailed on me. I had tried to sneak into the metal door earlier to go in and see if anyone was around, but I got chased out by some elderly Asian gentlemen (who seemed to be the security guard). He told me that no one was upstairs and that no one was planning on being there. Uh oh&#8230;<br />
Around 9:55AM, we get a call from the secretary my mom spoke to last night. She asked if we were still coming. &#8220;Still coming?&#8221; my mom said, &#8220;We&#8217;re waiting outside!&#8221; After about ten seconds had passed, a feeling of dread washed over me&#8230; Sure enough, my mom turns to be and says, &#8220;We&#8217;re in the wrong location! This is not the correct place! They are actually located around the place we were eating breakfast!&#8221;<br />
<figure id="attachment_5074" style="width: 330px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/nooooooo_luke_skywalker.gif"><img class="size-full wp-image-5074" alt="Noooooo!!!!!!" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/nooooooo_luke_skywalker.gif?resize=330%2C186" width="330" height="186" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Noooooo!!!!!!</figcaption></figure>
<p style="text-align: left;">Needless to say I was utterly blown and felt terrible since someone had come to teach me and I was about 20-30 minutes away from where they were. Luckily however, the teacher was not in a rush to leave and was willing to wait for me to go to the correct location.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">At this point, I had dragged my family on a 30 minute journey to a new part of the city. I could not bear the notion of dragging them 30 minutes back just so I could go to the HKGA. So  so I told them to go ahead and stay and explore the new part of the city. And with that, I ran off to find the place myself.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">So if you&#8217;re wondering at this point, this is the correct address: <strong>12/F, May May Building, No. 683-685 Nathan Road, Mongkok</strong>.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">After navigating my way back to Mongkok, I started looking for the sign that would signal me that I had found the building.</p>
<figure id="attachment_5049" style="width: 640px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-07.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-5049" alt="2014HKP3-07" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-07-1024x768.jpg?resize=640%2C480" width="640" height="480" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">This is it! In case you ever are visiting, this is the sign you should look for!</figcaption></figure>
<figure id="attachment_5050" style="width: 384px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-08.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-5050" alt="2014HKP3-08" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-08-768x1024.jpg?resize=384%2C512" width="384" height="512" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Here&#8217;s a shot of the entrance to let you know you&#8217;ve found the building. Much better than the other location right? Seems much more trustworthy.</figcaption></figure>
I was a bit out of breath by this point, but I was sure glad I had found the building within a reasonable time. And before I knew it I was riding the elevator up to the 12th floor.<br />
When the door opened, I was immediately greeted by a display case full of go memorabilia along with trophies and awards.<br />
<figure id="attachment_5051" style="width: 640px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-09.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-5051" alt="2014HKP3-09" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-09-1024x768.jpg?resize=640%2C480" width="640" height="480" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Stamps, signed fans, bowls, trophies etc. It was quite a sight!</figcaption></figure>
And after greeting the secretary at the front and exchanging the customary greeting and welcome, I turned left to see an incredible sight of go boards and bowls galore!<br />
<figure id="attachment_5052" style="width: 640px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-11.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-5052" alt="2014HKP3-11" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-11-1024x768.jpg?resize=640%2C480" width="640" height="480" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Isn&#8217;t this a magnificent sight? The only thing that would make it better would be people playing as well!</figcaption></figure>
Up on the left in the same room, there was a cork board where all the members had these mini tags with their names on it and hung by their respective rank.<br />
<figure id="attachment_5053" style="width: 640px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-12.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-5053" alt="2014HKP3-12" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-12-1024x768.jpg?resize=640%2C480" width="640" height="480" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Look at all those players! Each little tag is a person! If only I could have met and played one of them!</figcaption></figure>
In terms of my lesson that day, it turned out that I would be learning from the President of the Hong Kong Go Association himself! (I will refer to him as Shiu Lao Shi from this point on.)<br />
<figure id="attachment_5054" style="width: 640px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-13.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-5054" alt="2014HKP3-13" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-13-1024x768.jpg?resize=640%2C480" width="640" height="480" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">As you can see, my stuff is setup on the right table. This was where we had our lesson.</figcaption></figure>
For the first part of our lesson, we went over concepts regarding opening theory (i.e, fuseki). While this is a topic I have studied a bit overall (compared to other aspects of go), I was of course humbled by how Shiu Lao Shi was able to remind me of some fundamental principles when it came to fuseki.<br />
One of the key ideas I was taught was how the opening was a lot about balance. If you can get an even result, then you have done a good job with the fuseki. Too often players try to get some massive advantage and then end up in a bad position. This is still something I&#8217;m working on, but it was a much needed reminder since I&#8217;m an aggressive and impatient player as a whole.<br />
After more fuseki study, we played a 5-stone handicap game. Due to time constraints, I was not able to record the game. However, although I never got to spend the time I would have liked to try to recreate the full game, here is a partial kifu that I tried to recreate that day.*<br />
*Note: There is no commentary on this kifu due to how short it is, but I thought that being able to see how the game started up would be better than nothing.<br />

<div id='glift_display1' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display1","sgf":"http:\/\/bengozen.com\/\/wp-content\/uploads\/2014\/04\/2014.03.18-HKGA-Lesson.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014.03.18-HKGA-Lesson.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">[download label=&#8221;Download Kifu&#8221;]//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014.03.18-HKGA-Lesson.sgf[/download]
<p style="text-align: left;">After the lesson, I got to explore a little bit more and found their magnificent book collection.</p>
<figure id="attachment_5055" style="width: 640px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-14.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-5055" alt="2014HKP3-14" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-14-1024x768.jpg?resize=640%2C480" width="640" height="480" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Isn&#8217;t this massive? All Chinese books though! If only we had this many English go books&#8230;.</figcaption></figure>
Before I came to the HKGA, I had also envisioned that there might be a store or a pile of books where I could purchase something for me to remember the place by. Unfortunately all their books were on a loan basis only (which I would obviously not be doing since I&#8217;d never return it haha), and there was no &#8220;gift shop.&#8221; However, though I didn&#8217;t know it at the time, I was very lucky in that Shiu Lao Shi had no intentions of letting me leave empty handed.<br />
After walking around the HKGA a bit more and chatting with Shiu Lao Shi, I went up to the front desk to pay for the lesson. Next thing I know, Shiu Lao Shi was asking the secretary to give me a souvenir bag. The following are shots of the very generous gift that he ended up giving me.<br />
<figure id="attachment_5056" style="width: 640px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-15.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-5056" alt="2014HKP3-15" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-15-668x1024.jpg?resize=640%2C981" width="640" height="981" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Hong Kong Go Association reusable bag (one side)</figcaption></figure>
<figure id="attachment_5057" style="width: 640px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-16.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-5057" alt="2014HKP3-16" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-16-668x1024.jpg?resize=640%2C981" width="640" height="981" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Hong Kong Go Association reusable bag (other side)</figcaption></figure>
<figure id="attachment_5058" style="width: 640px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-17.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-5058" alt="2014HKP3-17" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-17-1024x768.jpg?resize=640%2C480" width="640" height="480" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">A neat calendar card to put in your wallet (front)</figcaption></figure>
<figure id="attachment_5059" style="width: 640px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-18.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-5059" alt="2014HKP3-18" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-18-1024x768.jpg?resize=640%2C480" width="640" height="480" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Calendar card for your wallet (back)</figcaption></figure>
<figure id="attachment_5060" style="width: 640px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-19.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-5060" alt="2014HKP3-19" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-19-1024x779.jpg?resize=640%2C486" width="640" height="486" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">5 issues of a Chinese go magazine</figcaption></figure>
<figure id="attachment_5061" style="width: 640px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-20.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-5061" alt="2014HKP3-20" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-20-1024x555.jpg?resize=640%2C346" width="640" height="346" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">A portable magnetic go set for the plane! (front)</figcaption></figure>
<figure id="attachment_5062" style="width: 640px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-21.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-5062" alt="2014HKP3-21" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-21-1024x576.jpg?resize=640%2C360" width="640" height="360" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Portable magnetic go set for the plane (back)</figcaption></figure>
<figure id="attachment_5063" style="width: 640px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-22.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-5063" alt="2014HKP3-22" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-22-1024x768.jpg?resize=640%2C480" width="640" height="480" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Portable go set removed from the box.</figcaption></figure>
<figure id="attachment_5064" style="width: 640px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-23.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-5064" alt="2014HKP3-23" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-23-1024x768.jpg?resize=640%2C480" width="640" height="480" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Portable go set board and stones.</figcaption></figure>
<figure id="attachment_5065" style="width: 448px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-24.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-5065 " alt="2014HKP3-24" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-24-768x1024.jpg?resize=448%2C597" width="448" height="597" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Aerial overview of the board and stones in action. And in case you&#8217;re wondering, this is the best magnetic go set I&#8217;ve used to date (excluding the YMImports Roll-up Magnetic Board because that is different from this kind of magnetic set).</figcaption></figure>
<figure id="attachment_5066" style="width: 384px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-25.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-5066" alt="2014HKP3-25" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-25-682x1024.jpg?resize=384%2C576" width="384" height="576" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">A clear go folder with the HKGA cartoon mascot on front!</figcaption></figure>
<figure id="attachment_5067" style="width: 384px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-26.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-5067 " alt="2014HKP3-26" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-26-719x1024.jpg?resize=384%2C547" width="384" height="547" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">And a handout that Shiu Lao Shi created on the opening.</figcaption></figure>
As you can imagine, I was very grateful and thanked him numerous times for such a generous gift. After all, I had expected to leave the HKGA with nothing but a good story and what I could carry in my brain. So I was like a little kid on Christmas when he gave me all of these souvenirs for me to bring home with me.<br />
<figure id="attachment_5068" style="width: 384px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-27.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-5068" alt="2014HKP3-27" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-27-810x1024.jpg?resize=384%2C485" width="384" height="485" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Here&#8217;s a shot of me and Shiu Lao Shi by the front desk.</figcaption></figure>
When the time came to part ways, we exchanged contact information and said our good-byes. I was certainly sad to leave since I would have loved to have stayed all day, but time was ticking and I had to go meet my family afterwards.<br />
Overall, I was glad that I was able to visit the HKGA and have a chance to learn from Shiu Lao Shi. It was a great experience and I certainly hope that I&#8217;ll be able to go back one day and play with other locals in the area. Maybe I&#8217;ll attend a tournament or something&#8230; you never know what the future holds&#8230; =)</p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">Conclusion</h2>
<p>With all that said and done, I hope that you enjoyed my Hong Kong series and felt that you could get a glimpse into my adventures in Hong Kong. As always, any feedback you have for me would be greatly appreciated. And if you ever have any questions or plan to go to Hong Kong yourself, please let me know and I&#8217;d be happy to chat with you!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/hong-kong-trip-part-3/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>18</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">4956</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Getting Stronger at Go (Overview)</title>
		<link>/getting-stronger-at-go-overview/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2012 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Guides]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Weekly Go Wednesday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[baduk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[getting stronger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[go]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[one stone stronger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weiqi]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=23</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Weekly Go Wednesday, Issue #3 Of all the go topics in the entire universe, this is by far the single most popular one. After all, getting one stone strong is the eternal pursuit of every go player. There are a plethora of articles out there on how to do so, but my goal is to [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: center;">
<h2><em>Weekly Go Wednesday, Issue #3</em></h2>
<p style="text-align: left;">Of all the go topics in the entire universe, this is by far the single most popular one. After all, getting one stone strong is the eternal pursuit of every go player. There are a plethora of articles out there on how to do so, but my goal is to provide the fastest route for you to progress as a go player (to SDK at the bare minimum).</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><span id="more-23"></span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: left;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>Things to Do<br />
</strong></span></h3>
<ol>
<li style="text-align: left;"><a title="How to Study Tsumego" href="//how-to-study-tsumego/">Properly study tsumego on a consistent basis.</a></li>
<li style="text-align: left;">Have a stronger player review your games with you.</li>
<li style="text-align: left;">Review every game you play (even if it&#8217;s just a basic overview and by yourself).</li>
<li style="text-align: left;">Play even games with stronger players.</li>
<li style="text-align: left;"><a title="Experimental Games" href="//experimental-games/">Play games where the purpose is to test out new concepts you&#8217;ve learned, as opposed to simply trying to win.</a></li>
<li style="text-align: left;">Review games that stronger players have played.</li>
<li style="text-align: left;">&#8220;Play lots of games.* Nothing can replace experience.&#8221; &#8211; X.C.</li>
</ol>
<p style="text-align: left;"><em>*With the caveat that you are learning from your games and not just blindly playing.</em></p>
<h3 style="text-align: left;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Things <span style="color: #ff0000; text-decoration: underline;">NOT </span>To Do<br />
</span></h3>
<ol>
<li style="text-align: left;">Memorize <a href="http://senseis.xmp.net/?Joseki">joseki</a>.</li>
<li style="text-align: left;"><a title="Blitz Go: To Play or Not to Play?" href="//blitz-go-to-play-or-not-to-play/">Consistently play blitz go.</a></li>
<li style="text-align: left;">Continue playing when you know you&#8217;re on <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tilt_(poker)">tilt</a>.</li>
<li style="text-align: left;">Taking the knowledge you obtain from books as absolute and final.</li>
<li style="text-align: left;">Avoid playing handicap games.</li>
<li style="text-align: left;">Memorize professional games.*</li>
</ol>
<p style="text-align: left;"><em>* Primarily geared towards DDK&#8217;s.</em></p>
<p><strong>In the future, be sure to come back and visit this post for updates (such as more detailed articles and new advice)!</strong>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">23</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>&#034;Beat a Stronger Player in an Even Game&#034; Accomplishment Complete!</title>
		<link>/beat-a-stronger-player-in-an-even-game-accomplishment-complete/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2012 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kifu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[achievement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[baduk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[even game]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[go]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kifu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stronger opponent]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weiqi]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=24</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[For those who have never tried it before, playing an even game against a player that is reportedly two stones stronger than you can be a scary feeling. On one hand, you think &#8220;This can&#8217;t be too bad.&#8221; Yet, on the other hand, the board looks quite naked as you stare at the empty board [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For those who have never tried it before, playing an even game against a player that is reportedly two stones stronger than you can be a scary feeling. On one hand, you think &#8220;This can&#8217;t be too bad.&#8221; Yet, on the other hand, the board looks quite naked as you stare at the empty board while knowing that you should have two handicap stones sitting on the board. As someone who&#8217;s been through a couple experiences recently, it is quite the daunting feeling&#8230;</p>
<div style="text-align: left;"><span id="more-24"></span></div>
<p>Now, I understand that rank is, more often than not, a rather subjective one. A player can be stronger or weaker than his reported rank, and then of course there is the issue of whether your opponent&#8217;s playing style is weak to yours. Nonetheless, especially for players not yet in the high SDK and dan levels, the rank difference ends up impacting your mindset to some degree.<br />
The game was an intense one that left me with a racing heart and slight anxiety that I would misclick as my shaking hands attempted to place each stone. That being said, I am proud to say that today&#8217;s kifu has allowed me to obtain the &#8220;Beat a Stronger Player in an Even Game&#8221; accomplishment! In addition, being able to win against a stronger player in an even game has helped to reinforce my confidence against stronger opponents. Granted, I&#8217;m not saying I believe I can knocking down high SDK&#8217;s with ease; but I am now at least able to stand a bit straighter when faced with stronger opponents.<br />
Finally, today&#8217;s kifu has a special guest appearance from one of my favorite sensei&#8217;s: frozensoul! The kifu has a lot of great commentary and variations that I&#8217;m sure you could benefit from. The key lesson that I took away from his review is the usage of the double hane. If you are still feel a bit confused about that technique, be sure to look over the kifu for that explanation and more!</p>
<div style="text-align: left;">
<div id='glift_display2' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display2","sgf":"http:\/\/bengozen.com\/\/wp-content\/uploads\/2012\/10\/2012.10.03-Beat-a-Stronger-Player-in-an-Even-Game.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='//wp-content/uploads/2012/10/2012.10.03-Beat-a-Stronger-Player-in-an-Even-Game.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p></div>
<div style="text-align: center;">[download label=&#8221;Download Kifu&#8221;]//wp-content/uploads/2012/10/2012.10.03-Beat-a-Stronger-Player-in-an-Even-Game.sgf[/download]</div>
<div style="text-align: left;"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">24</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Blitz Go: To Play or Not to Play?</title>
		<link>/blitz-go-to-play-or-not-to-play/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2012 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kifu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Weekly Go Wednesday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[baduk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blitz go]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[go]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weiqi]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=25</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Weekly Go Wednesday, Issue #2 For many players, one of the major obstacles to playing go is time. After all, an average game can take anywhere from 60 to 90 minutes depending on the level of thinking that goes into each game. So in order to accommodate the faster players and those without much time, [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 style="text-align: center;"><em>Weekly Go Wednesday, Issue #2</em></h2>
<p style="text-align: left;">For many players, one of the major obstacles to playing go is time. After all, an average game can take anywhere from 60 to 90 minutes depending on the level of thinking that goes into each game. So in order to accommodate the faster players and those without much time, the format known as blitz go was born.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">For new players who&#8217;ve never played blitz go, the general idea is that you have less than a minute to make each move. If you fail to make your move within the allotted time, you lose by default on time.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">While there are different perspectives on blitz go, you should seriously consider the following points as to whether or you should be playing blitz go:</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><span id="more-25"></span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: left;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Why You Should Play Blitz Go&#8230;</span></h3>
<ol>
<li>You can play an entire 19&#215;19 game if you&#8217;re under a time constraint.</li>
<li>It is an excellent way to see how good your instincts are. In other words, the strength of your fundamentals in the game and reading speed will be severely tested in this format.</li>
</ol>
<p><em>I really tried to come up with three reasons; but even when I included the obvious benefit that the games are much shorter, I don&#8217;t honestly believe there are any other strengths to this format. And you&#8217;ll see why with the following list.</em></p>
<h3 style="text-align: left;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Why You Shouldn&#8217;t Play Blitz Go&#8230;</span></h3>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><strong>#1. Players are often rewarded for bad or desperate moves.</strong></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">While this may seem like a reason to play go, in my opinion, this is ultimately a double edged sword that will often be more agonizing than anything else. Case and point, check out my game record below for two groups that are supposed to be utterly alive, but who get killed off in the end. And in the end, if one of your desperate plays happens to be successful, there is a pretty good chance you&#8217;ll think you figured out a clever play when in actuality it was just your opponent&#8217;s stupidity. So you&#8217;re ultimately just reinforcing an inflated ego that would be smashed to bits if your opponent just avoids stupid mistakes. Is that really the way you want to get stronger?</p>
<p style="text-align: left; padding-left: 30px;"><strong>#2. If players become accustomed to this format, it will often condition them to have the &#8220;play and hope it works&#8221; mentality. </strong></p>
<p style="text-align: left; padding-left: 30px;">Just like #1, this is a TERRIBLE habit for players to acquire. This will not only negatively impact your abilities, but it will make the game far less enjoyable because you&#8217;ll look back at your games only to regret the hopeful move you made that cost you the game.</p>
<p style="text-align: left; padding-left: 30px;"><strong>#3. In addition, players who become accustomed to blitz go will also be practically unable to return to regular go since their deep reading abilities will have ultimately become crippled. </strong></p>
<p style="text-align: left; padding-left: 30px;">Unless you happen to study your deep reading constantly on the side and have not been plagued with the impatience many blitz players acquire, your deep reading is going to go down the drain. On the other hand, a player who typically plays longer games of go will always have the ability to play blitz go.</p>
<p style="text-align: left; padding-left: 30px;"><strong>#4. Tournaments are rarely blitz go. </strong></p>
<p style="text-align: left; padding-left: 30px;">Let&#8217;s face it. The big tournaments around the world are primarily non-blitz. So when you go off to compete for prizes and such, you will be at a severe disadvantage compared to your opponents who are more accustomed to managing their time at different points in the game. Unless you are hoping to pressure your opponent into playing a faster game, I have a feeling you won&#8217;t be doing as well as you think.</p>
<p style="text-align: left; padding-left: 30px;"><strong>#5. It&#8217;s difficult to tell when you&#8217;re actually progressing. </strong></p>
<p style="text-align: left; padding-left: 30px;">If you were to chart your results and progress over time, there&#8217;s a good chance it looks like a roller coaster. There are times where you utterly crush your opponent&#8230; times you get crushed by your opponent&#8230;. and once every blue moon you&#8217;ll have a close game. Since a player&#8217;s rank is perhaps the most desirable aspect for most players, this would admittedly be frustrating to see no?</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">The kifu record today is an excellent demonstration of the points I mentioned above regarding blitz go: careless errors, weird moves, desperate attempts that succeed despite the fact they are supposed to be terribly doomed for failure, and so forth.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">
<div id='glift_display3' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display3","sgf":"http:\/\/bengozen.com\/\/wp-content\/uploads\/2012\/10\/2012.10.03-Blitz-Go.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='//wp-content/uploads/2012/10/2012.10.03-Blitz-Go.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">[download label=&#8221;Download Kifu&#8221;]//wp-content/uploads/2012/10/2012.10.03-Blitz-Go.sgf[/download]
<p style="text-align: center;">In your experience thus far, what are some of your thoughts on blitz go?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">25</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>&#034;Winning&#034; My First Shidougo Game</title>
		<link>/winning-my-first-shidougo-game/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 18:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kifu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[baduk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[go]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shidougo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weiqi]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=27</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Today&#8217;s shidougo lesson comes from a person that I&#8217;ve come to befriend and look up to: frozensoul. If you&#8217;d like to help support his efforts in helping out players trying to get stronger, please visit his site for more information! I guess you could call this my first &#8220;shidougo&#8221; victory&#8230; but I wouldn&#8217;t classify this [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Today&#8217;s shidougo lesson comes from a person that I&#8217;ve come to befriend and look up to: frozensoul. If you&#8217;d like to help support his efforts in helping out players trying to get stronger, please visit <a href="http://www.clossiusreviewroom.com/">his site</a> for more information!</em></p>
<p>I guess you could call this my first &#8220;shidougo&#8221; victory&#8230; but I wouldn&#8217;t classify this as that due to the fact that frozensoul was actually trying to create a tie. So in reality, congratulations are in order for frozensoul for being only one point away from creating a tie!<br />
Overall, I was really happy with my performance in this game. It honestly has nothing to do with the victory and more on the fact that I played almost every move with confidence. And for those who would remind me that frozensoul wasn&#8217;t actually trying to play anything crazy, the confidence I&#8217;m speaking of is more of a &#8220;I read it out to the best of my ability and I&#8217;ll give each move everything I got.&#8221;<br />
<span id="more-27"></span><br />
That being said, I still have a lot of work to do in regards to my connections and such. One example of an efficient connection that I&#8217;ve yet to really utilize fully is the hanging connection (see variation on Move 13). And even though I made a few moves that received compliments for being solid, I know that I have a ways to go before more of my moves are played with a simplicity and efficiency that gets a nod of approval from strong players such as frozensoul.<br />
Hope you enjoy the kifu and be sure to share any insights that you may have as you look over the game!<br />

<div id='glift_display4' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display4","sgf":"http:\/\/bengozen.com\/\/wp-content\/uploads\/2012\/10\/2012.10.01-First-Shidougo.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='//wp-content/uploads/2012/10/2012.10.01-First-Shidougo.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">[download label=&#8221;Download Kifu&#8221;]//wp-content/uploads/2012/10/2012.10.01-First-Shidougo.sgf[/download]
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">27</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Desire to Win &#8211; Part 2</title>
		<link>/the-desire-to-win-part-2/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2012 15:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[baduk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[desire to win]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[go]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weiqi]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=28</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I have to admit that the responses that I received yesterday from my post have certainly made me reconsider my position from yesterday&#8217;s post, but ultimately I think it is more of a paradigm shift than necessarily regretting my decision to resign. For those of you who have never seen this video, please take 20 [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I have to admit that the responses that I received yesterday from my post have certainly made me reconsider my position from yesterday&#8217;s post, but ultimately I think it is more of a paradigm shift than necessarily regretting my decision to resign.<br />
For those of you who have never seen this video, please take 20 seconds and watch this unbelievable and tragic event happen to a professional 9-dan.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='720' height='405' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/qt1FvPxmmfE?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;fs=1&#038;autohide=2&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;wmode=transparent' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;'></iframe>
<p><em>Can you imagine? Playing a professional game on live television as a professional 9-dan and then putting yourself in self-atari? Although you have to admit, the man handled himself quite well and his reaction was quite priceless.</em><br />
<span id="more-28"></span><br />
That being said, the reason for the second part of this post is due to a friend of mine, Justin, who commented on a distinction that I had not really considered: <strong>the competitive setting</strong>. For those who would like to read about his personal experience with both sides of the regretful win/loss, see his comment in <a title="The Desire to Win – Part 1" href="//the-desire-to-win-part-1/">Part 1 of this topic</a>.<br />
Although I may have declared that all games should be won with as much honor as possible, I was not fair in considering the many aspects that go contains.<br />
Like anything else in life, as much as we may try to make the right decisions, we are human and are prone to our mistakes. I recognize that the first post of this topic argued to &#8220;do the right thing,&#8221; but that does not take into account the fact that <strong>luck and mistakes are just as much a part of go as it is in anything else</strong>.<br />
Last night, my friend Nate said it best when he told me that, &#8220;<strong>In some regards, the basic notion of trying to catch up in a game is to hope that your opponent will make a slack move or even a mistake.</strong>&#8221; Those words really struck me and as a result, I&#8217;m sitting here re-evaluating the stance I had taken just hours ago.<br />
As Justin stated, competitive go is a completely different setting. Each win is coveted by every player. <strong>Your opponents will take advantage of every slack move, and they will punish you for your mistakes.</strong> Do not err in thinking that the &#8220;honorable win&#8221; will draw any sympathy from your opponents.<br />
Ultimately, for my own experience, the decision to resign is still not a regrettable one. While improving your rank may be arguably &#8220;competitive,&#8221; I would argue it&#8217;s more a casual thing where there is very little at stake except your ego and pride. (<em>Granted, some people would say that a person&#8217;s ego and pride is extremely important. I fall into the camp where I think ego and pride is overrated</em>.)<br />
When the time comes to tournament/competitive play however, I have every intention of winning with everything I have that day&#8230; and that includes skill, luck, and even my opponent&#8217;s mistake(s). Otherwise, I plan on winning with my strength alone, because that is the basis where our pursuit to become one stone stronger will ultimately come from.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">28</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Desire to Win &#8211; Part 1</title>
		<link>/the-desire-to-win-part-1/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2012 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kifu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[baduk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[desire to win]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[go]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weiqi]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=29</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Today, I am writing about a more solemn topic that I know most people would shy away from posting on. However, I believe that this post touches on something that almost every go player will encounter along their journey: the desire to win. It is a difficult topic for me to write at the moment [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Today, I am writing about a more solemn topic that I know most people would shy away from posting on. However, I believe that this post touches on something that almost every go player will encounter along their journey: <strong>the desire to win</strong>. It is a difficult topic for me to write at the moment since the disappointing kifu is fresh off the board, but by doing so I hope to capture a vulnerability that we all feel at one point or another.<br />
<span id="more-29"></span><br />
In terms of what I mean when I say the desire to win, I&#8217;m not just talking about the simple desire for victory. After all, most people enjoy winning and the feeling of doing so. Instead, I&#8217;m talking about the type of desperation to win that you lose your rationale and even if you somehow manage to win, it&#8217;s the type of win that eats away at you because you know you didn&#8217;t really deserve it.<br />
For <span style="text-decoration: underline;">Hikaru no Go</span> fans, the following scene should be familiar.<br />
<figure id="attachment_466" style="width: 392px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2012/09/hikaru83_06.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-466" title="Hikaru No Go - Chapter 83" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2012/09/hikaru83_06.jpg?resize=392%2C640" alt="" width="392" height="640" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Hikaru No Go &#8211; Chapter 83</figcaption></figure>
Who could possibly forget how tortured Hikaru felt afterwards? After all, is there really any honor or joy that can really come from a win like this?</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">The game record for today is precisely that kind of win.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">
<div id='glift_display5' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display5","sgf":"http:\/\/bengozen.com\/\/wp-content\/uploads\/2012\/09\/2012.09.27-The-Desire-to-Win.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='//wp-content/uploads/2012/09/2012.09.27-The-Desire-to-Win.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">[download label=&#8221;Download Kifu&#8221;]//wp-content/uploads/2012/09/2012.09.27-The-Desire-to-Win.sgf[/download]
<p>For those who don&#8217;t have time to see the game record and the commentary, it essentially consists of me trying to win a capture race where I&#8217;m about six moves behind. And it wasn&#8217;t a complicated race, my group was two moves away from death. Ultimately, my opponent&#8217;s overconfidence caused him to actually lose his entire group.<br />
Now he still thought he was going to win, so he played it out to the end; but when he realized he was short 3.5 points, he left the game &#8220;for obvious reasons.&#8221;<br />
At first, I tried justifying to myself that I deserved that win. After all, it was my opponent&#8217;s cockiness and carelessness that led him to the situation&#8230;. serves him right&#8230;. right? I didn&#8217;t want to lose&#8230; I wanted my rank to go up&#8230; why should I give up my win for his mistake&#8230;.<br />
So in regards to the results of the game, technically, I did win with a +3.5 margin. After some thought and in the midst of drafting this post, I came to a realization. <strong>Even though most people would have viewed their opponent escaping as a frustrating event that might have even demanded the attention of an admin since the game had been played out to the very end, this should instead be looked as an opportunity for me to do the right thing.</strong><br />
Many people would say that the lessons in Go are parallel to those in life, and this is precisely one of those moments. <strong>Everything in life can ultimately be boiled down to which perspective you choose to take. And in the end, it is precisely these choices that lead us down the various paths we call our life.</strong><br />
Faced with a major crossroad, I decided to do the right thing: I resigned. If I let an admin or the system eventually force the game in my favor, that would be a permanent mark that I would never be able to change. By resigning, my spirit is at rest and I can move forward without the guilt.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Update: This post has now become a two-part post in order to account for some great points that were brought up. <a title="The Desire to Win – Part 2" href="//the-desire-to-win-part-2/">Read The Desire to Win &#8211; Part 2 here</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">29</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Enter the Eagle</title>
		<link>/enter-the-eagle/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2012 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kifu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Weekly Go Wednesday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[baduk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[go]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kifu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[origin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weiqi]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=30</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Weekly Go Wednesday, Issue #1 Welcome to the start of my Weekly Go Wednesday (WGW) series! This purpose of this series is to add some excitement to the middle of the week, so that before you know it, it&#8217;ll be the weekend again! If you have any requests or would like to be a guest [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 style="text-align: center;"><em>Weekly Go Wednesday, Issue #1</em></h2>
<p style="text-align: left;"><em>Welcome to the start of my Weekly Go Wednesday (WGW) series! This purpose of this series is to add some excitement to the middle of the week, so that before you know it, it&#8217;ll be the weekend again! If you have any requests or would like to be a guest writer on this series, be sure to let me know!</em></p>
<p>Unlike the games I&#8217;ve posted so far, today&#8217;s opponent has a bit of history that deserves to be recorded down for the ages to come. For those who want to check out the game commentary beforehand, go ahead and scroll down to the bottom before settling down with a hot beverage for a tale of a chance encounter that has been a big impact in my life ever since.<br />
<span id="more-30"></span></p>
<h3 style="padding-left: 30px;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>Enter the Eagle</strong></span></h3>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">When I had just begun to become immerse in the world of go, I decided that even though I was stuck in DDK land, I would try and get private lessons. Looking back on it, I shake my head and laugh at myself since I had not even taken the time to properly learn the basics, and there I was trying to get private lessons. Anyhow, during my first lesson, my go teacher happened to mention that one of his students was around the same strength as I. Needless to say, as a new and enthusiastic player, I was thrilled at the idea of being able to play in person with someone around the same strength as me. After all, online go is fun; but it doesn&#8217;t come close to the enjoyment of being able to play on a real board with real stones.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">Unfortunately, that would be my last lesson due to financial constraints; but coincidentally, my go teacher also went to one of the local go clubs to teach/review games. I had not attended club meetings as consistently as I would have liked, but I decided to go on one of his teaching nights. My go teacher had mentioned that the player he had mentioned might be attending that night, but let&#8217;s just say that I was not prepared for what the night would bring.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">With my eagerness to meet this player, I couldn&#8217;t help but nervously scoping out the attendees in an attempt to figure out who it was. I can&#8217;t quite remember who attended that night, but one thing I&#8217;m utterly clear on is that I saw an American guy there with a motorcycle helmet and related gear. I remember looking over at him and thinking, &#8220;Whoa! What is a guy like him doing here?!&#8221; And this wasn&#8217;t in a bad way at all, in fact it was more of a &#8220;What is a cool guy doing here?! And wait a second, he&#8217;s staring at the go board intently?! What&#8217;s going on?!?!?!&#8221; After all, in all my naivety for being new to the go scene, I just had this mental image of all go players being skinny Asian guys who were a bit shy and reserved. In fact, I half expected to meet a little kid that night who would be around my rank and then promptly school me.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">The night went by with everyone huddled around the board as my go teacher went over games and questions. After all was said and done, in the midst of goodbyes with my go teacher, he signaled for the cool motorcycle guy to come on over, and as you might have guessed&#8230; this was the player he told me about. Needless to say, I was flabbergasted&#8230; although I did my best not to show it in my face. Haha.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">Since then, there have been many go games and adventures which would take many more blog posts for me to properly recount. Although I would have to say that one of the major highlights was getting to eat at this incredible ramen place&#8230;. what I would give to have a bowl of that right now&#8230; sigh&#8230;.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">Delicious food aside, he has not only served as a fantastic rival (who has trounced me time and time again); but a valued friend that I look forward to knowing for a long time.</p>
<p>That being said, we began a weekly tradition of playing each other once a week, and this game is the first that I have posted since well&#8230; the other ones were pretty miserable. In fact, I&#8217;ll probably post some of those up in the future when I do a series on lessons that DDK players can learn from.<br />

<div id='glift_display6' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display6","sgf":"http:\/\/bengozen.com\/\/wp-content\/uploads\/2012\/09\/2012.09.26-Enter-the-Eagle.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='//wp-content/uploads/2012/09/2012.09.26-Enter-the-Eagle.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">[download label=&#8221;Download Kifu&#8221;]//wp-content/uploads/2012/09/2012.09.26-Enter-the-Eagle.sgf[/download]
<p>Overall, I felt that this game was a sign of even greater games to come. Even though I lost a major group towards the middle of the game, I feel that it was a sign of growth to know that the game was not yet over. And with the proper fighting spirit, I&#8217;d be able to make it a decently close game. Hopefully, you&#8217;ll feel that I managed to do so as well. Till next week!<br />
&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">30</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>&#034;Play Against a Troll and Win!&#034; Achievement Complete!</title>
		<link>/play-against-a-troll-and-win-achievement-complete/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2012 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kifu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[achievement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how to deal with a troll]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kifu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[troll]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weiqi]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=31</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[ANNOUNCEMENT: All the games will now come with full commentary in order to minimize the complication of having to flip back and forth between the blog post and the game. I will do my best to diligently put down any variations I saw and why I played the moves that I did. So please be [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>ANNOUNCEMENT: All the games will now come with full commentary<del> in order to minimize the complication of having to flip back and forth between the blog post and the game</del>. I will do my best to diligently put down any variations I saw and why I played the moves that I did. So please be sure to <del>visit the link and then</del> let me know your thoughts! Enjoy! </strong><br />
This was a pretty scary game for me. I know I&#8217;ve been playing stronger opponents in the ASR League in even matches, but for some reason playing a ranked game against a 3k gave me the jitters. And I didn&#8217;t go looking for this game, this guy challenged me. Looking back on it, I&#8217;m pretty sure he was trying to play against weaker players so he could feel all big and mighty. Too bad he came out the loser&#8230;.<br />
<span id="more-31"></span><br />

<div id='glift_display7' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display7","sgf":"http:\/\/bengozen.com\/\/wp-content\/uploads\/2012\/09\/2012.09.20-Play-Against-a-Troll.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='//wp-content/uploads/2012/09/2012.09.20-Play-Against-a-Troll.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">[download label=&#8221;Download Kifu&#8221;]//wp-content/uploads/2012/09/2012.09.20-Play-Against-a-Troll.sgf[/download]
<p>This is definitely a game that I&#8217;m certainly proud to call my own. In addition, I had never really experienced playing against a troll until this game. If you want a glimpse as to what I&#8217;m talking about, you can see it in the kifu (more profanity and name calling occurs afterwards, but you&#8217;ll get the gist of it based on what I left in the record).<br />
I think this is a game that any players below 10k might find useful. So please check it out and hopefully you&#8217;ll learn something new from my game!<br />
As a final note, for players who have never encountered trolls before and have no idea how to deal with them properly, here is some advice from my personal experience today</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">1. <strong>Do not stoop to their level</strong> &#8211; In other words, don&#8217;t curse. Don&#8217;t insult. Nada. Nothing. Zip. Otherwise you can forget about reporting them to an admin and gaining any sympathy.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">2. <strong>Report it to an admin</strong> &#8211; This is particularly recommended when your opponent has either escaped and/or is threatening to drag the game on till the end of time by using byoyomi forever&#8230;. And if you&#8217;re wondering how to find an admin on KGS, they have a star symbol next to their username.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">3. <strong>Vent about it with a friend, and then move on</strong> &#8211; Thankfully I had frozensoul there at the time, who saw the debacle go down when it happened, and he helped me through it and thus I&#8217;ve come out unscathed. But seriously, once you&#8217;ve vented, don&#8217;t let the troll impact your joy and happiness in playing go. Completely not worth it.</p>
<p>That being said, I hope you guys will enjoy the commentary and the new format. Till next time!<br />
<del>In case anyone is wondering, it seems that the new updated template for Blogger seems to override the code for embedding Eidogo into the blog posts, so that&#8217;s the reason I&#8217;ve had to resort to linking out onto Eidogo. Sorry for the inconvenience!</del></p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">31</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>First Official Shidougo Game</title>
		<link>/first-official-shidougo-game/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2012 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kifu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[baduk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[go]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shidougo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weiqi]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=32</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Prior to this game, I was on a decent winning streak&#8230; so I was feeling pretty good. Feeling good enough to think I could outplay a 5d? Apparently so&#8230;. Now granted, this was a teaching game; but I assure you that I did nothing less than try to outplay him and hope to catch him [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prior to this game, I was on a decent winning streak&#8230; so I was feeling pretty good. Feeling good enough to think I could outplay a 5d? Apparently so&#8230;.<br />
Now granted, this was a teaching game; but I assure you that I did nothing less than try to outplay him and hope to catch him off guard. For those who are still new and wondering why this is incredibly stupid, the difference between a 5d and 9k is at the bare minimum 8 stones. So&#8230; yeah&#8230;<br />
It&#8217;s been so long since I played against an opponent so vastly stronger than me that I forgot what it was like to play just to simply survive. That&#8217;s right: just survive. Instead, I tried to take big points and was under the false assurance that my groups were alive and that I was giving frozensoul a good game.<br />
That being said. There are too many mistakes to be mentioned and the prized moments are practically nonexistent. If you would like to see what 9k mistakes look like and how they get properly demolished, please <del>take the time to visit the link above</del> see the kifu below!<br />
<span id="more-32"></span><br />

<div id='glift_display8' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display8","sgf":"http:\/\/bengozen.com\/\/wp-content\/uploads\/2012\/09\/2012.09.17-First-Official-Shidougo-Game.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='//wp-content/uploads/2012/09/2012.09.17-First-Official-Shidougo-Game.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">[download label=&#8221;Download Kifu&#8221;]//wp-content/uploads/2012/09/2012.09.17-First-Official-Shidougo-Game.sgf[/download]
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Many thanks to frozensoul for letting me post this up and use his name. If you are ever looking for a great go teacher, be sure to visit his room (Social &#8211;&gt; clossius review room) for game reviews or teaching games. Definitely worth it!</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">32</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
