<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>new approach &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/new-approach/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>A Slow and Steady Return</title>
		<link>/a-slow-and-steady-return/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2013 21:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[im back]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new approach]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[return]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=2683</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[While I already miss the awesome weather, incredible scenery (aka awesome beaches with super clear water), and not to mention amazing food, I am glad to be back! When I first left for my vacation, I thought that I would be itching to get back into go. To my surprise, it is still taking me [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>While I already miss the awesome weather, incredible scenery (aka awesome beaches with super clear water), and not to mention amazing food, I am glad to be back!<br />
When I first left for my vacation, I thought that I would be itching to get back into go. To my surprise, it is still taking me awhile to really get back into my routine. I&#8217;m still feeling a little apprehensive; but on the upside, I am starting to feel excited at the prospect of playing again! So, good news on that end!<br />
In the past, I used to come off of these breaks with an intent on studying like there was no tomorrow. This time though, I intend on taking it one step at a time and really figuring out where my groove is with studying and playing. My goal is to become the strongest player I can possibly be. If these last couple years have taught me anything, it  is that consistency is the best route to doing so. So I&#8217;m hoping that I can avoid burnout with this slower, but hopefully more solid approach.<br />
I apologize for not having a Monday Go Meditation ready for this week, but it seems that it may be a little bit before I get that back up and running since I&#8217;m out of games that have good material for a review. Just more motivation for me to finally start playing ranked games on KGS again. =)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2683</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
