<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>off days &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/off-days/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>Not Out of the Woods Yet</title>
		<link>/not-out-of-the-woods-yet/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2013 03:23:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[off days]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[still in a funk]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=1882</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[For my final game in ASR, I&#8217;m happy to report that it seems my losing streak has come to an end. Although based on previous experience, the single win is nowhere near indicative of whether the streak will truly end or whether it is simply an anomaly amongst the actual pattern of continued losing. Contrary [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For my final game in ASR, I&#8217;m happy to report that it seems my losing streak has come to an end. Although based on previous experience, the single win is nowhere near indicative of whether the streak will truly end or whether it is simply an anomaly amongst the actual pattern of continued losing.<br />
Contrary to how things used to be though, I don&#8217;t feel particularly relieved that I won. In fact, it seems that I still feel the weight of some invisible force pressing down on me. Hard to say whether this is good or bad, but it still seems that I am not out of the woods quite yet. There is still a bit of soul searching to be done.<br />
In regards to my training, I do want to clarify that even though it sounds like I&#8217;ve been trying to change it every few days, the reality of it is that I have gained a better understanding of where my time is best spent. So in regards to what I had planned for February, nothing has really changed. My goal to study Korean material continues to go on and the only real change that has been made is that I no longer have the goal of staying in Alpha class for the ASR League. By eliminating this goal, I&#8217;m hoping to spend more quality time on the rest of the goals I had for February.<br />
On a more upbeat note, the <a title="North American Go Convention!!!" href="//north-american-go-convention/">North American Go Convention</a> will be starting tomorrow! To be honest, I&#8217;m not quite sure what to expect; but I&#8217;m excited to find out what is in store for me. So be sure to be on the lookout for those posts in the near future!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1882</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
