<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>mistakes &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/mistakes/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>Monday Go Meditation: Game 02</title>
		<link>/monday-go-meditation-game-02/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2013 13:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Monday Go Meditation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[6k]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[black]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[even]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[loss]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mistakes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technical win]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=2137</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[[download label=&#8221;Download Kifu&#8221;]//wp-content/uploads/2013/03/2013.03.11-MGM-02.sgf[/download] One Point Lesson A one tracked mind with no regard to anything else is doomed for countless mistakes.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div id='glift_display1' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display1","sgf":"http:\/\/bengozen.com\/\/wp-content\/uploads\/2013\/03\/2013.03.11-MGM-02.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='//wp-content/uploads/2013/03/2013.03.11-MGM-02.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">[download label=&#8221;Download Kifu&#8221;]//wp-content/uploads/2013/03/2013.03.11-MGM-02.sgf[/download]
<h2 style="text-align: center;"><strong>One Point Lesson</strong></h2>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>A one tracked mind with no regard to anything else is doomed for countless mistakes.</strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2137</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Stopping While You&#039;re Ahead</title>
		<link>/stopping-while-youre-ahead/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2013 23:30:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[flaws]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mistakes]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=1781</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;ve been on a losing streak these last couple of days. I could blame it on any number of things, but I know that one of my immediate problems is not knowing when to stop while I&#8217;m ahead. In my quest to maintain zen state throughout the entire game, it seems that the red eyed [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve been on a losing streak these last couple of days. I could blame it on any number of things, but I know that one of my immediate problems is not knowing when to stop while I&#8217;m ahead.<br />
In my quest to maintain zen state throughout the entire game, it seems that the red eyed goblin still creeps up as the game goes on. My killing instinct is subdued to the point where I&#8217;m generally attacking without a thought of killing, but then it starts to move towards the end of the game and then I realize that capturing an entire group is possible. All of a sudden, the hunt is on and next thing I know I&#8217;m clicking the resign button since one of my groups dies in the battle.<br />
It seems I am still unable to step back and just ask myself, &#8220;What is the estimated score? Should I continue being so aggressive? Is it time to wrap up the game?&#8221; It&#8217;s something that dan players are telling me time and time again, but I keep getting caught up in the moment and being too focused on determining tactical strategies instead of figuring out if my global strategy needs to change.<br />
I do feel an urge to go play another game so I can (in my mind) beat my opponent and feel better about myself, but it is not as strong as it normally is. Hopefully this is a sign of growth on my part. I am happy with the game that I played (for the most part). I just wish I didn&#8217;t give it away due to being careless due to my blood lust. To keep myself from falling back into a reckless go state though, I will play it safe and just stop for now.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1781</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lightbulb&#8230;..</title>
		<link>/lightbulb/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2010 01:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[goals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mistakes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[private lesson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yuan zhou]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=110</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[So I had my second private lesson today, and I have to say I felt like such an idiot as we were going over my games. It&#8217;s funny how blatantly obvious my idiotic decisions and rationales are when pointed out. I&#8217;m still falling into the typical traps of a new player (e.g. focusing on local [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div style="clear: both; text-align: left;">
So I had my second private lesson today, and I have to say I felt like such an idiot as we were going over my games. It&#8217;s funny how blatantly obvious my idiotic decisions and rationales are when pointed out. I&#8217;m still falling into the typical traps of a new player (e.g. focusing on local areas, having no purpose, wishful thinking, etc.) Argh&#8230;. I think I&#8217;m going to have to come up with a handout for beginning Go players to look over once a day to help them out.<br />
One of the most critical aha moments that went off in my head today is the fact that I don&#8217;t and can&#8217;t quite read ahead worth crap. It&#8217;s definitely one of the reasons that I make the poor plays that I do. This is probably one of the reasons I hate half of the books that I&#8217;ve reviewed so far. They have so many complicated diagrams, but in reality there is probably more substance since they are probably assuming you can read it out in your head no problem. So far, I&#8217;ve been actually replaying variations on an actual board. This is useful to an extent, but I have to be able to play the simulations out in my head.<br />
As I mentioned at the beginning of this month, I&#8217;m trying to break the double digit kyu (DDK) by October 8th. It probably is near impossible to do so, but here&#8217;s my crazy game plan:</p>
<ol>
<li>Finish the following books:
<ul>
<li><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Opening Theory Made Easy</span> by Otake Hideo 9 dan</li>
<li><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Whole Board Thinking in Joseki &#8211; Volume One</span> by Yi-Lun Yang</li>
<li><span style="text-decoration: underline;">One Thousand and One Life-and-Death Problems</span> by Richard Bozulich</li>
<li><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Understanding Dan Level Play</span> by Yuan Zhou</li>
<li><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Tesuji</span> by James Davies</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Replay 25 moves of a professional game (that has commentary) everyday.</li>
<li>Play one serious game (not a bot) everyday where I don&#8217;t rush and try my hardest.</li>
</ol>
<p>It&#8217;s like my teacher said, &#8220;It&#8217;s not hard to rise levels at the stage you&#8217;re at, you just have to stop doing all these irrational and inefficient moves.&#8221; Time to topple over these obstacles.
</p></div>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">110</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
