<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>trip &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/trip/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>Hong Kong Trip: Part 3 &#8211; Weiqi</title>
		<link>/hong-kong-trip-part-3/</link>
		<comments>/hong-kong-trip-part-3/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2014 15:50:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Cultural]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[go]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hong kong]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hong kong go association]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shiu lao shi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[souvenir]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trip]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weiqi]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=4956</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Part 1 — The Scenery   &#124;&#124;   Part 2 — The Food   &#124;&#124;   Part 3 — Weiqi Introduction After much waiting and anticipation, I&#8217;m happy to release the final post on my Hong Kong trip. Since we always save the best for last, it should come as no surprise to you that you had to wait till [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><a title="Hong Kong Trip: Part 1 — The Scenery" href="//hong-kong-trip-part-1/">Part 1 — The Scenery</a>   ||   <a title="Hong Kong Trip: Part 2 — The Food" href="//hong-kong-trip-part-2/">Part 2 — The Food</a>   ||   <em>Part 3 — Weiqi</em></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">Introduction</h2>
<p>After much waiting and anticipation, I&#8217;m happy to release the final post on my Hong Kong trip. Since we always save the best for last, it should come as no surprise to you that you had to wait till the very end to hear about my go adventures! Before we go on however, I just wanted to clarify a couple of things. (1) The title of this post was originally &#8220;Go,&#8221; but due to the fact that I was in Hong Kong, I felt it was only appropriate to title it &#8220;Weiqi.&#8221; (2) However, in order to ease the readability of my post, I will be using &#8220;go&#8221; in the text instead of &#8220;weiqi&#8221; for simple consistency with English go literature. With that said, onwards with my go adventure in Hong Kong!</p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">Part 3 &#8211; Weiqi</h2>
<p>As I&#8217;m sure some of you remember, I posted on <a title="Reddit Hong Kong Post" href="http://www.reddit.com/r/baduk/comments/2059yl/go_players_clubs_in_hong_kong/">reddit</a> and <a title="Preparing for My Hong Kong Trip" href="//preparing-hong-kong-trip/">here</a> before the trip to see if anyone was in the area. Most of the feedback I got from people was that I should visit the <a title="Hong Kong Go Association Website" href="http://www.hkga.org.hk/">Hong Kong Go Association (HKGA)</a>. I was a little saddened by the fact that I was unable to find anyone who lived locally online, but I knew that I couldn&#8217;t bear the idea of going all the way to Asia and not do a single go-related activity. So I promised myself that if I were to do anything for myself this trip, it would be to visit the HKGA.<br />
When we first arrived in Hong Kong, one of the things we did was to go to one of the shopping districts. And believe it or not, as I&#8217;m walking down the street, I see this across the street.<br />
<figure id="attachment_5043" style="width: 640px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-01.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-5043" alt="2014HKP3-01" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-01-1024x768.jpg?resize=640%2C480" width="640" height="480" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Wait&#8230; why does that cartoon character look like he&#8217;s doing something I&#8217;m terribly familiar with&#8230;</figcaption></figure>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span id="more-4956"></span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;">*blink*</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">*double blink*</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">*rubs eyes*</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">*squints at the bus ad*</p>
<figure id="attachment_5044" style="width: 640px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-02.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-5044" alt="2014HKP3-02" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-02-1024x768.jpg?resize=640%2C480" width="640" height="480" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Oh&#8230;. my&#8230;.. Sai!!!!!!</figcaption></figure>
Yep. It was an ad for go on a bus. No it wasn&#8217;t some special bus for the HKGA. It was just your normal run of the mill bus with an ad for HKGA. You have no idea how excited I was to see it at the time. Haha. I probably even looked a little crazy to the people around as I&#8217;m pointing excitedly and trying to tell my family to look at the epicness painted on the bus.<br />
Now if anyone has visited the HKGA website, you&#8217;ll notice that it&#8217;s entirely in Chinese without any English version. And while I may be able to read and write Mandarin, trying to read a web page full of Chinese is a huge struggle for me since my Chinese is still rather basic.<br />
One of the things I noticed on the site was that there were classes being held at night throughout the week. They would cost money, but that didn&#8217;t bother me since it would be a brand new experience for me. So I had my mom call them (because I can&#8217;t speak Cantonese), and we find out that the classes were not actually running at the time.<br />
When my mom told me that, I then asked if they had a time where local players would come and play. As you might imagine, I was envisioning the HKGA to be something like the Nihon Ki-in in Japan where there&#8217;s a go salon in the building with a bunch of people playing throughout the day. To my surprise and disappointment, the secretary told my mom that they didn&#8217;t have anything like that.<br />
I was pretty bummed to hear that. After all, would my epic go adventure in Hong Kong be reduced to simply visiting the HKGA and maybe taking a few pictures? All hope was nearly gone until the secretary told my mom that I could take private lessons if I wanted to.<br />
After some back and forth, I found out that my teacher would be an amateur who was around 6-7 dan. He could speak Mandarin and English as well, so language wouldn&#8217;t be an issue. The only obstacle in my way was that it would be about $100USD for a lesson.<br />
I wrestled with the decision for a while. After all, $100USD is not cheap by any stretch of the imagination. However, for those who don&#8217;t know me, I&#8217;m more of the seize life by the moment kind of person. Since I had no idea when I would go back to Hong Kong, I ultimately decided to schedule a lesson for the next day in the morning at 10:00AM.<br />
The next day, I woke up excited to embark on my go adventure. My mom asked if I knew where I was going, and I told her that I had the address (252 Hennessy Road; Wan Chai; Hong Kong) already. I had confirmed it via Google maps and also a redditor had also told me the same address. Just to be safe though, my family was kind enough to be willing to go with me (in case I needed help getting around), so off we went.<br />
<figure id="attachment_5045" style="width: 640px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-03.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-5045" alt="2014HKP3-03" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-03-1024x682.jpg?resize=640%2C426" width="640" height="426" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">In Hong Kong, this is the symbol for the metro / subway line. If you see this, there is one very close by.</figcaption></figure>
After grabbing breakfast, we found ourselves the nearest metro line and headed off towards 252 Hennessy Road; Wan Chai; Hong Kong.<br />
<figure id="attachment_5046" style="width: 640px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-04.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-5046" alt="2014HKP3-04" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-04-1024x768.jpg?resize=640%2C480" width="640" height="480" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">The metro system is also way better than DC. Look. They have a map with electronic LED&#8217;s to show you where you are and what stop is next. Brilliant!</figcaption></figure>
Because I didn&#8217;t want to be late, we arrived with plenty of time to spare (around 9:30AM).<br />
<figure id="attachment_5047" style="width: 640px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-05.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-5047" alt="2014HKP3-05" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-05-1024x768.jpg?resize=640%2C480" width="640" height="480" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Woohoo! Here we are! The Hong Kong Go Association at 252 Hennessy Road; Wan Chai; Hong Kong.</figcaption></figure>
After finding the location, I turned around to look for the doorway and was instead greeted by a kind of creepy looking entrance.<br />
<figure id="attachment_5048" style="width: 384px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-06.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-5048 " alt="2014HKP3-06" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-06-768x1024.jpg?resize=384%2C512" width="384" height="512" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Tell me I&#8217;m not the only one who thought this looked like a scene out of a horror movie like Saw or something&#8230;</figcaption></figure>
After buzzing and waiting around for 15-20 minutes, I got a little nervous as I was wondering whether or not the teacher had bailed on me. I had tried to sneak into the metal door earlier to go in and see if anyone was around, but I got chased out by some elderly Asian gentlemen (who seemed to be the security guard). He told me that no one was upstairs and that no one was planning on being there. Uh oh&#8230;<br />
Around 9:55AM, we get a call from the secretary my mom spoke to last night. She asked if we were still coming. &#8220;Still coming?&#8221; my mom said, &#8220;We&#8217;re waiting outside!&#8221; After about ten seconds had passed, a feeling of dread washed over me&#8230; Sure enough, my mom turns to be and says, &#8220;We&#8217;re in the wrong location! This is not the correct place! They are actually located around the place we were eating breakfast!&#8221;<br />
<figure id="attachment_5074" style="width: 330px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/nooooooo_luke_skywalker.gif"><img class="size-full wp-image-5074" alt="Noooooo!!!!!!" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/nooooooo_luke_skywalker.gif?resize=330%2C186" width="330" height="186" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Noooooo!!!!!!</figcaption></figure>
<p style="text-align: left;">Needless to say I was utterly blown and felt terrible since someone had come to teach me and I was about 20-30 minutes away from where they were. Luckily however, the teacher was not in a rush to leave and was willing to wait for me to go to the correct location.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">At this point, I had dragged my family on a 30 minute journey to a new part of the city. I could not bear the notion of dragging them 30 minutes back just so I could go to the HKGA. So  so I told them to go ahead and stay and explore the new part of the city. And with that, I ran off to find the place myself.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">So if you&#8217;re wondering at this point, this is the correct address: <strong>12/F, May May Building, No. 683-685 Nathan Road, Mongkok</strong>.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">After navigating my way back to Mongkok, I started looking for the sign that would signal me that I had found the building.</p>
<figure id="attachment_5049" style="width: 640px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-07.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-5049" alt="2014HKP3-07" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-07-1024x768.jpg?resize=640%2C480" width="640" height="480" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">This is it! In case you ever are visiting, this is the sign you should look for!</figcaption></figure>
<figure id="attachment_5050" style="width: 384px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-08.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-5050" alt="2014HKP3-08" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-08-768x1024.jpg?resize=384%2C512" width="384" height="512" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Here&#8217;s a shot of the entrance to let you know you&#8217;ve found the building. Much better than the other location right? Seems much more trustworthy.</figcaption></figure>
I was a bit out of breath by this point, but I was sure glad I had found the building within a reasonable time. And before I knew it I was riding the elevator up to the 12th floor.<br />
When the door opened, I was immediately greeted by a display case full of go memorabilia along with trophies and awards.<br />
<figure id="attachment_5051" style="width: 640px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-09.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-5051" alt="2014HKP3-09" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-09-1024x768.jpg?resize=640%2C480" width="640" height="480" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Stamps, signed fans, bowls, trophies etc. It was quite a sight!</figcaption></figure>
And after greeting the secretary at the front and exchanging the customary greeting and welcome, I turned left to see an incredible sight of go boards and bowls galore!<br />
<figure id="attachment_5052" style="width: 640px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-11.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-5052" alt="2014HKP3-11" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-11-1024x768.jpg?resize=640%2C480" width="640" height="480" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Isn&#8217;t this a magnificent sight? The only thing that would make it better would be people playing as well!</figcaption></figure>
Up on the left in the same room, there was a cork board where all the members had these mini tags with their names on it and hung by their respective rank.<br />
<figure id="attachment_5053" style="width: 640px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-12.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-5053" alt="2014HKP3-12" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-12-1024x768.jpg?resize=640%2C480" width="640" height="480" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Look at all those players! Each little tag is a person! If only I could have met and played one of them!</figcaption></figure>
In terms of my lesson that day, it turned out that I would be learning from the President of the Hong Kong Go Association himself! (I will refer to him as Shiu Lao Shi from this point on.)<br />
<figure id="attachment_5054" style="width: 640px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-13.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-5054" alt="2014HKP3-13" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-13-1024x768.jpg?resize=640%2C480" width="640" height="480" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">As you can see, my stuff is setup on the right table. This was where we had our lesson.</figcaption></figure>
For the first part of our lesson, we went over concepts regarding opening theory (i.e, fuseki). While this is a topic I have studied a bit overall (compared to other aspects of go), I was of course humbled by how Shiu Lao Shi was able to remind me of some fundamental principles when it came to fuseki.<br />
One of the key ideas I was taught was how the opening was a lot about balance. If you can get an even result, then you have done a good job with the fuseki. Too often players try to get some massive advantage and then end up in a bad position. This is still something I&#8217;m working on, but it was a much needed reminder since I&#8217;m an aggressive and impatient player as a whole.<br />
After more fuseki study, we played a 5-stone handicap game. Due to time constraints, I was not able to record the game. However, although I never got to spend the time I would have liked to try to recreate the full game, here is a partial kifu that I tried to recreate that day.*<br />
*Note: There is no commentary on this kifu due to how short it is, but I thought that being able to see how the game started up would be better than nothing.<br />

<div id='glift_display1' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display1","sgf":"http:\/\/bengozen.com\/\/wp-content\/uploads\/2014\/04\/2014.03.18-HKGA-Lesson.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014.03.18-HKGA-Lesson.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">[download label=&#8221;Download Kifu&#8221;]//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014.03.18-HKGA-Lesson.sgf[/download]
<p style="text-align: left;">After the lesson, I got to explore a little bit more and found their magnificent book collection.</p>
<figure id="attachment_5055" style="width: 640px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-14.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-5055" alt="2014HKP3-14" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-14-1024x768.jpg?resize=640%2C480" width="640" height="480" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Isn&#8217;t this massive? All Chinese books though! If only we had this many English go books&#8230;.</figcaption></figure>
Before I came to the HKGA, I had also envisioned that there might be a store or a pile of books where I could purchase something for me to remember the place by. Unfortunately all their books were on a loan basis only (which I would obviously not be doing since I&#8217;d never return it haha), and there was no &#8220;gift shop.&#8221; However, though I didn&#8217;t know it at the time, I was very lucky in that Shiu Lao Shi had no intentions of letting me leave empty handed.<br />
After walking around the HKGA a bit more and chatting with Shiu Lao Shi, I went up to the front desk to pay for the lesson. Next thing I know, Shiu Lao Shi was asking the secretary to give me a souvenir bag. The following are shots of the very generous gift that he ended up giving me.<br />
<figure id="attachment_5056" style="width: 640px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-15.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-5056" alt="2014HKP3-15" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-15-668x1024.jpg?resize=640%2C981" width="640" height="981" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Hong Kong Go Association reusable bag (one side)</figcaption></figure>
<figure id="attachment_5057" style="width: 640px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-16.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-5057" alt="2014HKP3-16" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-16-668x1024.jpg?resize=640%2C981" width="640" height="981" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Hong Kong Go Association reusable bag (other side)</figcaption></figure>
<figure id="attachment_5058" style="width: 640px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-17.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-5058" alt="2014HKP3-17" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-17-1024x768.jpg?resize=640%2C480" width="640" height="480" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">A neat calendar card to put in your wallet (front)</figcaption></figure>
<figure id="attachment_5059" style="width: 640px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-18.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-5059" alt="2014HKP3-18" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-18-1024x768.jpg?resize=640%2C480" width="640" height="480" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Calendar card for your wallet (back)</figcaption></figure>
<figure id="attachment_5060" style="width: 640px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-19.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-5060" alt="2014HKP3-19" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-19-1024x779.jpg?resize=640%2C486" width="640" height="486" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">5 issues of a Chinese go magazine</figcaption></figure>
<figure id="attachment_5061" style="width: 640px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-20.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-5061" alt="2014HKP3-20" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-20-1024x555.jpg?resize=640%2C346" width="640" height="346" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">A portable magnetic go set for the plane! (front)</figcaption></figure>
<figure id="attachment_5062" style="width: 640px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-21.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-5062" alt="2014HKP3-21" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-21-1024x576.jpg?resize=640%2C360" width="640" height="360" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Portable magnetic go set for the plane (back)</figcaption></figure>
<figure id="attachment_5063" style="width: 640px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-22.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-5063" alt="2014HKP3-22" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-22-1024x768.jpg?resize=640%2C480" width="640" height="480" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Portable go set removed from the box.</figcaption></figure>
<figure id="attachment_5064" style="width: 640px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-23.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-5064" alt="2014HKP3-23" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-23-1024x768.jpg?resize=640%2C480" width="640" height="480" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Portable go set board and stones.</figcaption></figure>
<figure id="attachment_5065" style="width: 448px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-24.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-5065 " alt="2014HKP3-24" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-24-768x1024.jpg?resize=448%2C597" width="448" height="597" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Aerial overview of the board and stones in action. And in case you&#8217;re wondering, this is the best magnetic go set I&#8217;ve used to date (excluding the YMImports Roll-up Magnetic Board because that is different from this kind of magnetic set).</figcaption></figure>
<figure id="attachment_5066" style="width: 384px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-25.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-5066" alt="2014HKP3-25" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-25-682x1024.jpg?resize=384%2C576" width="384" height="576" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">A clear go folder with the HKGA cartoon mascot on front!</figcaption></figure>
<figure id="attachment_5067" style="width: 384px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-26.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-5067 " alt="2014HKP3-26" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-26-719x1024.jpg?resize=384%2C547" width="384" height="547" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">And a handout that Shiu Lao Shi created on the opening.</figcaption></figure>
As you can imagine, I was very grateful and thanked him numerous times for such a generous gift. After all, I had expected to leave the HKGA with nothing but a good story and what I could carry in my brain. So I was like a little kid on Christmas when he gave me all of these souvenirs for me to bring home with me.<br />
<figure id="attachment_5068" style="width: 384px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-27.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-5068" alt="2014HKP3-27" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP3-27-810x1024.jpg?resize=384%2C485" width="384" height="485" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Here&#8217;s a shot of me and Shiu Lao Shi by the front desk.</figcaption></figure>
When the time came to part ways, we exchanged contact information and said our good-byes. I was certainly sad to leave since I would have loved to have stayed all day, but time was ticking and I had to go meet my family afterwards.<br />
Overall, I was glad that I was able to visit the HKGA and have a chance to learn from Shiu Lao Shi. It was a great experience and I certainly hope that I&#8217;ll be able to go back one day and play with other locals in the area. Maybe I&#8217;ll attend a tournament or something&#8230; you never know what the future holds&#8230; =)</p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">Conclusion</h2>
<p>With all that said and done, I hope that you enjoyed my Hong Kong series and felt that you could get a glimpse into my adventures in Hong Kong. As always, any feedback you have for me would be greatly appreciated. And if you ever have any questions or plan to go to Hong Kong yourself, please let me know and I&#8217;d be happy to chat with you!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/hong-kong-trip-part-3/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>18</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">4956</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hong Kong Trip: Part 1 &#8211; The Scenery</title>
		<link>/hong-kong-trip-part-1/</link>
		<comments>/hong-kong-trip-part-1/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2014 02:57:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Cultural]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hong kong]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[scenery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the peak]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tian tan buddha]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tourist]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trip]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[victoria peak]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=4916</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Part 1 — The Scenery   &#124;&#124;   Part 2 — The Food   &#124;&#124;   Part 3 — Weiqi Introduction After much waiting and anticipation, I&#8217;m happy to finally release my Hong Kong post series! I originally had plans to do a day by day retelling of my adventures in Hong Kong, but I realized that it would take [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Part 1 — The Scenery</em>   ||   <a title="Hong Kong Trip: Part 2 — The Food" href="//hong-kong-trip-part-2/">Part 2 — The Food</a>   ||   <a title="Hong Kong Trip: Part 3 — Weiqi" href="//hong-kong-trip-part-3/">Part 3 — Weiqi</a></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">Introduction</h2>
<p style="text-align: left;">After much waiting and anticipation, I&#8217;m happy to finally release my Hong Kong post series! I originally had plans to do a day by day retelling of my adventures in Hong Kong, but I realized that it would take way too long to write and not to mention I would probably bore you to tears.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">In addition, since the trip wasn&#8217;t entirely centered on go, I wanted to capture as much of my trip as possible without taking too much time away from the main subject matter of this blog: go.  After all, as I&#8217;m sure you&#8217;ve noticed, I&#8217;ve worked hard to ensure that all my posts have always been related to go. So I hope you&#8217;ll forgive me for detracting from go these next couple of days to tell you about my trip. With that said, I hope you enjoy these posts!</p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">Part 1 &#8211; The Scenery</h2>
<p>The trip was a 13+ hour flight, so you can imagine our delight when we were finally off the plane and stepping foot into Hong Kong for the first time. After going through customs, getting our luggage, and a brief encounter of a taxi driver trying to hustle and get our family to take his taxi back to the city as opposed to the bus, we soon found ourselves on a bus driving down into the city.<br />
After about thirty minutes, we were driving through the city and I was greeted by the following view of Hong Kong for the first time:</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP1-01.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-4917 aligncenter" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP1-01-1024x682.jpg?resize=640%2C426" alt="2014HKP1-01" width="640" height="426" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></p>
<p><span id="more-4916"></span>Considering this is the first time my family and I have ever been to Hong Kong, it should be no surprise to you that we did a lot of exploring of the city. And even though I&#8217;ve been to my fair share of cities (i.e., Washington D.C., New York, Los Angeles, San Francisco), I have to say that Hong Kong was full of tall buildings.<br />
<figure id="attachment_4918" style="width: 384px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP1-02.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-4918" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP1-02-768x1024.jpg?resize=384%2C512" alt="2014HKP1-02" width="384" height="512" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">This building was so tall that I only managed to capture it using panoramic mode.</figcaption></figure>
And while one expect a city to be full of buildings, I couldn&#8217;t help but notice that Hong Kong had a lot of unique building designs sprinkled throughout as you would walk from place to place.<br />
<figure id="attachment_4919" style="width: 384px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP1-03.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-4919" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP1-03-768x1024.jpg?resize=384%2C512" alt="2014HKP1-03" width="384" height="512" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">The building on the left captured my attention for this shot. Isn&#8217;t it neat?</figcaption></figure>
One of the things that my brother wanted to do was visit The Peak (aka <a title="Victoria Peak Wikipedia" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Victoria_Peak">Victoria Peak</a> &#8211; which is a tourist location because it&#8217;s the tallest point in Hong Kong where you can see the entire city). So one night we decided to head up on our own (which was a fun adventure since neither of us spoke Cantonese), and after getting lost and nearly leaving the location (we thought we were in the wrong place but we were really just in the wrong building), we finally found ourselves at the right spot.<br />
<figure id="attachment_4920" style="width: 640px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP1-04.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-4920" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP1-04-1024x682.jpg?resize=640%2C426" alt="2014HKP1-04" width="640" height="426" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">For anyone coming to visit Victoria Peak, this is the building you&#8217;re looking for when you have the taxi take you up there. It is NOT the shopping mall that you first find yourself at when the taxi drops you at. Haha.</figcaption></figure>
My night photography skills need a lot of work, but here&#8217;s a semi-decent shot that I managed to get of the incredible view we had at the top.<br />
<figure id="attachment_4921" style="width: 640px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP1-05.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-4921" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP1-05-1024x682.jpg?resize=640%2C426" alt="2014HKP1-05" width="640" height="426" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Imagine that in real life&#8230; Although I will say that when I was leaning over the edge to take the picture, I looked down and my stomach immediately knotted up as I thought about what it would be like to fall down or drop my camera&#8230; *shudders*</figcaption></figure>
<figure id="attachment_4922" style="width: 640px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP1-06.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-4922" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP1-06-1024x682.jpg?resize=640%2C426" alt="2014HKP1-06" width="640" height="426" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Here&#8217;s a photo of my brother (on the left) and me (on the right).</figcaption></figure>
Another memorable aspect about Hong Kong is the fact that construction is going on EVERYWHERE. I swear, I don&#8217;t think I can recall a single time where I wasn&#8217;t walking down a street and not seeing some kind of construction going on. And to make it an even more memorable fact, a lot of the construction was done using bamboo structures to provide support.<br />
<figure id="attachment_4923" style="width: 640px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP1-07.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-4923" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP1-07-1024x767.jpg?resize=640%2C479" alt="2014HKP1-07" width="640" height="479" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Here&#8217;s a shot of the bamboo structures I was talking about. Though I&#8217;m aware of how strong bamboo can be, it was crazy seeing it being used as such a critical support structure for construction.</figcaption></figure>
Another thing that I noticed about Hong Kong is that while it lives up to what you expect of a city in terms of things being open late, everything that we went to in the morning (like shopping malls and such) were closed!!! In other words, it seems that the better approach for life in Hong Kong is to stay out real late, sleep-in, grab lunch, and then go out to do stuff. Haha.<br />
<figure id="attachment_4924" style="width: 640px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP1-08.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-4924" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP1-08-1024x767.jpg?resize=640%2C479" alt="2014HKP1-08" width="640" height="479" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">This was taken at a prominent mall called &#8220;The One.&#8221; It was like 11AM. Pretty much everything was closed&#8230; &gt;_&lt;</figcaption></figure>
After having gone to Times Square in New York, I have to say that I wasn&#8217;t expecting to be wowed by any LED lights or big fancy screens in Hong Kong; but I noticed some really gorgeous designs of Chinese characters shining brightly with LED lights.<br />
<figure id="attachment_4925" style="width: 384px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP1-09.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-4925" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP1-09-768x1024.jpg?resize=384%2C512" alt="2014HKP1-09" width="384" height="512" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">This is the Chinese character for &#8220;medicine.&#8221; As you can see, the calligraphy looks gorgeous even though it&#8217;s comprised of LED lights.</figcaption></figure>
The other big tourist thing my family and I did was to visit the <a title="Tian Tan Buddha Wikipedia" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tian_Tan_Buddha">Tian Tan Buddha</a>. It was a bit of a journey to get up there; but after two long bus rides, we finally arrived.<br />
<figure id="attachment_4926" style="width: 640px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP1-10.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-4926" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP1-10-1024x682.jpg?resize=640%2C426" alt="2014HKP1-10" width="640" height="426" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">This was the view I was greeted with when we got off the bus.</figcaption></figure>
<figure id="attachment_4927" style="width: 640px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP1-11.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-4927" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP1-11-1024x682.jpg?resize=640%2C426" alt="2014HKP1-11" width="640" height="426" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">When you are about to enter, you are greeted with this majestic white gate.</figcaption></figure>
After walking in, we were taking in the sights and then promptly noticed two dogs that were just relaxing in the sun. The atmosphere was already very calming and zen-like to begin with, but seeing these dogs just made it that much more so.<br />
<figure id="attachment_4928" style="width: 640px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP1-12.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-4928" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP1-12-1024x682.jpg?resize=640%2C426" alt="2014HKP1-12" width="640" height="426" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">This dog was just taking a nap in the middle of the central area without a care in the world. Doesn&#8217;t he look so peaceful?</figcaption></figure>
<figure id="attachment_4929" style="width: 640px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP1-13.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-4929" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP1-13-1024x682.jpg?resize=640%2C426" alt="2014HKP1-13" width="640" height="426" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">This dog was just chilling on the front steps and peering out as if calmly observing everything going around him.</figcaption></figure>
Before we headed up the long stairs to the Buddha statue, I experimented with my camera a bit.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP1-14.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-4930" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP1-14-1024x682.jpg?resize=640%2C426" alt="2014HKP1-14" width="640" height="426" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP1-15.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-4931" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP1-15-1024x682.jpg?resize=640%2C426" alt="2014HKP1-15" width="640" height="426" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">After a long trek up multiple flights of stairs, we were finally greeted by the immense statue of Tian Tan Buddha.</p>
<figure id="attachment_4932" style="width: 640px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP1-16.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-4932" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP1-16-1024x682.jpg?resize=640%2C426" alt="2014HKP1-16" width="640" height="426" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">It&#8217;s so big!!!!</figcaption></figure>
After walking around and going in to the museum (which I am unfortunately unable to feature on this post since no photography was allowed), I had a chance to explore around the area on my own for a bit and took a couple of shots.<br />
<figure id="attachment_4933" style="width: 640px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP1-17.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-4933" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP1-17-1024x682.jpg?resize=640%2C426" alt="2014HKP1-17" width="640" height="426" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">This was taken from the side of the Buddha looking out into the open. Doesn&#8217;t it look so serene?</figcaption></figure>
<figure id="attachment_4934" style="width: 640px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP1-18.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-4934" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP1-18-1024x682.jpg?resize=640%2C426" alt="2014HKP1-18" width="640" height="426" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Here&#8217;s a favorite of mine from the side of the Buddha statue.</figcaption></figure>
<figure id="attachment_4945" style="width: 640px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP1-19.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-4945" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP1-19-1024x682.jpg?resize=640%2C426" alt="2014HKP1-19" width="640" height="426" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">A shot of the Buddha from below.</figcaption></figure>
Once we had finished visiting the Buddha statue, we went to visit the rest of the temple and see what else was in the area.<br />
<figure id="attachment_4936" style="width: 640px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP1-20.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-4936" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP1-20-1024x682.jpg?resize=640%2C426" alt="2014HKP1-20" width="640" height="426" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Here&#8217;s a shot of a plant that bloomed into a lotus shape.</figcaption></figure>
<figure id="attachment_4937" style="width: 640px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP1-21.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-4937" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP1-21-1024x682.jpg?resize=640%2C426" alt="2014HKP1-21" width="640" height="426" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">The view of a temple from the bottom steps.</figcaption></figure>
<figure id="attachment_4938" style="width: 640px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP1-22.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-4938" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP1-22-1024x682.jpg?resize=640%2C426" alt="2014HKP1-22" width="640" height="426" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">The view from the top of the steps of the temple in the previous picture.</figcaption></figure>
<figure id="attachment_4939" style="width: 640px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP1-23.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-4939" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP1-23-1024x682.jpg?resize=640%2C426" alt="2014HKP1-23" width="640" height="426" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">This was a tree where people could hang wishes and such on there.</figcaption></figure>
<figure id="attachment_4940" style="width: 384px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP1-24.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-4940" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014HKP1-24-682x1024.jpg?resize=384%2C576" alt="2014HKP1-24" width="384" height="576" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">And finally, you have me being goofy and pretending to eat the large doughnut sculpture we found in the shopping district.</figcaption></figure>
While Hong Kong was not a huge culture shock to me in regards to living standards (i.e., not much different from what you&#8217;d expect after living in the U.S.), it was still a magnificent cultural experience. And even though I was in Hong Kong for about 10 days, I still feel as if I&#8217;ve only experienced and saw only a fraction of what it had to offer.<br />
I hope that this post offered you a glimpse into the wonders that Hong Kong has to offer, but don&#8217;t worry, our journey is not yet done. Tomorrow I have a rather scrumptious post for you, so get your salivating glands ready!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/hong-kong-trip-part-1/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>15</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">4916</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Preparing for My Hong Kong Trip</title>
		<link>/preparing-hong-kong-trip/</link>
		<comments>/preparing-hong-kong-trip/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2014 15:58:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hong kong]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[international]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trip]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=4797</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I haven&#8217;t had a chance to really talk about this much, but I&#8217;m actually going to be headed to Hong Kong in less than a week! As you might expect, it&#8217;s been a busy rush to get all my ducks in line and make sure I don&#8217;t have any lingering things to do when I [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I haven&#8217;t had a chance to really talk about this much, but I&#8217;m actually going to be headed to Hong Kong in less than a week! As you might expect, it&#8217;s been a busy rush to get all my ducks in line and make sure I don&#8217;t have any lingering things to do when I leave.<br />
One of the things I&#8217;m pondering about however, is how I&#8217;m going to be utilizing my time during those long hours on the plane. I&#8217;m debating bringing a magnetic go set so I can use it on the plane, but then I worry that I&#8217;ll spill the bowls and all the pieces will go everywhere on the plane. Still a little on the fence about what I&#8217;m going to do, but so far it seems like I might just use it to do some serious life and death studying. I&#8217;m open to suggestions though!<br />
Most importantly, <strong>if ANYONE has any connections to people who play go in Hong Kong (or know a friend of a friend who might be able to help me out)</strong>, please let me know since I would love to be able to do at least one go related activity while in Hong Kong. It would be awesome if I could play with some locals and have something go-related to commemorate the trip with!<br />
I definitely will be doing a post on my Hong Kong trip after I get back, but I&#8217;m really hoping to have some go-related material in there if possible. Although worst case scenario, you&#8217;ll just have to endure numerous photos of food and stories instead. Guess that&#8217;s not so bad right? But it would definitely be epic if I could have at least one go anecdote in there, here&#8217;s to hoping&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/preparing-hong-kong-trip/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>16</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">4797</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
