<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>direction of play &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/direction-of-play/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>Book Review: Perceiving the Direction of Play</title>
		<link>/book-review-perceiving-direction-play/</link>
		<comments>/book-review-perceiving-direction-play/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2013 11:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[direction of play]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[heart of go series]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kobayashi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[whole board thinking]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=4144</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Perceiving the Direction of Play Description: In the first volume of The Heart of Go Series, Kobayashi Satoru 9P focuses on an important concept many players are unfamiliar with: the direction of play. As a critical component in any game, Satoru familiarizes the reader with direction of play though positions of his own games to [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/10/heartofgov1cover.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-4145" alt="heartofgov1cover" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/10/heartofgov1cover.jpg?resize=248%2C400" width="248" height="400" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">Perceiving the Direction of Play</h2>
<p><strong>Description:</strong> In the first volume of The Heart of Go Series, Kobayashi Satoru 9P focuses on an important concept many players are unfamiliar with: the direction of play. As a critical component in any game, Satoru familiarizes the reader with direction of play though positions of his own games to illustrate direction of play in regards to fuseki, joseki, and fighting. This is an advanced book that should be read after one already has a basic understanding of direction of play.<br />
<span id="more-4144"></span><br />
[expand title=&#8221;Book Details&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
[table]
Title, Perceiving the Direction of Play<br />
Series, Heart of Go Discovery Series<br />
Author, Kobayashi Satoru 9P<br />
Translators, Robert Terry<br />
Publisher, Hinoki Press<br />
Published, &#8220;June 2007&#8243;<br />
Language, English<br />
ISBN, 978-0-9788874-2-1<br />
Length, 225 Pages<br />
[/table]
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Table of Content&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Chapter 1 － Thinking About The Direction of Play of the Stones
<ul>
<li>The Future Potential of Moves</li>
<li>Towards a Wide Place</li>
<li>The Direction of Joseki</li>
<li>The Direction in the Fuseki (the Opening)</li>
<li>The Direction of Fighting</li>
<li>Before Fuseki Theory Was Developed</li>
<li>Game 1 &#8211; Sansa-Rigen (Black)</li>
<li>Game 2 &#8211; Sansa-Rigen (Black)</li>
<li>Game 3 &#8211; Sansa-Rigen (Black)</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Chapter 2 &#8211; The Direction of Joseki
<ul>
<li>Problem 1 &#8211; Which Empty Corner?</li>
<li>Problem 2 &#8211; Giving Up on a Territorial Framework</li>
<li>Problem 3 &#8211; A Corner Enclosure from a Star Point</li>
<li>Problem 4 &#8211; The Placement of an Attack on a Corner</li>
<li>Problem 5 &#8211; A Big Point or an Urgent Point</li>
<li>Problem 6 &#8211; Whole Board Balance</li>
<li>Problem 7 &#8211; Holding a Territorial Frameowrk in Check</li>
<li>Problem 8 &#8211; Dodging the Beck and Call</li>
<li>Problem 9 &#8211; A Lull in Joseki</li>
<li>Problem 10 &#8211; The Direction of an Attachment</li>
<li>Problem 11 &#8211; Within the Opponent&#8217;s Sphere</li>
<li>Problem 12 &#8211; The Motivation to Play a Variation</li>
<li>Problem 13 &#8211; Being Only Fearful</li>
<li>Problem 14 &#8211; Counterattacking Against the Beck and Call</li>
<li>Problem 15 &#8211; After Joseki</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Chapter 3 &#8211; The Direction of Fuseki (the Opening)
<ul>
<li>Problem 1 &#8211; Where Territorial Frameworks Meet</li>
<li>Problem 2 &#8211; A Fight for the Initiative</li>
<li>Problem 3 &#8211; Opposing Territorial Frameworks</li>
<li>Problem 4 &#8211; A One-Sided Territorial Framework</li>
<li>Problem 5 &#8211; Three Big Points</li>
<li>Problem 6 &#8211; Unfocused Direction</li>
<li>Problem 7 &#8211; Territorial Frameworks Above and Below</li>
<li>Problem 8 &#8211; A Reinforcement for the Future</li>
<li>Problem 9 &#8211; Making Effective Use of Thickness</li>
<li>Problem 10 &#8211; Judging Strength and Weakness</li>
<li>Problem 11 &#8211; Direction and Place</li>
<li>Problem 12 &#8211; Depending on the Strength and Weakness of Stones</li>
<li>Problem 13 &#8211; Consciousness of Thickness</li>
<li>Problem 14 &#8211; The Number of Stones</li>
<li>Problem 15 &#8211; The Balance of Territory</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Chapter 4 &#8211; The Direction of Fighting
<ul>
<li>Problem 1 &#8211; Which Side to Reinforce</li>
<li>Problem 2 &#8211; The Attack and Defense of Forcing Moves</li>
<li>Problem 3 &#8211; Territory of a Fight?</li>
<li>Problem 4 &#8211; Dodging the Beck and Call</li>
<li>Problem 5 &#8211; Attack or Defense?</li>
<li>Problem 6 &#8211; A Single Stone&#8217;s Course of Action</li>
<li>Problem 7 &#8211; Forcing Moves and Counterattacks</li>
<li>Problem 8 &#8211; A Momentary Opportunity</li>
<li>Problem 9 &#8211; The Course to Lay Out for an Attack</li>
<li>Problem 10 &#8211; Reinforcing for an Attack</li>
<li>Problem 11 &#8211; Before Defending</li>
<li>Problem 12 &#8211; The Move Order for Counterattacking</li>
<li>Problem 13 &#8211; Fuseki Moves or Fighting Moves</li>
<li>Problem 14 &#8211; Neutralizing or Laying Waste</li>
<li>Problem 15 &#8211; The Relationship Between Two Sides</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Before I Read This Book&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
I got this book long ago, but I purchased this book because I felt that I was very lost when it came to choosing the direction of play. So while my ability to determine the direction of play has improved since then, I still feel rather skittish about my abilities to determine the correct direction of play and hope that this book will provide some guidance for me.<br />
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;My Review&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221; expanded=&#8221;true&#8221;]
When I first started reading this book, I felt a little uneasy as I was hit with commentary that just felt way over my head. Fortunately though, that didn&#8217;t last too long. Once the commentary was finished, there were mini-sections that summarized Kobayashi Satoru 9P&#8217;s advice on the direction of joseki, fuseki, fighting, and so forth. Though not helpful for weaker players, they seem to be great reinforcement to players who already have a grasp on this topic.<br />
Fortunately, I could breathe a sigh of relief since the remainder of the book focused on utilizing a problem format. Being presented with a problem and then having its various options analyzed at least gave me a chance to comprehend something. Though by the time I finished the book, I can only say that I only made a small improvement in my overall ability with direction of play.<br />
As much as I would love to rain the book with accolades, I found the overall experience of the book to be laborious and not user-friendly. To start, it is not always clear which diagram is the correct answer to the problem. I know this sounds ridiculous, but there were numerous times where I read a diagram thinking it was the correct answer when it was not. The labelling was not consistent and it made for a confusing learning experience.<br />
In addition, the translation of the book is what I would label as &#8220;understandable if you work at it.&#8221; In other words, there are times when you have to pause and try to rearrange words or replace grammatical structures in hopes of trying to understand what is being said. Example: &#8220;White 1 leaves rights and interests on the right side&#8230;&#8221; Huh? In addition, the overall tone of the book is very matter of fact. This is great if you already have a strong foundation of go, but completely bewildering if you a weaker player trying to understand what is going on. Some might say that this is the nature of translated work, but I think that&#8217;s just a load of BS.<br />
So bottom line, I <em>do not</em> recommend this book for kyu players. Whole board thinking and direction of play is difficult as it is for kyu players, so it would a travesty if I let kyu players try and tackle this book only to be discouraged and have little to show for it at the end. It might be useful to dan players; but again, I cannot emphasize enough that the overall experience has a lot of room for improvement. You have been warned.<br />
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Synopsis&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<strong>What did I enjoy about the book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The primary content of the book utilizes a problem format.</li>
<li>The problems are from real games which adds to its practicality.</li>
<li>Satoru always includes a diagram to show how the problem arose from game play.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What did I gain from reading this book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>A minor confident boost in direction of play.</li>
<li>A slightly better understanding of how to determine the direction of play.</li>
<li>Realization of just how little I know about direction of play.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What is the format of the book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The first chapter consists of high level professional game commentary that I had a hard time following.</li>
<li>The rest of the content is structured as follows:
<ul>
<li>Diagram with directions on what you&#8217;re looking for.</li>
<li>A diagram that shows the course of the game and how the problem came about.</li>
<li>Usually about two to four variations and why they are wrong.</li>
<li>And somewhere in that mix is the correct answer.</li>
<li>A diagram or two with how the actual game proceeded afterwards.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What aspects can be improved on?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>My biggest complaint is that the correct answer is not always obvious. Sometimes it&#8217;s very clear since the diagram is labelled &#8220;The Correct Direction,&#8221; but there are numerous times where you have to sort out what&#8217;s right and what&#8217;s wrong. In fact, there were a couple times I thought the diagram I was reading was the correct answer when it was not actually so.</li>
<li>The translation is very terse. I recognize that there is are difficulties when it comes to translating since you want to keep as much of the language as authentic as possible, but it made it difficult to read or understand at times.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Is this book easy to read?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>No. Even though I&#8217;m a huge go enthusiast and English is my first language, I still found it rather laborious to work through this book. And to be clear, it&#8217;s not so much that the translation is difficult as a whole; but there are enough discreprancies here and there that it interferes with the overall experience of reading the book.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Bottom Line</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>Appropriate for players who already have an understanding of direction of play.</li>
<li>Translation makes the overall experience of the book more difficult which reduces the value of the book to kyu players.</li>
<li>Recommended for dan players.</li>
</ol>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Recommended For&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Players who already have an understanding of direction of play.</li>
<li>Dan players who are not too concerned with explanations since the moves more or less speak for themselves.</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Where Can I Buy It?&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>GoGameGuru &#8211; <a href="http://shop.gogameguru.com/perceiving-the-direction-of-play/?acc=e4da3b7fbbce2345d7772b0674a318d5">$22.99</a> (shipping and handling not included)</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Other Books in This Series&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;lastExpandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Heart of Go Series &#8211; Volume 1: Perceiving the Direction of Play</li>
<li>Heart of Go Series &#8211; Volume 2: Catching Scent of Victory</li>
<li>Heart of Go Series &#8211; Volume 3: Otake&#8217;s Secrets of Strategy</li>
<li>Heart of Go Series &#8211; Volume 4: Changing One&#8217;s Conceptions: Awaji&#8217;s Aphorisms</li>
<li>Heart of Go Series &#8211; Volume 5: The Way of Creating a Thick and Strong Game</li>
<li>Heart of Go Series &#8211; Volume 6: Zone Press Park</li>
<li>Heart of Go Series &#8211; Volume 7: Breakthrough Attacking Power Yamashita Style</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
<p style="text-align: center;"><em><strong>Last Updated on October 13th, 2013</strong></em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/book-review-perceiving-direction-play/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">4144</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Book Review: The Direction of Play</title>
		<link>/book-review-the-direction-of-play/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2013 09:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[direction of play]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fuseki]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[global thinking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[opening]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[strategy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[whole board strategy]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=2924</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[[expand title=&#8221;Book Details&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;] [table] Title, The Direction of Play Author, Takeo Kajiwara Translators, John Fairbairn and The Ishi Press Staff Publisher, Kiseido Published, &#8220;1st Edition &#8211; March 1979&#8243; Language, English ISBN, 978-4-896574-26-2 Length, 250 Pages [/table] [/expand] [expand title=&#8221;Table of Content&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;] Introduction Chapter 1: The Direction of Play in the Opening: The Corner Stones Chapter 2: The Early [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/07/directionofplaycover.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3058" alt="directionofplaycover" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/07/directionofplaycover.jpg?resize=251%2C400" width="251" height="400" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><br />
[expand title=&#8221;Book Details&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
[table]
Title, The Direction of Play<br />
Author, Takeo Kajiwara<br />
Translators, John Fairbairn and The Ishi Press Staff<br />
Publisher, <a title="Kiseido Home Page" href="http://www.kiseido.com/">Kiseido</a><br />
Published, &#8220;1st Edition &#8211; March 1979&#8243;<br />
Language, English<br />
ISBN, 978-4-896574-26-2<br />
Length, 250 Pages<br />
[/table]
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Table of Content&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Introduction</li>
<li>Chapter 1: The Direction of Play in the Opening: The Corner Stones</li>
<li>Chapter 2: The Early Stages Are Decisive</li>
<li>Chapter 3: Move Two Lost This Game</li>
<li>Chapter 4: The Professional Approach</li>
<li>Chapter 5: The Direction of Play and Joseki</li>
<li>Chapter 6: Once Upon a Game</li>
<li>Chapter 7: Test Yourself</li>
<li>Chapter 8: The Direction of Play for Fighting</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Synopsis&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221; expanded=&#8221;true&#8221;]
<ol>
<li>An excellent, although a bit advanced, book on direction of play.</li>
<li>Fills a much needed gap in understanding the opening and fuseki as a whole.</li>
<li>Requires a basic understanding of whole board thinking to really appreciate and understand the explanations.</li>
</ol>
[/expand]
<span id="more-2924"></span><br />
[expand title=&#8221;Before I Read This Book&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<strong>My Abilities</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>I had little to no understanding of direction of play. I had heard the term used a lot in my reviews, but my understanding of it was practically nonexistent and any proper application of direction of play was usually just due to sheer luck. Although in my defense, I did have a moderate understanding of whole board thinking which would provide a good stepping stone to understanding this book.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>My Perspective</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Since I was going pretty much blind into the subject, I was really hoping to gain a good grasp on direction of play and be able to apply it when I was finished with the book.</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;My Review&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221; expanded=&#8221;true&#8221;]
<strong>What did I enjoy about the book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Direction of play is broken down into very simple components that make it easier for the reader to follow.</li>
<li>Kajiwara&#8217;s writing style makes for an entertaining read and helps make the lesson more memorable.</li>
<li>Although it is rather advanced and kind of went over my head, the book even goes into an explanation on how direction of play impacts fighting in a game.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What did I gain from reading this book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>A much better understanding of direction of play.</li>
<li>Though far from perfect, my ability to apply direction of play in my games has greatly improved.</li>
<li>A much greater appreciation for how important the opening and fuseki is in a game.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What style of teaching does the book use?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Lecture Approach
<ul>
<li>While there are numerous diagrams to try and illustrate the Kajiwara&#8217;s point, the gold mine of information in this book lies in his explanations and opinions about direction of play.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Primary Learning Mechanism:
<ul>
<li>Explanations with diagrams.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Other Learning Mechanisms:
<ul>
<li>Examples from actual games</li>
<li>Practice problems</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What aspect(s) can be improved on?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>While I loved the explanations and accompanying diagrams, it would have been great to have more practice problems.</li>
<li>Introductory problems that utilize the multiple choice format would also be nice for people new to direction of play.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Is this book easy to read?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Yes. Although not as entertaining as Kageyama&#8217;s writing style, Kajiwara&#8217;s writing style was still fun to read and really helped to make me feel comfortable with a topic that was once completely foreign to me.</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Recommended For&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Players looking to learn more about direction of play, even if only to simply be exposed to its concepts.</li>
<li>A basic understanding of the opening and whole board thinking is recommended to really appreciate the book as a whole, but this should not be a deterrent since this is a book that players will read multiple times in their journey as a go player.</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Where Can I Buy It?&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;lastExpandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>GoGameGuru &#8211; <a title="Go Game Guru Purchase Link" href="http://shop.gogameguru.com/the-direction-of-play/?acc=e4da3b7fbbce2345d7772b0674a318d5">$17.99</a> (shipping &amp; handling not included)</li>
<li>Kiseido &#8211; <a href="http://www.kiseido.com/go_books.htm">$18.00</a> (shipping &amp; handling not included)</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
<p style="text-align: center;"><em><strong>Last Updated on July 7th, 2013</strong></em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2924</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
