<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>my cat plays baduk &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/my-cat-plays-baduk/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>Weekly Progress Report: #06</title>
		<link>/weekly-progress-report-06/</link>
		<comments>/weekly-progress-report-06/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2014 11:15:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Progress Reports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[my cat plays baduk]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5895</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Overview As I continue into the second stretch of non-stop hammering of work and attempts to sustain consistency, I’m happy to report that while I feel pretty winded, I don’t feel anything close to burnout yet. On top of that, I’ve actually come to realize that executing my routines first thing in the morning seem [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>Overview</h2>
<p>As I continue into the second stretch of non-stop hammering of work and attempts to sustain consistency, I’m happy to report that while I feel pretty winded, I don’t feel anything close to burnout yet. On top of that, I’ve actually come to realize that executing my routines first thing in the morning seem to work out pretty well for me. On days that I didn’t manage to do so usually resulted in a last minute scramble to get it done at the end of the night, but I’m hanging on as best I can.<br />
On the upside, it looks like my correspondence go playing has started to pickup to a nice pace. Considering the fact that I haven’t been able to play a game in real time this entire week, it’s definitely nice knowing that I’m still “playing” to some degree.<br />
In addition, I’ve been meaning to make this announcement for some time, but I wanted to give a big shoutout to a go blogger who joined the ranks recently: <a title="My Cat Plays Baduk" href="http://mycatplaysbaduk.wordpress.com/">My Cat Plays Baduk</a>. Though it only has been around for a little bit, she has written quite a few posts and is worth following. So be sure to check out her blog!<br />
Other than that, I’ll try to approach the next week with a bit more fervor in an attempt to prepare the content on the blog to grow in the future. And even though it already sounds a bit ambitious in my head, I’m going to see what I can do about trying to release at least one book review a week. No promises yet, but I’ll definitely see what I can do.<br />
See you next week!</p>
<h2>Daily Training Regimen</h2>
<ul>
<li>Solve 100 easy problems from MagicBaduk.</li>
<li>Complete 4 pages of problems (approximately 15-20 problems) from Jump Level Up.</li>
<li>Playing at least one game a day (which usually defaults to a 9&#215;9 game on GoQuest).</li>
</ul>
<h2>Books</h2>
<ul>
<li><em>Jump Level Up 2</em> by Baduktopia</li>
<li><em>Handicap-Go Strategy and the Sanrensei Opening</em>by by Rob van Zeijst and Richard Bozulich</li>
</ul>
<h2>Games</h2>
<ul>
<li><a title="KGS Website" href="http://www.gokgs.com/">KGS</a> &#8211; 0 games</li>
<li><a title="Online Go Server" href="http://www.online-go.com/">OGS</a> &#8211;  4 ongoing game</li>
<li><a title="Dave Peck’s Go Site" href="&quot;http://go.davepeck.org/“">Dave Peck’s Go Site</a> &#8211; 1 ongoing game</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/weekly-progress-report-06/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>14</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">5895</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
