<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"

	>
<channel>
	<title>Comments on: How to &#034;Teach&#034; Go</title>
	<atom:link href="/teach-go/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/teach-go/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2015 12:34:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
	<item>
		<title>By: Ben</title>
		<link>/teach-go/#comment-2444</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ben]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2014 22:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5541#comment-2444</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[You&#039;re welcome! I&#039;m glad to help clear up some things. Best of luck with everything!]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>You&#8217;re welcome! I&#8217;m glad to help clear up some things. Best of luck with everything!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Daurak</title>
		<link>/teach-go/#comment-2443</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Daurak]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2014 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5541#comment-2443</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Wow, Thanks a bunch.  I definitely was &quot;teaching&quot;, and too much information.  I now remember when I first started and how it was hard for me to remember to place stones on the points of the grid, how corners and edges were awkward, and how a bunch of the other concepts were learned through practice, and not talk.  Thanks so much and I am definitely going to get into &quot;playing&quot; go rather than &quot;teaching&quot;.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Wow, Thanks a bunch.  I definitely was &#8220;teaching&#8221;, and too much information.  I now remember when I first started and how it was hard for me to remember to place stones on the points of the grid, how corners and edges were awkward, and how a bunch of the other concepts were learned through practice, and not talk.  Thanks so much and I am definitely going to get into &#8220;playing&#8221; go rather than &#8220;teaching&#8221;.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Ben</title>
		<link>/teach-go/#comment-2442</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ben]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 13 Jul 2014 16:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5541#comment-2442</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Thanks Todd! I guess I need to update the guide to clarify, but it&#039;s really meant as a skeleton for someone to follow. I&#039;m a big believer in customizing the teaching experience to every student. However, with so many people messing up when introducing new players to go, I wrote this article to give a blanket rule for a baseline for people to build off of. I figured, if people just followed what I wrote, nothing could go wrong.
After all, it&#039;s hard to teach people to be able to identify when someone is ready for life and death or needs it. So at the bare minimum, people won&#039;t mess up the majority of people they teach. But once again, I totally agree that the advanced topics should be introduced depending on the level of interest of the new player.
Education has always been a field that I&#039;ve had great interest in, so it&#039;s really funny that you should bring it up. For now, channelling my passion for teaching through go seems to be the best way to bring all my interests together! ]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Thanks Todd! I guess I need to update the guide to clarify, but it&#8217;s really meant as a skeleton for someone to follow. I&#8217;m a big believer in customizing the teaching experience to every student. However, with so many people messing up when introducing new players to go, I wrote this article to give a blanket rule for a baseline for people to build off of. I figured, if people just followed what I wrote, nothing could go wrong.<br />
After all, it&#8217;s hard to teach people to be able to identify when someone is ready for life and death or needs it. So at the bare minimum, people won&#8217;t mess up the majority of people they teach. But once again, I totally agree that the advanced topics should be introduced depending on the level of interest of the new player.<br />
Education has always been a field that I&#8217;ve had great interest in, so it&#8217;s really funny that you should bring it up. For now, channelling my passion for teaching through go seems to be the best way to bring all my interests together! </p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Ben</title>
		<link>/teach-go/#comment-2441</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ben]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 13 Jul 2014 16:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5541#comment-2441</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Interesting. I do hope to do more random demos of the game around town when I have a chance, but most of my experience comes from volunteering at Japanese or Chinese festivals where people have a genuine interest to learn about the game whenever they stop by. I&#039;ll be sure to update this guide when I have more experience with sitting around in random places!]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Interesting. I do hope to do more random demos of the game around town when I have a chance, but most of my experience comes from volunteering at Japanese or Chinese festivals where people have a genuine interest to learn about the game whenever they stop by. I&#8217;ll be sure to update this guide when I have more experience with sitting around in random places!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Todd Lee Rainey</title>
		<link>/teach-go/#comment-2440</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Todd Lee Rainey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 13 Jul 2014 05:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5541#comment-2440</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Love the post; this is especially relevant to me, as I pretty much have to teach any people who I want to play in my area.
I would caution a categorical avoidance of life and death; many of the people I have met and taught Go to are students, who relish the feeling of &quot;high concept&quot; stuff. I generally teach that &quot;the basic point is, surround territory without getting yourself captured. Then the game gets really interesting when you involve life and death.&quot;
Having said that, you are right that when teaching, we shouldn&#039;t rush to kill groups. But hopefully, they might spot that one of their groups didn&#039;t make a second eye at the end of the game - for them to discover it without it pointed out to them is a pretty big victory, especially if the stakes of the game are very low.
Otherwise, much of what you said is in line with the best lit we have on education; people are most motivated to learn when they get hooked on a subject, and that usually happens when there is a clear and easy point of entry. Don&#039;t rule out a career in education! :P]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Love the post; this is especially relevant to me, as I pretty much have to teach any people who I want to play in my area.<br />
I would caution a categorical avoidance of life and death; many of the people I have met and taught Go to are students, who relish the feeling of &#8220;high concept&#8221; stuff. I generally teach that &#8220;the basic point is, surround territory without getting yourself captured. Then the game gets really interesting when you involve life and death.&#8221;<br />
Having said that, you are right that when teaching, we shouldn&#8217;t rush to kill groups. But hopefully, they might spot that one of their groups didn&#8217;t make a second eye at the end of the game &#8211; for them to discover it without it pointed out to them is a pretty big victory, especially if the stakes of the game are very low.<br />
Otherwise, much of what you said is in line with the best lit we have on education; people are most motivated to learn when they get hooked on a subject, and that usually happens when there is a clear and easy point of entry. Don&#8217;t rule out a career in education! 😛</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Tim Cox</title>
		<link>/teach-go/#comment-2439</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tim Cox]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Jul 2014 19:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5541#comment-2439</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I&#039;ve had many people walk up to me and ask what the game is called. I always wonder to myself &quot;Do they really care?&quot; because they never show up the next week or so forth to show their interest. After getting the answer, I am sure they forget about the game later lol]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve had many people walk up to me and ask what the game is called. I always wonder to myself &#8220;Do they really care?&#8221; because they never show up the next week or so forth to show their interest. After getting the answer, I am sure they forget about the game later lol</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Ben</title>
		<link>/teach-go/#comment-2438</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ben]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Jul 2014 10:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5541#comment-2438</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Great point about keeping our &quot;enthusiasm&quot; in check since it can make the time spent on the game seem rather daunting. For me personally, I&#039;ve used the ranking system as more of a cool trivia aspect of go to show how players of different ranks can even out the game with handicap stones so it can be challenging for both sides.
Most of my teaching experience is usually in fairs and festivals or sorts, so it&#039;s not as easy to get players to play one another since usually space and equipment is limited. In addition, with the time and flood of people coming in and out, the 9x9 board is really the only option since I usually want to give as many people a chance at learning as possible. But I would definitely love to see what it&#039;s like to get two beginners in a room to test out some of your techniques as well!
Thanks for the feedback and advice!]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Great point about keeping our &#8220;enthusiasm&#8221; in check since it can make the time spent on the game seem rather daunting. For me personally, I&#8217;ve used the ranking system as more of a cool trivia aspect of go to show how players of different ranks can even out the game with handicap stones so it can be challenging for both sides.<br />
Most of my teaching experience is usually in fairs and festivals or sorts, so it&#8217;s not as easy to get players to play one another since usually space and equipment is limited. In addition, with the time and flood of people coming in and out, the 9&#215;9 board is really the only option since I usually want to give as many people a chance at learning as possible. But I would definitely love to see what it&#8217;s like to get two beginners in a room to test out some of your techniques as well!<br />
Thanks for the feedback and advice!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Guesulator</title>
		<link>/teach-go/#comment-2437</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Guesulator]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2014 19:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5541#comment-2437</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[As someone who has struggled over the past year explaining not only GO, but bitcoin to people, and &quot;teaching&quot; people all about both.  I think another key point is to sort of &quot;play it cool&quot; in a way.  Being considered an &quot;enthusiast&quot; makes you already seem like you need to give something a lot of time and attention to become good at it, thus, people are less likely to continue giving it that second shot BECAUSE they think it takes an enthusiast to play it (or to understand it).  Even a 20k &quot;enthusiast&quot; knows that this is partially true, but teaching new players about outlining territory, and then &quot;staying solid/strong&quot; and using a lot of metaphors to explain seem to work better.
I like to get two beginners in a room to play it and once they understand capturing and surrounding territory, the classic &quot;ladder and net&quot; example, and then they are off to the races.  Its cool seeing their eyes light up when they solve the ladder problem.  But I like to ask questions like &quot;OH You just going to TAKE that?  Thems fightin words!&quot;  Or something like &quot;She just touched your stones, and not in a good way!&quot;
One of my favourite things to ask when playing GO is &quot;Well, how does it look?  What looks like yours and mine?  How would you fight to keep it?  What if I wanted more than I deserve?  Should I be punished for it?  Should you put up a fight on a stone that looks lonely in your territory?
I will say, I&#039;m not a fan on 9x9 in teaching games, I think 13x13 has a lot more of the &quot;GO spirit&quot; in it, so I like to teach on that, but one thing I try not to do is abuse cutting points TOO severly.  I will cut, and tell them why I cut, but there are some BRUTAL cuts I see sometimes that I just shelf.  The classic two stone third line cut is a nice way to show newbies how to &quot;stay strong&quot;, but cuts more severe than that I try and avoid.
Anyway, good read, it has me thinking of ways to retool teaching the newbs!  Cheers!]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As someone who has struggled over the past year explaining not only GO, but bitcoin to people, and &#8220;teaching&#8221; people all about both.  I think another key point is to sort of &#8220;play it cool&#8221; in a way.  Being considered an &#8220;enthusiast&#8221; makes you already seem like you need to give something a lot of time and attention to become good at it, thus, people are less likely to continue giving it that second shot BECAUSE they think it takes an enthusiast to play it (or to understand it).  Even a 20k &#8220;enthusiast&#8221; knows that this is partially true, but teaching new players about outlining territory, and then &#8220;staying solid/strong&#8221; and using a lot of metaphors to explain seem to work better.<br />
I like to get two beginners in a room to play it and once they understand capturing and surrounding territory, the classic &#8220;ladder and net&#8221; example, and then they are off to the races.  Its cool seeing their eyes light up when they solve the ladder problem.  But I like to ask questions like &#8220;OH You just going to TAKE that?  Thems fightin words!&#8221;  Or something like &#8220;She just touched your stones, and not in a good way!&#8221;<br />
One of my favourite things to ask when playing GO is &#8220;Well, how does it look?  What looks like yours and mine?  How would you fight to keep it?  What if I wanted more than I deserve?  Should I be punished for it?  Should you put up a fight on a stone that looks lonely in your territory?<br />
I will say, I&#8217;m not a fan on 9&#215;9 in teaching games, I think 13&#215;13 has a lot more of the &#8220;GO spirit&#8221; in it, so I like to teach on that, but one thing I try not to do is abuse cutting points TOO severly.  I will cut, and tell them why I cut, but there are some BRUTAL cuts I see sometimes that I just shelf.  The classic two stone third line cut is a nice way to show newbies how to &#8220;stay strong&#8221;, but cuts more severe than that I try and avoid.<br />
Anyway, good read, it has me thinking of ways to retool teaching the newbs!  Cheers!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Ben</title>
		<link>/teach-go/#comment-2436</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ben]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2014 19:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5541#comment-2436</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Wait you&#039;ve actually encountered this in real life before?]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Wait you&#8217;ve actually encountered this in real life before?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: asdfhh</title>
		<link>/teach-go/#comment-2435</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[asdfhh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2014 19:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5541#comment-2435</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Oh god I hear that M&#038;M&#039;s comment from literally *every* person unfamiliar with go who sees me playing. I think I might go insane.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Oh god I hear that M&amp;M&#8217;s comment from literally *every* person unfamiliar with go who sees me playing. I think I might go insane.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
</channel>
</rss>
