<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>bad habits &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/bad-habits/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>Impulsive Recklessness</title>
		<link>/impulsive-recklessness/</link>
		<comments>/impulsive-recklessness/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2013 20:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bad habits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[impulsive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[obstacle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reckless]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=3850</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Last night I had the pleasure of playing fellow go twitter friend goBum. For our first game against one another, I thought it was exciting and a lot of fun. Afterwards though, we were severely reminded of the numerous mistakes that occurred throughout the game. Of the two of us though, I would have to say [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Last night I had the pleasure of playing fellow go twitter friend <a href="http://www.twitter.com/gobum">goBum</a>. For our first game against one another, I thought it was exciting and a lot of fun. Afterwards though, we were severely reminded of the numerous mistakes that occurred throughout the game. Of the two of us though, I would have to say that my play was probably the most shameful. Haha. And if you&#8217;re wondering what kind of moves I&#8217;m talking about, I mean the whole gamut of making empty triangles that are thank you moves along with playing impulsive moves that are the equivalent of passing. Needless to say, I got what I deserved when it came to verbal bashing. Haha. xD<br />
Since I&#8217;m a glutton for punishment, I decided to also show the game to sensei today. As I expected, the feedback wasn&#8217;t much better from his end either. Haha. However, he pointed out a critical flaw in my play: I still play from a pressured player mindset. In other words, I get so entangled in myself that I fail to analyze the board correctly. I fail to separate myself from what is happening on the board. Instead of calm analysis of what&#8217;s going on, any slight deviation from what I expected led to me feeling like it as a personal failure instead of a simple change on the board to be accounted for. As a result, the impulsive and reckless moves that plague my game are inevitable.<br />
To separate myself from the game when I play&#8230; What a cumbersome obstacle I have in my way&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/impulsive-recklessness/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3850</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remember to Breathe</title>
		<link>/remember-to-breathe/</link>
		<comments>/remember-to-breathe/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2013 16:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bad habits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[boxing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[breathing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kyu players]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[whole board thinking]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=3819</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A couple days ago, I was doing some mitt work with my partner at the local boxing gym. About halfway into the round, I was getting visibly tired and close to exhaustion from trying to push beyond my limits. It was then though, that my partner said something that struck me: Remember to breathe. Control [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A couple days ago, I was doing some mitt work with my partner at the local boxing gym. About halfway into the round, I was getting visibly tired and close to exhaustion from trying to push beyond my limits. It was then though, that my partner said something that struck me:</p>
<blockquote><p>Remember to breathe. Control your breathing.</p></blockquote>
<p>Seems like such an obvious statement no? After all, don&#8217;t we all breathe subconsciously? Without breathing, we&#8217;d all be dead! What a stupid thing to say!<br />
If you think such crude and rudimentary thoughts though, you are missing the point. The fact is that while I might have been &#8220;breathing,&#8221; the fact is that I was so caught up in punching and keeping good form that I forgot to breathe half the time. You might exclaim, &#8220;How does one forget to breathe Ben? That&#8217;s ridiculous!&#8221; And you&#8217;re right to some extent, but instead of breathing more efficiently through my nose and exhaling through my mouth, I was holding my breath half the time (without even realizing it due to concentrating so hard on punching and maintaing form) and taking short gasps of air with my mouth in between. It&#8217;s no wonder that I was winded and at the point of near collapse before the round was even halfway through.<br />
So how does this relate to go?<br />
The reason I went to great lengths to explain breathing in boxing is because it occurred to me that a similar thing was happening to kyu players. Instead of breathing however, I would make the analogy that kyu players often players fail to play moves with the whole board in mind. Similar to breathing, it is a given that every move that is played affects the board in some way shape or form. However, if we just play moves without making a conscious effort to understand or give it a purpose in regard to the entire board, it is just as if we are going through the motions of punching without remembering to breathe properly. And then the next thing you know, you&#8217;re out of breath and your opponent cuts off a big group and delivers the knockout punch.<br />
Of course with time and experience, playing moves with respect to the entire board will be second nature; but while we still remain the weak kyu players that we are, we must be sure to make a conscious effort to take the entire board into consideration at all times. So to put my partner&#8217;s advice into another context:</p>
<blockquote><p>Remember to consider the board as a whole before playing your next move.</p></blockquote>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/remember-to-breathe/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3819</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Book Review: How Not to Play Go</title>
		<link>/book-review-how-not-to-play-go/</link>
		<comments>/book-review-how-not-to-play-go/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2013 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bad habits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how not to play go]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kyu players]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[misconceptions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stuck]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wishful thinking]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=132</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[How Not to Play Go Description: Zhou clarifies the common kyu level misunderstandings of how to play which hold kyu players back from reaching dan level. The principles involved are not difficult to understand and Zhou clarifies them by giving detailed analyses of how they are being ignored in three different games between kyu level [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2010/09/hntpgcover.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2977" alt="hntpgcover" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2010/09/hntpgcover.jpg?resize=300%2C455" width="300" height="455" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">How Not to Play Go</h2>
<p><strong>Description:</strong> Zhou clarifies the common kyu level misunderstandings of how to play which hold kyu players back from reaching dan level. The principles involved are not difficult to understand and Zhou clarifies them by giving detailed analyses of how they are being ignored in three different games between kyu level players.<br />
<span id="more-132"></span><br />
[expand title=&#8221;Book Details&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
[table]
Title, How Not to Play Go<br />
Author, Yuan Zhou<br />
Publisher, <a href="http://www.slateandshell.com/">Slate &amp; Shell</a><br />
Published, &#8220;2009&#8221;<br />
Language, English<br />
ISBN, 1-932001-52-2<br />
Length, 32 Pages<br />
[/table]
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Table of Content&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Introduction</li>
<li>Chapter One: Common Misunderstandings</li>
<li>Chapter Two: An 8 Kyu Game</li>
<li>Chapter Three: A 4 Kyu Game</li>
<li>Chapter Four: A 1 Kyu vs. 2 Kyu Game</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Synopsis&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<strong>What did I enjoy about the book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The explanation regarding the principles that players constantly violate are explained very clearly and are very easy to understand.</li>
<li>The game diagrams are short and easy to follow.</li>
<li>The game commentaries range from 8 kyu up to 1 kyu.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What did I gain from reading this book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>A better understanding of potential flaws in my play.</li>
<li>A new list of questions to ask myself before playing each move.</li>
<li>An awareness of how careful I must be in order to not to fall into the typical mistakes of a kyu player.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What style of teaching does the book use?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Game Commentary Style
<ul>
<li>Utilizes game records to illustrate the author&#8217;s message.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Primary Learning Mechanism:
<ul>
<li>Game commentaries</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Other Learning Mechanisms:
<ul>
<li>Short chapter explaining the general principles of how not to play go.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What aspect can be improved on?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>I would have liked to see some practice problems to reinforce the concepts that Zhou tries to illustrate.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Is this book easy to read?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Yes. The explanation was easy to understand. In addition, the game diagrams were relatively short in length and easy to follow.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Bottom Line</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>A short and concise book on common misconceptions kyu players have.</li>
<li>Presents concepts that many kyu players would benefit from.</li>
<li>Uses game reviews as the primary teaching mechanism.</li>
</ol>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Before I Read This Book&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<strong>My Abilities</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>I&#8217;ve read a fair share of books and feel decently knowledgeable about the basic tactics and strategy of the game.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>My Perspective</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>As a kyu player, I am still trying to figure out what&#8217;s wrong with my play so that I can traverse into the dan levels. So I&#8217;m hoping this book will shed some light on that.</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;My Review&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221; expanded=&#8221;true&#8221;]
The first chapter, which explains the misconceptions players have when playing go, is not particularly long; but the information is absolutely critical. The beauty of it all is that it&#8217;s delivered in an extremely concise manner. No wading through a ton of terms just to understand what 1+1 is.<br />
In addition, while incorporating principles of play into his analysis, a second aspect that I absolutely love in these chapters is the fact that we get to find out why the players played the way they did. (I don&#8217;t know about you, but that really helps to make me feel less alienated since I&#8217;m like, &#8220;Hey! I&#8217;ve thought that too before!&#8221;) Once you are given the player&#8217;s reasoning (e.g. Black felt that white&#8217;s area was too big), Zhou gives immediate explanation for why it is faulty. SCORE!<br />
I also have to admit that it is actually more advanced that I thought when I first bought it. I&#8217;m not sure whether it&#8217;s just me, but I have always found example games to be rather hard to learn from since the reviews tend to require a well rounded understanding of all go basics in order for the game review to make much sense. As a result, the only real critique I have for the book is that it should be revised to be more robust with practice problems (or multiple choice questions) to further help reinforce the principles that so many kyu players violate.<br />
Overall though, I would still have to say that Zhou does a great job trying to provide some guidance for kyu players on habits that most players fail to realize are holding them back. I can definitely say that I still fall victim to some of the things that Zhou talks about. Definitely worth purchasing if you&#8217;re a kyu player and feel stuck no matter how many new tactics and tesujis you learn.<br />
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Recommended For&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Kyu players who feel they have hit a wall in their progress.</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Where Can I Buy It?&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;lastExpandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Slate &amp; Shell &#8211; <a href="http://www.slateandshell.com/SSYZ011.html">$8.50</a> USD (shipping and handling not included)</li>
<li>SmartGo Books &#8211; <a href="http://www.smartgo.com/books.htm">$3.99</a> USD (e-Book)</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
<p style="text-align: center;"><em><strong>Last Updated on August 4th, 2013</strong></em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/book-review-how-not-to-play-go/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">132</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Going On Tilt</title>
		<link>/going-on-tilt/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 13:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Weekly Go Wednesday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bad habits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emotional state]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emotions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[frustration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[on tilt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[poker]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=2203</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Weekly Go Wednesday #20 For those who are not familiar with the realm of poker (or gambling in general), going on tilt refers to a emotionally wild state where a player is prone to make irrational decisions and often ends in their unfortunate demise. To illustrate, imagine that you have a straight flush (5-6-7-8-9), which [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 style="text-align: center;">Weekly Go Wednesday #20</h2>
<figure id="attachment_2223" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/03/wgw19.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-2223" alt="Credit SilverOakCasino" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/03/wgw19.jpg?resize=300%2C225" width="300" height="225" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Credit SilverOakCasino</figcaption></figure>
For those who are not familiar with the realm of poker (or gambling in general), going on tilt refers to a emotionally wild state where a player is prone to make irrational decisions and often ends in their unfortunate demise.<br />
To illustrate, imagine that you have a straight flush (5-6-7-8-9), which happens to be second best hand that a player can have in the game. Mathematically speaking, the odds of your opponents having the royal flush (which is the best hand) is so slim that it&#8217;s practically not worth mentioning. To sweeten the deal, none of your opponents have any idea that you have this amazing hand and you&#8217;ve reeled them in for a ton of money. When time comes to show the cards, you find out that the impossible has happened: one of your opponents has the royal flush and cleans you out.<br />
In a fit of rage and frustration, you go to get more cash and start to play wildly and bet aggressively in an attempt to win back what &#8220;should have&#8221; been yours. Over the next few hours, not only do you fail to win any money back, but now you are in a bit of debt and in the most terrible of moods. That is what going &#8220;on tilt&#8221; is. And it is no different with go.<br />
<span id="more-2203"></span><br />
There are three main scenarios that cause players to go on tilt:</p>
<ol>
<li>Losing a won game.</li>
<li><span style="line-height: 13px;">Losing because of a mistake.</span></li>
<li>Losing because a large group was captured.</li>
</ol>
<p>Each time a player goes on tilt, a general cycle will occur: (1) The player will rush to play another game. (2) In order to &#8220;<a href="http://idioms.thefreedictionary.com/save+face">save face</a>,&#8221; they try to crush their opponent even though it is a completely different opponent than before. (3) They start to go on a losing streak, which only causes them to spiral further downwards. (4) They get fed up with go.<br />
As I said, aside from the fact that go games generally don&#8217;t consist of losing money, it&#8217;s practically one and the same. It&#8217;s a dangerous emotional state that will only do you harm and never any good.<br />
If you&#8217;re still not convinced though, here are three reasons why going on tilt is nothing but bad news:</p>
<ol>
<li><span style="line-height: 13px;"><strong>You will try to kill everything.</strong> For 99% of players out there, there is no greater euphoric feeling than killing off a large group. And since you&#8217;re on tilt and looking to try and make yourself feel better, the allure to kill will just be too strong. Unfortunately, killing things is not as easy as it looks. So instead of feeling better, odds are pretty good that you&#8217;ll end up overextending your attack and resigning when it is your group that dies instead.</span></li>
<li><strong>You start to play by impulse.</strong> No matter how strong your fundamentals are, unless you are a sandbagger, there is no way in hell that your opponent (who is a similar skill level to you) will make the mistakes you will make when playing impulse moves. Your opponent will be reading. You will not. And in case you haven&#8217;t put two and two together, that will spell out disaster for you.</li>
<li><strong>It&#8217;s only going to get worse.</strong> Although there is the rare occasion that you demolish your first opponent and then feel relieved and thus get out of tilt, most of the time you are only going to find yourself spiraling down into the abyss that we all know as a losing streak. And in the worst case scenario, it might get so bad that you just end up quitting go all together.</li>
</ol>
<p>In my journey thus far, these are some of the things I discovered on how to prevent yourself from going on tilt:</p>
<ol>
<li><span style="line-height: 13px;"><strong>Take a break before playing your next game.</strong> Even if it&#8217;s only five minutes, doing something like getting up and washing your face to clear your head will help to calm you down.</span></li>
<li><strong>Do some pushups and shadowbox.</strong> Especially if you&#8217;re feeling very frustrated, some physical activity will help to blow off some steam. Not to mention, exercise is good for you anyways! Although I will note that you should take a couple minutes after to calm down from the adrenaline.</li>
<li><strong>Let go of the emotional attachment to winning and losing.</strong> I know I&#8217;m starting to get in to philosophy territory, but I&#8217;m being perfectly serious. After all, going on tilt is rooted in the egocentric idea of having things go your way. And if you&#8217;re able to achieve this, the benefits you&#8217;ll see in your go and the rest of your life will be astounding.</li>
</ol>
<p>I know that #3 is rather abstract; but don&#8217;t worry, I will write more on this in next week&#8217;s post. So stay tuned. Meanwhile, I pose the following question to you:</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>How do you deal with / prevent going on tilt?</strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2203</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>To Resign or Not to Resign</title>
		<link>/to-resign-or-not-to-resign/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2013 14:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Weekly Go Wednesday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bad habits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kyu players]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[resigning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[when to resign]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=1904</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Weekly Go Wednesday, Issue #18 As most of us are aware, the game of go is rather unique in the sense that it is considered honorable to resign. Unfortunately, when it comes to kyu players (particularly mid-SDK&#8217;s and below), I have found that resignation is the bane of their existence. Instead of resignation being a [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 style="text-align: center;">Weekly Go Wednesday, Issue #18</h2>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/02/gobanwhiteflag.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2120" alt="gobanwhiteflag" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/02/gobanwhiteflag.jpg?resize=300%2C300" width="300" height="300" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></p>
<p>As most of us are aware, the game of go is rather unique in the sense that it is considered honorable to resign. Unfortunately, when it comes to kyu players (particularly mid-SDK&#8217;s and below), I have found that resignation is the bane of their existence. Instead of resignation being a quiet acknowledgment of their opponent&#8217;s strength, it becomes a self-imposed obstacle that prevents kyu players from getting stronger. If you don&#8217;t believe me, read on.<br />
<span id="more-1904"></span><br />
I&#8217;ve watched my fair share of games, and more often than not, all it takes to get kyu players to resign is the capture of a decent sized group. Granted, the loss of a group can be difficult to swallow for kyu players, but this is by no means a reason to give up on the game as a whole. After all, just because you lost one battle doesn&#8217;t mean you lost the war. As if that wasn&#8217;t enough, the resignations tend to occur in the early to middle game stages. Have players forgotten that endgame can make a huge difference in terms of who wins the game?<br />
While this is by no means an absolute guideline for when to resign as a kyu player, there are only three reasons when a player should resign in casual games:</p>
<ol>
<li><span style="line-height: 13px;"><strong>You&#8217;re just plodding along hoping for some monumentally huge error on your opponent&#8217;s part.</strong> If you&#8217;re doing this, it&#8217;s time to resign, take a break, and come back with a renewed spirit for your next game. </span></li>
<li><strong>Your group which took up half the board died.</strong> In this case, obviously the battle became the war. So no point wasting any more time.</li>
<li><strong>You can legitimately count and you know that you can&#8217;t catch up.</strong> Although if you can and have the patience to do this, you probably don&#8217;t have this tendency anyways.</li>
</ol>
<p>Otherwise, it is critical to remember that there is a lot to be said about seeing a game through to the end. Just because you feel behind doesn&#8217;t mean it&#8217;s time to go running to the resign button. In fact, one of the greatest accomplishments a player can have is being able to reverse a game to his/her favor. After all, who doesn&#8217;t love a good underdog story?<br />
So the next time you are thinking about resigning when things are looking bad, remember the following:</p>
<ol>
<li><span style="line-height: 13px;"><strong>These are the best opportunities to learn how to come back from behind</strong>. Even if you can&#8217;t reverse the game entirely, being able to close the gap is a critical skill that will become a dangerous weapon in your arsenal in your future. After all, if all your games are won or loss through resignation, when do you ever plan on practicing your endgame?</span></li>
<li><strong>It will become a terrible habit that will cause you to start resigning games where you are actually ahead.</strong> That&#8217;s right. You heard me. That habit of running off with your tail in between your legs just because you feel frustrated or badly is only going to cause unnecessary resignations in the future. So don&#8217;t do it. Just stop.</li>
<li><b>You start to get used to winning or losing by resignation. </b>This is especially bad for people who plan on playing in tournaments because I will tell you one thing for sure, people will go down fighting tooth and nail in tournaments. Being able to &#8220;win a won game&#8221; or &#8220;turning the tables&#8221; becomes critical in every game that you will play. And since you can&#8217;t control your opponents, the least you can do is reduce the frequency of you resigning your own games.</li>
</ol>
<p>Never forget that it is better to lose by a lot than never having fought at all. Do not cave in and resign easily, fight on till there is nothing left!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1904</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Thou Shalt Not Kill&#8230;</title>
		<link>/thou-shalt-not-kill/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2013 22:30:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lessons]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bad habits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[focus on profit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[overly aggressive]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=1686</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Lately, I have noticed that my games have become quite violent. =D And by that, I mean that the theme of my games are: threaten to make a huge moyo, and then kill whatever comes inside of it. While it lets me know that I will win with absolute certainty if I manage to kill [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lately, I have noticed that my games have become quite violent. =D And by that, I mean that the theme of my games are: threaten to make a huge moyo, and then kill whatever comes inside of it.<br />
While it lets me know that I will win with absolute certainty if I manage to kill the group, we all know that this strategy is extremely flawed and is extremely risky. And as if the fact that you will lose most of your games trying to do this wasn&#8217;t bad enough, I just get more discouraged and frustrated as time goes on. So I know that if I continue along this path, I will end up getting fed up and dropping go for no good reason.<br />
So the goal now is to train myself to steer away from that style of play. It&#8217;s not that I will be meek and never fight back, but I will focus on giving my attacks an edge that sends my opponents running while I gain the necessary points to win. For now, I will focus on a profit oriented style instead of the killing style that I am so habituated to. So in terms of the criteria for my games for a while:</p>
<ol>
<li>I will practice attacking while gaining profit.</li>
<li><span style="line-height: 13px">I shall not kill any group unless they are forced into a shape where I am absolutely sure of its demise (e.g., bent in three).</span></li>
</ol>
<p>And to continue a new tradition that frozensoul recommended to me, I will start a repetition exercise of writing any new go lesson I am trying to learn fifty times. By doing so, I&#8217;m hoping that it will sink it better than simply reading once and trying to remember amidst a game.<br />
<figure id="attachment_1687" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/01/lesson3.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1687" alt="&quot;Focus on profit, not killing.&quot;" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/01/lesson3.jpg?resize=300%2C225" width="300" height="225" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">&#8220;Focus on profit, not killing.&#8221;</figcaption></figure>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1686</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
