<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>Progress Reports &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/progress-reports/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>Weekly Go Progress: Week #15</title>
		<link>/weekly-go-progress-week-15/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 22:32:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Progress Reports]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=6305</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Overview I have to say that if you asked me two weeks ago whether or not I&#8217;d be in the midst of getting the go blog back and running, I would have told you that you were crazy because I was in the middle of five other things. Nonetheless, here we are and I&#8217;m very [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>Overview</h2>
<p>I have to say that if you asked me two weeks ago whether or not I&#8217;d be in the midst of getting the go blog back and running, I would have told you that you were crazy because I was in the middle of five other things. Nonetheless, here we are and I&#8217;m very happy to be back in the thick of things.</p>
<p>This week has been focused on simply getting reacquainted with everything again. That means figuring out the apps I&#8217;m using to train, books to read, styles to study, trends I missed, and other things as well. That said, it&#8217;s been wonderful seeing familiar faces in the community again and I can&#8217;t wait to settle into another step towards gaining that next stone.</p>
<h2>Training Regimen</h2>
<ul>
<li>Review a professional game every one to two days</li>
<li>Practice about 20-30 basic / easy go problems every day</li>
<li>Studying with frozensoul</li>
</ul>
<h2>Games</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://online-go.com/user/view/549/BenGoZen">OGS</a> &#8211;  3 ongoing games</li>
</ul>
<h2>Currently Reading</h2>
<ul>
<li>Commented Games by Lee Sedol, Vol. 3 by Lee Sedol 9P and Lee Sena</li>
<li>Positional Judgment by Cho-Chikun 9P</li>
</ul>
<h2>Reflections</h2>
<ol>
<li>With the incredible development in AI, it&#8217;s fascinating to see the entire world of go now being thrown into a new exploration of creativity as things once deemed &#8220;bad moves&#8221; are now being seen in a new light.</li>
</ol>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">6305</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Weekly Status Report: #12</title>
		<link>/weekly-status-report-12/</link>
		<comments>/weekly-status-report-12/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2015 13:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Progress Reports]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5961</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Overview With 2015 upon us, I wanted to start off right by kicking off the status reports again since they are a great way for me to keep myself accountable to what’s been happening. As you’ll notice, the training regimen has returned to its simplest form. This is primarily due to the desire to stay [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>Overview</h2>
<p>With 2015 upon us, I wanted to start off right by kicking off the status reports again since they are a great way for me to keep myself accountable to what’s been happening. As you’ll notice, the training regimen has returned to its simplest form. This is primarily due to the desire to stay the course without any wavering. So while this report is a little bare, I’m certainly hoping to grow it in time. Hope you all had a great New Years!</p>
<h2>Daily Training Regimen</h2>
<ul>
<li>Do 2 pages of Jump Level Up series.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Books</h2>
<ul>
<li><em>Jump Level Up 3</em> by Baduktopia</li>
<li><em>Handicap-Go Strategy and the Sanrensei Opening</em> by by Rob van Zeijst and Richard Bozulich</li>
</ul>
<h2>Games</h2>
<ul>
<li><a title="KGS Website" href="http://www.gokgs.com/">KGS</a> &#8211; 0 games</li>
<li><a title="Online Go Server" href="http://www.online-go.com/">OGS</a> &#8211;  1 ongoing game</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/weekly-status-report-12/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">5961</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Weekly Progress Report: #11</title>
		<link>/weekly-progress-report-11/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2014 12:33:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Progress Reports]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5954</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Overview Hey everyone. Sorry for not updating the weekly status report for the last two weeks. I’ve been doing a bit of introspection and came to the realization that everything had started to become a bit too mundane for my liking. I know that this runs slightly counter to my whole notion of “consistency,” but [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>Overview</h2>
<p>Hey everyone. Sorry for not updating the weekly status report for the last two weeks. I’ve been doing a bit of introspection and came to the realization that everything had started to become a bit too mundane for my liking. I know that this runs slightly counter to my whole notion of “consistency,” but I feel like there comes a point when it becomes robotic (which is the last thing I want for this blog).<br />
So as you’ve probably noticed, the official “Journal Entries” series was killed off since I felt like it was somewhat a repetition of this weekly status report. In addition, because I hadn’t been investing as much time in go as I would like, it felt like I was saying the same thing over and over again.<br />
Well forget all that. I’m going back to the basics and my roots as a blogger. Can’t quite articulate what that exactly entails, but I can tell you for sure that I am feeling a change in the wind. It’s going to be an exciting ride!</p>
<h2>Daily Training Regimen</h2>
<ul>
<li>Work on Jump Level Up series.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Books</h2>
<ul>
<li><em>Jump Level Up 3</em> by Baduktopia</li>
<li><em>Handicap-Go Strategy and the Sanrensei Opening</em> by by Rob van Zeijst and Richard Bozulich</li>
<li><em>The 21st Century Dictionary of Basic Joseki: Volume One</em> by Takao Shinji, 9-dan</li>
</ul>
<h2>Games</h2>
<ul>
<li><a title="KGS Website" href="http://www.gokgs.com/">KGS</a> &#8211; 1 game</li>
<li><a title="Online Go Server" href="http://www.online-go.com/">OGS</a> &#8211;  3 ongoing games</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">5954</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Weekly Progress Report: #10</title>
		<link>/weekly-progress-report-10/</link>
		<comments>/weekly-progress-report-10/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2014 12:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Progress Reports]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5934</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Overview Looks like Monday Go Meditation will continue to be on break for a little bit; but on the upside, that comes with the contingency that it seems like I am working my way back into playing games again (which will inadvertently make the MGM’s that much more meaningful as time goes on). Life and [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>Overview</h2>
<p>Looks like Monday Go Meditation will continue to be on break for a little bit; but on the upside, that comes with the contingency that it seems like I am working my way back into playing games again (which will inadvertently make the MGM’s that much more meaningful as time goes on).<br />
Life and work continues to try to drown me in all of its priorities as I shift gears and prepare to ramp up things. And while I am a tad tired and busted up (particularly from the workouts), it does feel like I am making progress. In addition, I’ve given my training regimen an official tweak with a more variety of problem difficulty along with a new training system I’ve been testing out for a little while. I’ll be sure to post a full review on it when I feel like I’ve fully vetted it.<br />
Other than that, I hope everyone is doing well and getting ready for next week’s food marathon of Thanksgiving! Bring on the food coma!</p>
<h2>Next Week’s Goal</h2>
<p>Settings goals for each week has been a good habit, but alas it’s been difficult trying to actually accomplish it due to how lofty they have been. So for next week, I’m going to aim for something measurable and realistic that I should have no problem hitting: 3 chapters from Handicap Go Strategy and the Sanrensei Opening.</p>
<h2>Daily Training Regimen</h2>
<ul>
<li>Work on Jump Level Up series.</li>
<li>Play one 9&#215;9 game on GoQuest.</li>
<li>Solve 90 problems on MagicBaduk.
<ul>
<li>50 Easy, 25 Intermediate, 10 Advanced, 5 Expert</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Solve 10 problems on Guo Juan’s Internet Go School Training System.
<ul>
<li>Life and Death (9 Old Problems / 1 New Problem)</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h2>Books</h2>
<ul>
<li><em>Jump Level Up 3</em> by Baduktopia</li>
<li><em>Handicap-Go Strategy and the Sanrensei Opening</em>by by Rob van Zeijst and Richard Bozulich</li>
</ul>
<h2>Games</h2>
<ul>
<li><a title="KGS Website" href="http://www.gokgs.com/">KGS</a> &#8211; 3 games</li>
<li><a title="Online Go Server" href="http://www.online-go.com/">OGS</a> &#8211;  3 ongoing games</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/weekly-progress-report-10/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">5934</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Weekly Progress Report: #09</title>
		<link>/weekly-progress-report-09/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2014 03:50:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Progress Reports]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5927</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Overview As the weeks have piled on, it’s only to be expected that I would eventually hit a burnout period of some sort. This week seemed to show signs of it, but I’ve managed to weather the storm for the most part. My training regimen hasn’t been impacted at all, but I’m afraid that Monday [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>Overview</h2>
<p>As the weeks have piled on, it’s only to be expected that I would eventually hit a burnout period of some sort. This week seemed to show signs of it, but I’ve managed to weather the storm for the most part. My training regimen hasn’t been impacted at all, but I’m afraid that Monday Go Meditation will have to be on break next week.<br />
Due to copious amounts of work, I did not manage to meet my goal of finishing <em>Handicap Go Strategy and the Sanrensei Openin</em>g last week. So I’ll be extending the same goal into next week. Here’s to hoping I have better luck this time.</p>
<h2>Daily Training Regimen</h2>
<ul>
<li>Work on Jump Level Up series.</li>
<li>Playing one 9&#215;9 game on GoQuest.</li>
<li>Solve/Practice 100 easy problems from MagicBaduk.</li>
<li>Solve/Practice 10 hard problems from MagicBaduk.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Books</h2>
<ul>
<li><em>Jump Level Up 3</em> by Baduktopia</li>
<li><em>Handicap-Go Strategy and the Sanrensei Opening </em>by by Rob van Zeijst and Richard Bozulich</li>
</ul>
<h2>Games</h2>
<ul>
<li><a title="KGS Website" href="http://www.gokgs.com/">KGS</a> &#8211; 0 games</li>
<li><a title="Online Go Server" href="http://www.online-go.com/">OGS</a> &#8211;  4 ongoing games</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">5927</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Weekly Progress Report: #08</title>
		<link>/weekly-progress-report-08/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2014 17:38:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Progress Reports]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5920</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Overview Two months has come and gone. While I haven’t been able to make much headway on time to play more games, it’s been satisfying to know that I have been able to maintain my training regimen all this time. The past me would have been unsatisfied with the progress I’ve made thus far, but [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>Overview</h2>
<p>Two months has come and gone. While I haven’t been able to make much headway on time to play more games, it’s been satisfying to know that I have been able to maintain my training regimen all this time. The past me would have been unsatisfied with the progress I’ve made thus far, but I know better than to expect more than what I’ve been able to accomplish. In fact, I’m even in the process of tweaking the training regimen so that it becomes even more effective with minimal effort. I’ll be sure to update it when I think I’ve made a change that has been useful.<br />
For next week, I aim to finish Handicap-Go Strategy and Sanrensei Opening so that I can work on getting the review on soon. Here’s to another productive week. See you guys next week!</p>
<h2>Daily Training Regimen</h2>
<ul>
<li>Work on Jump Level Up series.</li>
<li>Solve 100 easy problems from MagicBaduk.</li>
<li>Playing at least one game a day (which usually defaults to a 9&#215;9 game on GoQuest).</li>
</ul>
<h2>Books</h2>
<ul>
<li><em>Jump Level Up 2</em> by Baduktopia</li>
<li><em>Handicap-Go Strategy and the Sanrensei Opening</em>by by Rob van Zeijst and Richard Bozulich</li>
</ul>
<h2>Games</h2>
<ul>
<li><a title="KGS Website" href="http://www.gokgs.com/">KGS</a> &#8211; 0 games</li>
<li><a title="Online Go Server" href="http://www.online-go.com/">OGS</a> &#8211;  3 ongoing games</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">5920</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Weekly Progress Report: #07</title>
		<link>/weekly-progress-report-07/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 11:15:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Progress Reports]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5914</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Overview Man. The time sure does fly by doesn’t it? It only felt like just yesterday when I rebooted this series and yet here I am seven weeks in. To be honest, part of me feels like after almost two months, you would think I would have something significant to report; but even this week, [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>Overview</h2>
<p>Man. The time sure does fly by doesn’t it? It only felt like just yesterday when I rebooted this series and yet here I am seven weeks in.<br />
To be honest, part of me feels like after almost two months, you would think I would have something significant to report; but even this week, the focus is still on the same goal: consistency. At the end of the day, consistency is not nearly so glamorous as a huge gesture of studying that usually fizzles out with an equally bad burnout. On the upside though, I’m at least working on go on a daily basis without impacting the rest of my life in any significant way. And while it still takes a little bit out of me to keep this discipline, I’m thinking that eventually it will become more automatic and ingrained in my routine.<br />
In other news, I wanted to share two sites with you in case you haven’t heard about them:<br />
<a title="Dwyrin TV" href="http://www.dwyrin.tv/">Dwyrin.TV</a> &#8211; For those who don’t know Dwyrin (aka Battousai on KGS), he is a popular teacher who has a series of videos on YouTube that many people have learned a great deal from. This site was created as a response to the issue of trying to find his videos or watch them in any sort of hierarchical order. Be sure to check it out. I’m sure you won’t regret it!<br />
<a title="Goishi" href="http://www.goishi.nl/">Goishi</a> &#8211; This is a Dutch site that contains a <a title="Goishi Photo Album" href="http://www.goishi.nl/410849827">collection of high resolution photos</a>. Though the site is in Dutch, you can load it in Chrome and there should be an option for it to at least do a basic translation for you.<br />
With that said, I hope you all had a great Halloween and a great weekend. Till next week!</p>
<h2>Daily Training Regimen</h2>
<ul>
<li>Solve 100 easy problems from MagicBaduk.</li>
<li>Work on Jump Level Up series.</li>
<li>Playing at least one game a day (which usually defaults to a 9&#215;9 game on GoQuest).</li>
</ul>
<h2>Books</h2>
<ul>
<li><em>Jump Level Up 2</em> by Baduktopia</li>
<li><em>Handicap-Go Strategy and the Sanrensei Opening</em>by by Rob van Zeijst and Richard Bozulich</li>
</ul>
<h2>Games</h2>
<ul>
<li><a title="KGS Website" href="http://www.gokgs.com/">KGS</a> &#8211; 0 games</li>
<li><a title="Online Go Server" href="http://www.online-go.com/">OGS</a> &#8211;  4 ongoing games</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">5914</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Weekly Progress Report: #06</title>
		<link>/weekly-progress-report-06/</link>
		<comments>/weekly-progress-report-06/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2014 11:15:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Progress Reports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[my cat plays baduk]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5895</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Overview As I continue into the second stretch of non-stop hammering of work and attempts to sustain consistency, I’m happy to report that while I feel pretty winded, I don’t feel anything close to burnout yet. On top of that, I’ve actually come to realize that executing my routines first thing in the morning seem [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>Overview</h2>
<p>As I continue into the second stretch of non-stop hammering of work and attempts to sustain consistency, I’m happy to report that while I feel pretty winded, I don’t feel anything close to burnout yet. On top of that, I’ve actually come to realize that executing my routines first thing in the morning seem to work out pretty well for me. On days that I didn’t manage to do so usually resulted in a last minute scramble to get it done at the end of the night, but I’m hanging on as best I can.<br />
On the upside, it looks like my correspondence go playing has started to pickup to a nice pace. Considering the fact that I haven’t been able to play a game in real time this entire week, it’s definitely nice knowing that I’m still “playing” to some degree.<br />
In addition, I’ve been meaning to make this announcement for some time, but I wanted to give a big shoutout to a go blogger who joined the ranks recently: <a title="My Cat Plays Baduk" href="http://mycatplaysbaduk.wordpress.com/">My Cat Plays Baduk</a>. Though it only has been around for a little bit, she has written quite a few posts and is worth following. So be sure to check out her blog!<br />
Other than that, I’ll try to approach the next week with a bit more fervor in an attempt to prepare the content on the blog to grow in the future. And even though it already sounds a bit ambitious in my head, I’m going to see what I can do about trying to release at least one book review a week. No promises yet, but I’ll definitely see what I can do.<br />
See you next week!</p>
<h2>Daily Training Regimen</h2>
<ul>
<li>Solve 100 easy problems from MagicBaduk.</li>
<li>Complete 4 pages of problems (approximately 15-20 problems) from Jump Level Up.</li>
<li>Playing at least one game a day (which usually defaults to a 9&#215;9 game on GoQuest).</li>
</ul>
<h2>Books</h2>
<ul>
<li><em>Jump Level Up 2</em> by Baduktopia</li>
<li><em>Handicap-Go Strategy and the Sanrensei Opening</em>by by Rob van Zeijst and Richard Bozulich</li>
</ul>
<h2>Games</h2>
<ul>
<li><a title="KGS Website" href="http://www.gokgs.com/">KGS</a> &#8211; 0 games</li>
<li><a title="Online Go Server" href="http://www.online-go.com/">OGS</a> &#8211;  4 ongoing game</li>
<li><a title="Dave Peck’s Go Site" href="&quot;http://go.davepeck.org/“">Dave Peck’s Go Site</a> &#8211; 1 ongoing game</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/weekly-progress-report-06/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>14</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">5895</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Weekly Progress Report: #05</title>
		<link>/weekly-progress-report-05/</link>
		<comments>/weekly-progress-report-05/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2014 11:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Progress Reports]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5883</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Overview As predicted, I really am in the thick of things this week. In the midst of all this work though, I’ve managed to barely cling on to my training regimen (though it was rather difficult to do as each day went on). I’m currently testing different things to make the training more consistent (i.e., [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>Overview</h2>
<p>As predicted, I really am in the thick of things this week. In the midst of all this work though, I’ve managed to barely cling on to my training regimen (though it was rather difficult to do as each day went on). I’m currently testing different things to make the training more consistent (i.e., getting it done first thing in the morning). I’ll let you know when I discover my own magical formula for it.<br />
Otherwise, I’m working hard on the blog content and will definitely be releasing book reviews by Sunday. For those wondering why it’s taking me a little while, I’m actually trying to update the format of the book reviews to something more substantial and useful. I’m hoping you guys will like the new changes.<br />
With that said, I hope you guys had a great week. See you guys next week!</p>
<h2>Daily Training Regimen</h2>
<ul>
<li>Complete 4 pages of problems (approximately 15-20 problems) from Jump Level Up.</li>
<li>Playing at least one game a day (which usually defaults to a 9&#215;9 game on GoQuest).</li>
</ul>
<h2>Books</h2>
<ul>
<li><em>Jump Level Up 2</em> by Baduktopia</li>
<li><em>This is Hanegma</em> by Kim Sung-rae</li>
<li><em>100 Tips for Amateur Players I</em> by Youngsun Yoon</li>
<li><em>Handicap-Go Strategy and the Sanrensei Opening</em>by by Rob van Zeijst and Richard Bozulich</li>
</ul>
<h2>Games</h2>
<ul>
<li><a title="KGS Website" href="http://www.gokgs.com/">KGS</a> &#8211;  1.5 games (1 free and 1 unfinished game)</li>
<li><a title="Online Go Server" href="http://www.online-go.com/">OGS</a> &#8211;  1 ongoing game</li>
<li><a title="Dave Peck’s Go Site" href="http://go.davepeck.org/">Dave Peck’s Go Site</a> &#8211; 1 ongoing game</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/weekly-progress-report-05/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">5883</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Weekly Progress Report: #04</title>
		<link>/weekly-progress-report-04/</link>
		<comments>/weekly-progress-report-04/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2014 12:12:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Progress Reports]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5873</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Overview Whew. I’m hitting the one month milestone in my training and I’m proud to say that things are still going well. Granted, there are times where I almost skipped out on my regimen, but my past self was smart enough to keep it at a manageable level where the task was easy enough that [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>Overview</h2>
<p>Whew. I’m hitting the one month milestone in my training and I’m proud to say that things are still going well. Granted, there are times where I almost skipped out on my regimen, but my past self was smart enough to keep it at a manageable level where the task was easy enough that it wasn’t onerous to complete.<br />
And as a brief update to my game playing, it still has yet to really increase to anything significant, but it seems I’ve actually managed at least 2 games a week for the past couple of weeks! That’s quite exciting when you consider how I was avoiding games entirely at one point. One step at a time right? And on top of that, I forgot to mention that one of my games this week was ranked! Against a bot I know, but it was the best I could bring myself to do since I wanted to get rid of the question mark in my rank on KGS. Still, better than nothing right? Haha.<br />
Things are starting to pick up in other aspects of my life, so the true test to my training regimen starts here. And while this usually did not bode well for my go pursuits, I have a feeling that it will be very different this time around.</p>
<h2>Daily Training Regimen</h2>
<ul>
<li>Complete 4 pages of problems (approximately 15-20 problems) from Jump Level Up.</li>
<li>Playing at least one game a day (which usually defaults to a 9&#215;9 game on GoQuest).</li>
</ul>
<h2>Books</h2>
<ul>
<li><em>Jump Level Up 2</em> by Baduktopia</li>
<li><em>This is Hanegma</em> by Kim Sung-rae</li>
<li><em>100 Tips for Amateur Players I</em> by Youngsun Yoon</li>
</ul>
<h2>Games</h2>
<ul>
<li><a title="KGS Website" href="http://www.gokgs.com/">KGS</a> &#8211;  2 games (1 ranked and 1 teaching game)</li>
<li><a title="Online Go Server" href="http://www.online-go.com/">OGS</a> &#8211;  1 game ongoing</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/weekly-progress-report-04/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>10</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">5873</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
