<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>beginning &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/beginning/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>A Fresh and New Beginning</title>
		<link>/fresh-new-beginning/</link>
		<comments>/fresh-new-beginning/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 19:27:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beginning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fresh]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[productivity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[start]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5510</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Over the weekend, in the midst of my slump, I decided to step back and take a hard look at what I had been doing and what I had to show for it. And though many of you might think otherwise, I realized that I was far behind the pack when it came to what [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Over the weekend, in the midst of my slump, I decided to step back and take a hard look at what I had been doing and what I had to show for it. And though many of you might think otherwise, I realized that I was far behind the pack when it came to what I had accomplished so far.<br />
Upon that realization, I decided it was time to take a sledgehammer the systems and processes that I’ve been using over these past few years. As a result, I invested a lot of time, energy, and money into getting myself back on track. After all, people out there changing the world have the same hours that I do during the day, so it was time for me to make a change so that I could join the ranks of those hyper-productive people.<br />
What does this have to do with go? Well, as many of you know, running this blog consumes a lot of time and energy. And though it would be awesome if this were my full time job, I have many other things in my life that I need to attend to as well (i.e., my job, my girlfriend, friends, family, etc.). On top of all that, let’s not forget that I am also trying to get stronger at the same time as well! So when it comes down to it, the more inefficient I am at using my time, the more sporadic my results will be when it comes to things like my go abilities or the quality of the posts on my blog.<br />
And though I hate to admit it, I’ve hit a roadblock with go. In reality, it probably is a multi-faceted problem that has to do with the rest of my life; but I’m not too worried about it since I think the changes I’m making will help me overcome that roadblock in time.<br />
Being that today being the first day of July, it’s only appropriate that this mark of a fresh and new beginning. After all, weaknesses are simply opportunities to get stronger. So with that said, time to get to work.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/fresh-new-beginning/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>14</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">5510</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Book Review: 501 Opening Problems</title>
		<link>/book-review-501-opening-problems/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2013 23:30:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beginning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[opening]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[principles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[problems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tsumego]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=2635</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Overall Rating: 4 / 5 Ponnuki Basic Information Title: Mastering the Basics, Volume 1 &#8211; Five Hundred and One Opening Problems Authors: Richard Bozulich in collaboration with Rob van Zeijst Publisher: Kiseido Publication Date: August 2002 Page Length: 256 pages Number of Problems: 501 Synopsis A great basic book about opening problems that utilizes proverbs as directions instead of vague [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/04/mtb1cover.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2636" alt="mtb1cover" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/04/mtb1cover.jpg?resize=300%2C427" width="300" height="427" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">Overall Rating: 4 / 5 Ponnuki</h2>
<h3>Basic Information</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Title:</strong> Mastering the Basics, Volume 1 &#8211; Five Hundred and One Opening Problems</li>
<li><strong>Authors: </strong>Richard Bozulich in collaboration with Rob van Zeijst</li>
<li><strong>Publisher: </strong>Kiseido</li>
<li><strong>Publication Date: </strong>August 2002</li>
<li><strong>Page Length:</strong> 256 pages</li>
<li><strong>Number of Problems</strong>: 501</li>
</ul>
<h3>Synopsis</h3>
<ul>
<li>A great basic book about opening problems that utilizes proverbs as directions instead of vague statements.</li>
<li>Appropriate for 10 kyu and stronger.</li>
<li>Recommended for serious players.</li>
</ul>
<p><span id="more-2635"></span></p>
<h3>Detailed Review</h3>
<h4>Readability &#8211; 9 / 10</h4>
<p>The directions and explanations in this book are rather in depth for the number of problems in the book. While it may go over some players&#8217; head if they are not familiar with opening concepts, the explanations are long enough that players of the appropriate level will understand it fully while newer players will at least get some exposure to new ideas.</p>
<h4>Content Quality &#8211; 10 / 10</h4>
<p>One of my favorite aspects about this book is that their directions consist of principles like &#8220;Neutralize your opponent&#8217;s thickness while establishing a base for yourself&#8221; in order to give you a better idea of how to approach the problem. There are more principles than I can count on both hands and they are applied to a number of different scenarios. As a result, this book earns a perfect score since the reader is forced to think strategically in addition to figuring out the right move.</p>
<h4>Final Thoughts</h4>
<p>Since this book is part of the series geared toward helping players master the basics, I have found that <em>Five Hundred and One Opening Problems</em> does a great job exposing the player to a lot of different opening concepts and principles. I personally wish there was a bit more structure as to helping the players truly grasp each principle before moving on to other principles, but it is a great start for any player looking to get a better understanding of the opening.</p>
<h4>Table of Contents</h4>
<ol>
<li>Preface</li>
<li>Some Important Terms and Concepts</li>
<li>Introduction</li>
<li>How to Use This Book</li>
<li>501 Opening Problems</li>
</ol>
<h4>Recommended Vendors:</h4>
<ol>
<li>Kiseido &#8211; <a title="Kiseido Order Form" href="http://www.kiseido.com/go_books.htm">$21.00</a> (S&amp;H not included)</li>
<li>SmartGo Books (eBook) &#8211; <a href="http://www.smartgo.com/booksbycategory.htm">$8.99</a> (Apple users only)</li>
</ol>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Last updated May 14th, 2013 &#8211; 5 kyu</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2635</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
