<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>kiseido &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/kiseido/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>Book Review: The Road Map to Shodan, Volume 2</title>
		<link>/book-review-road-map-shodan-volume-2/</link>
		<comments>/book-review-road-map-shodan-volume-2/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2014 17:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kiseido]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[middle game]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[opening]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[principles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[richard bozulich]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rob van zeijst]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sabaki]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5887</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The Basic Principles of the Opening and the Middle Game Description: “In this book, 20 basic principles are presented. Each principle is accompanied by numerous examples and each section is followed by problems in which the application of these principles is required to solve them. The intuition of the novice player who studies the principles, [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/10/roadmaptoshodanv2cover.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-5888" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/10/roadmaptoshodanv2cover.jpg?resize=296%2C395" alt="roadmaptoshodanv2cover" width="296" height="395" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">The Basic Principles of the Opening and the Middle Game</h2>
<p><strong>Description:</strong> “In this book, 20 basic principles are presented. Each principle is accompanied by numerous examples and each section is followed by problems in which the application of these principles is required to solve them. The intuition of the novice player who studies the principles, examples, and problems presented in this book will quickly rise to the level of an expert go player.”<br />
<span id="more-5887"></span><br />
[expand title=&#8221;Book Details&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
[table]
Title, The Basic Principles of the Opening and the Middle Game<br />
Series/Volume, The Road Map to Shodan (Vol. 2)<br />
Author, Rob van Zeijst and Richard Bozulich<br />
Publisher, Kiseido (LINK)<br />
Published, “September 2014“<br />
Language, English<br />
ISBN, 978-4-906574-83-4<br />
Length, 146 pages<br />
Problems, 45 problems<br />
[/table]
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Table of Content&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ol>
<li>Preface</li>
<li>A Brief Glossary of Go Terms and Concepts</li>
<li>Section I: Extensions and Efficiency
<ol>
<li>Principle 1A</li>
<li>Principle 1B</li>
<li>Principle 1C</li>
<li>Principle 2</li>
<li>Principle 3</li>
<li>Problems 1 to 8</li>
<li>Answers to Problems 1 to 8</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>Section II: Confinement, Linkage, and Separation
<ol>
<li>Principle 4A</li>
<li>Principle 4B</li>
<li>Principle 5</li>
<li>Problems 9 to 14</li>
<li>Answers to Problems 9 to 14</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>Section III: Weak Stones and Weak Positions
<ol>
<li>Principle 6A</li>
<li>Principle 6B</li>
<li>Principle 7A</li>
<li>Principle 7B</li>
<li>Principle 8</li>
<li>Problems 15 to 22</li>
<li>Answer to Problems 15 to 22</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>Section IV: Handling Moyos &amp; Escaping
<ol>
<li>Principle 9A</li>
<li>Principle 9B</li>
<li>Principle 10</li>
<li>Problems 23 to 28</li>
<li>Answers to Problems 23 to 28</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>Section V: Handling Thickness
<ol>
<li>Principle 11</li>
<li>Principle 12</li>
<li>Principle 13</li>
<li>Principle 14</li>
<li>Problems 29 to 32</li>
<li>Answers to Problems 29 to 32</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>Section VI: The Third and Fourth Lines in the Opening &amp; Defending Against a 3-3 Invasion
<ol>
<li>Principle 15</li>
<li>Principle 16</li>
<li>Principle 17</li>
<li>Principle 18</li>
<li>Problems 33 to 38</li>
<li>Answer to Problems 33 to 38</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>Section VII: Turning a Moyo into Territory
<ol>
<li>Principle 19</li>
<li>Problems 39 to 40</li>
<li>Answers to Problems 39 to 40</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>Section VIII: How to Make Sabaki
<ol>
<li>Principle 20</li>
<li>Problems 41 to 45</li>
<li>Answers to Problems 41 to 45</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ol>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;My Review&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221; expanded=&#8221;true&#8221;]
<h3>Introduction</h3>
<p><em>The Basic Principles of the Opening and the Middle Game</em>, by Rob can Zeijst and Richard Bozulich, is the second volume to Kiseido’s new series: The Road Map to Shodan. Though the title might lead some astray, this book is not intended to be a definitive guide to all principles in regards to the opening and middle game. Instead, it would be more accurate to view the purpose of this book as a broad survey of common principles that beginner and intermediate players forget during their own games. And while some might write this book off as a simple marketing ploy, this book is truly a fantastic collection of principles that cover a wide range of material in an easy to understand manner.</p>
<h3>Summary of Content</h3>
<p>When first presented with the title, I must admit that I was initially skeptical of what it could contain. After all, I had already read 20 Principles of the Opening, Get Strong at the Opening, 501 Opening Problems, etc. To my delight, the content of the book exceeded my expectations. Just look at the topics covered: (1) Extensions and Efficiency, (2) Confinement, Linkage, and Separation, (3) Weak Stones and Weak Positions, (4) Handling Moyos &amp; Escaping, (5) Handling Thickness, (6) The Third and Fourth Lines in the Opening, (7) Defending Against a 3-3 Invasion, (8) Turning a Moyo into Territory, and (9) How to Make Sabaki.<br />
While the topics do not receive a comprehensive explanation of each topic, the book does a great job providing a survey of the topic with the key points highlighted. After all, don’t forget that this series is meant to be a guide for those who are kyu players looking to gain strength. So the most effective method for helping players do that is to provide the most common mistakes that players make and how to fix them. More advanced techniques and principles would naturally be reserved for other books.<br />
Unlike most of the other books I have read, this book does an excellent job of keeping things as simple as possible. For example, instead of inundating the reader with numerous of examples taken from professional games, the examples consist of straight-forward examples that are easy to follow. In addition, each principle is given a good mixture of examples and explanation. As a result, novice and/or more casual players would not be overwhelmed and can digest the material much more easily.</p>
<h3>Intended Audience</h3>
<p>The strength of players who would benefit most from this book would be around 10k and stronger.<br />
While there are other books out there that contain similar information in various forms, this book is best suited for players who approach the study of go with a more casual approach.<br />
In other words, the material is written in such a way that it is quite easy to get through and absorb without multiple intense readings. That’s not to say that you can read it once and be done with it, but it is not so dense that you would have to reread a paragraph multiple times just to understand its basic meaning (let alone trying to apply it in your own games). In addition, the diagrams are short enough that it is not necessary to have a board in order to comprehend the flow of the stones (though it is certainly recommended if you have it in front of you).</p>
<h3>Layout</h3>
<p>The content is laid out in a way that is analogous to a textbook. First you have a section explaining the principles that you should learn along with a few examples to illustrate their point. The explanations are then followed up with a few problems for you to reinforce what you have just learned. And to ensure that you don’t accidentally glance at the solutions while trying to solve the problems, they are kept in a separate section after the problems are presented.</p>
<h3>Analysis and Evaluation</h3>
<p>The key to understanding the brilliance of this book lies in its accessibility to players of all kinds. Even when I consider players like myself who have read numerous books and take the game quite seriously, there is something to be appreciated about the simplicity to which this book approaches the topic. And though my understanding of this topic most likely has already encroached on dan territory, I still felt that the book provided a great reinforcement of things I knew and helped fill some areas that I didn’t realize were missing.<br />
In terms of shortcomings, there is only one aspect that I would have liked to have seen: more practice problems. While there are a handful of problems to review each section, there was more than one occasion where I would have liked just a few more problems. To be clear though, this is not to say that the problems in the book do not cover the topics presented. It’s just I would have liked a few more than what is in the book.</p>
<h3>Conclusion</h3>
<p>While there will be players who may scoff at this book, Kiseido has done a great job of finally providing a stepping stone that beginner and intermediate players can actually benefit from. So if you have any interest in the topics mentioned above and think you could benefit from the style of teaching being used, then I highly recommend that you get a copy of this book pronto!<br />
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Where Can I Buy It?&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221; expanded=&#8221;true&#8221;]
<ul>
<li><a title="Kiseido Go Shop" href="http://kiseido.com/go_books.htm">Kiseido</a> &#8211; $21 (shipping and handling not included)</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Other Books in This Series&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;lastExpandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Volume 1: Handicap-Go Strategy and the Sanrensei Opening (Making the Transition from Handicap to Even Games)</li>
<li><strong>Volume 2: The Basic Principles of the Opening and the Middle Game</strong></li>
<li>Volume 3: The Basic LIfe and Death Positions</li>
<li>Volume 4: A Survey of the Basic Tesujis</li>
<li>Volume 5: All About the Endgame</li>
<li>Volume 6: Sabaki: The Art of Settling Groups and Making Good Shape</li>
<li>Volume 7: Attacking Weak Groups</li>
<li>Volume 8: The Chinese and Mini-Chinese Openings</li>
<li>Volume 9: The Kobayashi Opening</li>
<li>Volume 10: Tasuki Openings</li>
<li>Volume 11: Parallel Openigs</li>
<li>Volume 12: The Shusaku Opening</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
<p style="text-align: center;"><em><strong>Last Updated on October 19th, 2014</strong></em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/book-review-road-map-shodan-volume-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>12</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">5887</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Journal Entry: #05</title>
		<link>/journal-entry-05/</link>
		<comments>/journal-entry-05/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2014 17:27:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kiseido]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5864</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[As I’ve started to ramp things up again, I am noticing that I’m entering that dangerous zone of treading the line between being productive or becoming so busy I eventually enter burnout. In order to temper that, I’ve been keeping better track of my time so that I don’t lose myself in my endeavors too [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As I’ve started to ramp things up again, I am noticing that I’m entering that dangerous zone of treading the line between being productive or becoming so busy I eventually enter burnout. In order to temper that, I’ve been keeping better track of my time so that I don’t lose myself in my endeavors too much. It seems to be moderately successful so far, but I’ll need to keep close watch as the weeks progress.<br />
Meanwhile, I’ve been happy to reintegrate reviewing games into my schedule. Though this might come to no surprise for most, it still astounds me much you can pick up by reviewing your own games (especially if you can maintain an objective view on the game). I’m still in the process of finding the right balance of commenting on them, but it’s one of those things that I just have to get a feel for over time.<br />
And last but not least, I am happy to announce that I will be releasing a new book review soon: <a title="The Road Map to Shodan (Volume 2) Kiseido" href="http://kiseido.com/road.htm#K83">The Road Map to Shodan (Volume 2): The Basic Principles of the Opening and Middle Game</a>. So be on the lookout for that as I make my return to reviewing go books and other products!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/journal-entry-05/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>10</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">5864</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Book Review: Graded Go Problems for Dan Players &#8211; Vol. 1</title>
		<link>/book-review-graded-go-problems-dan-players-vol-1/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2014 12:15:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[collection]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[go problems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kiseido]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life and death]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reading]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tsumego]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=4735</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Graded Go Problems for Dan Players: Volume One &#8211; 300 Life-and-Death Problems (5-kyu to 3-dan) Description: This is the first volume of the continuing series to the popular &#8220;Graded Go Problems for Beginners.&#8221; This first book is focused on providing life-and-death techniques that are foundational to developing stronger reading abilities as players try to climb [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/02/ggpdpv1cover.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-4736" alt="ggpdpv1cover" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/02/ggpdpv1cover.jpg?resize=288%2C373" width="288" height="373" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">Graded Go Problems for Dan Players: Volume One &#8211; 300 Life-and-Death Problems (5-kyu to 3-dan)</h2>
<p><strong>Description:</strong> This is the first volume of the continuing series to the popular &#8220;Graded Go Problems for Beginners.&#8221; This first book is focused on providing life-and-death techniques that are foundational to developing stronger reading abilities as players try to climb their way into dan status.<br />
<span id="more-4735"></span><br />
[expand title=&#8221;Book Details&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
[table]
Title, GGPDP: Volume One &#8211; 300 Life-and-Death Problems (5-kyu to 3-dan)<br />
Series, Graded Go Problems for Dan Players (GGPDP)<br />
Compiled by, Masaru Aoki and Hirokazu Sato<br />
Translator, Richard Bozulich<br />
Publisher, <a href="http://www.kiseido.com/">Kiseido</a><br />
Published, &#8220;November 2009&#8243;<br />
Language, English<br />
ISBN, 978-4-906574-61-2<br />
Length, 232 pages<br />
Problems, 300 problems<br />
[/table]
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Table of Content&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Translator&#8217;s Preface</li>
<li>Glossary of Go Terms Used in this Book</li>
<li>300 Life and Death Problems (#1-300)</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Before I Read This Book&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
As an enthusiast of the &#8220;Graded Go Problems for Beginners&#8221; series, I have to say that I was ecstatic when I heard about this series. After all, every kyu player dreams of making it to the big dan league and being able to solve &#8220;dan level&#8221; problems. And even though I got myself a copy of this book quite a while ago, this book seemed quite daunting to me for some time due to the fact that I just felt I wasn&#8217;t ready for &#8220;dan&#8221; problems. Anyhow, I&#8217;m glad I finally got around to reading it so that you can hear my thoughts on the book itself.<br />
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;My Review&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221; expanded=&#8221;true&#8221;]
Perhaps my favorite aspect about the entire &#8220;Graded Go Problems&#8221; series as a whole is the extremely clean format. For those who don&#8217;t know what I&#8217;m talking about, every page that contains the problems is divided into four clean and even rectangles. Secondly, the numbering, diagram, directions, and even hints are all in universal places so that once you get exposed to the format, you&#8217;ll never wonder where to look next. And last but not least, the solutions are never exposed on the same page (aka you can&#8217;t see the solution as you&#8217;re trying to solve the problem). And thankfully, Graded Go Problems for Dan Players continues that tradition.<br />
One of the new things I noticed with this series is that they added an actual rank estimation for the problem difficulty. So a few examples of this might include: &#8220;Solve at a glance = 4-kyu, Solve within five minutes = 3-dan, etc.&#8221; While this is rather neat since you feel a sense of accomplishment if you&#8217;re able to solve it within the allotted time-frame, it&#8217;s important to realize that these rank estimations are a bit arbitrary. Just because you&#8217;re able to solve a few dan level problems at a glance does not necessarily mean you are &#8220;dan&#8221; level (whether it&#8217;s reading ability or playing ability). If you&#8217;re able to solve the whole book at a glance though, then it goes without saying you are way stronger than a dan player. xD<br />
When it comes to the solutions, they have a set standard format for how solutions are displayed and approached. In terms of basic format, every problem gets three solution diagrams. This generally includes the correct variation, an alternate variation / continuation of the correct variation, and an incorrect variation. In addition, there is usually at least a sentence to two explaining each of the variations in order to help the reader understand what&#8217;s going on.<br />
If there were to be any complaint about this series, it would probably be that the problems are not segmented into different techniques. However, I would remind the reader that the purpose of this series is to provide a collection of high-quality problems. As a result, the problems would be an assortment of different problems as opposed to a hierarchy of problems broken down by techniques. If you&#8217;re looking for problems categorized in such a fashion, you might benefit from checking out the Level Up Series along with Life and Death Problems 1 Basics by Robert Jasiek.<br />
Overall, I think that this series is destined for the same greatness as the &#8220;Graded for Go Problems for Beginners&#8221; when it comes to high quality problems that are displayed in an easy to read format. Definitely a must-have for any player serious about practicing their reading and looking for ways to keep honing their ability. Highly recommended!<br />
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Synopsis&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<strong>What did I enjoy about the book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Continues to provide the easy to read format you come to love from &#8220;Graded Go Problems for Beginners.&#8221;</li>
<li>Attempts to provide accurate rank difficulty estimations for problems through the time it takes to solve it.</li>
<li>Lots of high-quality problems that you can rely on without worrying about a mistake in the solution.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What did I gain from reading this book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Exposure to a lot of new techniques or moves I would have never considered when solving life and death.</li>
<li>Reassurance that my reading abilities have been improving.</li>
<li>Realization that I still had a ways to go before I could consider myself having &#8220;dan-level&#8221; reading.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What is the format of the book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>You get a set of problems and then when you turn the page you get the respective solutions (so that they are not within the same reading area). Very easy to follow and read.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What aspect can be improved on?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Nothing. I really think this book is perfect as it stands.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Is this book easy to read?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Absolutely. Very clear and concise.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Bottom Line</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>Great problem set for players 5 kyu and stronger.</li>
<li>Continues to uphold the quality and ease of reading you come to expect from the &#8220;Graded Go Problems&#8221; series.</li>
<li>Highly recommended for anyone looking to take the next steps to raising their reading ability to &#8220;dan&#8221; level!</li>
</ol>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Recommended For&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Players 5-kyu and stronger.</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Where Can I Buy It?&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Kiseido &#8211; <a href="http://kiseido.com/go_books.htm#K15">$25</a> (shipping and handling not included)</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Other Books in This Series&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;lastExpandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>GGPDP &#8211; Volume One: 300 Life-and-Death Problems (5-kyu to 3-dan)</li>
<li>GGPDP &#8211; Volume Two: 300 Tesuji Problems (5-kyu to 3-dan)</li>
<li>GGPDP &#8211; Volume Three: 300 Joseki Problems (1-dan to 3-dan)</li>
<li>GGPDP &#8211; Volume Four: 300 Life-and-Death Problems (4-dan to 7-dan)</li>
<li>GGPDP &#8211; Volume Five: 300 Tesuji Problems (4-dan to 7-dan)</li>
<li>GGPDP &#8211; Volume Six: Joseki Problems (TBD)</li>
<li>GGPDP &#8211; Volume Seven: 256 Opening and Middle Game Problems (1-dan to 7-dan)</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
<p style="text-align: center;"><em><strong>Last Updated on March 2nd, 2014</strong></em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">4735</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Book Review: Get Strong at Tesuji</title>
		<link>/book-review-get-strong-tesuji/</link>
		<comments>/book-review-get-strong-tesuji/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2013 11:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bozulich]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[get strong]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kiseido]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tesuji]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=4014</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Get Strong at Tesuji Description: In the sixth volume of the Get Strong at Go Series, Bozulich has compiled a fantastic set of tesuji problems that focus on developing a player&#8217;s intuition through practicing lots of easier problems. Though there are a few intermediate/hard problems dispersed throughout the book, this is a great book for [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/09/getstrongv6.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-4015" alt="getstrongv6" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/09/getstrongv6.jpg?resize=280%2C400" width="280" height="400" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">Get Strong at Tesuji</h2>
<p><strong>Description:</strong> In the sixth volume of the Get Strong at Go Series, Bozulich has compiled a fantastic set of tesuji problems that focus on developing a player&#8217;s intuition through practicing lots of easier problems. Though there are a few intermediate/hard problems dispersed throughout the book, this is a great book for players of all levels (especially beginnger and intermediate levels).<br />
<span id="more-4014"></span><br />
[expand title=&#8221;Book Details&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
[table]
Title, Get Strong at Tesuji<br />
Series, Get Strong at Go Series<br />
Author, Richard Bozulich<br />
Publisher, <a href="http://www.kiseido.com/">Kiseido</a><br />
Published, &#8220;First Printing September 1996 | Second Printing June 2006&#8243;<br />
Language, English<br />
ISBN, 4-906574-56-4<br />
Length, 184 Pages<br />
Problems, 534 Problems<br />
[/table]
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Table of Content&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Preface</li>
<li>Some Important Terms and Concepts</li>
<li>Tesuji Problems</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Before I Read This Book&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
Besides the common tesuji that everyone learns when they first start out playing (i.e., snapback, crane&#8217;s nest, etc.), I would have to say that I did not feel like I knew that many tesuji. In addition, I always found it very difficult to identify tesuji in the middle of an actual game. So I was hoping that this book would give me a better foothold in identifying tesuji in common shapes and positions that might arise in my games.<br />
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Synopsis&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<strong>What did I enjoy about the book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Problems have a difficulty rating to inform the players how hard the problem is.</li>
<li>The problem set is overall very accommodating to beginner and intermediate players. In fact, a few of the &#8220;advanced&#8221; problems could be even be solved by a high SDK with some ease.</li>
<li>There is a nice repetition of techniques (that are dispersed throughout the book) to allow for excellent reinforcement of the technique.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What did I gain from reading this book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>A greater comfort level with tesuji as a whole.</li>
<li>Increased confidence in my ability to identify tesuji in positions that once were obscure to me.</li>
<li>Renewed faith in my ability to eventually go back and attempt <a title="Book Review: 501 Tesuji Problems" href="//book-review-501-tesuji-problems/">501 Tesuji Problems</a> once again.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What is the format of the book?</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>A set of problems followed by their solutions and explanation. Repeat. Repeat. Repeat.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>What aspects can be improved on?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>No complaints here!</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Is this book easy to read?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Yes. Explanations and solutions are short and clear cut. In addition, the diagrams are not complicated, so the solutions are easy to follow.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Bottom Line</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>Though I was skeptical of the book at first, this book is actually very accessible to beginner and intermediate players (though a bit more towards intermediate players) who want to practice tesuji.</li>
<li>Provides a lot of opportunities for practice and reinforcement of common tesuji techniques.</li>
<li>Continues the quality of content you come to expect from the &#8220;Get Strong at Series&#8221; and is well worth the money.</li>
</ol>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;My Review&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221; expanded=&#8221;true&#8221;]
As some of you are aware, when I tried to work my way through <a title="Book Review: 501 Tesuji Problems" href="//book-review-501-tesuji-problems/">Mastering the Basics: 501 Tesuji Problems</a>, I had an incredibly difficult time getting through it (for whatever reason I stil cannot identify). And since I always thought that the &#8220;Get Strong at Series&#8221; would be considered a more advanced level than the &#8220;Mastering the Basics Series,&#8221; I was a little worried about what I might encounter. Luckily for me though, I did not let my dread delay me any longer and I am so glad that I finally got opened it up!<br />
Get Strong at Tesuji continues the tradition of being a problem book that centers around giving readers numerous opportunities to practice their skills. The problems are not categorized in any particular manner, but a new aspect to the design (that I found very helpful) is the usage of stars in order to designate the problems difficulty. The problems ranged from 1 star (easy) to 4 stars (difficult). The book primarily consists of 1 star and 2 star problems, an occasional 3 star problem, and only a handful of 4 star problems towards the very end. And for those who might be wondering how difficult the 3 star problems are, I am approximately 4 kyu at this time and found them to be manageable. So based on that analysis, it should be pretty clear that the book is actually very accessible to beginner and intermediate players.<br />
Though there is no introductory section on the techniques that are used in the book, something that I want to remind readers out there is that the concept of tesuji is to find a move that works in your favor no matter how your opponent responds. Though some techniques can be neatly categorized and labelled, it would be impossible to collectively explain every technique that might ever arise in your game. So at the end of the day, the best way to build one&#8217;s ability to find and identify tesuji is to be exposed to more ideas and examples that already exist.<br />
Overall, I am very pleased with the quality of content and level of problems that this book provided. Although I wouldn&#8217;t necessarily give this book to someone who is 20 kyu, I would highly recommend this book to any player who has had some basic knowledge to tesuji and is looking for a book on tesuji that will not overwhelm them with overly difficult problems.<br />
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Recommended For&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ol>
<li>Players looking to improve their basic abilities in identifying and using tesuji.</li>
</ol>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Where Can I Buy It?&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>GoGameGuru &#8211; <a title="Get Strong at Tesuji GoGameGuru Purchase Link" href="http://shop.gogameguru.com/get-strong-at-tesuji/?acc=e4da3b7fbbce2345d7772b0674a318d5">$20.99</a> USD (shipping and handling not included)</li>
<li>Kiseido &#8211; <a title="Kiseido Purchase Form" href="http://www.kiseido.com/go_books.htm">$21.00</a> USD (shipping and handling not included)</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Other Books in This Series&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;lastExpandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li><a title="Book Review: Get Strong at the Opening" href="//book-review-get-strong-at-the-opening/">Get Strong at the Opening</a></li>
<li><a title="Book Review: Get Strong at Joseki 1" href="//book-review-get-strong-at-joseki-1/">Get Strong at Joseki 1</a></li>
<li><a title="Book Review: Get Strong at Joseki 2" href="//book-review-get-strong-joseki-2/">Get Strong at Joseki 2</a></li>
<li><a title="Book Review: Get Strong at Joseki 3" href="//book-review-get-strong-joseki-3/">Get Strong at Joseki 3</a></li>
<li>Get Strong at Invading</li>
<li>Get Strong at Tesuji</li>
<li>Get Strong at the Endgame</li>
<li>Get Strong at Life and Death</li>
<li>Get Strong at Handicap Go</li>
<li>Get Strong at Attacking</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
<p style="text-align: center;"><em><strong>Last Updated on September 28th, 2013</strong></em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/book-review-get-strong-tesuji/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">4014</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Book Review: Get Strong at Invading</title>
		<link>/book-review-get-strong-invading/</link>
		<comments>/book-review-get-strong-invading/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2013 13:58:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bozulich]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[get strong]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[invading]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kiseido]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=4011</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Get Strong at Invading Description: In the fifth volume of the Get Strong at Go Series, Bozulich provides a ground-breaking book on a topic that every player in go encounters: invasions. Once the spheres of influences have been established, being able to choose the correct invasions is a key skill to becoming stronger and winning. [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/09/getstrongv5cover.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-4012" alt="getstrongv5cover" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/09/getstrongv5cover.jpg?resize=280%2C400" width="280" height="400" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">Get Strong at Invading</h2>
<p><strong>Description:</strong> In the fifth volume of the Get Strong at Go Series, Bozulich provides a ground-breaking book on a topic that every player in go encounters: invasions. Once the spheres of influences have been established, being able to choose the correct invasions is a key skill to becoming stronger and winning. Through 171 problems, readers will have many opportunities to practice and hone their invasion abilities.<br />
<span id="more-4011"></span><br />
[expand title=&#8221;Book Details&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
[table]
Title, Get Strong at Invading<br />
Series, Get Strong at Go Series<br />
Author, Richard Bozulich<br />
Publisher, <a href="http://www.kiseido.com/">Kiseido</a><br />
Published, &#8220;First Printing May 1995 | Second Printing January 2010&#8243;<br />
Language, English<br />
ISBN, 987-4-906574-55-1<br />
Length, 152 Pages<br />
Problems, 171 Problems<br />
[/table]
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Table of Content&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Preface</li>
<li>Part One &#8211; Invasions on the Side</li>
<li>Part Two &#8211; Invading Corner Enclosures</li>
<li>Part Three &#8211; Invading Large Territories</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Before I Read This Book&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
Since I tend to be more of a &#8220;jump before you look&#8221; type of player, I&#8217;ve played my fair share of invasions without any regards as to whether or not it would be successful or whether it even hits the weak point. So in some regards, I have developed a basic understanding of how to invade based on trial and error. However, there have been numerous times where I wished that my decisions were made with a bit more sound judgment. So when I found out about this book, I couldn&#8217;t get around to ordering it fast enough.<br />
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Synopsis&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<strong>What did I enjoy about the book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Bozulich breaks invasions up into three common categories that players encounter: corner, sides, and frameworks.</li>
<li>There are numerous opportunities to practice identifying a similar type of weakness so that you can reinforce it in your mind.</li>
<li>In addition to identifying weaknesses and common invasion points, there are numerous problems that show the reader how to handle some common responses that their opponent might play.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What did I gain from reading this book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>A greater understanding and ability to identify how stronger players identify places to invade.</li>
<li>A much better grasp of what proper follow up moves are and the reason behind them.</li>
<li>A lot of new ideas regarding how to invade what I once considered &#8220;solid territory.&#8221;</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What is the format of the book?</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>A set of problems followed by their solutions and explanation. Repeat. Repeat. Repeat.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>What aspects can be improved on?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>I&#8217;m not sure of how feasible this really is, but I think it would have been helpful if there was a one-page summary of basic invasion principles that players should keep in mind when invading.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Is this book easy to read?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Yes. Explanations and solutions are very short and clear cut. In addition, the diagrams are not very complicated, so the solutions are typically very easy to follow.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Bottom Line</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>Currently the only book (I&#8217;m aware of) that focuses exclusively on invasions.</li>
<li>Provides a great way for players to get familiar with what are considered good invasion points and how they generally proceed afterwards.</li>
<li>Highly recommended and worth the money for anyone interested in getting stronger at invading.</li>
</ol>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;My Review&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221; expanded=&#8221;true&#8221;]
When I first started playing, I remember how difficult it was for me to choose points of invasion. More often than not, I would stare at my opponent&#8217;s formation and feel so intimidated by it that I would never invade. Luckily for me, this book really helped to open my eyes in regards to where the weaknesses in popular formations are, along with the common follow-up move to make sabaki or life.<br />
The first section on &#8220;Invasions on the Side&#8221; was very informative in helping me recognize what was considered thin and where the weak points were. In addition, there are variation in the problems regarding how the opponent responds and recommended responses along with the rationale for why the result is considered acceptable. Definitely very helpful.<br />
The next section on &#8220;Invading Corner Enclosures&#8221; might be my favorite in this book. The reason for this is that I believe that kyu players often have difficulty identifying where to invade in an opponent&#8217;s corner enclosure. So more often than not, the territory is left untouched and assumed complete. By exposing players to the weaknesses and ways of living in &#8220;completed territory,&#8221; I think this will help a lot of players get stronger since they will feel better equipped to fight back when they are behind in territory.<br />
In the last section on &#8220;Invading Large Territories,&#8221; Bozulich does a great job heping readers identify weak points in very common moyo shapes. Though focused on teaching players common invasion/reduction points, it also serves as a great way to practice analyzing the board as a whole.<br />
My final piece of advice to players thinking about buying this book is this: Being able to choose the right invasion point and being able to make your invasion successful are two VERY DIFFERENT things. Aside from figuring out the proper timing, you must be aware of the fact that successful invasions involve lots of fighting and ability to make living shapes. So while this book will provide you the foundation you need for launching your invasions, just remember that there are multiple aspects to a successful invasion.<br />
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Recommended For&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ol>
<li>Players looking to strengthen their ability to invade their opponent&#8217;s positions.</li>
</ol>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Where Can I Buy It?&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>GoGameGuru &#8211; <a title="Get Strong at Invading GoGameGuru Purchase Link" href="http://shop.gogameguru.com/get-strong-at-invading/?acc=e4da3b7fbbce2345d7772b0674a318d5">$20.99</a> USD (shipping and handling not included)</li>
<li>Kiseido &#8211; <a title="Kiseido Purchase Form" href="http://www.kiseido.com/go_books.htm">$21.00</a> USD (shipping and handling not included)</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Other Books in This Series&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;lastExpandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li><a title="Book Review: Get Strong at the Opening" href="//book-review-get-strong-at-the-opening/">Get Strong at the Opening</a></li>
<li><a title="Book Review: Get Strong at Joseki 1" href="//book-review-get-strong-at-joseki-1/">Get Strong at Joseki 1</a></li>
<li><a title="Book Review: Get Strong at Joseki 2" href="//book-review-get-strong-joseki-2/">Get Strong at Joseki 2</a></li>
<li><a title="Book Review: Get Strong at Joseki 3" href="//book-review-get-strong-joseki-3/">Get Strong at Joseki 3</a></li>
<li>Get Strong at Invading</li>
<li>Get Strong at Tesuji</li>
<li>Get Strong at the Endgame</li>
<li>Get Strong at Life and Death</li>
<li>Get Strong at Handicap Go</li>
<li>Get Strong at Attacking</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
<p style="text-align: center;"><em><strong>Last Updated on September 24th, 2013.</strong></em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/book-review-get-strong-invading/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">4011</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Book Review: Get Strong at Joseki 3</title>
		<link>/book-review-get-strong-joseki-3/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2013 20:25:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bozulich]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[get strong]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[joseki]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kaz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kiseido]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[star point]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=3972</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Get Strong at Joseki 3 Description: In the fourth volume of the Get Strong at Go Series, Bozulich and Kazunari familiarizes the reader with 10 josekis that commonly occur around the star point, how to handle them in regards to their variations, choosing the correct joseki given the whole board, and how to play after [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/09/getstrongv4cover.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3973" alt="getstrongv4cover" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/09/getstrongv4cover.jpg?resize=280%2C400" width="280" height="400" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">Get Strong at Joseki 3</h2>
<p><strong>Description:</strong> In the fourth volume of the Get Strong at Go Series, Bozulich and Kazunari familiarizes the reader with 10 josekis that commonly occur around the star point, how to handle them in regards to their variations, choosing the correct joseki given the whole board, and how to play after the joseki is completed. A great book for players who want a better grasp on joseki as a whole.<br />
<span id="more-3972"></span><br />
[expand title=&#8221;Book Details&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
[table]
Title, Get Strong at Joseki 3 (Vol. 4)<br />
Series, Get Strong at Go Series<br />
Author, Richard Bozulich &amp; Furuyama Kazunari<br />
Publisher, <a href="http://www.kiseido.com/">Kiseido</a><br />
Published, &#8220;First Printing May 1996 | Second Printing August 2008&#8243;<br />
Language, English<br />
ISBN, 987-4-906574-54-4<br />
Length, 208 Pages<br />
Problems, 194 Problems<br />
[/table]
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Table of Content&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Preface</li>
<li>Introduction &#8211; Ten Basic Joseki</li>
<li>Problems Part One &#8211; Joseki Variations (Problems 1-116)</li>
<li>Problems Part Two &#8211; Choosing the Right Joseki (117-140)</li>
<li>Problems Part Three &#8211; How to Play After the Joseki (141-194)</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Before I Read This Book&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
As I mentioned before in the previous two volumes (<a title="Book Review: Get Strong at Joseki 1" href="//book-review-get-strong-at-joseki-1/">GTAJ1</a> &amp; <a title="Book Review: Get Strong at Joseki 2" href="//book-review-get-strong-joseki-2/">GTAJ2</a>), joseki is not a real strength of mine. While I have become aware of some common ones due to experience using them or making mistakes, learning joseki has always been a bit of a challenge for me. With this final volume though, I was really looking forward to seeing star point joseki be featured.<br />
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Synopsis&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<strong>What did I enjoy about the book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>I really liked the fact that Bozulich &amp; Kazunari included joseki that are not commonly found in resources like Josekipedia. An example of this include the high one space double approach.</li>
<li>I enjoy the fact that Bozulich &amp; Kazunari includes some common trick plays and how to handle them.</li>
<li>The problems contain variations on different scenarios that really help acclimate the reader to seeing how just one slight chance in the sequence can completely change the outcome.</li>
<li>There is a whole section devoted to choosing joseki in regards to the entire board.</li>
<li>Proper attention is given to how to play once a joseki is finished.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What did I gain from reading this book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>A realization that there is a lot more to start point joseki than I was aware.</li>
<li>A better understanding of some of the reasons behind why certain joseki are played.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What is the format of the book?</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>Similar to the <a title="Book Review: Get Strong at Joseki 1" href="//book-review-get-strong-at-joseki-1/">GTSAJ1</a> and <a title="Book Review: Get Strong at Joseki 2" href="//book-review-get-strong-joseki-2/">GTSAJ2</a>, there is an introduction section that familiarizes the reader with the featured joseki in the book. Afterwards, the rest are practice problems accompanied by their solutions to help the reader gain a better grasp on the joseki.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>What aspects can be improved on?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>No complaints here!</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Is this book easy to read?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Yes and no. The explanations are short and concise for those who are familiar with much of go strategy and its terminology. For those who might be unfamiliar with things such as a &#8220;severe pincer&#8221; or how moves are &#8220;pressuring another group&#8221; might find it a little hard to comprehend.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Bottom Line</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>Excellent format for players to familiarize themselves with some common star point joseki along with some not so common ones as well.</li>
<li>Gives great practice for trying to see the board as a whole instead of localized sequences.</li>
<li>A fantastic way for players to gain a better handle on using joseki instead of simply memorizing them.</li>
</ol>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;My Review&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221; expanded=&#8221;true&#8221;]
As with the previous volumes, I was very pleased overall with the quality of problems in this book. Bozulich &amp; Kazunari continued to live up to my expectations and did a great job with the star point joseki featured in this book. Just like before though, I found that the first section regarding joseki variations was still quite difficult for me to work through. To be clear though, Bozulich acknowledges that this will be common for many players at first due to unfamiliarity with the material. So it&#8217;s nothing to fret about.<br />
The favorite part of my book is still the section on &#8220;Choosing the Right Joseki and Playing the Right Joseki&#8221; since it is geared toward getting to the reader to take into account the whole board when making their decision. This is a wonderful change of scenery from the narrow perspective that players often practice on (such as focusing on just a corner or two groups for life and death). Definitely the best section of the entire series.<br />
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Recommended For&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ol>
<li>Players looking to study some common (and a couple uncommon) star point joseki and its application to actual board positions.</li>
</ol>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Where Can I Buy It?&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>GoGameGuru &#8211; <a title="Get Strong at Joseki 3 GoGameGuru Purchase Link" href="http://shop.gogameguru.com/get-strong-at-joseki-3/?acc=e4da3b7fbbce2345d7772b0674a318d5">$20.99</a> USD (shipping and handling not included)</li>
<li>Kiseido &#8211; <a title="Kiseido Purchase Form" href="http://www.kiseido.com/go_books.htm">$21.00</a> USD (shipping and handling not included)</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Other Books in This Series&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;lastExpandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li><a title="Book Review: Get Strong at the Opening" href="//book-review-get-strong-at-the-opening/">Get Strong at the Opening</a></li>
<li><a title="Book Review: Get Strong at Joseki 1" href="//book-review-get-strong-at-joseki-1/">Get Strong at Joseki 1</a></li>
<li><a title="Book Review: Get Strong at Joseki 2" href="//book-review-get-strong-joseki-2/">Get Strong at Joseki 2</a></li>
<li>Get Strong at Joseki 3</li>
<li>Get Strong at Invading</li>
<li>Get Strong at Tesuji</li>
<li>Get Strong at the Endgame</li>
<li>Get Strong at Life and Death</li>
<li>Get Strong at Handicap Go</li>
<li>Get Strong at Attacking</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
<p style="text-align: center;"><em><strong>Last Updated on September 14th, 2013.</strong></em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3972</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Book Review: Get Strong at Joseki 2</title>
		<link>/book-review-get-strong-joseki-2/</link>
		<comments>/book-review-get-strong-joseki-2/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2013 10:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[5-3]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[5-4]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[joseki]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kiseido]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[whole board]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=3888</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Get Strong at Joseki 2 Description: In the third volume of the Get Strong at Go Series, Bozulich familiarizes the reader with 8 josekis that commonly occur around the 5-4 and 5-3 point, how to handle them in regards to their variations, choosing the correct joseki given the whole board, and how to play after [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/08/getstrongv3cover.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3889" alt="Get Strong at Joseki 2 Cover" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/08/getstrongv3cover.jpg?resize=280%2C400" width="280" height="400" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">Get Strong at Joseki 2</h2>
<p><strong>Description:</strong> In the third volume of the Get Strong at Go Series, Bozulich familiarizes the reader with 8 josekis that commonly occur around the 5-4 and 5-3 point, how to handle them in regards to their variations, choosing the correct joseki given the whole board, and how to play after the joseki is completed. A great book for players who want a better grasp on joseki as a whole.<br />
<span id="more-3888"></span><br />
[expand title=&#8221;Book Details&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
[table]
Title, Get Strong at Joseki 2<br />
Series, Get Strong at Go Series<br />
Author, Richard Bozulich in collaboration with Furuyama Kazunari<br />
Publisher, <a href="http://www.kiseido.com/">Kiseido</a><br />
Published, &#8220;First Printing January 1996&#8243;<br />
Language, English<br />
ISBN, 4-906574-053-X<br />
Length, 174 Pages<br />
Problems, 172 Problems<br />
[/table]
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Table of Content&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Preface</li>
<li>Introduction &#8211; Eight Basic Joseki</li>
<li>Part One &#8211; After the Joseki and Joseki Variations (Problems 1-122)</li>
<li>Part Two &#8211; Choosing the Right Joseki and Playing after the Joseki (Problems 123-172)</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Before I Read This Book&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<strong>My Abilities</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>I have had some exposure to joseki, but for the most part I have avoided the study of joseki for a long time. As a result, I would consider my knowledge and ability to use joseki to be very weak, ESPECIALLY when it comes to the 5-4 and 5-3 points.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>My Perspective</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>After reading <a title="Book Review: Get Strong at Joseki 1" href="//book-review-get-strong-at-joseki-1/">Get Strong at Joseki 1</a>, I was looking forward to what this book had to offer. And to be clear, I was hoping to get more exposure to more joseki and continue familiarizing myself with it.</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Synopsis&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<strong>What did I enjoy about the book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>I enjoy the fact that Bozulich includes some common trick plays and how to handle them.</li>
<li>The problems contain variations on different scenarios that really help acclimate the reader to seeing how just one slight chance in the sequence can completely change the outcome.</li>
<li>There is a whole section devoted to choosing joseki in regards to the entire board.</li>
<li>Proper attention is given to how to play once a joseki is finished.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What did I gain from reading this book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>An increased liking and familiarity with joseki.</li>
<li>A better understanding of how to apply or even deviate from joseki in my own games.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What is the format of the book?</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>Similar to the Get Strong at Joseki 1, there is an introduction section that familiarizes the reader with the featured joseki in the book. Afterwards, the rest are practice problems accompanied by their solutions to help the reader gain a better grasp on the joseki.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>What aspects can be improved on?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>No complaints here!</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Is this book easy to read?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Yes and no. The explanations are short and concise for those who are familiar with much of go strategy and its terminology. For those who might be unfamiliar with things such as a &#8220;severe pincer&#8221; or how moves are &#8220;pressuring another group&#8221; might find it a little hard to comprehend.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Bottom Line</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>Excellent format for players to familiarize themselves with joseki.</li>
<li>Gives great practice for trying to see the board as a whole instead of localized sequences.</li>
<li>A fantastic way for players to gain a better handle on using joseki instead of simply memorizing them.</li>
</ol>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;My Review&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221; expanded=&#8221;true&#8221;]
Overall, I was very happy with the continued quality of problems in this book. Similar to the previous volume, I found that the first section regarding joseki variations was rather hard for me to work through. Though to be clear, Bozulich acknowledges that this will be common for many players at first due to unfamiliarity with the material. So it&#8217;s nothing to fret about.<br />
The favorite part of my book continues to be the section on &#8220;Choosing the Right Joseki and Playing the Right Joseki&#8221; since it is geared toward getting to the reader to take into account the whole board when making their decision. This is a wonderful change of scenery from the narrow perspective that players often practice on (such as focusing on just a corner or two groups for life and death). So much love for this section. Definitely hoping to see more of this in the next volume!<br />
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Recommended For&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ol>
<li>Players looking to study 5-3 and 5-4 joseki and its application to actual board positions.</li>
</ol>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Where Can I Buy It?&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>GoGameGuru &#8211; <a title="Get Strong at Joseki 2 GoGameGuru Purchase Link" href="http://shop.gogameguru.com/get-strong-at-joseki-2/?acc=e4da3b7fbbce2345d7772b0674a318d5">$20.99</a> USD (shipping and handling not included)</li>
<li>Kiseido &#8211; <a title="Kiseido Purchase Form" href="http://www.kiseido.com/go_books.htm">$21.00</a> USD (shipping and handling not included)</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Other Books in This Series&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;lastExpandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li><a title="Book Review: Get Strong at the Opening" href="//book-review-get-strong-at-the-opening/">Get Strong at the Opening</a></li>
<li><a title="Book Review: Get Strong at Joseki 1" href="//book-review-get-strong-at-joseki-1/">Get Strong at Joseki 1</a></li>
<li>Get Strong at Joseki 2</li>
<li>Get Strong at Joseki 3</li>
<li>Get Strong at Invading</li>
<li>Get Strong at Tesuji</li>
<li>Get Strong at the Endgame</li>
<li>Get Strong at Life and Death</li>
<li>Get Strong at Handicap Go</li>
<li>Get Strong at Attacking</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
<p style="text-align: center;"><em><strong>Last Updated on September 7th, 2013.</strong></em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/book-review-get-strong-joseki-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3888</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Book Review: Get Strong at Joseki 1</title>
		<link>/book-review-get-strong-at-joseki-1/</link>
		<comments>/book-review-get-strong-at-joseki-1/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2013 09:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[get strong]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[joseki]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kiseido]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[variations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[whole board]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=3837</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Get Strong at Joseki 1 Description: In the second volume of the Get Strong at Go Series, Bozulich familiarizes the reader with 11 basic josekis that commonly occur around the 3-4 point and how to handle them in regards to their variations, choosing the correct joseki given the whole board, and how to play after [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/08/getstrongv2.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3838" alt="Get Strong at Joseki 1 Cover" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/08/getstrongv2.jpg?resize=280%2C400" width="280" height="400" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">Get Strong at Joseki 1</h2>
<p><strong>Description:</strong> In the second volume of the Get Strong at Go Series, Bozulich familiarizes the reader with 11 basic josekis that commonly occur around the 3-4 point and how to handle them in regards to their variations, choosing the correct joseki given the whole board, and how to play after the joseki is completed. A great book for players who want a better grasp on joseki as a whole.<br />
<span id="more-3837"></span><br />
[expand title=&#8221;Book Details&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
[table]
Title, Get Strong at Joseki 1<br />
Series, Get Strong at Go Series<br />
Author, Richard Bozulich<br />
Publisher, <a href="http://www.kiseido.com/">Kiseido</a><br />
Published, &#8220;First Printing September 1995 | Second Printing November 2002&#8243;<br />
Language, English<br />
ISBN, 4-906574-52-1<br />
Length, 176 Pages<br />
Problems, 178 Problems<br />
[/table]
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Table of Content&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Preface</li>
<li>Introduction</li>
<li>Part One &#8211; Joseki Variations (Problems 1-99)</li>
<li>Part Two &#8211; Choosing the Right Joseki (Problems 100-124)</li>
<li>Part Three &#8211; How to Play After the Joseki (Problems 125-178)</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Before I Read This Book&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<strong>My Abilities</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>I have had some exposure to joseki, but for the most part I have avoided the study of joseki for a long time. As a result, I would consider my knowledge and ability to use joseki to be very weak.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>My Perspective</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>As I am a big fan of the Get Strong at Go Series, I&#8217;m really hoping that this will help me gain more familiarity with joseki and increase my comfort with using them.</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Synopsis&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<strong>What did I enjoy about the book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>I enjoy the fact that Bozulich includes some common trick plays and how to handle them.</li>
<li>The problems contain variations on different scenarios that really help acclimate the reader to seeing how just one slight chance in the sequence can completely change the outcome.</li>
<li>There is a whole section devoted to choosing joseki in regards to the entire board.</li>
<li>Proper attention is given to how to play once a joseki is finished.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What did I gain from reading this book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>An increased liking and familiarity with joseki.</li>
<li>A better understanding of how to apply joseki to my own games.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What is the format of the book?</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>Introduction to the 11 basic joseki focused on in this book.</li>
<li>A section of practice problems focusing on joseki variations.</li>
<li>A section of practice problems focusing on choosing the correct joseki given the whole board context.</li>
<li>A section of practice problems on how to continue play once the joseki is complete.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>What aspects can be improved on?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>No complaints here!</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Is this book easy to read?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Yes and no. The explanations are short and concise for those who are familiar with much of go strategy and its terminology. For those who might be unfamiliar with things such as a &#8220;severe pincer&#8221; or how moves are &#8220;pressuring another group&#8221; might find it a little hard to comprehend.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Bottom Line</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>Excellent format for players to familiarize themselves with joseki.</li>
<li>Gives great practice for trying to see the board as a whole instead of localized sequences.</li>
<li>A fantastic way for players to gain a better handle on using joseki instead of simply memorizing them.</li>
</ol>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;My Review&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221; expanded=&#8221;true&#8221;]
Overall, I was very impressed with this book. While the first section of the book regarding joseki variations was a bit difficult for me to work through (since my own knowledge of joseki is very weak), the other two sections were very helpful and enjoyable to practice since I was able to be exposed to a lot of new ideas and practice my whole board evaluation ability. As mentioned above in the &#8220;Before I Read This Book&#8221; section, I am someone who has always been adverse to joseki and have thus avoided the topic as a whole. So the fact that I did not find this book excruciating to work through speaks quite a bit about it.<br />
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Recommended For&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ol>
<li>Players looking to study joseki and its application to actual board positions.</li>
</ol>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Where Can I Buy It?&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>GoGameGuru &#8211; <a title="Get Strong at Joseki 1 GoGameGuru Purchase Link" href="http://shop.gogameguru.com/get-strong-at-joseki-1/?acc=e4da3b7fbbce2345d7772b0674a318d5">$20.99</a> USD (shipping and handling not included)</li>
<li>Kiseido &#8211; <a title="Kiseido Purchase Form" href="http://www.kiseido.com/go_books.htm">$21.00</a> USD (shipping and handling not included)</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Other Books in This Series&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;lastExpandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li><a title="Book Review: Get Strong at the Opening" href="//book-review-get-strong-at-the-opening/">Get Strong at the Opening</a></li>
<li>Get Strong at Joseki 1</li>
<li>Get Strong at Joseki 2</li>
<li>Get Strong at Joseki 3</li>
<li>Get Strong at Invading</li>
<li>Get Strong at Tesuji</li>
<li>Get Strong at the Endgame</li>
<li>Get Strong at Life and Death</li>
<li>Get Strong at Handicap Go</li>
<li>Get Strong at Attacking</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
<p style="text-align: center;"><em><strong>Last Updated on August 25th, 2013</strong></em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/book-review-get-strong-at-joseki-1/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3837</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Book Review: Handicap Go</title>
		<link>/book-review-handicap-go/</link>
		<comments>/book-review-handicap-go/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2013 09:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[elementary go series]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[handicap go]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[introductory]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kiseido]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=3577</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Handicap Go Description: In the final installment of the Elementary Go Series, Yoshiaki and Bozulich lay down some basic principles for how one should play handicap go as black. In addition, there is advice on how to handle games as White along with practice problems to reinforce some of the lessons. [expand title=&#8221;Book Details&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;] [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/07/egsv7cover.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3578" alt="Handicap Go Cover" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/07/egsv7cover.jpg?resize=300%2C437" width="300" height="437" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">Handicap Go</h2>
<p><strong>Description: </strong>In the final installment of the Elementary Go Series, Yoshiaki and Bozulich lay down some basic principles for how one should play handicap go as black. In addition, there is advice on how to handle games as White along with practice problems to reinforce some of the lessons.<br />
<span id="more-3577"></span><br />
[expand title=&#8221;Book Details&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
[table]
Title, Handicap Go (Volume 7)<br />
Series, Elementary Go Series<br />
Author, Nagahara Yoshiaki (7P) &amp; Richard Bozulich<br />
Publisher, <a href="http://www.kiseido.com/">Kiseido</a><br />
Published, &#8220;1st Edition: October 1982, Revised Edition: May 2013&#8243;<br />
Language, English<br />
ISBN, 978-4-906574-16-2<br />
Length, 208 Pages<br />
[/table]
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Table of Content&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Preface</li>
<li>Some Important Terms and Concepts</li>
<li>Chapter One: The Strategic Principles of Handicap Go</li>
<li>Chapter Two: A Winning Strategy for Black</li>
<li>Chapter Three: Playing with White</li>
<li>Chapter Four: Example Games</li>
<li>Chapter Five: 38 Problems</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Synopsis&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221; expanded=&#8221;true&#8221;]
<ol>
<li>A fantastic book on handicap go.</li>
<li>Provides great explanations for Black&#8217;s strategy along with some advice for White as well.</li>
<li>Has an array of example games and problems for the reader to use as additional learning material.</li>
</ol>
[/expand]
<!--more--><br />
[expand title=&#8221;Before I Read This Book&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<strong>My Abilities</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>While I have done some studying on handicap go, my knowledge is primarily a compilation of advice from other people along with my own experience as well. Overall, I would say that I believe I have a basic understanding of how handicap games should be played.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>My Perspective</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Though I&#8217;ve read tidbits on handicap go here and there, I am hoping that this book will be the first that tries to break down handicap go into into simplest components in order to provide guidance to players new to handicap go.</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;My Review&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221; expanded=&#8221;true&#8221;]
<strong>What did I enjoy about the book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The advice for Black is broken down into 20 strategic principles.</li>
<li>There is a chapter devoted to advising how one should play with White.</li>
<li>There are example games that range from professionals level to amateur dan level.</li>
<li>There are practice problems to help reinforce the concepts the reader just learned.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What did I gain from reading this book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>A better understanding of how to play as Black in handicap games.</li>
<li>Realization that as White it is not actually beneficial to make overplays consistently, but rather to play solid moves with strategic value and to take advantage of Black&#8217;s inefficient moves and/or strategic plans.</li>
<li>A new perspective on how handicap games actually should go all the way into the endgame for the handicap to be considered fair in relation to the ranks.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What style of teaching does the book use?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Textbook Approach
<ul>
<li>Explanations can be very dense at times and it uses problems or examples to try and illustrate its message. This is not a negative thing though, since it allows for re-readability in the future.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Primary Learning Mechanism:
<ul>
<li>Explanations.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Other Learning Mechanisms:
<ul>
<li>Practice problems.</li>
<li>Examples from professional and amateur level games.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What aspect can be improved on?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>In the future, I think it would be nice to see strategic principles organized for White the way it is designed for Black. Not sure how possible this really is, but it&#8217;d be neat if it were possible.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Is this book easy to read?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Yes. Though some explanations may be advanced at times, Bozulich strikes a great balance between introductory explanations and advanced concepts. It makes for a solid book that will be worth re-reading in the future.</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Recommended For&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Any player looking to learn more about handicap go.</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Where Can I Buy It?&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Kiseido &#8211; <a title="Kiseido Purchase Link" href="http://kiseido.com/go_books.htm">$18.00</a> USD (shipping &amp; handling not included)</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Other Books in This Series&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;lastExpandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li><a title="Book Review: In the Beginning" href="//book-review-in-the-beginning/">Elementary Go Series, Volume 1 &#8211; In the Beginning</a></li>
<li><a title="Book Review: 38 Basic Joseki" href="//book-review-38-basic-joseki/">Elementary Go Series, Volume 2 &#8211; 38 Basic Joseki</a></li>
<li><a title="Book Review: Tesuji" href="//book-review-tesuji/">Elementary Go Series, Volume 3 &#8211; Tesuji</a></li>
<li><a title="Book Review: Life and Death" href="//book-review-life-and-death/">Elementary Go Series, Volume 4 &#8211; Life and Death</a></li>
<li><a title="Book Review: Attack and Defense" href="//book-review-attack-and-defense/">Elementary Go Series, Volume 5 &#8211; Attack and Defense</a></li>
<li><a title="Book Review: The Endgame" href="//book-review-the-endgame/">Elementary Go Series, Volume 6 &#8211; The Endgame</a></li>
</ul>
[/expand]
<p style="text-align: center;"><em><strong>Last Updated on July 28th, 2013</strong></em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/book-review-handicap-go/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3577</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Book Review: The Endgame</title>
		<link>/book-review-the-endgame/</link>
		<comments>/book-review-the-endgame/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2013 02:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[counting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kiseido]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the endgame]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=3507</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Description: In this installment of the Elementary Go Series, Ogawa and Davies attempts to lay out the basic tactics, strategies, and techniques required to fully master the endgame. While an excellent reference for players with an understanding of endgame, this may prove to be slightly advanced for someone brand new to endgame. [expand title=&#8221;Book Details&#8221; [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/07/egsv7theendgame.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3508" alt="The Endgame Cover" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/07/egsv7theendgame.jpg?resize=276%2C400" width="276" height="400" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><br />
<strong>Description: </strong>In this installment of the Elementary Go Series, Ogawa and Davies attempts to lay out the basic tactics, strategies, and techniques required to fully master the endgame. While an excellent reference for players with an understanding of endgame, this may prove to be slightly advanced for someone brand new to endgame.<br />
<span id="more-3507"></span><br />
[expand title=&#8221;Book Details&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
[table]
Title, The Endgame (Volume 6)<br />
Series, Elementary Go Series<br />
Author, Tomoko Ogawa &amp; James Davies<br />
Publisher, <a href="http://www.kiseido.com/">Kiseido</a><br />
Published, &#8220;September 1976&#8243;<br />
Language, English<br />
ISBN, 978-4-906574-15-5<br />
Length, 214 Pages<br />
[/table]
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Table of Content&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Chapter 1: Introducing the Endgame</li>
<li>Chapter 2: Counting</li>
<li>Chapter 3: Endgame Tesuji</li>
<li>Chapter 4: The Macro-Endgame</li>
<li>Chapter 5: Games</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Synopsis&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221; expanded=&#8221;true&#8221;]
<ol>
<li>A comprehensive book that covers quite a great deal of content regarding the endgame.</li>
<li>Masterfully utilizes multiple choice questions to help train the reader on gaining a better understanding of why one answer is better than another.</li>
<li>It is more advanced than I was anticipating. Not necessarily the most beginner friendly when it comes to endgame.</li>
</ol>
[/expand]
<!--more--><br />
[expand title=&#8221;Before I Read This Book&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<strong>My Abilities</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>I have never formally studied endgame. However, I have some preliminary knowledge of some basic concepts like reverse-sente and doubling the value of a move because it is sente. I also have some exposure to determining value for endgame moves, but I&#8217;m terrible at it.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>My Perspective</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>I was really hoping to clear up any confusion I had about determining the value of endgame moves. In other words, I am hoping that by the end of this book, any failure to play the biggest endgame moves will only be due to laziness and not inability to calculate it.</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;My Review&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221; expanded=&#8221;true&#8221;]
<strong>What did I enjoy about the book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>I really enjoyed the endgame tesuji section. Lots of great explanations along with practice problems.</li>
<li>I was also really surprised by how thorough and useful the macro-endgame chapter was. The use of multiple choice questions was definitely ideal for learning.</li>
<li>They use a sequence of problems with scores for the respective answers to &#8220;grade&#8221; your endgame abilities. I thought this was pretty cool.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What did I gain from reading this book?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>A greater appreciation for the importance of endgame.</li>
<li>More perspective on not responding automatically for endgame moves and trying to find sequences that are either sente for myself or at least only give a gote sequence for my opponent.</li>
<li>Improved understanding of whole board decisions when it comes to endgame.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What style of teaching does the book use?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Textbook Approach
<ul>
<li>Explanations can be very dense at times and it uses problems or examples to try and illustrate its message.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Primary Learning Mechanism:
<ul>
<li>Explanations.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Other Learning Mechanisms:
<ul>
<li>Practice problems.</li>
<li>Multiple choice problems.</li>
<li>Examples from professional games.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What aspects can be improved on?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The first chapter is pretty frightening for anyone who is new to endgame and cannot process a million things going on at once.</li>
<li>The material and level of explanation was much more accommodating to players new to endgame as the book progressed, which is contrary to what most people would expect (aka easy to understand into dense material).</li>
<li>The section on teaching how to count could be enhanced to accommodate introduction problems and more opportunity to practice how to count the value of endgame sequences.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Is this book easy to read?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>For the most part, yes. The first chapter was incredibly difficult for me to work through there was a lot of high level discussion that just went over my head. When the book go into the endgame tesujis and multiple choice problems, it became a lot easier to read and understand.</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Recommended For&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>Players who have a basic understanding of endgame.</li>
<li>Players looking for an opportunity to test their knowledge of endgame using the graded problems in this book.</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Where Can I Buy It?&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;expandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li>GoGameGuru &#8211; <a title="Go Game Guru Purchase Link" href="http://shop.gogameguru.com/the-endgame/?acc=e4da3b7fbbce2345d7772b0674a318d5">$17.99</a> USD (shipping &amp; handling not included)</li>
<li>Kiseido &#8211; <a title="Kiseido Purchase Link" href="http://kiseido.com/go_books.htm">$18.00</a> USD (shipping &amp; handling not included)</li>
<li>SmartGo Books &#8211; <a title="SmartGo Book Link" href="http://www.smartgo.com/books.htm">$9.99</a> USD (e-Book for iPad &amp; iPhone Only)</li>
</ul>
[/expand]
[expand title=&#8221;Other Books in This Series&#8230;&#8221; trigclass=&#8221;lastExpandTitle&#8221;]
<ul>
<li><a title="Book Review: In the Beginning" href="//book-review-in-the-beginning/">Elementary Go Series, Volume 1 &#8211; In the Beginning</a></li>
<li><a title="Book Review: 38 Basic Joseki" href="//book-review-38-basic-joseki/">Elementary Go Series, Volume 2 &#8211; 38 Basic Joseki</a></li>
<li><a title="Book Review: Tesuji" href="//book-review-tesuji/">Elementary Go Series, Volume 3 &#8211; Tesuji</a></li>
<li><a title="Book Review: Life and Death" href="//book-review-life-and-death/">Elementary Go Series, Volume 4 &#8211; Life and Death</a></li>
<li><a title="Book Review: Attack and Defense" href="//book-review-attack-and-defense/">Elementary Go Series, Volume 5 &#8211; Attack and Defense</a></li>
<li><a title="Book Review: Handicap Go" href="//book-review-handicap-go/">Elementary Go Series, Volume 7 &#8211; Handicap Go</a></li>
</ul>
[/expand]
<p style="text-align: center;"><em><strong>Last Updated on July 22nd, 2013</strong></em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/book-review-the-endgame/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3507</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
