<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>risky &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/risky/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>Pursuing Zen Under Siege</title>
		<link>/pursuing-zen-siege/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2013 23:36:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[risky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[siege]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zen]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=4281</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;ve been thinking a lot about life lately something about myself. For those who know me in real life, it&#8217;s probably safe to say that I can get a little overly excited about something most people would consider mundane. It&#8217;s not because I was deprived as a child or anything; but I believe that each [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve been thinking a lot about life lately something about myself. For those who know me in real life, it&#8217;s probably safe to say that I can get a little overly excited about something most people would consider mundane. It&#8217;s not because I was deprived as a child or anything; but I believe that each day should be lived to the fullest and that every moment we have is something to be excited about.<br />
The downside, however, is that while I am able to keep my emotions and mental state very positive for a majority of the time, one wrong misstep can throw me into a weird limbo where I kind of just fall off the deep end. And whether I like it or not, this is clearly reflected in my go. So in order to try and train my ability to be calm and collected, I decided to do the one thing I generally advise against: playing blitz games.<br />
With the time pressure and the fact that I tend to take my losses in blitz pretty hard (due to the fact that I often lose due to a stupid mistake as opposed to actually being weaker than my opponent), this approach is essentially the equivalent of trying to achieve enlightenment in the middle of a war zone. It&#8217;s not that it&#8217;s impossible, but it&#8217;s pretty risky and could be dangerous for my go. However, I know that trying to take any other route will probably delay my ability to overcome this hurdle.<br />
See you on the other side.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">4281</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
