<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"

	>
<channel>
	<title>Comments on: Still Deep in the Trenches</title>
	<atom:link href="/still-deep-trenches/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/still-deep-trenches/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2015 12:34:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
	<item>
		<title>By: Moboy78</title>
		<link>/still-deep-trenches/#comment-2502</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Moboy78]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2014 02:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5575#comment-2502</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The lack of a &quot;final answer&quot; in go can sometimes be a bit of a good thing in my opinion.  Usually the only times in go when there is a level of ambiguity to what move might be considered the &#039;best move&#039; on the board is the opening and early middle game. It is in those two stages of the game where peoples&#039; individual styles of play are shown.  I think people are able to have such different styles of play in go because of that ambiguity and lack of a &quot;final answer&quot;.  Objectively speaking, move x might not be any better than move y, but it might resonate more with my style of playing go than with someone else&#039;s.  I think that makes go a more forgiving game than chess and makes those stages of the game a bit easier to master.
I&#039;d also like to clarify my earlier statement about sequences and the example I&#039;d used with me asking a stronger player about a sequence.  It wasn&#039;t the variation (moves x, y, and z) that I found irksome, it&#039;s the fact that if I don&#039;t know that particular joseki then I&#039;d have to spend a very inconvenient amount of time during a game reading out the different variations to see which one is best.  It&#039;s not really a big deal in casual games, but I find it very annoying during a tournament game and I encounter a joseki I don&#039;t know.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The lack of a &#8220;final answer&#8221; in go can sometimes be a bit of a good thing in my opinion.  Usually the only times in go when there is a level of ambiguity to what move might be considered the &#8216;best move&#8217; on the board is the opening and early middle game. It is in those two stages of the game where peoples&#8217; individual styles of play are shown.  I think people are able to have such different styles of play in go because of that ambiguity and lack of a &#8220;final answer&#8221;.  Objectively speaking, move x might not be any better than move y, but it might resonate more with my style of playing go than with someone else&#8217;s.  I think that makes go a more forgiving game than chess and makes those stages of the game a bit easier to master.<br />
I&#8217;d also like to clarify my earlier statement about sequences and the example I&#8217;d used with me asking a stronger player about a sequence.  It wasn&#8217;t the variation (moves x, y, and z) that I found irksome, it&#8217;s the fact that if I don&#8217;t know that particular joseki then I&#8217;d have to spend a very inconvenient amount of time during a game reading out the different variations to see which one is best.  It&#8217;s not really a big deal in casual games, but I find it very annoying during a tournament game and I encounter a joseki I don&#8217;t know.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: MolokaiCowboy</title>
		<link>/still-deep-trenches/#comment-2501</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[MolokaiCowboy]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2014 02:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5575#comment-2501</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[An issue I have had with Go (versus chess) over the years is
that Go is &#039;softer&#039; less deterministic. You mention how you ask about x, y, z and
the answer you receive from the stronger player is not fully satisfying.
 In
chess, usually (not always) you can drill down to a &#039;final&#039; answer with hard analysis. Go is just
too deep for that most times. Hard analysis is difficult because there are so
many variations and few of them are forcing as in chess. In chess if the
variation loses a piece - its over. In Go if the variation loses a small group
- it may just be the beginning of things at the whole-board level. This is one reason why the Monte Carlo sampling technique works better in Go than in chess - the distribution of samples in Go is relatively smooth. In chess, most moves just lose outright so samples are unreliable.
I do think
chess combinations are more aesthetically satisfying (and diverse) than Go
combinations - but perhaps that is just because I am a better chess player than
Go player.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An issue I have had with Go (versus chess) over the years is<br />
that Go is &#8216;softer&#8217; less deterministic. You mention how you ask about x, y, z and<br />
the answer you receive from the stronger player is not fully satisfying.<br />
 In<br />
chess, usually (not always) you can drill down to a &#8216;final&#8217; answer with hard analysis. Go is just<br />
too deep for that most times. Hard analysis is difficult because there are so<br />
many variations and few of them are forcing as in chess. In chess if the<br />
variation loses a piece &#8211; its over. In Go if the variation loses a small group<br />
&#8211; it may just be the beginning of things at the whole-board level. This is one reason why the Monte Carlo sampling technique works better in Go than in chess &#8211; the distribution of samples in Go is relatively smooth. In chess, most moves just lose outright so samples are unreliable.<br />
I do think<br />
chess combinations are more aesthetically satisfying (and diverse) than Go<br />
combinations &#8211; but perhaps that is just because I am a better chess player than<br />
Go player.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: MolokaiCowboy</title>
		<link>/still-deep-trenches/#comment-2500</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[MolokaiCowboy]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2014 01:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5575#comment-2500</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[That&#039;s definitely a rub in Go. Even to local situations there is a &#039;complexity&#039; factor that just a small difference completely changes things. But, still, I think there is a geometric paradigm to find...somehow, somewhere.
Like chess tactic problems, I think the value of doing endless life-death and tesuji problems can only take one so far in Go... I am sure I am in the minority on that line of thinking. Visualization has to come before pattern recognition.
Go and chess do share the similar &#039;tactics&#039; and &#039;strategy&#039; as it were - &#039;reading/calculation and chess/go &#039;thinking.&#039; On the latter I found Ben&#039;s Monday Meditations extremely valuable to my study. They remind me of Irving Chernev&#039;s chess books with an annotation each move. Ben is clearly a superior communicator and I hope he puts the pieces together soon, comes back with both barrels firing.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>That&#8217;s definitely a rub in Go. Even to local situations there is a &#8216;complexity&#8217; factor that just a small difference completely changes things. But, still, I think there is a geometric paradigm to find&#8230;somehow, somewhere.<br />
Like chess tactic problems, I think the value of doing endless life-death and tesuji problems can only take one so far in Go&#8230; I am sure I am in the minority on that line of thinking. Visualization has to come before pattern recognition.<br />
Go and chess do share the similar &#8216;tactics&#8217; and &#8216;strategy&#8217; as it were &#8211; &#8216;reading/calculation and chess/go &#8216;thinking.&#8217; On the latter I found Ben&#8217;s Monday Meditations extremely valuable to my study. They remind me of Irving Chernev&#8217;s chess books with an annotation each move. Ben is clearly a superior communicator and I hope he puts the pieces together soon, comes back with both barrels firing.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Ben</title>
		<link>/still-deep-trenches/#comment-2499</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ben]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2014 00:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5575#comment-2499</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I would never laugh! It would definitely be an honor to see your game and even review it for you if you&#039;d like!
Haha. If I can even have a game against Lee Sedol on the blog, I think that would be a dream come true.
Best of luck on your studies till then!]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I would never laugh! It would definitely be an honor to see your game and even review it for you if you&#8217;d like!<br />
Haha. If I can even have a game against Lee Sedol on the blog, I think that would be a dream come true.<br />
Best of luck on your studies till then!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: MolokaiCowboy</title>
		<link>/still-deep-trenches/#comment-2498</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[MolokaiCowboy]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2014 21:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5575#comment-2498</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Howdy, Ben -
My first game is probably a few months away, as per my plan. I am endeavoring to learn from the mistakes I feel I made when I first studied chess.
 But I will certainly share it if you promise not to laugh! By then I also expect to see your beat-down of Lee Sedol here! :)]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Howdy, Ben &#8211;<br />
My first game is probably a few months away, as per my plan. I am endeavoring to learn from the mistakes I feel I made when I first studied chess.<br />
 But I will certainly share it if you promise not to laugh! By then I also expect to see your beat-down of Lee Sedol here! 🙂</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Ben</title>
		<link>/still-deep-trenches/#comment-2497</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ben]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Aug 2014 12:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5575#comment-2497</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[There&#039;s no shame in plugging away at the Baduktopia books! After all, I still haven&#039;t finished Jump Level Up 5! Though I totally feel you on the need to branch out, it&#039;s probably the reason I haven&#039;t gone back to finish it yet.
And no worries about still wanting to add more books, I think I&#039;m one of the worst when it comes to constantly trying to grow my library (even though I still have books to read). Haha.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There&#8217;s no shame in plugging away at the Baduktopia books! After all, I still haven&#8217;t finished Jump Level Up 5! Though I totally feel you on the need to branch out, it&#8217;s probably the reason I haven&#8217;t gone back to finish it yet.<br />
And no worries about still wanting to add more books, I think I&#8217;m one of the worst when it comes to constantly trying to grow my library (even though I still have books to read). Haha.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Todd Bowlby</title>
		<link>/still-deep-trenches/#comment-2496</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Todd Bowlby]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Aug 2014 04:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5575#comment-2496</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Looking forward to the reviews!
I&#039;m STILL plugging away at the baduktopia books, believe it or not.  They&#039;ve been so good for me, and now, finally at jump level up v.2, I&#039;m feeling a real challenge, and a need to branch out ... with the compass and the essential life and death books!
Part of me is sick of the same thing all the time, but the other part of me really likes that I&#039;m actually improving.  But I really look forward to hearing about more books to put on my list, which is strange and consumerist of me, but I get that way when it comes to Go stuff.:)]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Looking forward to the reviews!<br />
I&#8217;m STILL plugging away at the baduktopia books, believe it or not.  They&#8217;ve been so good for me, and now, finally at jump level up v.2, I&#8217;m feeling a real challenge, and a need to branch out &#8230; with the compass and the essential life and death books!<br />
Part of me is sick of the same thing all the time, but the other part of me really likes that I&#8217;m actually improving.  But I really look forward to hearing about more books to put on my list, which is strange and consumerist of me, but I get that way when it comes to Go stuff.:)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Moboy78</title>
		<link>/still-deep-trenches/#comment-2495</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Moboy78]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Aug 2014 03:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5575#comment-2495</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The really annoying part about the Go geometry you&#039;re referring to is that the issue of what to do when you&#039;re in an unfamiliar position.  Invariably, when I&#039;m reviewing a game with a stronger player and I ask them about how to play out a position, they&#039;ll say something like, &quot;Well, moves x. y. and z are joseki here, but if you don&#039;t know that then just trust your reading&quot;.  As annoying as it can be at times, I&#039;ve always found this advice to be true.  Thus, in my opinion, the &quot;key&quot; you seek is in reading.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The really annoying part about the Go geometry you&#8217;re referring to is that the issue of what to do when you&#8217;re in an unfamiliar position.  Invariably, when I&#8217;m reviewing a game with a stronger player and I ask them about how to play out a position, they&#8217;ll say something like, &#8220;Well, moves x. y. and z are joseki here, but if you don&#8217;t know that then just trust your reading&#8221;.  As annoying as it can be at times, I&#8217;ve always found this advice to be true.  Thus, in my opinion, the &#8220;key&#8221; you seek is in reading.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Ben</title>
		<link>/still-deep-trenches/#comment-2494</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ben]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2014 18:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5575#comment-2494</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Great advice. I know that one of my biggest weakness is laziness at being precise in my reading. Whenever I overcome that hurdle, I&#039;m sure it will show itself in my games as well. And like you said, things sort of have to organically happen anyhow, so I won&#039;t spend energy and effort trying to force it anymore.
Hope your studies are going well and that I&#039;ll be able to see one of your games someday!]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Great advice. I know that one of my biggest weakness is laziness at being precise in my reading. Whenever I overcome that hurdle, I&#8217;m sure it will show itself in my games as well. And like you said, things sort of have to organically happen anyhow, so I won&#8217;t spend energy and effort trying to force it anymore.<br />
Hope your studies are going well and that I&#8217;ll be able to see one of your games someday!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: MolokaiCowboy</title>
		<link>/still-deep-trenches/#comment-2493</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[MolokaiCowboy]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2014 16:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5575#comment-2493</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Take as long as you need to sort it all out in your mine, Ben.
I have about 150 Go books now and with Internet content more than enough to be 9p! :)
I have around 6000 chess books - I am a collector and a player. Remember that only a few get to the top of either game. If you do what everyone else does - you can&#039;t get there, not room for everybody. I study chess for 40 years, never get much past 2000 ELO (probably around 1kyu-1d). So many study so much - but never make significant progress, My teacher a 2400 ELO told me to &#039;jiggle the tumblers&#039; and study in a different way. I took his advice and studied the Endgame when others were studying opening and middle game. I think it was good advice, otherwise I probably never get past 1700-1800.
Endgame in Go is not quite the microcosm of the entire game as it is in chess - but it is where I am studying Go right now. I think accurate &#039;reading&#039; in Go and &#039;calculation&#039; in chess is what keeps those who read books and study so much from getting to the top. Sadly, &#039;you either have it or you don&#039;t&#039; - and I don&#039;t. But you can at least fully develop whatever native skills you have and that is what I am trying to do. Endgame study and problems, lots of Lee Chang Ho games (along with my hero Takagawa!). The core skill in both games I conclude is &#039;visualization&#039; so I am burning the goban into my mind, doing simple problems and ladders &#039;blindfold.&#039;
I also conclude local Go positions can be broken down into perhaps a dozen &#039;templates&#039; for study - but I am not there quite yet! :) There is a &#039;key&#039; to the Go geometry, I am sure, and it is not in any books that I have seen.
Also, psychologically, you have to sort of let it happen. The more you force things, the bigger the wall you make to have to get through.
Just my thoughts...]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Take as long as you need to sort it all out in your mine, Ben.<br />
I have about 150 Go books now and with Internet content more than enough to be 9p! 🙂<br />
I have around 6000 chess books &#8211; I am a collector and a player. Remember that only a few get to the top of either game. If you do what everyone else does &#8211; you can&#8217;t get there, not room for everybody. I study chess for 40 years, never get much past 2000 ELO (probably around 1kyu-1d). So many study so much &#8211; but never make significant progress, My teacher a 2400 ELO told me to &#8216;jiggle the tumblers&#8217; and study in a different way. I took his advice and studied the Endgame when others were studying opening and middle game. I think it was good advice, otherwise I probably never get past 1700-1800.<br />
Endgame in Go is not quite the microcosm of the entire game as it is in chess &#8211; but it is where I am studying Go right now. I think accurate &#8216;reading&#8217; in Go and &#8216;calculation&#8217; in chess is what keeps those who read books and study so much from getting to the top. Sadly, &#8216;you either have it or you don&#8217;t&#8217; &#8211; and I don&#8217;t. But you can at least fully develop whatever native skills you have and that is what I am trying to do. Endgame study and problems, lots of Lee Chang Ho games (along with my hero Takagawa!). The core skill in both games I conclude is &#8216;visualization&#8217; so I am burning the goban into my mind, doing simple problems and ladders &#8216;blindfold.&#8217;<br />
I also conclude local Go positions can be broken down into perhaps a dozen &#8216;templates&#8217; for study &#8211; but I am not there quite yet! 🙂 There is a &#8216;key&#8217; to the Go geometry, I am sure, and it is not in any books that I have seen.<br />
Also, psychologically, you have to sort of let it happen. The more you force things, the bigger the wall you make to have to get through.<br />
Just my thoughts&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
</channel>
</rss>
