<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>studying &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/studying/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>No More Cutting Corners</title>
		<link>/cutting-corners/</link>
		<comments>/cutting-corners/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2014 00:43:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[basics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dojang]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[level up]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[no cutting corners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[studying]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yunguseng]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5283</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Up till now, my go studies have been pretty sporadic. I may have read my fair share of books and watched my fair share of videos, but I would have to say that I really never spent the time and energy really absorbing them. Sure, I was exposed to lots of new concepts and ideas; [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Up till now, my go studies have been pretty sporadic. I may have read my fair share of books and watched my fair share of videos, but I would have to say that I really never spent the time and energy really absorbing them. Sure, I was exposed to lots of new concepts and ideas; but implementing them in my games was a whole different animal.<br />
After reading a <a title="What Was Nonsense Becomes Possible - Noseki" href="http://noseki.com/2014/05/08/what-was-nonsense-becomes-possible/">post</a> from fellow go blogger Noseki, I was inspired to take a new approach with my go studies by fully immersing myself in it. For example, in my game for <a title="Yunguseng Dojang" href="http://www.yunguseng.com/">Yunguseng Dojang</a>, I replayed every move on the real board and really took my time to absorb each and every move (which is the reason I ended up losing on time since I completely did not pay attention to my computer which was telling me I was running out of time).<br />
In addition, I&#8217;ve also revamped my primary study materials for books. I&#8217;m going back to the Level Up Series (starting with <a title="Book Review: Level Up Review 1" href="//book-review-level-up-review-1/">Level Up! Review 1</a> since I don&#8217;t have time to start all the way back at <a title="Book Review: Level Up 1" href="//book-review-level-up-1/">Level Up 1</a>) and working my way through it with extreme thoroughness. In other words, no solution whatsoever. I will work through every problem and solve it with absolute certainty before moving on.<br />
If I have any hope of becoming any stronger, I think that it&#8217;s finally time that I stopped cutting corners. The time for me to be knocking at the door of the dans is fast approaching, and I have no intention of letting myself be caught unawares when that time comes.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/cutting-corners/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">5283</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Two Degrees of Lee Sedol</title>
		<link>/two-degrees-lee-sedol/</link>
		<comments>/two-degrees-lee-sedol/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2013 03:39:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eric lui]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[insight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lee sedol]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mind blown]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[studying]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=3931</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I don&#8217;t know if any of you have ever heard of the game &#8220;Six Degrees of Kevin Bacon&#8221; (which is a deviation from the theory &#8220;six degrees of separation&#8220;), but it essentially boils down to the idea that every person is connected to another within six connections. And as you might guess based on the [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_3934" style="width: 560px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/09/Lee-Sedol-Eric-Lui-2013-Samsung-Cup.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-3934" alt="That's my friend Eric!!! Soo awesome!!! Credit to GoGameGuru" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/09/Lee-Sedol-Eric-Lui-2013-Samsung-Cup.jpg?resize=560%2C373" width="560" height="373" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">That&#8217;s my friend Eric Lui playing against Lee Sedol!!! AHH!!!!!!!! Photo Credit to <a href="http://gogameguru.com/2013-samsung-cup-group-stage-wrap-up/">GoGameGuru</a></figcaption></figure>
I don&#8217;t know if any of you have ever heard of the game &#8220;Six Degrees of Kevin Bacon&#8221; (which is a deviation from the theory &#8220;<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Six_degrees_of_separation">six degrees of separation</a>&#8220;), but it essentially boils down to the idea that every person is connected to another within six connections. And as you might guess based on the title of my post, I am writing because my friend Eric Lui had the honor of competing in the 2013 Samsung Cup and got to play against Lee Sedol!!!! I would be lying if I said I wasn&#8217;t jealous in the least, but that is still just plain epic!!!!!!<br />
Now of course, while this usually is worthy of a post all on its own, there is another reason I&#8217;m also writing about Lee Sedol. Prior to all of above, I injured my left hand from boxing and have had to take it a little easier as of late. Since I&#8217;m trying to rest in order to quickly recover, what better way to fill the time than to study some go? And guess who&#8217;s book I happened to decide to study. That&#8217;s right. <a title="GoGamGuru Commented Games by Lee Sedol Vol 1 Purchase Link" href="http://shop.gogameguru.com/commented-games-by-lee-sedol-1/?acc=e4da3b7fbbce2345d7772b0674a318d5">Commented Games by Lee Sedol Volume 1</a>!<br />
As I was working through it, I came upon an anecdote where his sister described how his father used to train him when it came to solving life and death. Lee Sedol&#8217;s father stressed accuracy and would scold him harshly whenever he solved a problem incorrectly. As a result, Lee Sedol would check his answer 100 times over before showing his father the answer regardless of how simple the problem might seem. Though seemingly harsh at the time, his sister believes that this is one of the reasons that Lee Sedol&#8217;s reading is as strong as it is today.<br />
So how does this relate to me? Well I am the first to admit that I am pretty lazy when it comes to solving problems. I might give a problem anywhere from a glance to 30 seconds (depending on my mood) before checking out the answer. I tried to tell myself that this is because I wanted more exposure to new sequences; but in reality, this has probably been hurting my reading more than helping it.<br />
And then as if I wasn&#8217;t already feeling guilty enough about my lazy approach to studying life and death, Lee Sedol makes the following statement:</p>
<blockquote><p>Fighting spirit without the base of thorough reading is nothing but recklessness that leads directly to defeat.</p></blockquote>
<p style="text-align: left;"><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/09/mindblown.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-3936 aligncenter" alt="mindblown" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/09/mindblown.jpg?resize=450%2C268" width="450" height="268" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></p>
<p>While I was blown away by how insightful that comment is, another part of me also felt incredibly sheepish as I realized that Lee Sedol had just summed up why I lose most of my games in one line. Heh&#8230; Perhaps it&#8217;s time to take a moment and rethink my approach to studying&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/two-degrees-lee-sedol/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3931</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Friday Go Forward: Week 24</title>
		<link>/friday-go-forward-week-24/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2013 09:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Progress Reports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[need to scale back]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[studying]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[too many books]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=3444</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Friday Go Forward: Week 24 Overview While it&#8217;s been fun reading so many books at once, I am starting to feel the weight of my training bear down on me. My usual nightly routine now essentially is comprised of me trying to study until I literally pass out. Then I wake up randomly in a [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_3555" style="width: 230px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/07/toomanybooks.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-3555  " alt="You can never have too many books" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/07/toomanybooks.jpg?resize=230%2C299" width="230" height="299" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Credit to <a href="http://wordpainting.tumblr.com/post/4848869704/you-can-never-have-too-many-books">WordPainting</a></figcaption></figure>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">Friday Go Forward: Week 24</h2>
<h2>Overview</h2>
<p>While it&#8217;s been fun reading so many books at once, I am starting to feel the weight of my training bear down on me. My usual nightly routine now essentially is comprised of me trying to study until I literally pass out. Then I wake up randomly in a couple of hours, and make my way to bed. Needless to say, it&#8217;s not the most productive route and it definitely starting to take a toll on me. I need a more efficient system then what I&#8217;ve been doing. Haha. So starting next week, I plan on cutting down the number of books and trying to get everything into a better balance.</p>
<h2>Games</h2>
<ul>
<li>KGS &#8211; 1 game</li>
<li>DGS &#8211; 3 ongoing games</li>
<li>Nova &#8211; 4 ongoing games</li>
</ul>
<h2>Education &amp; Training</h2>
<ul>
<li>Finished <em>Level Up Review 1</em>.</li>
<li>Finished <em>Elementary Go Series, Vol. 6 &#8211; The Endgame</em>.</li>
<li>Finished <i>Whole Board Thinking of Joseki, Vol. 1</i>.</li>
<li>Finished <em>Essential Life &amp; Death 3.</em></li>
<li><em></em>Started and finished <em>Level Up 6</em>.<em><br />
</em></li>
<li>Started and finished <em>Elementary Go Series, Vol. 7 &#8211; Handicap Go</em>.</li>
<li>Started and finished <i>Whole Board Thinking of Joseki, Vol. 2</i>.</li>
<li>Started working on <i>Level Up 7.</i></li>
<li>Started working on <em>Essential Life &amp; Death 4.</em></li>
<li>Worked on <em>Mastering the Basics, Vol. 8 &#8211; Fight Like a Pro</em>.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Lesson Learned</h2>
<ol>
<li>Unless I actually take the time to count and estimate the board position, I am no longer allowed to resign.</li>
</ol>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3444</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>I Lost to Cloudbrows + E-mail Newsletters</title>
		<link>/i-lost-to-cloudbrows-e-mail-newsletters/</link>
		<comments>/i-lost-to-cloudbrows-e-mail-newsletters/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2013 03:40:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloudbrows]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[email newsletter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[studying]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=3548</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In lieu of my last post on the desire to lose, I thought it would only be appropriate that I title this blog post after a marvelous game I played on Monday. It&#8217;s already slated for a Monday Go Meditation, so more on that game in a couple of weeks! With that being said, I&#8217;m [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In lieu of my last post on <a title="The Desire to Lose" href="//the-desire-to-lose/">the desire to lose</a>, I thought it would only be appropriate that I title this blog post after a marvelous game I played on Monday. It&#8217;s already slated for a Monday Go Meditation, so more on that game in a couple of weeks!<br />
With that being said, I&#8217;m sure that some of you have noticed that the email subscription widget on the right has changed a bit. And in case you didn&#8217;t, here&#8217;s the basic rundown!</p>
<ol>
<li><span style="line-height: 13px;">E-mail newsletters now have a new look and feel that should make the reading process more enjoyable!</span></li>
<li>You can now choose the frequency at which you want to receive your email newsletter!</li>
</ol>
<p>The only drawback to the plugin I&#8217;m using is that it isn&#8217;t very easy to switch to a different list, so if anyone would like to switch the frequency of their newsletter, feel free to contact me or go ahead and unsubscribe to the current list you&#8217;re on and resubscribe to the new one you want to be on. Either one works.<br />
Finally, as you all have definitely noticed, I am on a book review rampage. I&#8217;ve gotten in a really great study groove, but I&#8217;m starting to feel the need to take it down a couple of notches since I have a few books I would like to spend more time on. Anyhow, more on that later on. Need to get some studying in before I pass out. XD<br />
<em>PS. To all my first email subscribers (who were all immediately being updated whenever I posted something), in order to prevent everyone from feeling like I am spamming your inbox, I switched everyone over to the Daily Newsletter in order to keep my emails to one per day. If you would like to be switched back to the Immediate Newsletter, just let me know!</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/i-lost-to-cloudbrows-e-mail-newsletters/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3548</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Friday Go Forward: Week 23</title>
		<link>/friday-go-forward-week-23/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2013 09:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Progress Reports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[educational]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[intense training]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[korean books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[level up]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[studying]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=3299</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Overview As many of you probably noticed, I have been pretty consumed with studying go and releasing book reviews as fast as I can. My progress with the Level Up series has been great! I&#8217;ve been averaging about 1.5 days for each volume. Not as fast as I wish I was, but not bad in [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2><strong>Overview</strong></h2>
<p>As many of you probably noticed, I have been pretty consumed with studying go and releasing book reviews as fast as I can. My progress with the Level Up series has been great! I&#8217;ve been averaging about 1.5 days for each volume. Not as fast as I wish I was, but not bad in the scheme of things. It&#8217;s been really great to see what kids in Korea have been learning and realizing how unstable my fundamentals were in comparison. I&#8217;m hoping that I will be finished with the Level Up series by next week so that I can find out what&#8217;s in store for me in the Jump Level Up series.<br />
Also, many thanks to Malcolm for setting me on the path to finally working out the kinks in the email subscriptions. As some of you might have noticed, email newsletters are going to be looking a lot different! The design is far from finished, but I wanted to at least release the initial version of the email layout so that you wouldn&#8217;t have to deal with the horrendous layout that Jetpack was sending at one point. Hope it makes for a better reading experience!<br />
<strong>**Update:</strong> It seems that Jetpack was still turned on this morning so the email newsletter might have been sent twice. Sorry to anyone on the subscriber list! I am working to iron out all the kinks with the new email subscription plugin.</p>
<h2><strong>Games</strong></h2>
<ul>
<li>DGS &#8211; 3 ongoing games</li>
<li>Nova &#8211; 3 ongoing games</li>
</ul>
<h2><strong>Education &amp; Training</strong></h2>
<ul>
<li>Finished <em>Modern Master Games, Vol. 1</em>.</li>
<li>Finished <i>Elementary Go Series, Vol 5 &#8211; Attack and Defense</i>.</li>
<li>Finished <em>Level Up 2.</em></li>
<li><em></em>Started and finished <em>Level Up 3, 4 and 5.</em></li>
<li>Started working on <em>Level Up Review 1.</em></li>
<li>Started working on <em>Mastering the Basics, Vol. 8 &#8211; Fight Like a Pro.</em></li>
<li>Started working on <em>Elementary Go Series, Vol 6 &#8211; The Endgame.</em></li>
<li>Worked on <i>Whole Board Thinking of Joseki, Vol. 1</i>.</li>
<li>Worked on <em>Essential Life &amp; Death 3.</em></li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3299</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Keep Studying Interesting</title>
		<link>/how-to-keep-studying-interesting/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2013 09:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Weekly Go Wednesday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bored]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[consistency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entertaining]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[exploring]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fun]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[studying]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[topics of interest]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=2548</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Weekly Go Wednesday, Issue #25 Whether you like it or not, studying is one of the most important aspects of getting stronger at go. While some players are able to simply learn everything through playing and reviewing, this is often reliant on stronger players or even simple luck of figuring out what is wrong with [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 style="text-align: center;">Weekly Go Wednesday, Issue #25</h2>
<figure id="attachment_2631" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/04/wgw25.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-2631" alt="Credit to Gagful" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/04/wgw25.jpg?resize=300%2C252" width="300" height="252" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Credit to <a href="http://www.gagful.com/uploads/2012_9/1347619043_studying_gag.jpg">Gagful</a></figcaption></figure>
Whether you like it or not, studying is one of the most important aspects of getting stronger at go. While some players are able to simply learn everything through playing and reviewing, this is often reliant on stronger players or even simple luck of figuring out what is wrong with your moves or thinking process. As a result, there is no telling how fast you will improve.<br />
Unfortunately, this is one of the most dreaded aspects of trying getting stronger for most players. After all, it reminds us of our school days where homework and projects were a drag and no one ever wanted to do them. So, as the last installment of Weekly Go Wednesday (at least for the time being), I thought it would be best to leave you with my thoughts on how you can keep your study of go interesting so that you can continue to climb the ranks.<br />
<span id="more-2548"></span><br />
In order to help make studying more interesting, we must start by giving ourselves the right mindset when thinking about studying. Although the image jokes about how studying ends with the word &#8220;dying,&#8221; one should not view studying as a dreaded chore; but instead as <strong>an opportunity to explore topics of interest</strong>. By doing so, one no longer thinks of the cumbersome tasks that lie ahead; but will instead look forward to each studying session.<br />
Once you have the right mindset, here are some tips that I use to help keep myself motivated to consistently study go:<br />
<strong>1. Only study things that are of interest to <em>you</em>.</strong> As much as everyone goes on about how important life and death is, if that subject bores you to tears, don&#8217;t do it. Study whatever else makes <em>you</em> happy and makes the game enjoyable. That might be attacking, joseki, tesuji, fuseki, endgame, whatever. Although it might seem like you are neglecting other areas, I have found that those other areas eventually become topics of interest as you gain a greater understanding of the game.<br />
<strong>2. Follow a couple of professional players that you are fans of. </strong>It&#8217;s much more fun studying professional games when you are rooting for your favorite player or trying to understand why your pro played the way he did. In addition, the emotional attachment you have to your favorite player winning or losing will make the things you learn stick that much more in your brain. And if you don&#8217;t know which professionals to follow, two easy names that I would recommend starting with are <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gu_Li">Gu Li</a> and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lee_Sedol">Lee Sedol</a>.<br />
<strong>3. Keep your study sessions short.</strong> If the study sessions are too long, it can cause you to study more infrequently and procrastinate study sessions since you&#8217;ll always have the excuse, &#8220;I don&#8217;t have enough time.&#8221; It&#8217;s better to cut your studying in chunks in order to allow more material to be dispersed over time which inadvertently marinates in your brain and has more time to be absorbed into your actual play.<br />
Best of luck in your studies and pursuit of the next stone. Till next time!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2548</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
