<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>long term &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/long-term/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>Friday Go Forward: Week 69</title>
		<link>/friday-go-forward-week-69/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2014 15:03:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Progress Reports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[consistency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[efficiency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[long term]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[scrivener]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5496</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Overview I swear my training regimen is getting shorter with each week that goes on by, but in all fairness, I am working on developing a system that focuses on consistency over a long period of time as opposed to having my life be extremely skewed towards one direction or another based on how I [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="overview">Overview</h2>
<p>I swear my training regimen is getting shorter with each week that goes on by, but in all fairness, I am working on developing a system that focuses on consistency over a long period of time as opposed to having my life be extremely skewed towards one direction or another based on how I feel. Of course, this doesn’t mean that I’m only doing that much every day, but it’s my bare minimum requirement per day.<br />
One of the things I’ve been working on throughout the week is designing a better blogging system. I was currently working directly out of WordPress and collecting notes where I could here and there, but it wasn’t a very efficient system and took up quite a bit of time. To my luck, in the process of me restructuring other aspects of my life (i.e., time management, project management, finances, etc.), I actually stumbled across <a title="Scrivener Official Page" href="http://www.literatureandlatte.com/scrivener.php">Scrivener</a> and have been testing out recently. I’m still in the trial period, but I have to say that this tool is really quite impressive for serious writers out there. It’s starting to really help me get my thoughts together and allow me to blog more effectively.<br />
Another thing that I want to mention is that after next week’s Friday Go Forward, I will most likely be pushing out these progress reports to Saturday since they are more status updates than anything else and can be scheduled ahead of time. I’ve found it to be near impossible to blog on Saturday, so this will add a consistent content item to Saturday while allowing me to blog about more personal things on Friday if I want to.<br />
Finally, I plan on releasing an online document that will allow you to check my training and efforts in go in real time! By doing so, you can get a real detailed look at what I’m doing since status reports are generally more an overview than anything else. Hopefully this will be of interest to some of you, but if not, at least it will be another artifact to track my progress and possible analysis in the future.<br />
With all that said, hope all those living in the US have a great 4th of July weekend! See you all next week.</p>
<h2 id="trainingregimen">Training Regimen</h2>
<ul>
<li>Work on go for at least 10–15 minutes a day.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="games">Games</h2>
<ul>
<li><a title="KGS Website" href="http://www.gokgs.com/">KGS</a> &#8211;  3 games</li>
<li><a title="Dragon Go Server - BenGoZen's Profile" href="http://www.dragongoserver.net/userinfo.php?uid=60385">DGS</a> &#8211; 6 ongoing games</li>
<li><a title="Online Go Server - BenGoZen's Profile" href="http://online-go.com/user/view/549/BenGoZen">OGS</a> &#8211;  5 ongoing games</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="books">Books</h2>
<ul>
<li><a title="Book Review: Get Strong at Tesuji" href="//book-review-get-strong-tesuji/"><em>Get Strong at Tesuji</em></a> by Richard Bozulich</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="videos">Videos</h2>
<ul>
<li><a title="Yunguseng Dojang - Season 9 - 2nd Month - 5th Round Reviews" href="http://ayd.yunguseng.com/videos/index.php?id=1287">YSD 2nd Month 5th Round Reviews</a></li>
</ul>
<h2 id="lessonslearned">Lessons Learned</h2>
<ul>
<li>I’m still bad at framing moves in terms of how many points / potential it can provide when playing games.</li>
<li>I need to start trusting my instinct more. Apparently it is correct more often than I give it credit for.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">5496</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
