<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>shidougo &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/shidougo-2/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>&#034;Winning&#034; My First Shidougo Game</title>
		<link>/winning-my-first-shidougo-game/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 18:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kifu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[baduk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[go]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shidougo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weiqi]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=27</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Today&#8217;s shidougo lesson comes from a person that I&#8217;ve come to befriend and look up to: frozensoul. If you&#8217;d like to help support his efforts in helping out players trying to get stronger, please visit his site for more information! I guess you could call this my first &#8220;shidougo&#8221; victory&#8230; but I wouldn&#8217;t classify this [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Today&#8217;s shidougo lesson comes from a person that I&#8217;ve come to befriend and look up to: frozensoul. If you&#8217;d like to help support his efforts in helping out players trying to get stronger, please visit <a href="http://www.clossiusreviewroom.com/">his site</a> for more information!</em></p>
<p>I guess you could call this my first &#8220;shidougo&#8221; victory&#8230; but I wouldn&#8217;t classify this as that due to the fact that frozensoul was actually trying to create a tie. So in reality, congratulations are in order for frozensoul for being only one point away from creating a tie!<br />
Overall, I was really happy with my performance in this game. It honestly has nothing to do with the victory and more on the fact that I played almost every move with confidence. And for those who would remind me that frozensoul wasn&#8217;t actually trying to play anything crazy, the confidence I&#8217;m speaking of is more of a &#8220;I read it out to the best of my ability and I&#8217;ll give each move everything I got.&#8221;<br />
<span id="more-27"></span><br />
That being said, I still have a lot of work to do in regards to my connections and such. One example of an efficient connection that I&#8217;ve yet to really utilize fully is the hanging connection (see variation on Move 13). And even though I made a few moves that received compliments for being solid, I know that I have a ways to go before more of my moves are played with a simplicity and efficiency that gets a nod of approval from strong players such as frozensoul.<br />
Hope you enjoy the kifu and be sure to share any insights that you may have as you look over the game!<br />

<div id='glift_display1' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display1","sgf":"http:\/\/bengozen.com\/\/wp-content\/uploads\/2012\/10\/2012.10.01-First-Shidougo.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='//wp-content/uploads/2012/10/2012.10.01-First-Shidougo.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">[download label=&#8221;Download Kifu&#8221;]//wp-content/uploads/2012/10/2012.10.01-First-Shidougo.sgf[/download]
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">27</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>First Official Shidougo Game</title>
		<link>/first-official-shidougo-game/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2012 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kifu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[baduk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[go]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shidougo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weiqi]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=32</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Prior to this game, I was on a decent winning streak&#8230; so I was feeling pretty good. Feeling good enough to think I could outplay a 5d? Apparently so&#8230;. Now granted, this was a teaching game; but I assure you that I did nothing less than try to outplay him and hope to catch him [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prior to this game, I was on a decent winning streak&#8230; so I was feeling pretty good. Feeling good enough to think I could outplay a 5d? Apparently so&#8230;.<br />
Now granted, this was a teaching game; but I assure you that I did nothing less than try to outplay him and hope to catch him off guard. For those who are still new and wondering why this is incredibly stupid, the difference between a 5d and 9k is at the bare minimum 8 stones. So&#8230; yeah&#8230;<br />
It&#8217;s been so long since I played against an opponent so vastly stronger than me that I forgot what it was like to play just to simply survive. That&#8217;s right: just survive. Instead, I tried to take big points and was under the false assurance that my groups were alive and that I was giving frozensoul a good game.<br />
That being said. There are too many mistakes to be mentioned and the prized moments are practically nonexistent. If you would like to see what 9k mistakes look like and how they get properly demolished, please <del>take the time to visit the link above</del> see the kifu below!<br />
<span id="more-32"></span><br />

<div id='glift_display2' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display2","sgf":"http:\/\/bengozen.com\/\/wp-content\/uploads\/2012\/09\/2012.09.17-First-Official-Shidougo-Game.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='//wp-content/uploads/2012/09/2012.09.17-First-Official-Shidougo-Game.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">[download label=&#8221;Download Kifu&#8221;]//wp-content/uploads/2012/09/2012.09.17-First-Official-Shidougo-Game.sgf[/download]
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Many thanks to frozensoul for letting me post this up and use his name. If you are ever looking for a great go teacher, be sure to visit his room (Social &#8211;&gt; clossius review room) for game reviews or teaching games. Definitely worth it!</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">32</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>My First One Point Lesson</title>
		<link>/my-first-one-point-lesson/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2010 04:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kifu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lessons]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[14k]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[3 step thinking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shidougo]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=65</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[So I played my first teaching game on KGS today. It was a pretty quick game with a 3-dan who UTTERLY demolished me. I couldn&#8217;t help but laugh as I watched my shapes get cut up into tiny little pieces and get swallowed up whole by Leviathan. Don&#8217;t even want to think about what it [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>So I played my first teaching game on KGS today. It was a pretty quick game with a 3-dan who UTTERLY demolished me. I couldn&#8217;t help but laugh as I watched my shapes get cut up into tiny little pieces and get swallowed up whole by Leviathan. Don&#8217;t even want to think about what it would be like to play a pro right now&#8230;. *head explodes*<br />
Anyhow, here is the following onslaught. The 3-dan has an interesting idea called: <strong>One Point Teaching Game</strong>. At first I was like do I pay him a point or something&#8230;. but then it became clear to me at the end. He gives one solid point for the player to work on. BRILLIANT! Considering weak players are being pulled five millions different directions at once (e.g. life and death, tesuji, opening theory, etc.), it&#8217;s nice to have one solid thing to focus on.<br />
So I&#8217;m sure the question then is, what was my one point lesson for today?<br />
<span id="more-65"></span><br />
<strong>Practice 3-Step Thinking for Every Move</strong> &#8211; In other words, think what move you intend to play, how your opponent could respond, and how you&#8217;d respond to your opponent&#8217;s response. This process will give a player a better overview as to the board position and whether it is favorable or not.<br />
He said that a number of SDK don&#8217;t even do this consistently, so it may be difficult for me to incorporate it as second nature. I would like to note that we played a relatively quick game, so most of my moves were instinctual. Nonetheless, I must train myself to do 3-Step Thinking instinctively or else the pursuit to become stronger will be futile. Now grab your bag of popcorn, and enjoy the onslaught.<br />

<div id='glift_display3' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display3","sgf":"http:\/\/bengozen.com\/\/wp-content\/uploads\/2010\/10\/2010.10.17-My-First-One-Point-Lesson.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='//wp-content/uploads/2010/10/2010.10.17-My-First-One-Point-Lesson.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">65</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
