<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>north american go convention &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/north-american-go-convention/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>North American Go Convention &#8211; Day 5</title>
		<link>/north-american-go-convention-day-5/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2013 22:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kifu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[1p]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[9p]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[first professional win]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[myung wan kim]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nagc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[north american go convention]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stephanie yin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tournament]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=1934</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Introduction &#8212; Day 1 &#8212; Day 2 &#8212; Day 3 &#8212; Day 4 &#8212; Day 5 &#8212; Conclusion For my final day at the NAGC, I woke up a little later since I was pretty tired from the past four days. After all, on top of all the go and staying out late, I had been [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><a title="North American Go Convention!!!" href="//north-american-go-convention/">Introduction</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 1" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-1/">Day 1</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 2" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-2/">Day 2</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 3" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-3/">Day 3</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 4" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-4/">Day 4</a> &#8212; <strong>Day 5</strong> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Conclusion" href="//north-american-go-convention-conclusion/">Conclusion</a></p>
<p>For my final day at the NAGC, I woke up a little later since I was pretty tired from the past four days. After all, on top of all the go and staying out late, I had been working as well. So when I found out that the first round was starting at 8:30am, I decided to forgo competing all together and just get there later for the pro events.<br />
When I arrived, it was approximately 9:15am. As I looked at the schedule for the day, I noticed that the pro events were once again scheduled during the second half of each round. In addition, there were no breaks in between the rounds. If you wanted lunch or dinner, you had better hope your match ends early. So in short, trying to compete, have your meals, and attend pro events would nearly kill you.<br />
Since the first pro event was starting at 10;00am, I went ahead and walked upstairs to see how the tournament was progressing. You can imagine my surprise when I arrived at the playing room to find that they needed another player since someone didn&#8217;t show up. Since there was still some time before the match and I felt bad that someone was missing an opponent, I decided to go ahead and play to help out. Since there was only 30 minutes before the pro event though, I tried to play as quickly as I could with the most aggressive method possible so that the game could possibly end early.<br />
<span id="more-1934"></span><br />
Like I predicted, there was no chance of us finishing the game before the pro event. And to be honest, I can&#8217;t blame my opponent for wanting to take his time to see if he could actually manage to live. With the amount of fighting left to do, I would even be willing to bet that we still had a good 30 &#8211; 45 minutes left before we were close to finishing. So when the time came, there was no choice to resign. Below is the game record.<br />

<div id='glift_display1' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display1","sgf":"http:\/\/bengozen.com\/\/wp-content\/uploads\/2013\/02\/2013.02.21-NAGC-Day-5-Game-1.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='//wp-content/uploads/2013/02/2013.02.21-NAGC-Day-5-Game-1.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">[download label=&#8221;Download Kifu&#8221;]//wp-content/uploads/2013/02/2013.02.21-NAGC-Day-5-Game-1.sgf[/download]
<p>I will admit that I part of me wanted to see how the game might&#8217;ve ended, but I knew I was playing a rather high risk approach and could very well have lost anyways. So all in all, I was happy to give my opponent the win since I wasn&#8217;t going to win any awards anyways. =D<br />
When the time came from the simul game with Myung, as one might expect with the schedule that day, I was the only one who showed up. So, in order to try and make things for interesting for him, we decided to do a 9 stone handicap where I could put the stones anywhere I wanted.<br />
At first, I set up a setting relatively similar to your standard 9 stone handicap formation with a chance in regards to using a Chinese opening; but then Myung suggested it might be better for me to secure a couple of corners to begin with. I think he soon regretted his suggestion however, because when he looked at the board again and was about to play his first move, he said, &#8220;Oh man&#8230; this is going to make it a lot harder.&#8221;<br />

<div id='glift_display2' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display2","sgf":"http:\/\/bengozen.com\/\/wp-content\/uploads\/2013\/02\/2013.02.21-NAGC-Day-5-Game-2.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='//wp-content/uploads/2013/02/2013.02.21-NAGC-Day-5-Game-2.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">[download label=&#8221;Download Kifu&#8221;]//wp-content/uploads/2013/02/2013.02.21-NAGC-Day-5-Game-2.sgf[/download]
<p>When I played that final move, you have no idea the relief and rush of excitement I felt when I heard him say, &#8220;Oh! Good! You saw that!&#8221; and then put down his stone and focus his attention on the three players who had come in after we had started. So while my 9 stone handicap was a free placement style, this was a huge moment for me because I actually managed to win against a professional. It helped to renew my confidence in myself to feel growth over the past five days.<br />
Afterwards, Myung and I went to pick up James and grabbed lunch at Cosi&#8217;s. We had fun talking about all sorts of random things, but tennis was a pretty big topic and it was fun finding out their different styles and such. I had no idea that there are certain types of racket strings that were specialized for specific playing styles! Definitely a fun time.<br />
When we got back, it was time another lecture from Myung. This time we reviewed part of the 1st game from the Samsung Cup between Lee Sedol and Gu Li. The concept was a bit more abstract this time around. James and I discussed it while we played later on, so I feel like I have a better understanding of it. Granted, like the rest of the lectures from this convention, it will probably take some time before I get write a solid article on it.<br />
For the final pro event, I had to make a choice between attending another lecture by Myung or play a simul game with Stephanie Yin (1P).<br />
<figure id="attachment_1998" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/02/stephanieyin.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1998" alt="Stephanie (Ming Ming) Yin (1P)" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/02/stephanieyin.jpg?resize=300%2C207" width="300" height="207" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Stephanie (Ming Ming) Yin (1P)</figcaption></figure>
After a bit of thought, I decided that I didn&#8217;t want to pass up the opportunity to play another pro. So with that said, I sat down for my final simul game of the NAGC. Below is the game record.<br />

<div id='glift_display3' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display3","sgf":"http:\/\/bengozen.com\/\/wp-content\/uploads\/2013\/02\/2013.02.21-NAGC-Day-5-Game-3.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='//wp-content/uploads/2013/02/2013.02.21-NAGC-Day-5-Game-3.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">[download label=&#8221;Download Kifu&#8221;]//wp-content/uploads/2013/02/2013.02.21-NAGC-Day-5-Game-3.sgf[/download]
<p>When the game was over, Stephanie told me that she definitely thought I was stronger than 6 kyu. She recommended I further practice my life and death and reading, and I would progress very quickly. ^.^ It made me happy to hear that and I was very grateful for her compliment and advice.<br />
With all the events over, Myung, James and I tried to see if we could grab a bite to eat before the awards ceremony. Unfortunately there just didn&#8217;t seem to be enough time, but we decided that we would get food afterwards.<br />
The award ceremony room was decorated quite nicely with various flags and all the glass trophies up front. In addition, they managed to fill the entire lecture hall and more with people, which was rather impressive.<br />
There were all kinds of awards, but the most coveted ones went to a number of players from China who participated. I would be lying if I said I wasn&#8217;t the least bit envious and curious as to how I might have fared in the competition, but trust me when I say I do not regret my decision to not compete. Haha.<br />
For the final night of the NAGC, Myung, James and I went back to Bonchon for one last hurrah. Like a blur, all the food and good conversation was suddenly over. Before I knew it, I was dropping them off outside their hotel. With a firm handshake and an assurance that we&#8217;d be in touch, we parted ways for the final time.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a title="North American Go Convention!!!" href="//north-american-go-convention/">Introduction</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 1" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-1/">Day 1</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 2" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-2/">Day 2</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 3" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-3/">Day 3</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 4" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-4/">Day 4</a> &#8212; <strong>Day 5</strong> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Conclusion" href="//north-american-go-convention-conclusion/">Conclusion</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1934</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>North American Go Convention &#8211; Day 4</title>
		<link>/north-american-go-convention-day-4/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2013 22:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kifu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[9p]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[james]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[myung wan kim]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nagc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[north american go convention]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartgo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tournament]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=1932</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Introduction &#8212; Day 1 &#8212; Day 2 &#8212; Day 3 &#8212; Day 4 &#8212; Day 5 &#8212; Conclusion For Day 4, I had the honor of having my mom come and join me for the day! She just learned the rules recently and I was excited when she told me that she wanted to come to [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><a title="North American Go Convention!!!" href="//north-american-go-convention/">Introduction</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 1" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-1/">Day 1</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 2" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-2/">Day 2</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 3" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-3/">Day 3</a> &#8212; <strong>Day 4</strong> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 5" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-5/">Day 5</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Conclusion" href="//north-american-go-convention-conclusion/">Conclusion</a></p>
<p><em>For Day 4, I had the honor of having my mom come and join me for the day! She just learned the rules recently and I was excited when she told me that she wanted to come to an all day go convention!! Woot!!</em><br />
When we arrived at the convention, I was pleasantly surprised to see a lot of people at the registration room. As we settled down, I heard an announcement that everyone needed to check in if they wanted to compete. At the time, I was rather split as to what to do. On one hand, I wasn&#8217;t sure what the schedule for the professional events (i.e. lectures, simul games, reviews) was. In addition, I wasn&#8217;t sure I was okay with the idea of my mom sitting around for hours on end watching me play games when she was still so new to the game.<br />
Once registration was finished, I thought it would be a good idea to show my mom what competitive go looks like. Upon our arrival upstairs, we found them posting up the pairings for the first round. For some reason, I had a feeling that I might have been included even though I did not check in. Sure enough, I found my name after a quick glance at the list.<br />
<span id="more-1932"></span><br />
Shortly afterwards, I noticed that they posted up the schedule for the day and saw that the professional events had been scheduled at the end of Round 1 and 3. To clarify though, I do not mean that the events were scheduled after the rounds were over. In fact, they were scheduled at the tail end of the round time which meant that if I wanted to attend a pro event, I would face one of two situations: (1) I play in every round, but I&#8217;m forced to rush and hope that the game ends before the event. (2) I play every round, but end up resigning most of my games since I like to take my time with each move anyways.<br />
As I stood there trying to figure out what to do, my opponent found me. After panicking for a moment, I quickly found the tournament director and tried to tell him that I was not going to be playing (at least in the first round). Coincidentally, a fellow go player who was around our level had shown up late and so I tried to get the director to make a swap since it would keep the pairings equal. There was a bit of resistance at first, and it took quite a bit of back and forth before  they resolved the situation amongst themselves.<br />
In my defense though, I never checked in as they told us to do in order to be paired, so why would should I expect to be included? Not to mention, I was not in the mood to showing my mom a rushed game where I don&#8217;t play my best. And if that weren&#8217;t enough, I would probably end up resigning all my games since the pro events were during the rounds. So why make the day extra stressful and draining? No thank you.<br />
While we waited for the simul game with Myung to start, my mom and I had the pleasure of chatting with a local player (by the name of Mr. Choi) who was a director of some sort at a local Korean Baduk club. We found out that he was a 7 dan amateur who had won numerous competition in the United States before and enjoyed teaching go. In fact, we seemed to get along so well that he even started a teaching game with me. Haha.<br />
We only got a few moves into the game before it was time to start the simul game though. And before I knew it, I was sitting once again before Myung as I placed 9 stones on the board. With a renewed spirit from my defeat on <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 3" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-3/">Day 3</a>, it was time to try again! Ikuzo!<br />

<div id='glift_display4' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display4","sgf":"http:\/\/bengozen.com\/\/wp-content\/uploads\/2013\/02\/2013.02.20-NAGC-Day-4.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='//wp-content/uploads/2013/02/2013.02.20-NAGC-Day-4.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">[download label=&#8221;Download Kifu&#8221;]//wp-content/uploads/2013/02/2013.02.20-NAGC-Day-4.sgf[/download]
<p>Once the game was over, Mr. Choi, Myung, my mom and I went out to grab lunch at <a href="http://www.yelp.com/biz/el-pollo-rico-arlington">El Pollo Ricco</a> and had a delicious lunch!<br />
<figure id="attachment_1973" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/02/elpolloricco.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1973" alt="elpolloricco" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/02/elpolloricco.jpg?resize=300%2C225" width="300" height="225" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Credit to Yelp (Andrew C.)</figcaption></figure>
<p style="text-align: left;">Afterwards, we drove Myung back to the hotel so he could rest for the afternoon. Since we were going to pick him up later on and there were no pro events for the rest of the afternoon, my mom and I just went to a nearby mall to hangout. While it was a detour from the &#8220;all-day go convention,&#8221; we had some great conversation and the thought that I could be at the go convention instead never crossed my mind.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Later on that day, after picking Myung and James up, I found myself sitting in my first professional lecture. Myung was giving a lecture on the final game between Lee sedol and Gu Li in the recent Samsung Cup. Even though we were only able to really spend time on the opening (and a little bit of endgame), it was a really interesting review that definitely opened my eyes to some new ideas. I&#8217;ll be sure to write more about them when I&#8217;ve managed to digest them and can write them in a comprehensible fashion. One thing I can say for sure though, is that my appreciation for pro lectures has definitely grown since then!</p>
<p>With the day coming to an end, I thought that it would be a good idea to take Myung and James out to a local Vietnamese restaurant that we love called <a href="http://www.yelp.com/biz/viet-royale-falls-church">Viet Royale</a> (FYI. The Yelp reviews do not do the restaurant justice. I don&#8217;t think people know what to order. =D). I wish I had taken pictures of all the food we ordered, but it is suffice to say that it was full of delicious food and great conversation.<br />
<figure id="attachment_1975" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/02/pho.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1975" alt="Credit to Yelp (Ruth C.)" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/02/pho.jpg?resize=300%2C225" width="300" height="225" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Credit to Yelp (Ruth C.)</figcaption></figure>
All in all, it was a fantastic day full of great company and great memories. Here&#8217;s to hoping that Day 5 will live up to even 50% of it!</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a title="North American Go Convention!!!" href="//north-american-go-convention/">Introduction</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 1" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-1/">Day 1</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 2" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-2/">Day 2</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 3" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-3/">Day 3</a> &#8212; <strong>Day 4</strong> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 5" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-5/">Day 5</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Conclusion" href="//north-american-go-convention-conclusion/">Conclusion</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1932</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>North American Go Convention &#8211; Day 3</title>
		<link>/north-american-go-convention-day-3/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2013 17:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kifu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[9p]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[james]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[myung wan kim]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nagc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[north american go convention]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[simul game]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tournament]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=1929</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Introduction &#8212; Day 1 &#8212; Day 2 &#8212; Day 3 &#8212; Day 4 &#8212; Day 5 &#8212; Conclusion Shortly before leaving the convention on Day 2, I had mentioned to Myung and James that if they were free and didn&#8217;t have plans, I would be happy to take them out to dinner since they didn&#8217;t [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><a title="North American Go Convention!!!" href="//north-american-go-convention/">Introduction</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 1" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-1/">Day 1</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 2" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-2/">Day 2</a> &#8212; <strong>Day 3</strong> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 4" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-4/">Day 4</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 5" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-5/">Day 5</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Conclusion" href="//north-american-go-convention-conclusion/">Conclusion</a></p>
<p>Shortly before leaving the convention on <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 2" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-2/">Day 2</a>, I had mentioned to Myung and James that if they were free and didn&#8217;t have plans, I would be happy to take them out to dinner since they didn&#8217;t know the area very well. They told me that they would let me know how their schedule was the next day, so you can imagine how excited I was when I received a phone call letting me know that they would like to get dinner with me! Since they were in the Annandale area, I suggested that we meet at the Bonchon to get dinner.<br />
As per usual, the traffic to Virginia was not cooperating with me as I attempted to make my way to them. When I finally reached my destination, I arrived to find Myung and James outside with a local Korean go player. I was a bit bewildered at first as to why they were outside, but then I realized that the Bonchon was closed!!! Bleh. Definitely not what I anticipated. So we adapted and headed off to the Fairfax location.<br />
<figure id="attachment_1947" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/02/bonchonwings.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1947" alt="Credit to HauteLiving.com" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/02/bonchonwings.jpg?resize=300%2C224" width="300" height="224" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Credit to HauteLiving.com</figcaption></figure>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>If you&#8217;ve never had it before, it&#8217;s just heavenly&#8230;. Just thinking about it is making me hungry&#8230;.</em></p>
<p>Before I knew it, we were munching and chatting the night away. Time passed us by rather quickly because before we knew it it was 7:00pm and we needed to rush back to the convention. Fortunately we weren&#8217;t too far away, but I did feel bad that I didn&#8217;t do a better job keeping track of the time. Since we were running a behind though, we went ahead and dropped Myung off before heading off to do a coffee run.<br />
Once we got back and arrived at the building, we ran into a local go player who had stopped by for the convention but was leaving since there were only dans upstairs. When James hit the button to go to the 9th floor and nothing happened, you can imagine my face as I could only laugh as I realized that we would have to take the stairs once again. On the upside, having James helped to make the climb pass by much quicker.<br />
<span id="more-1929"></span><br />
When we finally arrived on the 9th floor, I was relieved to see familiar faces and the tournament room in clear sight. As we made our way into the tournament room, I saw that Myung was already in the middle of two simul games. At first I wasn&#8217;t sure if we would be too late to join, but before I knew it James took a seat and setup his handicap stones. I quickly followed suit and before I knew it, I was playing my third official professional simul game (the second one with Joanne Missingham doesn&#8217;t count since it never finished and was played in a more blitz manner than anything else). Below is the game record from that night:<br />

<div id='glift_display5' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display5","sgf":"http:\/\/bengozen.com\/\/wp-content\/uploads\/2013\/02\/2013.02.19-NAGC-Day-3.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='//wp-content/uploads/2013/02/2013.02.19-NAGC-Day-3.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">[download label=&#8221;Download Kifu&#8221;]//wp-content/uploads/2013/02/2013.02.19-NAGC-Day-3.sgf[/download]
<p>After I resigned, I spent a good 10 minutes going over the game and looking at Myung&#8217;s responses. I could only marvel in their simplicity as I tried to make my way through the game I had just played. I didn&#8217;t get too far because James and I decided to play a game together while Myung was focusing on his simul games. James is around 2 kyu, so I think the game took him by surprise when he learned my fighting abilities were not quite the same as a typical meek 6 kyu. I don&#8217;t have the game record for that night, but it was a fun game that was full of experiment and new ideas. =) Once all was said and done though, it seemed that Myung and James&#8217; ride still had things he needed to do, so I was more than happy to give them a ride back to their hotel.<br />
Once I dropped them off, I realized that I probably needed to get gas before heading home. I was a bit frustrated with past me for procrastinating this task because finding a gas station at 11:30pm is not very easy to do. My GPS was great at finding nearby gas stations, only they were all closed. (&gt;.&lt;) So after driving around for 15 minutes and burning more gas, I decided that it would be better to take my chances of getting home than getting stranded in the middle of Virginia. Fortunately for me, I ran into an open gas station before getting on a highway. So glad to know that I would not end the night stranded on the highway. Whew.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a title="North American Go Convention!!!" href="//north-american-go-convention/">Introduction</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 1" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-1/">Day 1</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 2" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-2/">Day 2</a> &#8212; <strong>Day 3</strong> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 4" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-4/">Day 4</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 5" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-5/">Day 5</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Conclusion" href="//north-american-go-convention-conclusion/">Conclusion</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1929</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>North American Go Convention &#8211; Day 1</title>
		<link>/north-american-go-convention-day-1/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 22:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kifu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[6d]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[joanne missingham]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nagc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[north american go convention]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tournament]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=1895</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Introduction &#8212; Day 1 &#8212; Day 2 &#8212; Day 3 &#8212; Day 4 &#8212; Day 5 &#8212; Conclusion The day got off to a rather dreary start as I spent about an hour in rainy traffic trying to make my way down to the event. After grabbing a quick bite to eat, I found myself standing [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><a title="North American Go Convention!!!" href="//north-american-go-convention/">Introduction</a><strong> &#8212; Day 1</strong> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 2" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-2/">Day 2</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 3" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-3/">Day 3</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 4" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-4/">Day 4</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 5" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-5/">Day 5</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Conclusion" href="//north-american-go-convention-conclusion/">Conclusion</a></p>
<p>The day got off to a rather dreary start as I spent about an hour in rainy traffic trying to make my way down to the event. After grabbing a quick bite to eat, I found myself standing outside the building wondering how to get in. There was construction going on and with all the doors locked down I was running around trying to figure out how to get in for about 10 minutes. Thankfully someone was kind enough to let me in on their way out.<br />
As I rode the elevator up to the 9th floor, I was a little anxious as I expected a bit of a crowd since I was running late. Although I think the real concern for me was missing the opportunity to play a teaching/game with the professionals. When I arrived however, there were only around six to eight people in the waiting area. For those who aren&#8217;t aware, the North American Go Convention (NAGC) is a two part convention that started out in New Jersey and made its way down to DC. With the traffic and crummy weather, the bus was unfortunately running late and thus everything was pushed back. So all my rushing to get there on time was for naught. xD On the upside, it gave me a chance to settle down and catch my breath.<br />
While sitting in the waiting area, I couldn&#8217;t help but overhear as people were talking about their strengths and how long they&#8217;d been studying. There were a few Korean players and a couple Chinese players. The two younger players (around my age) had apparently started studying when they were around 5 years old and were 7 dan and 4 dan respectively. You can only imagine how I felt when I realized that I was the only kyu player in the room. Haha.<br />
As if things couldn&#8217;t get worse, one of the moms asked me later on how strong I was. After all the conversation in the room about how the children were dans and had started studying go since they were young, I think she just naturally expected me to say I was X dan. When I responded that I was 6 kyu, she gave me a quizzical look as if she had never heard of the rank. In fact, someone even asked, &#8220;So wait, is 6 kyu higher than 1 kyu?&#8221;<br />
&#8220;Dear lord,&#8221; I thought, &#8220;They don&#8217;t even recognize the kyu levels.&#8221; *hangs head in shame*<br />
<span id="more-1895"></span><br />
Of course, all you can do is really laugh as you realize how vast the world of go is and how strong people are.<br />
Anyhow, we eventually moved into the tournament room and I had the pleasure of catching up with Yuan Zhou while we waited. In addition, I played a friendly game with a someone who told me he had not played in a while. In terms of evaluating his strength, I could tell that he was no pushover and probably even stronger than me. So much for letting him take black. =D It was a fun game and it would&#8217;ve been interesting to see how it ended. Before we could really get into the middle game fighting though, we were happy to stop our game since <a href="http://senseis.xmp.net/?JoanneMissingham">Joanne Missingham</a> arrived!<br />
<figure id="attachment_1918" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/02/joannemissingham.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1918" alt="Joanne Missingham (Hei Jia Jia) 6P" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/02/joannemissingham.jpg?resize=300%2C200" width="300" height="200" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Joanne Missingham (Hei Jia Jia) 6P</figcaption></figure>
The next thing I know, I was sitting before her as I was about to play my second professional simultaneous game. Earlier that night, I had learned that the Chinese word for dan is pronounced dee and the Chinese word for kyu is jee. So when she came around, everyone else had told her their rank in Chinese, I decided to do the same. Due to my nervousness however, I ended up saying &#8220;6 dee&#8221; instead of &#8220;6 jee.&#8221; You can only imagine my surprise when she only told me to put down 2 stones when she told the other dans to put down three. Hahaha. After realizing what had happened, I quickly got her attention as I was like, &#8220;Wait wait! I&#8217;m 6 kyu! Not 6 dan!!&#8221; xD<br />
Even though this is not my first time playing a professional, it still blew my mind as to how strong professionals are. Their adherence to the fundamentals and unwavering will to exploit weaknesses and determine these things in matters of seconds is astonishing. Definitely awe-inspiring. I only hope that one day I will amount to even 10% of what they are.<br />
Below is the game record for my game with Joanne Missingham (6P). Due to the event starting late however, I didn&#8217;t really get a chance to discuss the game much with her. On the upside, I did get a couple of comments from her to clarify a few areas that I was positive caused my downfall. =)<br />

<div id='glift_display6' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display6","sgf":"http:\/\/bengozen.com\/\/wp-content\/uploads\/2013\/02\/2013.02.14-NAGC-Day-1.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='//wp-content/uploads/2013/02/2013.02.14-NAGC-Day-1.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">[download label=&#8221;Download Kifu&#8221;]//wp-content/uploads/2013/02/2013.02.14-NAGC-Day-1.sgf[/download]
<p>And for those who don&#8217;t happen to follow my twitter, the day ended with a bit of a hitch. You see, I followed the signs for visitors to park in the garage. Lo and behold, you can imagine my surprise when I came down to the garage to get my car and saw the garage doors shut. I thought I was going to be stranded outside for the rest of the night. Hahaha. But luckily I found a way into the garage and then eventually got out. Lesson learned for the next two nights!</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a title="North American Go Convention!!!" href="//north-american-go-convention/">Introduction</a><strong> &#8212; Day 1</strong> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 2" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-2/">Day 2</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 3" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-3/">Day 3</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 4" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-4/">Day 4</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 5" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-5/">Day 5</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Conclusion" href="//north-american-go-convention-conclusion/">Conclusion</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1895</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>North American Go Convention!!!</title>
		<link>/north-american-go-convention/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2012 19:30:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[2013]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[go event]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nagc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[north american go convention]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tournament]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=1178</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Introduction &#8212; Day 1 &#8212; Day 2 &#8212; Day 3 &#8212; Day 4 &#8212; Day 5 &#8212; Conclusion Big announcement everyone! I am ecstatic to tell you about a brand new go event coming to the East coast! North American Go Convention 2013 (NAGC) Here is a high level overview of all the exciting things [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>Introduction</strong> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 1" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-1/">Day 1</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 2" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-2/">Day 2</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 3" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-3/">Day 3</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 4" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-4/">Day 4</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 5" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-5/">Day 5</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Conclusion" href="//north-american-go-convention-conclusion/">Conclusion</a></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>Big announcement everyone! I am ecstatic to tell you about a brand new go event coming to the East coast!</strong></p>
<h1 style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2012/11/nagc.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1179" title="North American Go Convention Logo" alt="North American Go Convention Logo" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2012/11/nagc.jpg?resize=240%2C100" width="240" height="100" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></h1>
<h1 style="text-align: center;"><a title="North American Go Convention" href="http://www.ngol.us/">North American Go Convention 2013 (NAGC)</a></h1>
<p>Here is a high level overview of all the exciting things you can expect:</p>
<ol>
<li>Game review sessions with professionals!</li>
<li>Simultaneous games with professionals!</li>
<li>Lectures from professionals!</li>
<li>Multiple open tournaments for players of all ranks that are AGA rated and can be up to 23 rounds for kyu players and 17 rounds for dan players!</li>
<li>Pair Go (Rengo)</li>
<li>Blitz Go</li>
<li>Lots of awards!!!</li>
<li><a title="NAGC Features" href="http://www.ngol.us/nagc/nagc-introduction">And more more more!!!</a></li>
</ol>
<p>So if you&#8217;re even thinking about possibly going, go ahead and pre-register <a title="NAGC Online Registration" href="http://www.ngol.us/nagc/online-registration">here</a> because there is no obligation to commit to anything but you will at least have your name down early on in case spots for simul games or reviews from pros become unavailable due to high demand (which you know is inevitable). So don&#8217;t hesitate and hurry up and go pre-register! I&#8217;m already pre-registered for Gold Access in DC, but I&#8217;d also be open to going to NJ as well if given enough persuasion!<br />
If you are going, be sure to let me know because I&#8217;ll definitely be there! Ahhhhh!!!! So exciting!!!!</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>Introduction</strong> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 1" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-1/">Day 1</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 2" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-2/">Day 2</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 3" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-3/">Day 3</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 4" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-4/">Day 4</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 5" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-5/">Day 5</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Conclusion" href="//north-american-go-convention-conclusion/">Conclusion</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1178</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
