<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>episode &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/episode/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>Watching BadukTV for the First Time</title>
		<link>/watching-baduktv-first-time/</link>
		<comments>/watching-baduktv-first-time/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2013 16:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[baduktv]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[episode]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gogameguru]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lee changho]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lee sedol]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tv]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=4001</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[After I got back from boxing last night, I was pretty much wiped out. The funny thing about me is that no matter how tired I am though, it seems that I somehow manage to find the energy and motivation to do something go related. So I decided to check out my first episode of [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After I got back from boxing last night, I was pretty much wiped out. The funny thing about me is that no matter how tired I am though, it seems that I somehow manage to find the energy and motivation to do something go related. So I decided to check out my first episode of a BadukTV English game review of Lee Changho 9P vs. Lee Sedol 9P.<br />
For those who aren&#8217;t aware of the popularity of go in the rest of the world, there are actual television channels that are ENTIRELY dedicated to go. Now, I don&#8217;t know about you, but I would love it if we had something equivalent here in the Western world. Unfortunately though, go has not yet risen to that level of popularity. On the upside though, pioneers like GoGamGuru and BadukTV have taken the first big step to bringing us one step closer to that dream.<br />
Here is the video that I watched last night:<br />
<iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='720' height='405' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/videoseries?list=PLq69jNwwOmf-Lkbyny1HwiRUKMg6uuFo2&#038;hl=en_US' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;'></iframe>
Since I had never watched a TV episode dedicated entirely to go (excluding <em>Hikaru no Go</em>), I was a little nervous that I might get bored or that I would be unable to gain anything from it. Contrary to my fears however, I was pleasantly surprised at how much I enjoyed it. Though many complain about the co-host interrupting often and saying &#8220;Yes&#8221; all the time, you have to be conscious of the fact that the English is clearly not her first language and that chances are pretty good that her mannerisms derive from Korean culture. So with that in mind, I was able to look past it rather easily and just enjoy all the marvelous go.<br />
<em>For those who enjoyed the video above or would like to find out more about where you can watch more episodes like this, check out <a href="http://gogameguru.com/baduk-tv/">GoGameGuru&#8217;s BadukTV</a> to get access to more BadukTV that is accessible to English speakers!</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/watching-baduktv-first-time/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>19</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">4001</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
