<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"

	>
<channel>
	<title>Comments on: Monday Go Meditation: Game 49</title>
	<atom:link href="/monday-go-meditation-game-49/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/monday-go-meditation-game-49/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2015 12:34:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
	<item>
		<title>By: Ben</title>
		<link>/monday-go-meditation-game-49/#comment-1729</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ben]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 02:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=4816#comment-1729</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It&#039;s funny you mention Kageyama because I was thinking the exact same thing. And the sheer fact of my laziness is exactly the kind of thing he criticized about amateur players. Just need to read it out one move at a time.
I think it&#039;s funny we&#039;re opposite on that. I think I just got traumatized by letting my opponent reverse the game due to one big overplay that I missed. But you are right, it&#039;s a lot easier to deal with them compared to people who are more consistent overall. I&#039;m flattered that I provide that challenge to you! Hopefully I will be able to continue to do so!]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s funny you mention Kageyama because I was thinking the exact same thing. And the sheer fact of my laziness is exactly the kind of thing he criticized about amateur players. Just need to read it out one move at a time.<br />
I think it&#8217;s funny we&#8217;re opposite on that. I think I just got traumatized by letting my opponent reverse the game due to one big overplay that I missed. But you are right, it&#8217;s a lot easier to deal with them compared to people who are more consistent overall. I&#8217;m flattered that I provide that challenge to you! Hopefully I will be able to continue to do so!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Nate Eagle</title>
		<link>/monday-go-meditation-game-49/#comment-1728</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nate Eagle]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 02:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=4816#comment-1728</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I missed the ladder in our game, too, so I&#039;m not really in a position to judge. I have a bunch of recurring blind spots when it comes to fighting that I have to work on, things like shortage of liberty issues, missed ataris... the list is too embarrassing to enumerate. But maybe it&#039;ll help to think about Kageyama&#039;s rule of thumb: always ask yourself two questions. 1) Can I capture this in a ladder? 2) Can I capture this in a net? And only when these two have definitely been answered in the negative do you move on.
&quot;I think I just get nervous I&#039;ll make a stupid mistake and make their overplays work out.&quot;
It&#039;s funny that we&#039;re the reverse on that. Yeah, I&#039;d take them over a properly cautious player any day of the week. When I play someone like you, I&#039;ve got to both read accurately and demonstrate consistent, good judgment about the whole board. When I play someone like them, all I have to do is not make mistakes! They&#039;ll make my moves obvious and easy.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I missed the ladder in our game, too, so I&#8217;m not really in a position to judge. I have a bunch of recurring blind spots when it comes to fighting that I have to work on, things like shortage of liberty issues, missed ataris&#8230; the list is too embarrassing to enumerate. But maybe it&#8217;ll help to think about Kageyama&#8217;s rule of thumb: always ask yourself two questions. 1) Can I capture this in a ladder? 2) Can I capture this in a net? And only when these two have definitely been answered in the negative do you move on.<br />
&#8220;I think I just get nervous I&#8217;ll make a stupid mistake and make their overplays work out.&#8221;<br />
It&#8217;s funny that we&#8217;re the reverse on that. Yeah, I&#8217;d take them over a properly cautious player any day of the week. When I play someone like you, I&#8217;ve got to both read accurately and demonstrate consistent, good judgment about the whole board. When I play someone like them, all I have to do is not make mistakes! They&#8217;ll make my moves obvious and easy.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Ben</title>
		<link>/monday-go-meditation-game-49/#comment-1727</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ben]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2014 21:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=4816#comment-1727</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Good point about S14! I was thinking small potatoes at the time. Should have envisioned things larger.
Ahhh!!! Those ladders that I keep missing!!! I need to stop missing those. Gahhh... If I had just read like three moves in I would have saw exactly what you&#039;re saying about Move 153. Sigh. Must read read read!
Thanks for the compliment! Oftentimes when I review the games, I&#039;m often trying to provide the most commentary I can within a concise amount of time (since I&#039;m often racing to finish these so that I don&#039;t miss a week). I&#039;m hoping that over time they will continue to improve in quality so that they are more useful to people. Appreciate the supporting words!
It&#039;s funny you should mention that you enjoy playing against them (i.e., Russian and German players). I have seen you trounce your opponents with solid reading time and time again, so it comes to no surprise that you enjoy there types of players who overplay a lot. I think I just get nervous I&#039;ll make a stupid mistake and make their overplays work out. Guess that means I still have some work to do!]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Good point about S14! I was thinking small potatoes at the time. Should have envisioned things larger.<br />
Ahhh!!! Those ladders that I keep missing!!! I need to stop missing those. Gahhh&#8230; If I had just read like three moves in I would have saw exactly what you&#8217;re saying about Move 153. Sigh. Must read read read!<br />
Thanks for the compliment! Oftentimes when I review the games, I&#8217;m often trying to provide the most commentary I can within a concise amount of time (since I&#8217;m often racing to finish these so that I don&#8217;t miss a week). I&#8217;m hoping that over time they will continue to improve in quality so that they are more useful to people. Appreciate the supporting words!<br />
It&#8217;s funny you should mention that you enjoy playing against them (i.e., Russian and German players). I have seen you trounce your opponents with solid reading time and time again, so it comes to no surprise that you enjoy there types of players who overplay a lot. I think I just get nervous I&#8217;ll make a stupid mistake and make their overplays work out. Guess that means I still have some work to do!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Nate Eagle</title>
		<link>/monday-go-meditation-game-49/#comment-1726</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nate Eagle]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2014 18:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=4816#comment-1726</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[S14 instead of R15 at move 128 is a classic tesuji to take even more advantage of white&#039;s shape, using the aji of your cutting stone at P14 to the fullest.
Also: an atari on the outside at M9 for move 153 leads to a nice, lethal ladder, making things simpler for black.
This was a good review; I was struck by how usefully you were explaining some of the fundamental ideas behind profiting through attack, which might be the core concept of the period one spends as an SDK. The ko in the lower left was a particular highlight - to embrace and manage a ko with confidence is a real mark of skill.
It also showed why I&#039;m perfectly happy to play a game against the kind of Russian or German players you&#039;re talking about (I have less experience playing Koreans). Their desire to win through fighting means they&#039;re constantly starting fights where they have fewer resources, which means that prudence and careful reading results in a game that&#039;s actually pretty easy.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>S14 instead of R15 at move 128 is a classic tesuji to take even more advantage of white&#8217;s shape, using the aji of your cutting stone at P14 to the fullest.<br />
Also: an atari on the outside at M9 for move 153 leads to a nice, lethal ladder, making things simpler for black.<br />
This was a good review; I was struck by how usefully you were explaining some of the fundamental ideas behind profiting through attack, which might be the core concept of the period one spends as an SDK. The ko in the lower left was a particular highlight &#8211; to embrace and manage a ko with confidence is a real mark of skill.<br />
It also showed why I&#8217;m perfectly happy to play a game against the kind of Russian or German players you&#8217;re talking about (I have less experience playing Koreans). Their desire to win through fighting means they&#8217;re constantly starting fights where they have fewer resources, which means that prudence and careful reading results in a game that&#8217;s actually pretty easy.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
</channel>
</rss>
