<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>hikaru no go &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/hikaru-no-go/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>WGW 38: I Want to Play Go Like That&#8230;</title>
		<link>/wgw-38-i-want-play-go-like-that/</link>
		<comments>/wgw-38-i-want-play-go-like-that/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2014 19:25:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Weekly Go Wednesday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[baduk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beautiful]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[championship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hikaru no go]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inspirational]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inspired]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inspiring]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[interlude]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[open]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[park sohyun]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tournament]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[washington]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5141</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Part I &#8211; Interlude &#8211; Part II Weekly Go Wednesday, Issue #38 Though some of you may hate me for delaying Part II of my 1st Washington Open Baduk Championship series, the funny thing is that the Weekly Go Wednesday series actually fits in perfectly with the story. So hold your horses for one more [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><a title="1st Washington Open Baduk Championship — Part I" href="//1st-washington-open-baduk-championship-part/">Part I</a> &#8211; <strong>Interlude</strong> &#8211; <a title="1st Washington Open Baduk Championship — Part II" href="//1st-washington-open-baduk-championship-part-ii/">Part II</a></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">Weekly Go Wednesday, Issue #38</h2>
<p>Though some of you may hate me for delaying Part II of my <a title="1st Washington Open Baduk Championship — Part I" href="//1st-washington-open-baduk-championship-part/">1st Washington Open Baduk Championship</a> series, the funny thing is that the Weekly Go Wednesday series actually fits in perfectly with the story. So hold your horses for one more day, and let&#8217;s dive right into this shall we?<br />
So where were we? Ah yes. I had finished off the <a title="1st Washington Open Baduk Championship — Part I" href="//1st-washington-open-baduk-championship-part/">first day of the tournament</a> with the second to worst record you can have: 1 win with 2 loss. To compound on that embarrassment, I won one and then proceeded to lose each game afterwards with each being a more epic failure than the last. After all, it would have been way better if I had lost the first two games and then won the last one. Then at least I could feel like I improved over the day instead of the epic plummet that actually happened.<br />
Usually when I undergo a shocking disappointment like I did that day, my first reaction is to try and figure out what went wrong. After all, it wasn&#8217;t as if some freak accident happened where I hallucinated and put the stones in the wrong place. No, especially with go, there are no such things. So for the rest of the day, I kept thinking about what went wrong. Many things crossed my mind&#8230;<br />
<span id="more-5141"></span><br />
The first (and most self-pitying) of my thoughts was the simple fact that I wasn&#8217;t actually 3 kyu. KGS and the AGA might have ranked me as 3 kyu, but maybe the statistics were biased and overly generous since I did not play often enough to get an accurate measurement of my strength. So perhaps I was really more like 4-5 kyu when it came to the competitive scene. But after trying to entertain that thought a bit longer, even I realized how absurd that notion was.<br />
Since that wasn&#8217;t it, the next thing that I came up with was the fact that I lacked the stamina to survive tournaments. In other words, I might be able to play one serious game a day and then a few casual ones; but in a tournament setting with all the pressure and intensity, I ran out of steam and could barely win one game. After all, I had stopped playing ranked games (aka serious games with strangers) and was probably more out of practice than I was willing to admit at the time.<br />
Okay. That made sense, but I concluded that it could not be the only reason. After all, being tired doesn&#8217;t explain the self-destruction that occurred as the day went on. After all, it&#8217;s not as if I just made a few bad reading mistakes, it&#8217;s like my brain decided to take a vacation and I was playing like a mad man. So there must be more&#8230;<br />
Ah. Could a part of it be arrogance from the fact that the last full tournament I played in (<a title="NOVA Pumpkin Classic Tournament 2012 — Introduction" href="//nova-pumpkin-class-2012-intro/">NOVA Pumpkin Classic</a>) resulted in me have a perfect record and getting 1st place? And in hindsight, I had not really prepared for that tournament, so perhaps I subconsciously thought that this tournament might be similar. Maybe I could just wing it and do well like last time. Not necessarily win, but at least do well. You know?<br />
<span style="line-height: 1.5em;">Well, that was about how far I got with my introspection when I arrived in a nearby conference room to see Park Sohyun (3p) playing a teaching game with one of the VIPs.*</span><br />
<em>*To give some background on this story though, the VIP she was playing a teaching game with was actually an insei when he was younger. So while he was older now and out of practice, there was no doubt in my mind that he was pretty strong (i.e., he only took 2 stones for the game).</em><br />
<figure id="attachment_5164" style="width: 420px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014-WOpen-10.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-5164" alt="2014-WOpen-10" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/2014-WOpen-10.jpg?resize=420%2C560" width="420" height="560" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">I didn&#8217;t want to take a picture of her from the front at this time because I didn&#8217;t get a chance to ask if it would be okay and she was in a middle of the game.</figcaption></figure>
They would play for like 30-40 moves, and then he would have a question for her and they would rewind the game back like 20 moves or clear off an area of the board to talk about a particular sequence or concept. And then the game would resume another 30-40 moves before the same thing happened again.<br />
I could not understand anything they were talking about since they spoke in Korean. However,as I watched the game unfold, I would watch as her moves exuded with power as they came down on the board. And at the same time, I watched as the VIP tried his best to hold his ground against her while ending up with this very over concentrated groups that she would harass while continuing to gain a greater advantage on the board with each move.<br />
The weird thing is that it&#8217;s not as if I had never met a professional or seen a professional play against an amateur before. Yet for some reason, her moves captivated me in a way I had never quite felt before. As I watched in awe, each and every move came flowing down with a grace and beauty that I can only describe as surreal.<br />
<figure id="attachment_5192" style="width: 560px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/wgw38-01.png"><img class=" wp-image-5192" alt="wgw38-01" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/wgw38-01.png?resize=560%2C422" width="560" height="422" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Hikaru No Go Anime, Kuwabara Hon&#8217;inbo (Epsiode 29)</figcaption></figure>
<figure id="attachment_5193" style="width: 576px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/wgw38-02.png"><img class=" wp-image-5193" alt="wgw38-02" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/wgw38-02.png?resize=576%2C430" width="576" height="430" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Hikaru No Go Anime, Kuwabara Hon&#8217;inbo (Epsiode 29)</figcaption></figure>
&#8220;This&#8230;&#8221; I thought, &#8220;The way she plays&#8230; I want to play go like that&#8230;&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/wgw-38-i-want-play-go-like-that/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>11</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">5141</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>WGW37: Tesuji More Useful Than Tsumego?</title>
		<link>/wgw37-tesuji-more-useful-than-tsumego/</link>
		<comments>/wgw37-tesuji-more-useful-than-tsumego/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2014 11:15:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Weekly Go Wednesday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[amazing moves]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[awe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[getting stronger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hikaru no go]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meijin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tesuji]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tsumego]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=5039</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Weekly Go Wednesday, Issue #37 Last Friday, I mentioned an article that was shared with me on how to improve at go by Lynx. According to conventional wisdom, the one piece of advice that everyone seem to agree upon is that studying life and death is critical to getting stronger. And to be honest, it&#8217;s [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 style="text-align: center;">Weekly Go Wednesday, Issue #37</h2>
<p>Last <a title="Friday Go Forward: Week 58" href="//friday-go-forward-week-58/">Friday</a>, I mentioned an <a title="Lynx's How to Improve at Go" href="http://shobia.com/w/How_to_Improve_at_Go">article</a> that was shared with me on how to improve at go by Lynx. According to conventional wisdom, the one piece of advice that everyone seem to agree upon is that studying life and death is critical to getting stronger. And to be honest, it&#8217;s something I never really questioned. However, after reading Lynx&#8217;s article, I was confronted with an eye-opening question: <strong>Is studying tesuji more useful than tsumego? </strong><br />
After a lot of thought,  I would have to concur  with Lynx&#8217;s perspective. In fact, it is one of the key components to breaking the glass ceiling when trying to gain that next stone. However, because the masses constantly spout how important life and death is, it is often forgotten in all the noise.<br />
<span style="line-height: 1.5em;">Now now, before you grab your pitchforks and torches, hear me out won&#8217;t you?</span><br />
<span id="more-5039"></span><br />
To start, I will go ahead and address probably the strongest argument against Lynx&#8217;s theory: What is the use of tesuji if you die everywhere?<br />
True. If your life and skills are so abysmal that you are slaughtered around the board, I agree with you in that tesuji will not do you much good. However, the reality of the situation is that most games don&#8217;t consist of groups dying all over the board (unless the rank is horribly imbalanced). And though this can partially be attributed to people studying life and death, my personal experience has shown me that the bottom line is that <em>it is really hard to kill groups in go</em>.<br />
Though people might not realize it, I think that players will inevitably learn about life and death as they play. Why do I say this? Because whenever your group dies, it is usually pretty traumatic. Who can remember that time when they thought their corner was alive and then died in a magnificent burst of flames? I know I can recount it on multiple occasions. And what happens when you die? Well usually you might go back to figure out how you could&#8217;ve avoided it. After all, who likes dying?<br />
On top of that, let&#8217;s not forget the fact that players constantly miss tesuji in their games. It is usually very obvious to players who are much stronger, but unless someone is having their game reviewed by such a player, how many people are going to spend time going over their game to figure out the numerous tesuji they missed? Highly unlikely. They are way more likely to just move on and play another game.<br />
In addition, no matter how peaceful a player you are, you are eventually going to get into fights on the board. I&#8217;m sure there are kifu that exists where no one challenged each other at all, but I&#8217;m pretty sure they only exist at the beginner level since they aren&#8217;t aware they are capable of invading and living. And when it comes to fighting, there is no better weapon than being better at tesuji than your opponent.<br />
Who remembers this scene?<br />
<figure id="attachment_5114" style="width: 422px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/wgw37tesuji01.png"><img class=" wp-image-5114" alt="wgw37tesuji01" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/wgw37tesuji01.png?resize=422%2C312" width="422" height="312" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Ring any bells? [Credit: Hikaru No Go Anime]</figcaption></figure><figure id="attachment_5115" style="width: 384px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/wgw37tesuji02.png"><img class=" wp-image-5115" alt="wgw37tesuji02" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/wgw37tesuji02.png?resize=384%2C291" width="384" height="291" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">How about this one? [Credit: Hikaru no Go Anime]</figcaption></figure><figure id="attachment_5116" style="width: 384px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/wgw37tesuji03.png"><img class=" wp-image-5116" alt="wgw37tesuji03" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2014/04/wgw37tesuji03.png?resize=384%2C291" width="384" height="291" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Still no? [Credit: Hikaru no Go Anime]</figcaption></figure>Many of you probably figured it out after the second screenshot, but the answer for those who couldn&#8217;t remember is: Episode 56, &#8220;After a Millennium Comes an Answer.&#8221;<br />
Anyhow, was this a move that dealt with life and death? Did Sai&#8217;s incredible move kill the Meijin&#8217;s group? No. It was a brilliant tesuji that made all spectators watch in amazement. And in fact, if you think about it, most of the moves that are met with astonishment and awe in the show are usually tesuji. They are all about how brilliant that connection was, or how this peep is an excellent forcing move that allows XYZ tesuji to work.<br />
Finally, I want to remind you that Lynx&#8217;s point is <strong><em>not</em></strong> to burn all your tsumego books and never life and death. Instead, she&#8217;s simply trying to remind us of how important tesuji are when it comes to gaining that next stone. So the next time you are thinking about what to study, I hope that you&#8217;ll consider making some time to study tesuji in your busy schedule. It&#8217;ll definitely be worth your while in the long run.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/wgw37-tesuji-more-useful-than-tsumego/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>12</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">5039</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Desire to Lose</title>
		<link>/the-desire-to-lose/</link>
		<comments>/the-desire-to-lose/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2013 12:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[akira]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[back to tygem]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[desire to lose]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[happy to lose]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hikaru no go]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=3494</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[So I think I have to revise my one post a day rule to exclude book reviews because at the rate I&#8217;m releasing book reviews, I&#8217;m never going to get a chance to write for the sake of writing. Haha. With that said, let&#8217;s unload some things off my brain. I recently re-watched the episode [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_3497" style="width: 400px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/07/sad-robot.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-3497" alt="sad robot lose" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/07/sad-robot.jpg?resize=400%2C250" width="400" height="250" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Credit to <a href="http://aybanlim.wordpress.com/">abyanlim</a></figcaption></figure>
So I think I have to revise my one post a day rule to exclude book reviews because at the rate I&#8217;m releasing book reviews, I&#8217;m never going to get a chance to write for the sake of writing. Haha. With that said, let&#8217;s unload some things off my brain.<br />
I recently re-watched the episode in <em>Hikaru No Go</em> (Episode 66 &#8211; &#8220;Fateful Encounter&#8221;) where they do the prelude to the whole series. For those who might not remember, the episode features a child who recently is crowned Child Meijin and wants to challenge Akira to prove he is the strongest. Right before the game, he pridefully challenges Akira with the following statement:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">Child Meijin: When I win, tell everyone, &#8220;I lost to Hideki Isobe.&#8221;</p>
<p>Though most might shy away from the idea of boasting to everyone that they lost, Akira&#8217;s reaction reminded me of something I had forgotten long ago.</p>
<blockquote><p>Akira (with the utmost excited face): I will! I sure will!</p></blockquote>
<p>How long ago has it been since I last sought out a match where I would be proud to say, &#8220;Look! I lost, but it was a great game!&#8221; When was the last time I felt a desire to lose?<br />
Nowadays, I just slink away like a dog with his tail between his legs hoping secretly hoping to quickly nab a win afterwards to cover up my shame. What a pitiful state I&#8217;ve fallen into&#8230; Haha. No matter though, today is a new day! I will return back to the battlefield of Tygem and restart my training against dan players! Ikuzo!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/the-desire-to-lose/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>11</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3494</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Tip of Their Swords&#8230;</title>
		<link>/the-tip-of-their-swords/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2010 14:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kifu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hikaru no go]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[overcoming fear]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sai's wisdom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tip of their swords]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=59</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Lately I&#8217;ve been looking at my style of play. It&#8217;s always safe, nice to opponents, and afraid to try anything new for fear of losing. Erm&#8230; yeah that wasn&#8217;t working out. Evolution requires trial and error, to think anything less will only result in a stable condition which will allow others to surpass you. Who [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lately I&#8217;ve been looking at my style of play. It&#8217;s always safe, nice to opponents, and afraid to try anything new for fear of losing. Erm&#8230; yeah that wasn&#8217;t working out. Evolution requires trial and error, to think anything less will only result in a stable condition which will allow others to surpass you.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Who remembers the following scene?</em></p>
<figure id="attachment_644" style="width: 492px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img class=" wp-image-644 " title="fear1" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2010/10/fear1-615x1024.jpg?resize=492%2C819" alt="" width="492" height="819" data-recalc-dims="1" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Hikaru No Go: Volume 7</figcaption></figure>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span id="more-59"></span>So what do we do to overcome our fear?</p>
<figure id="attachment_645" style="width: 508px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img class=" wp-image-645 " title="fear2" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2010/10/fear2-635x1024.jpg?resize=508%2C819" alt="" width="508" height="819" data-recalc-dims="1" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Hikaru No Go &#8211; Volume 7</figcaption></figure>
With Sai&#8217;s wisdom in mind, here is me diving straight in to try things out without fear of its consequences in an even game against a 12k. (Not that I didn&#8217;t read, but I just was no longer afraid.) I lost a few groups as a result, and a few misreadings caused the game to flip, but the game was by far one of the most interesting ones I think you&#8217;ll have seen so far.<br />

<div id='glift_display1' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display1","sgf":"http:\/\/bengozen.com\/\/wp-content\/uploads\/2010\/10\/2010.10.22-The-Tip-of-Their-Swords.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='//wp-content/uploads/2010/10/2010.10.22-The-Tip-of-Their-Swords.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
And for my other rabbit jumpers on KGS, don&#8217;t even pay mind to gaining that stone on KGS. Just trust your abilities and keep honing your skills. I guarantee you, the results will show itself without you keeping track of how many games till the next promotion. Cause ultimately the true promotion will manifest in you, not your KGS account.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">59</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
