<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>joanne missingham &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/joanne-missingham/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>I&#039;m on TV!! Sort Of&#8230;</title>
		<link>/im-on-tv-sort-of/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 02:35:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[interview]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[joanne missingham]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=2410</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[For those of you who read my series of posts on the North American Go Convention, you might recall that on Day 2, there was a crew doing a special interview with Joanne Missingham. Guess who made the cut? I guess my play was so incredible they decided to feature me! Hahaha. Just kidding! Anyhow, [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For those of you who read my series of posts on the <a title="North American Go Convention!!!" href="//north-american-go-convention/">North American Go Convention</a>, you might recall that on <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 2" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-2/">Day 2</a>, there was a crew doing a special interview with Joanne Missingham. Guess who made the cut? I guess my play was so incredible they decided to feature me! Hahaha. Just kidding! Anyhow, I can&#8217;t seem to download the video from Facebook. So here is the link to the video and some screenshots below:</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://www.facebook.com/video/embed?video_id=523594844357220">Joanne Missingham Interview</a></p>
<figure id="attachment_2485" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/03/interview1.png"><img class="size-full wp-image-2485" alt="interview1" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/03/interview1.png?resize=300%2C170" width="300" height="170" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">1:30</figcaption></figure>
<figure id="attachment_2486" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/03/interview2.png"><img class="size-full wp-image-2486" alt="interview2" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/03/interview2.png?resize=300%2C170" width="300" height="170" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">7:00</figcaption></figure>
<p style="text-align: center;">
<figure id="attachment_2487" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/03/interview3.png"><img class="size-full wp-image-2487" alt="interview3" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/03/interview3.png?resize=300%2C170" width="300" height="170" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">8:10</figcaption></figure>
<p style="text-align: center;">
<p style="text-align: center;">Fun times. xD</p>
<p>*Thanks to DeepSnow for seeing the scene at 8:10. I have no idea how I missed it.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2410</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>North American Go Convention &#8211; Day 2</title>
		<link>/north-american-go-convention-day-2/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2013 22:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kifu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[6p]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[9p]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[joanne missingham]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[myung wan kim]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nagc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[professional review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartgo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tournament]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=1915</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Introduction &#8212; Day 1 &#8212; Day 2 &#8212; Day 3 &#8212; Day 4 &#8212; Day 5 &#8212; Conclusion Although the weather was much nicer this time around, it seems the fates were conspiring against me as I spent a good twenty minutes stuck in traffic due to an accident. Fortunately for me, I had left early [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><a title="North American Go Convention!!!" href="//north-american-go-convention/">Introduction</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 1" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-1/">Day 1</a> &#8212; <strong>Day 2</strong> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 3" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-3/">Day 3</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 4" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-4/">Day 4</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 5" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-5/">Day 5</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Conclusion" href="//north-american-go-convention-conclusion/">Conclusion</a></p>
<p>Although the weather was much nicer this time around, it seems the fates were conspiring against me as I spent a good twenty minutes stuck in traffic due to an accident. Fortunately for me, I had left early enough that the delay was not going to make me incredibly late. On top of that, based on my experience yesterday, I didn&#8217;t have good reason to believe that arriving late would cause me to miss anything nor should I have worried that a huge crowd of people would suddenly appear on a Thursday night. Nonetheless, I still couldn&#8217;t help but feel anxious that I would arrive to find that the teaching/simultaneous games had started or were full.<br />
By the time I parked my car, it was about 3 minutes prior to 7pm. I rushed into the building fully expecting to grab the first elevator and make it there just on time. Lo and behold, what do I see when I walk in the lobby? The elevators are being maintained. In case you&#8217;re not getting the full effect of what I felt, remember that the convention is on the 9th floor. (-.-)<br />
Next thing I know, I&#8217;m bolting up 9 flights (although more like 18 since they were two flights per level) of stairs in a rush to get there on time. And when I finally make it up to the 9th floor, I am crestfallen as I look around and fail to see anyone around. The room that was setup for go lecture was full of employees holding a meeting, and the room where the we played our simul game yesterday was completely covered up.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">&#8220;CRAP. Did I miss the memo about it getting cancelled or the address moving?!?!?!&#8221;</p>
<p><span id="more-1915"></span><br />
Panic mode started to set in as I thought back to the fact I just rushed up all those stairs and might actually be in the wrong place. Gah!!! After a couple of calls in hopes of getting in contact with someone (which were all failures), I stood around a bit helpless and frustrated as I thought I had missed something. Fortunately, I did not leave in a big rush because I see someone who looks like they are associated with the convention walking around and he lets me in (the doors to the office are locked from the elevator lobby).<br />
When I&#8217;m outside the go room, I find out that Joanne Missingham is being interviewed (by a group that I cannot remember right now). I breathed the biggest sigh of relief as I realized that I had not missed anything and that nothing was cancelled. Since it didn&#8217;t seem like anyone was there yet, I sat outside in the hall listening to music and practicing some easy tsumego problems. After 20 minutes or so, I notice that some of the staff are looking for an overflow room in case a lot of people show up. They never come back to the interview area, so I figure that they must have found it.<br />
I walk around and end up finding everyone sitting in the waiting area enjoying iced tea. I hesitated for a moment before joining them, but realized that it was probably in my best interest to wait with them since they will be the first to find out if anything is starting. To my great surprise, the next thing I know I am being introduced to Myung Wan Kim (9P) and his friend James.<br />
<figure id="attachment_1922" style="width: 241px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/02/MyungwanKim.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1922" alt="Myung Wan Kim (9P)" src="https://i0.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/02/MyungwanKim.jpg?resize=241%2C300" width="241" height="300" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Myung Wan Kim (9P)</figcaption></figure>
After the basic introductions and finding out I was 6 kyu, Myung asked me if I had a game for him to review. I was a bit taken aback at first since I did not expect such an incredible opportunity, but told him I did and started getting my iPad out. In the middle of getting my iPad however, the conversation somehow turned into wondering if we could play on my iPad. And without missing a beat I responded, &#8220;Of course!&#8221; (Thank you SmartGo Kifu!!!!!) Myung then suggested that I play with James and then he would review the game afterwards. Words cannot describe how excited I was to hear him suggest that.<br />
We were about 11 moves in when we were interrupted and asked if we would be willing to play with Joanne. The interviewers wanted to get some footage of Joanne playing amateurs. Play with Joanne? Possibly be part of some interview footage? Yes please!<br />
In a whirlwind change of events, I suddenly find myself in front of Joanne once again. Earlier in the day, I thought that I might ask if it would be okay to play an even game with her since I wanted to see how she would play under non-handicap circumstances. With the video recording and all though, I thought it best just to play at 4 stones again. Below is a partial record of the game since I thought the game was more for show than for a serious game, so this was the best I could do with the recreation in the midst of all the craziness.<br />

<div id='glift_display1' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display1","sgf":"http:\/\/bengozen.com\/\/wp-content\/uploads\/2013\/02\/2013.02.15-NAGC-Day-2.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='//wp-content/uploads/2013/02/2013.02.15-NAGC-Day-2.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">[download label=&#8221;Download Kifu&#8221;]//wp-content/uploads/2013/02/2013.02.15-NAGC-Day-2.sgf[/download]
<p>We got a little further than my record, but the game was ended prematurely in order to allow the interviewers to get other footage.<br />
As everyone took a break and went off to get a drink and such, I stood around wondering what would happen next. After all, it seemed that Joanne was rather busy with the interview and was clearly in high demand. A tournament was out of the question since I was one of two local players who came. So, what would happen the rest of the night?<br />
Before I could think too much about it though, Myung and James walked over to where I was standing and Myung asked if I would like to review the game I mentioned earlier. Um&#8230; YES!!!! (And I should mention that being able to tether my iPad to my phone so I could download SGF files from the KGS Archives was a 1000% win!)<br />
For my first professionally reviewed game, the best way I can summarize it is to say that I was absolutely blown away. Myung&#8217;s review and insight into various aspects of the game were so eye opening and revealing. I wish there was a way for me to capture everything onto an SGF, but so much of what I was told involved conceptual gaps that I still haven&#8217;t quite come to terms with. When I do though, I promise that I will make it my first priority to write an article on it.<br />
As someone who has had his games reviewed a number of times, I had forgotten what it was like to have a game reviewed in person. It&#8217;s really a completely different atmosphere. Although much of the credit is due to Myung&#8217;s ability to teach and illustrate his points clearly, I do think that reviews flow much better in person. Not only can Myung use my facial expressions to determine whether or not I&#8217;m understanding something, a real board makes it very easy to switch out positions and show why one is better than another. Maybe it&#8217;s just me or the fact that Myung was reviewing my game, but the game review just felt extremely effective.<br />
Although the night was rather uneventful in the sense that I was the only person there, the time that I got to spend talking and learning with Myung and James was invaluable and has already made the convention incredibly worthwhile. Definitely looking forward to tonight!</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a title="North American Go Convention!!!" href="//north-american-go-convention/">Introduction</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 1" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-1/">Day 1</a> &#8212; <strong>Day 2</strong> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 3" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-3/">Day 3</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 4" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-4/">Day 4</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 5" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-5/">Day 5</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Conclusion" href="//north-american-go-convention-conclusion/">Conclusion</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1915</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>North American Go Convention &#8211; Day 1</title>
		<link>/north-american-go-convention-day-1/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 22:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kifu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[6d]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[joanne missingham]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nagc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[north american go convention]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tournament]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=1895</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Introduction &#8212; Day 1 &#8212; Day 2 &#8212; Day 3 &#8212; Day 4 &#8212; Day 5 &#8212; Conclusion The day got off to a rather dreary start as I spent about an hour in rainy traffic trying to make my way down to the event. After grabbing a quick bite to eat, I found myself standing [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><a title="North American Go Convention!!!" href="//north-american-go-convention/">Introduction</a><strong> &#8212; Day 1</strong> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 2" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-2/">Day 2</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 3" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-3/">Day 3</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 4" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-4/">Day 4</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 5" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-5/">Day 5</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Conclusion" href="//north-american-go-convention-conclusion/">Conclusion</a></p>
<p>The day got off to a rather dreary start as I spent about an hour in rainy traffic trying to make my way down to the event. After grabbing a quick bite to eat, I found myself standing outside the building wondering how to get in. There was construction going on and with all the doors locked down I was running around trying to figure out how to get in for about 10 minutes. Thankfully someone was kind enough to let me in on their way out.<br />
As I rode the elevator up to the 9th floor, I was a little anxious as I expected a bit of a crowd since I was running late. Although I think the real concern for me was missing the opportunity to play a teaching/game with the professionals. When I arrived however, there were only around six to eight people in the waiting area. For those who aren&#8217;t aware, the North American Go Convention (NAGC) is a two part convention that started out in New Jersey and made its way down to DC. With the traffic and crummy weather, the bus was unfortunately running late and thus everything was pushed back. So all my rushing to get there on time was for naught. xD On the upside, it gave me a chance to settle down and catch my breath.<br />
While sitting in the waiting area, I couldn&#8217;t help but overhear as people were talking about their strengths and how long they&#8217;d been studying. There were a few Korean players and a couple Chinese players. The two younger players (around my age) had apparently started studying when they were around 5 years old and were 7 dan and 4 dan respectively. You can only imagine how I felt when I realized that I was the only kyu player in the room. Haha.<br />
As if things couldn&#8217;t get worse, one of the moms asked me later on how strong I was. After all the conversation in the room about how the children were dans and had started studying go since they were young, I think she just naturally expected me to say I was X dan. When I responded that I was 6 kyu, she gave me a quizzical look as if she had never heard of the rank. In fact, someone even asked, &#8220;So wait, is 6 kyu higher than 1 kyu?&#8221;<br />
&#8220;Dear lord,&#8221; I thought, &#8220;They don&#8217;t even recognize the kyu levels.&#8221; *hangs head in shame*<br />
<span id="more-1895"></span><br />
Of course, all you can do is really laugh as you realize how vast the world of go is and how strong people are.<br />
Anyhow, we eventually moved into the tournament room and I had the pleasure of catching up with Yuan Zhou while we waited. In addition, I played a friendly game with a someone who told me he had not played in a while. In terms of evaluating his strength, I could tell that he was no pushover and probably even stronger than me. So much for letting him take black. =D It was a fun game and it would&#8217;ve been interesting to see how it ended. Before we could really get into the middle game fighting though, we were happy to stop our game since <a href="http://senseis.xmp.net/?JoanneMissingham">Joanne Missingham</a> arrived!<br />
<figure id="attachment_1918" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/02/joannemissingham.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1918" alt="Joanne Missingham (Hei Jia Jia) 6P" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/02/joannemissingham.jpg?resize=300%2C200" width="300" height="200" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Joanne Missingham (Hei Jia Jia) 6P</figcaption></figure>
The next thing I know, I was sitting before her as I was about to play my second professional simultaneous game. Earlier that night, I had learned that the Chinese word for dan is pronounced dee and the Chinese word for kyu is jee. So when she came around, everyone else had told her their rank in Chinese, I decided to do the same. Due to my nervousness however, I ended up saying &#8220;6 dee&#8221; instead of &#8220;6 jee.&#8221; You can only imagine my surprise when she only told me to put down 2 stones when she told the other dans to put down three. Hahaha. After realizing what had happened, I quickly got her attention as I was like, &#8220;Wait wait! I&#8217;m 6 kyu! Not 6 dan!!&#8221; xD<br />
Even though this is not my first time playing a professional, it still blew my mind as to how strong professionals are. Their adherence to the fundamentals and unwavering will to exploit weaknesses and determine these things in matters of seconds is astonishing. Definitely awe-inspiring. I only hope that one day I will amount to even 10% of what they are.<br />
Below is the game record for my game with Joanne Missingham (6P). Due to the event starting late however, I didn&#8217;t really get a chance to discuss the game much with her. On the upside, I did get a couple of comments from her to clarify a few areas that I was positive caused my downfall. =)<br />

<div id='glift_display2' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display2","sgf":"http:\/\/bengozen.com\/\/wp-content\/uploads\/2013\/02\/2013.02.14-NAGC-Day-1.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='//wp-content/uploads/2013/02/2013.02.14-NAGC-Day-1.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">[download label=&#8221;Download Kifu&#8221;]//wp-content/uploads/2013/02/2013.02.14-NAGC-Day-1.sgf[/download]
<p>And for those who don&#8217;t happen to follow my twitter, the day ended with a bit of a hitch. You see, I followed the signs for visitors to park in the garage. Lo and behold, you can imagine my surprise when I came down to the garage to get my car and saw the garage doors shut. I thought I was going to be stranded outside for the rest of the night. Hahaha. But luckily I found a way into the garage and then eventually got out. Lesson learned for the next two nights!</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a title="North American Go Convention!!!" href="//north-american-go-convention/">Introduction</a><strong> &#8212; Day 1</strong> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 2" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-2/">Day 2</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 3" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-3/">Day 3</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 4" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-4/">Day 4</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Day 5" href="//north-american-go-convention-day-5/">Day 5</a> &#8212; <a title="North American Go Convention — Conclusion" href="//north-american-go-convention-conclusion/">Conclusion</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1895</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
