<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>balance &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/balance/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>Need More Even Games&#8230;</title>
		<link>/need-more-even-games/</link>
		<comments>/need-more-even-games/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2013 21:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[balance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[more even games]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[studying going well]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=3616</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I had a chance to go to one of Yuan Zhou&#8217;s Monthly Go Workshops yesterday, and I was severely reminded of I have been severely lacking when it comes to playing even games. There will be more on the workshop later on this week, but I&#8217;ve been looking at my games lately (from DGS and [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I had a chance to go to one of Yuan Zhou&#8217;s Monthly Go Workshops yesterday, and I was severely reminded of I have been severely lacking when it comes to playing even games. There will be more on the workshop later on this week, but I&#8217;ve been looking at my games lately (from DGS and Nova) and realized how they all consist of handicap games. This is not a bad thing by any stretch of the means, but it has certainly caused my go playing to become slightly lopsided since I&#8217;m either a lot more reckless as White or simply focused on attacking as Black. Not very good for training a calm go style you know? xD<br />
On another note, my studying has been going pretty well. I have been reading a lot of books (if it wasn&#8217;t clear as day already), and am really loving the Level Up series. As it stands right now, the only thing I regret is that I did not find this series when I first started go. I am just astounded as to how intensely they focus on the fundamentals and have already been taught a thing or two even though the book is supposedly aimed at like 15 kyus. Also, I am really trying to have entire Level Up series reviewed before the month of July is up. So though I won&#8217;t be able to play as much for now, I have plans to reincorporate ranked games back into my routine. Back to studying I go!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/need-more-even-games/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3616</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
