<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>go theory &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/go-theory/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>False Sense of Security</title>
		<link>/false-sense-of-security/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2012 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kifu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[7k]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[even game]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[go theory]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new opening]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[resignation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[victory]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[white]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=7</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[As a game progresses over time, it is very easy to lose track of the connections between your groups. After all, if you&#8217;re intently staring at the board for a long time, it&#8217;s not so far fetched to start seeing groups being connected when in fact they aren&#8217;t. In fact, if you take a quick [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: left;">As a game progresses over time, it is very easy to lose track of the connections between your groups. After all, if you&#8217;re intently staring at the board for a long time, it&#8217;s not so far fetched to start seeing groups being connected when in fact they aren&#8217;t. In fact, if you take a quick look at the kifu snapshot above, it would seem that the top black group is doing alright. Unfortunately, nothing could be further from the truth.</p>
<p><span id="more-7"></span><br />
While I&#8217;ve played a number of games recently where either I or my opponent failed to keep track of our connections, the kifu for today&#8217;s game is one that demonstrates this concept very well. As you go over the kifu, you&#8217;ll notice that for the most part, Black has done a pretty good job keeping all of his groups connected. As a result, White had to be careful about his own connections and determining whether a cut will actually work or not. Unfortunately for Black, the game progressed to a point where he got so caught up in the running battle that he failed to realize that White was aiming to disconnect his group the entire time.<br />
<strong>Remember, it&#8217;s critical that you are never lulled into a false sense of security at any point during the game</strong>. It is precisely during these times that the opponent will find the game changing move to turn the game in his/her favor.<br />
To help you avoid the false sense of security, always be sure to check on the following whenever your opponent makes a move:</p>
<ol>
<li>Are my groups alive?</li>
<li>Are my groups connected at the key locations? Or in another sense, is it easy for my opponent to cut my groups apart and get away with it?</li>
</ol>
<div>If you can answer those questions with confidence, then it is irrelevant whether your reading abilities fall short. You did the basic steps of being sensitive to your stones. The mistakes will come, and you will learn from it. By following this path, you will inevitably get stronger.</div>
<div></div>
<div>And as always, if your groups are fine, the fun part comes when seeing whether or not your opponent&#8217;s groups are prime for attack and even death.</div>
<div></div>
<div>
<div id='glift_display1' style='height:500px; width:100%; position:relative;'></div>
<script type='text/javascript'>gliftWidget = glift.create({"divId":"glift_display1","sgf":"http:\/\/bengozen.com\/\/wp-content\/uploads\/2012\/10\/2012.10.19-False-Sense-of-Security.sgf","display":{"theme":"DEFAULT","drawBoardCoords":"1"}});</script>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div align ='center'><noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view this game.</noscript> <a href='//wp-content/uploads/2012/10/2012.10.19-False-Sense-of-Security.sgf' download>Download SGF</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p></div>
<div style="text-align: center;">[download label=&#8221;Download Kifu&#8221;]//wp-content/uploads/2012/10/2012.10.19-False-Sense-of-Security.sgf[/download]</div>
<div style="text-align: center;"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Weighing Your Priorities</title>
		<link>/weighing-your-priorities/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2010 04:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[go theory]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[philosophy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[priorities]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[whole board thinking]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=111</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[So as someone who has officially left the comfort zone of school (I don&#8217;t consider grad school an umbrella to hide under anymore), one of the questions I&#8217;m hit the hardest with deals with whether or not I&#8217;m going to end up becoming a &#8220;Go junkie.&#8221; The deal is: I see Go as a pillar [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_863" style="width: 337px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img class="size-full wp-image-863" title="Priorities by xkcd" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2010/09/priorities.png?resize=337%2C276" alt="Priorities by xkcd" width="337" height="276" data-recalc-dims="1" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Priorities by xkcd</figcaption></figure>
So as someone who has officially left the comfort zone of school (I don&#8217;t consider grad school an umbrella to hide under anymore), one of the questions I&#8217;m hit the hardest with deals with whether or not I&#8217;m going to end up becoming a &#8220;Go junkie.&#8221;<br />
The deal is: I see Go as a pillar to understanding fundamental principles in life. It&#8217;s true. Go may not be the most ideal way to sustain yourself, but the life lessons that a person can derive from it is worth far more in my opinion. That is not to say that Go will be the sole focus of my life however. I&#8217;m going to job hunt, focus on spending time with people important to me, and expand other job-related skills since I&#8217;m hoping to open a business someday. Go is just something I view as critical to self-growth, so it does rank high in my priorities; but I won&#8217;t let it consume my life.<br />
For all those who are striving to live in reality right now, weigh your priorities as well. I am one of the most enthusiastic players that would encourage people using go as a tool to learning life lessons and self-improvement. However, if it gets to the point that it is damaging other portions of your life, it may be time where you ask yourself whether or not you are falling into the folly of focusing on the local battle of the board.<br />
Don&#8217;t forget that the Go board is often reflective of your life. Focusing on go alone while letting the rest of your framework go to hell will only come to haunt you later on. No different from trying to control a single corner while letting your opponent consume the rest of the board.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">111</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
