<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>awesome &#8211; BenGoZen</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/awesome/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Not your average go blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">144214914</site>	<item>
		<title>Study Session at the Local Community College</title>
		<link>/study-session-local-community-college/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2013 23:18:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[awesome]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[guessed a pro's move]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[milestone]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=3901</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[As some of you might know, I finished my Master&#8217;s a little over a year ago, so why am I at the local community college you might wonder? Well, though my girlfriend and I are working professionals, it seems that learning will be never ending for both of us and she decided to take a [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_3902" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/09/mcstudysession2.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-3902" alt="mcstudysession2" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/09/mcstudysession2.jpg?resize=300%2C157" width="300" height="157" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">For those curious ones, the books are Fight Like a Pro, Jump Level Up 2 + Answer Book, and Get Strong at Joseki 3, and the set I&#8217;m using is a portable shin-kaya board with biconvex yunzi stones in kitani bowls.</figcaption></figure>
As some of you might know, I finished my Master&#8217;s a little over a year ago, so why am I at the local community college you might wonder? Well, though my girlfriend and I are working professionals, it seems that learning will be never ending for both of us and she decided to take a class this semester. So while she&#8217;s at her class, I figured, perfect opportunity to use this time as if I&#8217;m in a go class! (If anyone is interested in joining me, be sure to let me know!)<br />
With that said, the reason I&#8217;m writing is because I am wrapping up the final chapter of Fight Like a Pro, and something funny happened. About forty moves into the kifu, the authors asked the reader to guess what move they would choose to continue the attack on the Black group. Normally with this type of question, I end up only choosing an area I think would be correct and then look at the solution. This time around however, I decided to place a stone boldly onto the board as if to declare to the world what I would have done.<br />
After turning the page, I first see that my answer is not the correct answer. It turns out my move was contrary to the principle of attacking from my weak group in order to simultaneously strengthen it. &#8220;Makes sense.&#8221; I think, but just as I&#8217;m about to look for the next move in the actual game, I see that the next move the professional chose was mine! Hardy har har!!!<br />
<a href="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/09/ogxe6.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3903" alt="ogxe6" src="https://i2.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/09/ogxe6.jpg?resize=350%2C350" width="350" height="350" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a>And with that epic moment recorded, I end this post on a high note. xD</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3901</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>New Discovery: Nova Go Server</title>
		<link>/new-discovery-nova-go-server/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2013 16:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BenGoZen]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[awesome]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[go server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[live go]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nova]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[turn based]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">//?p=2470</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[For those who have veered away from turn based go due to the antiquity of the Dragon Go Server system, I am super excited to tell you about a new go server that was introduced to me by flakeman2! Nova Go Server Here are 10 reasons why you should join me and play on Nova [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For those who have veered away from turn based go due to the antiquity of the Dragon Go Server system, I am super excited to tell you about a new go server that was introduced to me by flakeman2!</p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.nova.gs/">Nova Go Server</a></h2>
<p style="text-align: left;">Here are 10 reasons why you should join me and play on Nova Go Server!</p>
<ol>
<li><span style="line-height: 13px;"><strong>It&#8217;s a turn-based AND real time go server.</strong> So in the event both players are online, you can play moves and chat as if you were on the live go server. And then, if anyone has to leave, no problem! It becomes turn-based go just like that!</span></li>
<li><strong>It updates in real time!!!!!</strong> I don&#8217;t know about any of you, but the worst thing for me on Dragon Go Server is the fact that when both players are online at the same time, you have to keep refreshing the page in anticipation of the next move. So with Nova Go Server, I can just leave the kifu open and it&#8217;ll automatically updated whenever my opponent plays a move.</li>
<li><strong>It is a web based app!</strong> That means no downloading or installing while getting a crisp and clean interface.</li>
<li><strong>It has features that Dragon Go Server lacks.</strong> Example: Planning conditional moves so that you can save moves that you know you will play in the event your opponent plays X.</li>
<li><strong>You can login using social media.</strong> Although a small benefit, it&#8217;s nice being able to login with my Twitter account instead of having to manage another go server account. (And FYI, for anyone looking to play with me, you can find me under my usual username: bengozen).</li>
<li><strong>It&#8217;s actively being developed!</strong> This means that the technology and features are still being updated and you can actually look forward to seeing actual updates!</li>
<li><strong>The user interface is so much cleaner!!</strong> You have a notifications button on top that updates real time, a sleek modern menu on the top for easy navigation, great user interface for how to play moves or access certain features&#8230;. THIS IS SO EXCITING!!!!!!!</li>
<li><strong>There is a spectator chat window!</strong> So people can come in and kibitz on your game for your review when the game is over! (This is something I miss when it comes to turn based go on Dragon Go Server).</li>
<li><strong>They even offer a Malkovich Log!</strong> This is not a feature I&#8217;ve ever used, but I know it&#8217;s really popular so another kudos to them!</li>
<li><strong>Oh yeah, did I mention that IT&#8217;S FREE!!!!!!!!!! </strong></li>
</ol>
<p><a href="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/04/nuffsaid.jpeg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2471" alt="nuffsaid" src="https://i1.wp.com/bengozen.com//wp-content/uploads/2013/04/nuffsaid.jpeg?resize=300%2C200" width="300" height="200" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">&#8216;Nuff said.</h2>
]]></content:encoded>
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2470</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
